All right, Mark, what's happening, man?
Hey, tim.erg.
Yeah, I'm doing pretty well. Beautiful
weather out here in Colorado. How about
yourself?
I'm doing well. I've been super busy.
Just moved back to New Mexico a little
while ago, so still organizing my life.
But overall, pretty good, brother.
Nice, nice. Yeah, I'm about to move. I
just packed everything up in the pod.
About to ship that off here today to
Florida. I'm about to be in it.
Yeah, dude. We got some cool stuff going
on around ERG. I see we got a hackathon
coming up. You want to talk about that a
little bit? I don't actually know that
much about it. I haven't had time.
Yeah, certainly. So there's the, I think
it's the ErgoHack 9. It is on enhancing
user experience and user experience
innovations and UX. This is really
confusing to read, sorry. Enhancing user
experience innovations in UI, UX and
mining. I think it's because it has user
experience in there twice with the UX.
It's in any case. So whether you are UI
and UX designer, front end developer,
blockchain enthusiast or mining expert,
this event offers the chance to
collaborate, learn and create. And so
yeah, highly, highly recommend, even if
it's just like sort of a white paper,
putting some ideas on paper. I think it's
great to get feedback. It looks like
there's a schedule this time to where
there's going to be a workshop, several
workshops. So workshop on the first day,
seems like every day in between, even some
Q and A, whereas I don't think that's been
the case before. That's great.
I like the workshop idea. So that's just
like how the community is, right? It's
like, people just, if someone's willing to
work on something and learn, everyone will
help you kind of do it.
Yeah, totally. I mean, you just got to
show the initiative because I mean, I
think oftentimes someone would be like,
hey, I have this cool idea. Let me hand it
off to you. And it's like, dude, people
are already working on stuff. So it's
like, and maybe you don't have time and
that's fine, right? But if you do have
time and it is your idea, maybe there
needs to be some more pillars, right? To
help support you and the community will
come in and do that, right? They've done
that with me for sure. And then from
there, you can kind of have your own
support and then kind of go on your own
sort of, whatever you're trying to do.
Like me and Tim, I talked to Tim yesterday
about creating a dApp. And so yeah, I
think the Ergo hacks are great, great
opportunity for people to kind of just to
figure out the ecosystem to one, be able
to ask for help because the whole event is
to sort of do development. And so it's a
perfect opportunity to be able to ask for
help and to get help.
Yeah, that's cool. And I think UI UX is a
really good place for us to invest some
time and energy. I'm just imagining some
of the dApps are like, the bones are
there. It's really cool. But yeah, just to
take that next level. I'm just thinking of
just the ones I've used the most like
DuckPools is like almost there. It's the
dApp side into the back end. It's working.
And then just like that next little level
to make us on par with really the top top
chains.
What do they have exactly? Sorry, not to
cut you off. But what do they have?
Because I always hear that, oh, well, the
Ergo dApps, they don't have the user
interface or the user experience that
we're kind of used to. Like, can you
explain what is sort of like the vibe and
feel that when people say that, what are
we talking about, I guess, in more like
words?
Yeah, sure. So, okay, I will preface this
by saying, I think DuckPools is awesome.
And I don't mean this to be like any
cutting criticism. But so things I've seen
before is just like, really clear
indication of when I might be liquidated.
And just little things like that, or I've
seen... There was one app called Balancer
on Ethereum, and I thought this was really
cool. It was like, you could just create
your own pool, and it's more than just two
coins. So you could set up a whole
portfolio. I want 15% this, 20% that, and
just build the whole pool. And that will
maintain your the proportion of all your
positions and then route trades through
your pool to help balance that as prices
change. Which is sick. And so but just
like setting it up was just very, very
easy. And I was able to get more
information about my positions.
Gotcha. Okay, so kind of like an
understanding of like what it's doing, why
it's doing it, and then like maybe why you
would want to do it. I kind of, I guess
less of like clicking buttons, I guess,
right?
Yeah, yeah, just like a polished
dashboard. And I felt like I had all the
information that I needed to make
decisions right away. And I guess I
wouldn't say that's true of everything in
Ergo, right? Like, SigmaFi, all the info
is right there. It's good. I kind of like
it. There's maybe some other things.
Sometimes there's a lot of loans that show
up in SigmaFi. Being able to kind of
filter those might be cool, might be a
little bit better, or I'm excited about,
what is it, the proposals currently kind
of go one direction, so you might make a
loan request. I think they're going to
implement a lend request as well. Which is
interesting and helpful.
Yeah. OK. Yeah. I mean, so that's really
good feedback, because I mean, for
somebody who does want to do something in
the UI UX ErgoHack, right. So now if
you're going to design something right,
take some of what Tim was saying here and
integrate that sort of into your design,
because I mean, I think totally right,
especially with blockchain needs to be
simple, clean, concise. Doesn't need to
have like all this sort of stuff sort of
happening, I guess, in the background. And
then, but I mean, even I know from making
the Sigmanauts mining dashboard, at some
point, though, it's like, all right, this
is too much. But also, I cannot not have
this metric. And so there's got to be a
definitely a balance. But I'm glad I'm not
really a UI person, because that's a lot.
Yeah, I think something I keep hearing is
we need to get to the point where people
don't realize they're using the
blockchain. And I think that's probably a
great benchmark to hit. It's like, oh, no,
I'm just doing banking or I'm just using
this application that I need to do my
business. Totally. I'm not to feel like a
hacker.
Right, and then and that even comes up
with like, or comes back to sort of like,
okay, so the user interface, what is that?
Should that even have like tons of crypto
feel? Right? Should have these crypto
tokens. And I know some of the Ethereum
sort of wallets and stuff. And they got
these crazy headers, things are bouncing.
It's like a, you're like at a casino kind
of a thing. And it's just like, hey, I'm
just trying to buy a token or something
like that. So yeah, definitely, again,
more you have really good feedback,
because I mean, you're totally right,
right? Like, if I was going to buy, if
somebody was going to legit buy a loan
that's backed by a blockchain, or not a
loan, or it could be a loan, a loan or
insurance, whatever, they want to make
sure again, that's trustworthy, it's
reputable. And then a lot of this other
crypto stuff meme coins and stuff has like
sort of a bad connotation to it. So
definitely got to be choosy with the
audience demographic words verbiage.
Yeah, and the symbols like I always was
kind of taken aback by the food themed
everything. Like, I guess like, sushi swap
is kind of huge now. And nobody even
thinks about it as like a food thing, but
then we, now we have SundaeSwap and
PancakeSwap on, come on about that.
Yeah. All the toasty swap. I think that's
a food, right? Yeah, there's a lot. Yeah.
Yeah, totally. So it's like, and that's
even kind of going to some of the Ergo, I
guess, manifesto and stuff, like in the
sense of like, we're trying to be unique.
We're trying to do our own thing, trying
to pave our own path, I suppose. Yeah.
I guess something I wanted to bring up
and I guess a good point here. It's okay
if people just kind of have some fun too.
We have a new dApp called MewFinance. Have
you seen that?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I bought some
cyberverse emotes on it.
I bought some honey.
Oh, okay. Yeah.
Yeah, awesome. I bought some honey. So I
don't know when that's coming in. But I
thought it was a pretty cool. A pretty
cool use. Like it was actually really
easy. I didn't feel didn't feel janky at
all. Yeah, excuse that stuff cooking for
sure. Yeah, I just I mean, I just like
bought food off the internet from somebody
I don't know. So that's like a little bit
of a risk. But we'll see. We'll see. I'll
give it the smell test.
Yeah, yeah, I'm excited to see where this
goes. I was talking to qx(), he wants to
do sort of like a hash rate system or not
hash rate system, a GPU system where we
can buy and sell them. And then we can
escrow them. And so we'll test them to
make sure they're good. And then we're in
all those details and stuff. So it's just
like, kind of started from like the
Sigmanauts swag where that qx() got for
Vegas and then now it's like become this
and so I'm pretty excited to see like
maybe a year from now it becomes like this
just diverse on-chain real world asset
sort of ecosystem of just like buying and
selling stuff and then the mining pool we
might get linked up in there and so then
we could be like Oh, that cup of honey or
the jar of honey, whatever. I want to mine
that. But it takes me two weeks to mine
however much you bought it for say, but
it'll be like a layaway sort of thing. So
I mean, there's just so many different
applications to be able to use this sort
of thing, especially if shipping is
cheaper if you can get around like deport
or the taxes. But that's I don't know.
Yeah, dude, I think it's cool. And
something I remember, I think it was a TED
talk a while ago, a guy was just like
getting into the black market and just
like seeing what he could buy several
years ago. And one of the things that he
learned was that when it's like this open
market, reputation is literally
everything. And so the quality control
that people implement on these open
markets is really high, because all they
have is the reviews. And there's not this
barrier of entry that protects people. So
when I go to Smith's or whatever and I get
rotten grapefruits, it's a recent
experience. It doesn't matter if I go
bitch them out because nobody else is
selling grapefruit. But on an open market,
your reputation is everything and there is
competition because the barrier of entry
is very low. Right. So that to me just
really vibes with Ergo's whole philosophy
and my own.
100% man. I mean, and now like, if you
make if you can have like a little hobby
that does something like you make key
chains, you can sell those key chains
straight out of your house. Now, start to
build a brand in some aspects, join the
Sigmanauts do it for the Sigmanauts. Like,
yeah, man, there's gonna be a lot more
grassroots I feel like can maybe happen
now. Whereas early on it's like, the idea
is cool and it's like nebulous, but how
can I help? And then as we kind of move
forward, sort of, it's like a river and
it's like slowly growing and then, and
then that like is affecting the ability or
the applicability of the technology and
then usability too, I suppose. And so now
it can like affect more people. And so,
like you were saying earlier, where it's
like, what if someone can buy something on
MewFinance, buy it with dollars, switch to
ERG, do all that stuff in the back end,
not even know they're using the crypto,
and then just know that, like, oh,
MewFinance is this like peer to peer
system, it's got a reputation system, and
I'm going to trust it, as opposed to this
other stuff. And then, yeah, that's just
so cool.
Yeah. So, another thing kind of taking
steps forward is Rosen. Do you see what's
going on there?
Yeah, right. They've crossed the bridge
to Ethereum. I haven't seen any bots pop
up on X or anything, so that's been good.
But yeah, exciting, right?
Yeah, yeah. Not a ton of LP over there
yet, but I saw like a screenshot of the
last, I don't know, 24 hours of volume and
like there's ERG is getting picked up on
that side and. It's just out of an
exciting first little day of activity over
there.
Yeah. And I think someone started an Ergo
raffle too. So you can afford the
liquidity and there's some stuff. So I'm
not sure if that's still going on, but
definitely check that out.
Yeah. You can, he'll give you your LP
tokens, right? Is that? Yeah, I think so.
Something like that. So I really wonder
how that's all going to work out because
I, I guess as soon as somebody is
interacting with both chains, they're just
going to realize it is like 1% the cost to
operate on Ergo. Like you could make a
position, take it away, do a different
one, take it away. But in ETH, you just
have to be really sure that what you're
doing is correct, because it costs you $17
to do something. And unless you're putting
in thousands of dollars, it's not even
worth it. Right.
So you think the ecosystem will start to
see more Ethereum-related apps? Or I guess
it's made on Ergo, but for Ethereum? Do
you think those apps will start to be
created.
I didn't get that. Maybe. Maybe. I think
either it'll be large positions of ERG on
the Ethereum side where the fees are worth
it. Or people from ETH are going to be
like, oh, this is maybe nice over here.
And so I don't know if they would just
bring their ETH over or would they pick up
ERG? Probably they would want to keep
their ETH. I don't know if they would
invest in a coin that they didn't fully
understand. It's just going to be
interesting to see.
Yeah, yeah, because I guess like, now
what's the incentive? The incentive is now
here for Ethereum developers, right? It's
like, you don't have to just be an Ergo
developer and just to support Ergo. Be an
Ethereum developer, come over here, use
our TX fees, right? And then do whatever
you need to do on our chain and then
facilitate it back over to Ethereum. Or
just keep it in Ergo because you can have
the RSV asset and so I they've been
pumping out a lot of those so and I'm not
really too keen on I guess the Ethereum
ecosystem but it would be an interesting
sort of idea to kind of even for like a
hackathon to sort of attach on sort of
dApps for other chains, but they're on
Ergo, I mean, similar to Rosen Bridge, I
guess, but to save in those fees. So and
then be able to swap back or whatever the
case.
Yeah, it'll be interesting to see how
people use it. I I'm also interested in
like, how are the other tokens, like you
mentioned all the tokens from ADA, like
SundaeSwap tokens are now on Ethereum.
What are the consequences of that going to
be? Who knows?
Yeah, yeah, now those tokens are
susceptible to like all the bullshit in
terms of like, or not bullshit, but just
like, potentially getting locked on
Ethereum, right? Or like stolen on
Ethereum or, whatever people, like we were
just talking about people developing
stuff. Well, all that is still, all that
stuff that has happened to Ethereum is
still maybe gonna be applied and now maybe
new attack vectors for specific tokens are
now open, right? Because they're on, I
mean, arbitrage, right? That's a new thing
because now we have all this, and it's
almost like an oracle in and of its own
sense, right? Because the oracle rate
isn't just catching up fast enough because
people aren't exchanging, buying and
selling on these individual sort of island
of tokens and stuff. So it's going to be
interesting to watch the landscape kind of
is it a weevil wobble tilting towards one
maybe crypto, hopefully Ergo, right? Or is
it gonna be balanced or is it, how's it
gonna look, right?
Yeah. How interesting. I'm excited for
the rest of the crypto sphere to get
connected. They're talking about Binance
chain. Yeah. I don't know much about Sui,
but I saw that come up. I'm really
interested to see Monero get connected.
They're waiting on a major update that's
happening there. And then that might be a
priority. Yeah, that would be sweet.
What do you like in terms of privacy that
Monero, I think we talked about it a
little bit before, but what do you like
about Monero specifically that maybe Ergo
doesn't have?
I think that it's necessary to have an
option that is, so privacy is optional on
Ergo. And I think that's probably the most
widely usable way, I guess. How do I say?
If you're building something for everyone,
privacy should be optional, not mandatory,
but I think everyone should have a choice
to use Monero because it's like 100%
private by design, like in the core
protocol. And I don't want to say 100%
private because nothing's 100% private,
but that level of privacy is just there,
and it's simple for people. Whereas for
us, it's like, oh, we have to download the
front end for the mixer and do these
steps. There's a little bit of a barrier.
And people might not prefer that. And I
think if you could just, oh, I'll just
bridge to Monero and then make a
transaction and then bridge back to a new
wallet. mixed.
Okay, I see what you're saying. So you're
suggesting maybe taking your funds,
bridging them to Monero, then do the whole
privacy and then maybe bridge back again
from Rosen Bridge, but then to a new Ergo
wallet and then go from there, right?
Maybe. Yeah, yeah, that's something that
could happen. And it could also happen the
other way where Monero is like, oh, I have
all this Monero and I want to borrow
against my Monero. and accessed proper
DeFi, that's not quite possible there on
Monero.
Yeah, no, that's a great point. And then
like to that point, right, if you think
about the total crypto market cap, right,
from a loan perspective, it's like we've
got all this money to loan out. Because
people are probably just sitting on their
bags and stuff. And so using DeFi and Ergo
as that sort of ability, like you're
saying, DuckPools is awesome. I love
DuckPools, participated in the IDEO
yesterday. But yeah, having that
capability and, again, going back to
trustworthiness, it's like, okay, yeah,
I'll give out some of my ERGs to loan out
or whatever the case, SigmaUSD when that
was popping. We were looking at a thing
this last weekend, man, it was like 40% or
20%. That's crazy. It's dropped a lot.
Yeah. Oh, man, it was really high for a
while. It was like, 60s, like 70% like it
was it was high. It was 120% at one point.
Yeah, dude.
It's 2.5 right now.
Interesting how interesting you would
think people would be like going long now.
Right? Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's kind
of weird for sure. Maybe they all got
wiped out. Yeah, right. Nobody else has
any funds. That's why it's just stayed
around like 65 cents, 70 cents. Yeah.
Yeah. I was just waiting for Bitcoin to
carry the way it carry us through. Right.
The wave.
Yeah. All right. So hey, I had a couple
other things for us to talk about. So
something that I came across when I first
joined Ergo was called Metal Saturdays.
And I just thought this is so cool. Have
you seen Metal Saturdays?
No, I haven't.
I saw kushti say, hey, can I get proof of
metal? And so everybody started just
sharing their YouTube links for their
favorite metal songs or just whatever they
were jamming that day. And it's kind of
every Saturday. I say Saturday, but it's
like a UTC type of thing. So like, I don't
know if it's Friday or Saturday. And every
week I probably, you probably see like 20
or so links to, I don't know, just
somebody's Lamb of God or, whatever they
got going on.
What channel is that happening in?
Just the main one, just the main one.
It's every now and then somebody will
start it off. There's a guy named MX, you
know MX. No, he's one of the OGs. He's, I
think he's kind of the anchor and kushti
as well. And then we'll see, cafe and all
the people who've been here for a long
time and like throwing their stuff in. I
just thought it was cool. Like when I
first started in crypto. everyone was
serious. Not serious, but it's about this
thing. And then I just got to see actual
culture emerge from this thing. And it's
like, oh, these are humans. These are
humans. And they like to rock.
Do you like something else that I like?
Oh, that's awesome. Yeah.
Totally. Yeah.
I'm not a big fan of metal, I would say.
But I will listen to it. I'm a big fan of
reggae. Oh, yeah. like 311. I'm like
blanking at all the bands right now.
Revolution, Irish.
Cool, man. Yeah, yeah. I would say I'm
not like a metal fan either. Like, there's
a time and a place.
Yeah, absolutely. Yeah, we can start a
reggae Sundays. Yeah, any case, that'd be
funny.
So that kind of inspired me to start
something a while ago. I don't know how
long it's been. But so I started a channel
called the Ergo Fight Club. And it's not
terribly popular. But so every every
Saturday or like every other Saturday, any
Saturday that there's a fight, there's a
group of maybe there's probably like eight
of us that we just hop on the chat anytime
there's a UFC event or like maybe a
headline boxing match or something. We got
the tipper bot in there. So we're, betting
one ERG here and there on who it is. And I
think this next big event, I think in
November, we're going to do like a parlay,
like, you're going to pick, we're going to
pick the whole card. the outcome and
whoever has the most correct guesses is
gonna take the pot.
There you go. That sounds like fun. Well,
yeah. Where can people find out about
that? Cause I know they have like that big
list of like all the groups, but I don't
think I've, I don't think I'm in there.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You should get that out
and talk to Glasgow or something.
I will. I will. Yeah. Every now and then
I'll put it out on, on Twitter just to
like, see if anyone wants to join, or in
the main one. But every time we do it on
Twitter, you would pick up like seven bots
and then have to just remove it.
Yeah, that's how it goes, I guess. Yeah,
I put it in the main because Ergo platform
one.
Yeah. But yeah, so that was me just
trying to contribute after seeing like,
Metal Saturdays, like people just doing
the thing that they like. And then turns
out there's a bunch of people that enjoy
the fights too. So yeah, so crazy thing
happened actually. So got to talking with
one of the guys there. And I won't say who
it is just for privacy. Turns out that me
and him trained at the same gym in like
2011. Like we were definitely training at
the same gym at the same time in
Albuquerque, New Mexico.
Oh, wow.
And like, that's as far as it went. We
didn't see each other. We don't live in
the same state. And it was just like, oh,
I was there. I trained there for three
years. I was like, oh, yeah, me too.
And like, that's as far as it went, you
know, we didn't like, did you guys
recognize each other after like, you saw
each other again, or?
That's so funny. Yeah, it's funny how
that all works. That's hilarious. Small
world. Yeah, absolutely. You're like, oh,
I can't remember if I kicked your butt or
not, but I definitely did. No. That's
awesome. No, that's super sick. Have you
talked to CannonQ about some of this?
Because he's developing a dApp called The
Field. And then you'll be able to do the
parlay stuff on chain.
and bedding and stuff. I'm super excited.
So I really, I was really disappointed
when Night Owl casino didn't pan out. And
I saw Jay around actually recently, but I
didn't bring anything up, but I was super
disappointed because I wanted the sports
betting. Like that's a killer dApp. and
I'm really glad that CannonQ picked it up
and just looking forward to it. Tipper
bot's cool. Sorry, Lou. But this will be
better.
Yeah, for sure. So how do you guys do the
tipper bot? You just say, hey, I'll take
this bet. Someone's like, all right,
agreed. And then whoever wins or loses,
wins or loses. Then you're like, all
right, tip it out, one ERG or whatever.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We just keep it
small. That way it's never like, you know.
Yeah, absolutely. Absolutely. Yeah. No,
that's a lot of things. That's a lot of
fun. I mean, especially to like if you
had, like with CannonQ's app, like get
something integrated to where you can just
put, connect to your credit card,
translate some ERGs, and then again, going
back to you're not even know this user's
crypto.
Yeah, that'll be cool. So I was thinking,
it's on the topic of culture and
principles. Some of the apps that I've
seen, I just thought it was so cool when I
first was exploring Ergo. It was like the
Ergo Lend or EXLE. And they've kind of set
up this, I guess, relationship. They've
built a relationship with people in Kenya,
just kind of regularly take out some 0%
loans and they pay it back and then they
take another one and they pay. I mean, to
me that just really underscores the power
of what this is capable of doing. And I'm
excited to see it grow. I don't know
anyone in Kenya, but one of the guys
that's around for a long time, his name is
Riro. Do you know Riro?
I've heard the name.
Yeah, he's he's in Mumbai. And just like,
nice guy in Mumbai just sends pictures of
like, what he's making for dinner or
whatever. And it's cool. It's like, this
is benefit him or people like him. Totally
see an actual change.
Yeah, yeah, for sure. Finance and kind of
benefiting us and more of a like you're
saying cultural ecosystems kind of raise
everybody up by the bootstraps rather than
just like a select few.
Yeah, yeah. And then that that kind of
gives gets into like the local exchange
trading system. Have you come across that
yet?
Okay, no, I haven't heard of that one
then.
So LETS is like a circular economy. So it
will kind of be a dApp. And it's kind of
like ChainCash maybe. I think ChainCash is
maybe more of an open ecosystem where you
can have something as collateral and then
you can lend your token or send your token
backed by that. And then you can always
somebody can always redeem the token for
the collateral. And ChainCash also has
this aspect where like the next person can
have collateral. And so the tokens are
actually backed by everyone's collateral
eventually. Okay. And that I think has
like, bigger implications like a country
or a state might like, I have all this oil
and I want to issue a coin against it. So
people can interact. But LETS is more like
small. So let's say if you had like, I
don't know, just like a little village or
something and you needed a system for
accounting, that's it, right? It's like,
here's the tokens. They could have it be
backed by something. And it's just like,
for them to monitor. And it's actually an
old idea, local exchange trading system,
it's been done a bunch of times. But now
it's like, with this technology, and, you
bring up all the other stuff, NIPoPoWs,
and whatever. It's like, yeah, anyone can
do this. Like you just need like a tiny
bit of internet and you're good to go.
Yeah, that's pretty powerful. I think I
did see LETS on like, one of the EIPs.
They were talking about like, some dApps
and like suitable ways to like mock them
up. But yeah, I mean, again, bringing real
world, applications is going to be huge
and where blockchains really shows its
strength are these applications to where
you can loan out somebody on a good faith
loan. Yeah here Don't worry about any of
the interest but know that you're going to
get paid back There is collateral
collected within the blockchain. So if
they don't pay you back, that sucks, but
there are things kind of in place to kind
of facilitate that And be able to kind of
you know, I guess in a sense, siphon some
of our wealth off into these other places.
And then again, just start to bolster up
these other economies. That'd be cool to
see. Yeah, man. Probably be some years
before it's all like out the wild, but
yeah, probably more dApps, easier to use,
like you were saying, from a real world,
I'm curious how they would actually use it
though in Africa. Right. And then like
connected to all on chain, and then like
how many computers did they have access
to? And then like, so what sort of dApp
would be even optimal to facilitate that?
And then, of course, replicating it and
stuff. Yeah, I think probably are, yeah,
indeed, some time away just because I
think we're still igleys and Ergo's kind
of facilitating the, I think that we have
dApps right but I think we're on the verge
of just like explosive dApps and sense of
like, we have a lot of them, or they have
a lot of punch not the not to say that the
ones don't now but. I think we're
attracting more people to the ecosystem,
especially with the Ergo hacks and things
like that. And so hopefully we'll start to
see more and more of these types of
applications. I know with the good things
that qx(), wants to do more lending and do
things like that. So that'll be really
neat. I wonder what he's doing with that.
We'll have to ask him next time he's on.
Yeah.
Yeah. So anyways, that's my list of
topics for today. You have anything else
you want to chat about?
I don't know. That's all good on my end.
I need to get back to it. The boxes are
calling. Not the UTXO boxes.
Best of luck with that, man. Drive safe
and don't let your cat cause an accident.
Absolutely. All right. Take care. See you
everybody.