Hello and welcome to the weekly Ergo AMA.
Today with me, we have, wait, what's your
name? I forgot.
Hey guys, I'm MGPai. Super excited to be
on again.
MGPai, aren't you that guy that was
working on Ergo names?
Yeah.
How's that going?
It's such an intricate project. I bet.
We're just busting it right off the bat.
What's new? What's new?
I've been trying to get some work in for
Ergo names. I definitely want to finish it
off. I just been really busy with school.
We just had midterm midterms and all. So
we have Thanksgiving coming up in the US
in about a week and a half. So hoping to
use that time to get more involved again
in Ergo names, but we have Thanksgiving
and Christmas. So I'm pretty confident I
can finish it then because all our smart
contracts are done. It's just off chain
stuff, getting the contracts to run
itself. And that's all already has
progress on it. So hopefully we can have
that going.
So it'll be a nice little Christmas
present you're saying.
That's my hope.
Fantastic. Fantastic. What else is new?
How's Palmyra? How's ZenGate? How's all
that cross-chain business going with
commodities and trading of them?
Yeah, it's going pretty well. A lot of
progress. We keep onboarding new
developers and scaling, because there's
just so much work to be done and so many
opportunities to seize with RWAs. It's
quite popular, especially in this new
cycle right. A lot of people are realizing
that RWAs are really the path for real
world utility and involvement rather than
just NFTs itself right. Something a little
more beneficial so yeah, a lot of progress
is being done. I think the community will
be really happy. Again, I don't know how
much I can say, it's not my control so
I'll just leave it at that.
You're not gonna pull a Tom Holland and
give away everything after me. That's
right, that can be pretty scary can it?
Dan's probably no, he sees a wake. I'm
sure right now. It's pretty early over
there. Nice nice. Well, what do you think
of the... are we in a bull?
Oh yeah, it's pretty cool to see Bitcoin
go across 90k, right? Again, it's always
kind of weird though, right? From like
2022 or 2021, where alts were also
pumping. It's really just Bitcoin. Little
liquidity, I guess, started to flow into
altcoins, but it's still not significant,
which is very surprising. Hopefully, we'll
see at least something, right? When
Bitcoin crossed its original all-time high
from 2020, it was still pretty, it was
very stagnant the altcoins, but now at
least we are seeing something like 10%
20%. So yeah, so maybe it's the small
spark to something.
10% 20% on what?
Like across most altcoins.
Yeah, well, I would say Ergo's performing
quite a bit better than that. Yes. Yeah,
but on average I would say probably that
yeah. Yeah, so it'll be interesting to see
when that if it's gonna keep on kind of a
trickle in flow or it's gonna be a season
again where it just spanks out and you're
like, whoa, there it goes kind of thing.
Exactly. Who knows, but very happy with
the Ergo movement right now coming back to
what the price was about a year ago and...
So hopefully the community can take
advantage of this momentum. I'm very happy
Rosen is doing that. I've been talking to
Joe a lot about the progress for Rosen. We
have Dogecoin coming up and I don't know
if you guys follow the US news, but it
seems that Trump has opened a new
department called Department of Government
efficiency DOGE. So that's quite
something. So I'm sure Dogecoin will pump
in the future.
Yeah, I think it's up from 11 cents to 30
some cents last time I checked or
something. So it's already three times.
Absolutely. But we're gonna take
advantage of that right. We're gonna go to
DOGE right and... Again, it's just like
Bitcoin, so people don't have much to do
there. So maybe we can convince them to
leverage the Rosen Bridge and do something
on other ecosystems with their Dogecoins.
And then we're also getting Binance Smart
Chain. And now I think you will start to
see more fun. We've been seeing some
transfers to Ethereum, but the problem is
it's very expensive. So having on Binance
Smart Chain allows you for a very similar
environment with high liquidity, but much,
much, much cheaper fees.
And another cool thing I realized is
Alephium has their Binance Smart Chain
bridge also coming out. So it might even
be possible to interact with Alephium
through each other's chains because I
think they can also bridge native assets.
And since Rosen already bridges native
assets, maybe it's possible to go to
Alephium without using Rosen, using
whatever bridge infrastructure they have,
since they both connect to Binance Smart
Chain. So that's interesting. I've been
talking to some people, but that would be
pretty cool to have working. I think
definitely these UTXO blockchains needs to
work closer together, since there's just
so few of them with less liquidity these
days. So I think that'll be fun to see.
Yeah, and I think once, I don't want to
say more mainstream, but once people get
used to the fact of crypto isn't just
going to something like Robinhood on your
phone and clicking and not having your own
custody of your assets, and they get used
to that, it's not going to be instant. I
think it's going to be a long time before
that happens. You'll see, I think you'll
see a big spread out of liquidity across
these decentralized bridges. That's where
Rosen's goal is. So that's the hope I
mean.
I think it's good that there are things
like central exchanges around for people
who want that comfort, but I think in
order for the survival and the
sustainability and the kind of
unstoppable-ness of crypto, there has to
be a healthy liquidity and a healthy
amount of things like Uniswap, like those
kind of decentralized exchanges. Yeah, for
sure. Yeah. Otherwise it's like, no, we
don't feel like interacting with you,
MGPai. Sorry. Or we don't like a country
of origin that this person's from. Nope.
That's it. Bye bye kind of thing. So yeah.
I mean, exchanges certainly already do
that with US citizens. Right.
Right. Yeah. I was trying to, speaking of
that, I was trying to give a little plug
out for Cyberverse right now. Cyberverse,
as some of you know, are working a lot
cross-chain. So they've moved to Cardano.
They are now working on the gaming chain,
trying to get in there. It's called Ronin.
And there's a vote up on the Ronin Discord
right now. In order to be part of that,
you have to have some Ronin in your Ronin
wallet and connect it to the Discord, and
then you can vote in Discord kind of
thing. Discord DAO, I guess. Joe Arminio
likes to call them. So I downloaded the
Ronin app to support Cyberverse and I
clicked the buy fiat, buy from fiat button
directly, you know. It's gonna put in my
card and I was like, nah, sorry here in
the U.S. Womp womp.
Yeah, so common.
So I just pinged Dan this morning. I was
like, Dan, can you send me a couple ADA so
that I can simple swap them over to Ronin
and then vote for those guys? So I suggest
if any of you guys have heard of
Cyberverse, if you're up for supporting an
amazing Ergo project that's actually a
really fun game too, it's really simple.
Just download a Ronin wallet, join the
Discord and use Simple Swap to go from ADA
to Ronin. You can do a very small amount.
You can do like 20 ADA and you'll get a
handful of Ronin on the other side and
then you can vote for them in the Discord.
I think they're aiming to be in the top
13. And I think they're teetering on that.
So any support here...
Yeah, let's help them out. Yeah.
Would be very, very helpful. Yeah. Oh,
thanks. You have ADA? Of course. He told
me you didn't. I'm just kidding.
And what was I going to say earlier
about... what were we talking about?
Liquidity. I can't remember. What's new in
the Sigmanauts? We have, if some of you
have noticed, we found a guy from the
drama a couple of weeks ago. We found a
guy that came forward and was like, hey,
I'll help you run the account. And that's
SuperGeometry. He is doing an amazing job
at the Sigmanauts Twitter. So if you guys
are seeing that and appreciating that,
please interact with that account and talk
to it. I think he's done a post almost
every day now, good posts, gives
giveaways, those kind of things. He's also
put up a vote for, I think, 100 ERGs
giveaway per month, so he can kind of
design these giveaways to get engagement
on that platform and get people
interacting. So that's really awesome,
very active. I'm trying to repost as much
as I can from the main account that is
suitable, but yeah, so that's fun.
We are also in the midst of getting a new
multisig in the Sigmanauts. The issue with
the current multisig is it's made up of
early members and those early members are
not always in the ecosystem hanging out.
So when we want to do a transaction it
takes quite a while. I think this last one
took two weeks and it failed because we
weren't on the same version of Minotaur.
MGPai that reminds me. Where's Minar? What
is it? Minar Finance? What's the name of
it?
It's Moria.
Moria Finance, where's Moria? Is it ready
for us? Come on. Moria Finance, for those
that don't know, is a very awesome web
interface for multisig. It's kind of like
a Cardano roundtable, if you guys have
seen that, but it's very simple. You go
there, you connect your own wallet, which
is your own part of the multisig, and then
you put in other wallets and they can go
there, they can connect and sign, and it
does like a round robin. It lets you know
who's next and that kind of thing. So it's
a really cool project for, you did for
ErgoHack, two ErgoHacks ago?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, two ErgoHacks ago,
yeah, yeah. I would definitely maybe
that'll be Easter or something. I think
possible work or Christmas because I need
Nautilus like an updated version of
Nautilus and Nemo has been working on it
and... So I think it should be out pretty
soon. I don't know if you guys have been
following, but Captain Nemo has been doing
a lot of updates for Nautilus as well.
It's really, really good now. Especially
the UI, the transaction history, and now
even better transaction submissions called
chained transactions. So we're definitely
getting upgrades and it's preparing for
sub-blocks. They've been doing really good
work. So I think they've been a bit busy
trying to do my interaction because it's
very cryptography heavy, which is boring
for anyone. But I think they'll have it.
So Nemo told me that they'll get on it.
The new version will show incoming
transactions that you can then send before
they're even out of the mempool, right?
You can chain transactions. So something
can come in and you can be like, oh crap,
I sent it to the wrong one.
That's perfect. Yeah. I mean, developers
could always do that, but we need a
better, we need a good interface so anyone
can do that, right? Exactly. That's the
challenge.
Yep. Yeah, that is neat. So the multisig
we put in a vote to Paideia to have some
new multisig members that are very active
Sigmanauts. I believe it's Luivatra, CW,
Mark the Shark, Jake the Snake, and
CannonQ. We had CW like just Jake's and
CannonQ myself. And I think that's at
least seven of us. So once that vote
passes, it should pass later today, I
believe, unless a big no brigade comes up,
we'll create the multisig in a little
ceremony with wine and cheese, maybe some
sausage. And then we'll send one big
transaction from the old multisig to the
new one.
And then we'll talk about, eventually,
the eventual goal, guys, is that we fully
rely on Paideia. But as Paideia is just
moving out of beta into non-beta, you
know, production, it's still, we only hold
maybe a couple thousand ERGs in there just
to be safe in case something really bad
happens. Like I think in the beta guys we
had a vote going on and I made the vote
and luckily, I didn't attach any money to
it as a reason. Well, I guess that
wouldn't have mattered but I made the vote
and it... And Louie didn't use, he used a
greater than sign instead of a greater
than less than equation. So the vote could
never reach consensus because I set it to,
oh, that's what I did. I made a vote that
would change the configs to have more of a
consensus. And Louie wrote us immediately,
he was like, guys, that's going to break
your DAO. Because you're never gonna be
able to get any money out of it because
you're never gonna be able to get greater
than a hundred essentially. And so the new
version that he wrote actually has a
greater than less than there so you can do
those kind of things and they shouldn't
fail.
But yeah, so we're just being cautious
there. Once we fully trust that, you'll
see most of our funds flow into Paideia
there for that kind of group management as
opposed to something happening on Paideia
and if it's more than a couple thousand
ERGs we need to pay out or a special token
that we have in the treasury then it's up
to the manual multisig there to say yes
we're seeing the vote and we're going to
obey the vote and go from there. So yeah
soon, super super exciting. Love Paideia.
I guess we should talk. What's that? It's
awesome. It's awesome that Paideia is out.
I think it's been in development for
almost three years, right? Two and a half,
three years. So that's a really big
milestone, especially for Luivatra and the
team behind it.
Yeah. Well, let's talk about real quick
the announcement yesterday about ErgoPad,
right? Marty is kind of winding down at
least his oversight of ErgoPad and
Coinecta. I believe both IDO platforms on
Cardano and Ergo. And I was talking to you
last night about it. I think Ergo is...
So, I don't know what the term for is it,
but we have so many options on how to
non-KYC these kind of token launches that
Paideia, not Paideia, ErgoPad and Coinecta
I imagine have a tough time competing with
that kind of thing. You can come in, you
can lock your tokens, do some other stuff.
We're working on SigmaLock with you guys
as well, which you can do it through. It's
just it's a tough tough call there. So I
feel for Marty, I feel for that. But he
did offer that right. It's code that he
can let anybody use and keep spinning up.
So if the Sigmanauts want to take it over
and have it there just so people can
unstake that still don't come around for
six months then that's fine. You know, I
don't imagine it's too hard to keep that
up. But the tough part is managing all the
KYC in the back end and doing that. I
imagine that is a thankless hard kind of
thing to do. That's a very big headache.
So I don't blame him when you got this
state of the community, right?
Yeah, right. Right. Exactly. All right.
Let's see, anything else in the Sigmanauts
we've had... I think that's it. Why don't
we jump to questions and we can go off
that. Let's see what we have.
Alright, let's see we have HQx says good
morning. That's very clever HQx from
MewFinance. We have Ahmet says do you like
the QX Turkey group? Is there a specific
QX Turkey? Were you asking if I like the
Turkey group? There's a Turkey group, it's
like at least the one that I was sucked
into a couple months ago, maybe six months
ago, felt like a mix between Gulag and the
old bad Baseless kind of thing right in
between there. It felt like the outcasts
from Baseless before they got put into
Gulag. At least a group I was in. I don't
know if I was in an official Turkey group,
but there were some pretty angry people in
there. But then there were also some good
people that reached out to me on DM and
said, hey, don't listen to this guy. He's
just being crazy. So you get a mix of
everything. But I haven't been in there in
a while. Maybe I'll check it out again.
We'll see. We'll see what it's like.
Let's see. Oh, here we go. It's a good
question from Wombo 22. Hi, MG. How's it
like being in the EF? Anything you can
share from an insider perspective for
others wanting to look in?
Oh, yeah. I mean, EF, it's very, very
good to get oversight and understanding of
their operations and all. And I would say
a lot of cool things that I get to do as
part of EF is on some development
proposals. So EF is open to anyone
submitting a proposal for, like making the
ecosystem better or more specifically like
development-wise, right? Like make a
better infrastructure. For example, we
support like Sigma Explorer or something
along those lines. It's an explorer by PGR
and it is a really good explorer, a very
good UI and it has a completely different
back end built from the ground up. The
Ergo Explorer just uses the same API as
the normal main Explorer. But this new
Explorer, Sigma Explorer, it's completely
done from the ground up. So it's very
impressive and it has the best
performance. It's definitely the fastest
and most scalable Explorer we have today.
That's one of the projects that we help
sponsor for hosting and all, because it
gets expensive when you need it to scale.
And we help out with Stability Nexus,
right, with their protocols, such as
Gluon. Yeah, a lot of projects, what is
it, Cyberverse as well, we helped out. So
that's really cool. We get to vote,
there's also a bunch of projects that we
can't, right? But we try to help them if
they have an impact on the overall
ecosystem. I think a recent one is the
Sigmanauts mining proposal so I think
that's very interesting and I'm supportive
of it so we're still waiting to achieve a
consensus on that because it's a good
chunk of funds that they requested but I
believe mining is an integral part of Ergo
and we really ought to push for mining
when we have this momentum because there's
really no good GPU mineable coins at the
moment. Maybe like one or two but they're
all new blockchains so you don't have much
trust or... They're just not very hard. Or
they're just tokens that you mine on other
blockchains, which is also just as much
more useless. It's just a mineable meme
coin at that point. So Ergo has a huge gap
to fill. So hopefully, the Sigmanauts are
doing a great job at trying to claim it.
And to speak of that, Mark, for I think a
day or so, on Monday the 11th, released
his technique for mining Rosen tokens or
ecosystem tokens. So the way it works is,
you point to the pool you go to the
dashboard where the stats dashboard and
the payout dashboard? So you go to that
and there's a mint button and on that mint
page you can choose I want all Rosen
tokens or I want all Rosen Bitcoin or I
want all Rosen ADA or I want all CYPX or I
want all ERGs and then you can say I want
you to pay me out when it reaches the
equivalent of 20 or 50 or so for the big
miners. They're not getting their wallet
dusted every time we get a block. So you
can set that there. But then the cool
thing is, too, is you can set percentages.
So I can say, look, I want 10% of my token
in CYPX, because I love Cyberverse. I want
50% in ERG. And I want 20% in Gluon Gold.
So you can actually mine gold. It's
countless thing. And so then you just
leave that NFT that mints in your wallet,
and Mark's software will scan your wallet
and do your payouts based on that.
So it's super, super cool. He had it on
for, I think, two days and then pulled it
back and turned on mine core payments
again. He's just got a couple more tweaks
to do. Sometimes when you're doing stuff
in testnet, and you have, even if you have
a couple people using it, there's so many
things that you don't get like you would
from the main group and 45 people banging
against it kind of thing. So, of course,
that's the beauty of the Sigmanauts DAO,
Mining DAO, is that everybody that's there
for the most part, is in agreement that
this is a community-run mining pool and
we're all there to test it, we're all
there to push kind of the boundaries and
do that. So that's super cool that we have
that platform to do that on and that we
have somebody like Mark the Shark to do
those kind of new things and testing.
So that's also kind of what the proposal
is for the EF that Mark put out there. As
well as kind of utilizing Ergo mining as
an education tool for other miners and
other non miners. So big project. Super
cool. I hope the funding comes through for
them. Because I think that's wildly
important. I mean we're a proof-of-work
chain. It's how we secure the damn
network. We need to make sure that people
know why it happens and how it happens and
make it cool.
I mean mining, mining core has been the
same or mining pools have been the same
like forever, right? Now that we're doing
storage rent and this kind of swap in the
middle, that's like super cool. There's
what, there's that mining site that you
can CPU mine like bitcoin even kind of
thing? It's like a swap site. Oh nice
hash. No, no nice hash...
unMineable
No, no, no, no, there's a specific site
you go to and you can mine whatever coin
you want with whatever card you want,
swaps in the background for you, but
people have gone there on mine. Oh, yeah.
There you go. Thank you. And the fees are
just absolutely outrageous. Complete, when
you're dealing with a small margin when
you're mining, you got to be careful with
those fees because it's gonna eat into
your damn thing. So Mark is very
positioned it very competitively.
Yeah, HQx says unMineable here. Yeah, so
competitively, so that's super cool. The
other cool thing about the mining is that
we've been getting a lot of notice on
socials on Twitter saying, holy cow, Ergo
is like number two or number one in the
profitable coin to mine when it was up
around 130, which I think it's around 124
right now. So we're in that threshold
there where I see people saying, oh, I'm
firing up my GPUs again. I'm pointing to
Ergo again. Kind of thing. So that's
really really exciting to see. Yeah, yeah.
All right. Let's see. Who do we have
here? Ahmet wants to know if kushti got
mad at him. That's why he's not here. I
don't think kushti stays too mad for too
long, but no, he didn't get mad at you.
Andy explained in the next bit there. Oh,
here we go. We got Jonas, Jonas, Jonas,
Jonas, if he's European, Jonas, Keystone
wallet soon. That's a PGR 456, right? I
think he said the end of the year
recently. He said for sure.
Yeah. Currently we're blocked by a
library, a rust library. What is it?
There's some issue with one of the Sigma
rusts, how the code works. So we have
another developer, Dusek, who works on the
rust. So he's trying to fix that up. So as
soon as he fixes that up, PGR can continue
the Keystone work he's been doing. Again,
it's some cryptography thing, which is
quite time consuming and tedious.
And for those PGR is the guy who also did
Sigma Explorer, the new explore. So just
so you guys are aware of what his
capabilities are. Super, super cool. Yeah,
I'm looking forward to buying a Keystone
wallet. They look pretty damn cool. At
least the paper, like the paper like one,
right? With the paper, the E ink screen
looks really, really cool. Right now I
use, let's see... Is this a Nano or
something? I don't know. But this is
pretty good. But the issue is when we do a
refill of the GARD wallet, are you doing
this or is this LGD?
For Cardano, it's LGD.
LGD? LGD? I don't know. I forget. I mix
it up.
Okay, so the funny, that's LGD. The funny
thing is when you do that, they're like
you have to verify like 15 transactions,
15 outputs. So you're literally like with
your little two fingers going button
button button button button button button
button button button. Like so many times
you have to view it, verify it then say
yes and slide over and you have to do that
like ten sometimes. So while this is cool
and functional and... It definitely hurts
for those bigger things. So it'll be nice
to use Keystone for that kind of thing. I
guess you can already for Cardano, right?
Yes, yes. So I could get that up there in
the pipes and test it. Yeah, cool.
You should, yeah.
I should. You want to send me one, MG?
We've got Ahmet is on fire today like
third question. Asked is Kraken listing
imminent. Well, I mean at this point after
that leak on the Sigmanauts Twitter,
whoever that was, we fired them. They're
no longer working for the Sigmanauts
Twitter anymore. That's why you have
SuperGeometry there. You know as much as
we do at this point. That means that we're
on the shortlist. They have a backlog of
things on the shortlist, so we're at their
whim essentially when they decide to look
further into us and put that work in.
That being said, I still DM Mark Twitter
little sweet nothings. I think my last DM
was that I couldn't stop thinking about
him and gave him a Willie Nelson YouTube
link "Always On My Mind." He left me
unread this time. Usually he answers me.
So that's I'm hopeful. I'm hopeful he left
me unread for a reason. Usually he writes.
Yeah. Yeah, it's on the backlog, nothing
no news yet kind of thing. So we'll see.
I'm hoping, I'm hoping, I'm hoping these
central exchanges at some point will
think, in order for us to survive... Cause
these meme tokens, right? These meme
chains, like you saw the post from Mark
the other day, he's like, Oh, I can
finally retire. I got dog with hat listed
in the U S or something. And like, like...
I can imagine Mark coming home from work
and he sits down and his wife and kids are
like, Mark, did you change the world
today? And Mark's like, I did. I brought
dog with hat to the U.S. for purchasing.
And they were like, that's amazing.
In all seriousness though, I think
eventually these central exchanges, when
this kind of money runs out, if it will,
or when it burns down a little bit, we'll
eventually see that there's value in
listing something that's unstoppable,
that's sustainable, that has an amazing
community, like Proof of Work Ergo, like
other projects as well that are similar,
and they'll see a value in that. And then
at some point, of course, when while
trading on exchanges becomes a little more
I don't know legal or whatever that's
gonna be perhaps we'll be forced to
actually invest in things and onboard
things that are legal and are organic. So
that's that's my hope there of our overall
kind of thing.
But then my crypto cyberpunk hope is that
they all burn up in a fire and they go
away. And we rely on decentralized
exchanges and fiat on-ramps direct into
the ecosystems for that kind of stuff. So
my word to the central exchanges are, you
know, be nice to be on there, but
hopefully you guys can get with the times
and start backing projects that are
sustainable, legal, and are organic. So
that's my message to them.
Alright, let's see. Here we go. This is
from Odi Boja. I hear Cardano will build a
layer 2 partner chain where BTC will be
the token. Wouldn't it make sense if Ergo
joins the effort? The new chain would be a
partner chain on Cardano and a layer 2 on
Ergo? Are you talking about Bitcoin OS? Is
that a whole other layer kind of thing?
Yeah. I mean, we already have that
function, right? You can bring your
Bitcoin over to Ergo and do whatever the
hell you want. And you can bring your
Bitcoin over to Cardano, do whatever the
hell you want. You can bring your Bitcoin
to Ethereum and do whatever you want. I
mean, I get the idea, but I don't see if
we already have that functionality. Of
course it's an open system, whatever
anybody wants to do. But we already have
that functionality as far as that goes,
right. In some parts. What's your thoughts
there? Are you paying attention?
Yeah, I think their technology is
interesting. They use ZK proofs instead of
a multisig bridge, which is very, I think,
new. Not many people have done it. It's
very convincing, right? The idea is you
don't even need any multisig trust, right?
You just have to trust one person or
something like that, and you can make that
yourself. That's the whole idea behind the
bridge. So I think that's very
interesting. Also, you've got to remember
Cardano has so much money, so much
developers, right? So they can do so much
compared to us. We're just basically hobby
developers, except for kushti. So there's
not too much we can do, but I will say
that whatever layer 2 they achieve, Rosen
will be able to bridge to that.
Right, right, right, right. Didn't kushti
at some point during one of the ErgoHacks,
two ErgoHacks ago, develop some sort of
messaging or consensus mechanism? He read
Bitcoin proofs and verified them on the
Ergo chain? So is that a similar thing
that they're doing with their tech? Is it
the same kind of thing or no?
I mean, I guess it's more advanced,
right? But I guess the ideas were quite
similar.
Right, right, right. Right, it's like,
kushti's like rule 34. Do you know what
rule 34 on the internet is?
Oh yeah, the artwork thing, yeah.
It's uh, this is not a PG show MGPai.
It's all right. Rule 34 states that if it
exists there's porn of it on the internet,
right? So kushti is like a rule 34 of
crypto space. If it exists out there,
kushti's probably done it six months ago.
There's got to be a kushti rule 34 or
something like that. That's usually the
case. Oh, yeah, I did something like that
a couple years ago when Ergo first came
out. Yeah, it didn't work out and this is
why so we did this kind of thing. The
common thing you hear from kushti.
All right, let's see what we have here.
We have, oh, Bayoke saying good night from
Indonesia. Let's see. Oh, here we go.
Here's a question for you, MGPai. Let's
see how much time you're spending deep in
the ecosystem. HQx wants to know your
thoughts on MewFinance, which I imagine
includes like the utility tools that they
have, the shop that they have, the mart
that they have, that's the physical site
as well. They're kind of staking tiers
where you can get discounts on listing
things based on how much you're staking
and also like I think they have revenue
sharing as well in those tiers as well
kind of thing. So all built in there. What
are your thoughts? Oh also escrow service,
right? You can I can go there I can put
something in a package and put your
address on it and then you can come pick
it up if you pay the fee that I say. What
are your thoughts MGPai?
Yeah, of course, I think it's very cool.
And I'm glad that people are spinning up
new projects in the ecosystem. I think
they're trying to fill up a gap that
Spectrum DEX kind of left us. They're not
really maintaining much on Ergo. I mean,
they built really a lot of cool tooling
already. But it's good that it's the power
of open source. If it dies, the community
can always take over. And I think that's
what we are seeing that's happening. I
know I heard that, I think a couple of
Sigmanauts are selling on that, the
marketplace, right? So I think, that's
very interesting.
Yeah, he's selling like organic honey on
there as well. Sigmanauts have some, yeah.
Yeah.
And then we have, I posted these guys.
Ooh. So if anybody, I posted them for 75
ERGs. They're Radeon 7s. One of them
doesn't post on Windows, the other one
runs fine. I ran it for a day at 75% and
just needs a little fan work, that's all.
So 75 ERGs and you can get two Radeon 7s
which... I guess if nobody buys it, I'll
lower it down. I just want to get out and
get them out of here. And I want to get
people pointed towards MewMart. So it's
more of an experience kind of thing, but
they're sitting on the side of my desk,
ready to be boxed up for anybody that
wants them. So super cool that you can go
there and get approved and sell actually
physical merch. Super, super neat.
Alright, let's see. Oh, Wombo, what are
your thoughts on Ergo needing memes? So I
talked to kushti about this last week,
right? And unofficially got kushti's idea
of what memes are, right? MGPai, I'll let
you start. What are your thoughts?
Yeah, I think, of course, that's how you
gain viral posts. I think Joe's been doing
a good job. He's been posting a lot of...
Oh, he's been killing it with those two
videos, right?
Like the wedding video from... Was that
Old School? What was that? That was Old
School, the wedding video with the Will
Ferrell and then the show where the Sal
guy from... Oh, yeah beats crap out of
everybody on the bus. Absolutely. Yeah, I
think the first one, the first video with
Will Ferrell got... I think 10,000 views,
something like that. So really, really
good exposure. I wrote Joe, I was like,
that's great. And he's like, is that good?
I was like, for not having breasts, Joe,
that's a pretty good post. I mean, it's
true, right?
Yeah, of course. I told Joe to make it
shorter right because if it's too long
then you lose attention. I think five ten
seconds is much better right because if
people like it they'll spend that much
time where you have to grab attention in
the first few seconds. But yeah it's very
good. I'm glad he's doing it. It's a good
way to convey his point.
And you'll start seeing slowly, kind of,
not like crazy memes, but you'll start
seeing slowly some more, kind of, not
official, but more appropriate memes from
the main Ergo account, perhaps, until
people get really pissed. But we'll see.
Right now, SuperGeometry is doing a great
job from Sigmanauts. He's got a lot more
leeway to post kind of crazy content. So
he's doing that and filling that role
greatly. I sound like Donald Trump. And
we'll try to start, interacting that from
the main account to with memes. So we'll
see how it goes. If you have a good one
send them to us and we'll see what we can
do.
All right. Let's see. Wendy moon. Hi,
Wendy. Wendy is a frequenter. Is there any
way to swap between Ergo and BTC and keep
it off exchanges? Just do it in your
wallet wrapped or BTC wallet. Yeah, yes,
of course. Right. We have, you can do it
on any chain, right? There's a lot of
liquidity, where's the most BTC liquidity
is in Cardano or is it in...
I think Cardano, but I'm not sure. I
haven't messed with it. I have no reason
to go to BTC.
Let me see. But yeah, yeah, of course,
Wendy, you can go to, let me go to ErgoDEX
right now while I'm talking. You can go
right from BTC through Rosen to wrapped
BTC and set it right in your Ergo wallet.
That way you didn't even hit ErgoDEX, or
right now you could. Let's see. Let's see
what the slippage is. If I want to swap a
thousand ERG. Yeah, if I want to swap a
thousand ERG on ErgoDEX right now without
even touching Bitcoin and just get Rosen
BTC, you'll take a 7.8% hit on liquidity.
So liquidity is not that high on ErgoDEX,
at least, or MewFinance, same smart
contracts. So your best bet would be
definitely to send it over the bridge,
most likely if you have more than that,
and just hold on to that Rosen BTC in your
Ergo wallet, knowing that you have the
security of Rosen Bridge and the security
of another proof of work chain.
I thought it was interesting that, and I
talked to, mentioned this with Joe quite a
bit in our talks, maybe late at night when
you're drinking whiskey on the live
versions of the dev updates. I thought it
was interesting that people would want to
send their Bitcoin to something like
Ethereum. I get that there's a lot of
liquidity there and a lot of financial
tooling, but it's literally, I feel it's
literally like taking your money out of a
bank and just leaving your wallet and
walking through the market essentially,
whereas Ergo has developed a massive
amount of tooling that lets you interact
with it right from the bank and the
security of that kind of thing, or
essentially walk around with a safe in
your pocket. So I always thought it was
interesting that, that's not a thought
like I'm actually going to a less secure
chain essentially from something like
Bitcoin. So I was, the thought that the
allure of at least Ergo and the financial
tooling that we have would be like, we are
not compromising any security by going
over to Ergo and using the financial
tooling there. So I think that's something
we need to try to sell a little bit more
as well for that.
Let's see. Answer that already. Oh,
here's a hype one. You like hype
questions. A big 3D question to both of
you. Do you guys think Ergo can hit top 20
this bull market like Dan believes? Like
Dan believes, we got to check in with Dan.
I'm gonna send him that one. Yeah, you
know if Dan believes it I certainly
believe it. I think I think anything can
happen. I'm not trying to predict
anything, but I think Ergo at least has
the ability to shine in the manner of
security and the tooling that's there
already. The lending protocols, the I mean
your let alone your NFT release platform
is awesome and... All the projects we have
that are ready and fully baked and ready
for customers, essentially, there's no
reason and sub-blocks.
You guys aren't ready for that. It's
going to be really good. I mean, that's a
big missing piece.
Hang on. MGPai. Do you have your hat?
Oh, that's a bit far away.
There we go. Make mining great again.
Yeah, I think we're primed for it. I think
we definitely have the ability to be there
and sustain, have sustainability there.
The question just is, is the rest of the
space ready for that are going to realize
that? So we can't predict it, but...
My assumption is that Ergo closely
follows Cardano, right? So if Cardano does
well, I'm certain Ergo will do well. They
always move so super close to each other.
So I know Cardano is going to do well for
sure. They've been doing really good stuff
lately. So I'm certain Ergo is going to go
up much more.
You heard it right there, folks. That's
not with your EF hat on though. That's
with your community developer hat on. You
said that. Right. Perfect. All right. All
right. Good timing. Kilver, Kilver, our
buddy Kilver. If you miss Kilver hasn't
streamed in a while. Kilver, have you
streamed in a while? Where are your
streams been, buddy? Maybe I've just
missed it. But Kilver has been an avid
Cyberverse player, community member, and
streamer of Cyberverse. Do you guys think
now with Trump being so crypto friendly,
we will see a new alt mining resurgent?
You know, regardless of political
standings there, I will say, I think I
said it in the last AMA, prepare to be not
surprised, but prepare to be like, from
what I know about my experiences with
being an American or a United States
citizen and having Trump as president for
four years and what he promised before
campaigns and what he delivers on some of
these things. Some of it's hype, right?
Some of it's just to get voters kind of
thing. But you got to look at actions. So
the facts are that he's brought on your
buddies, Elon Musk, right? Who is fairly,
I don't know if, is Elon...
Considered crypto friendly with Elon.
He's not against it. But I don't know if
it's like friendly. I don't know. He's
really weird. He just does Dogecoin like I
think it's more of like personal amusement
for him, right? Like you guys are bored,
right?
I really feel that way. I do. I do. I
feel like if you ever finish a video game,
think of it this way, and then you put in
the cheat codes, you just get bored after
a while. You start throwing people off
cliffs or shooting people up in crazy
stuff. You just do crazy stuff. So I
wonder if Elon... And I think he's such a
bored.
I think some people try to say he's like
manipulating the market. Like he's a
billionaire. I don't think he cares. No, I
think he has more money than the market
cap of Dogecoin or something. Yeah, market
cap Dogecoin is like what 30 40 billion
and he bought Twitter for more. So like I
don't think he's trying to manipulate
anything. He's just...
No, no. No. Yeah. Yeah. So yeah, he's
definitely poking stuff. So I hope I still
have a worry that those kind of things
with how he talks about Dogecoin and those
things like what's the utility of Dogecoin
right now, right? Is there any utility in
Dogecoin? No, no, I mean he's obviously
promoting something for the social aspects
and the idea of I guess a currency that's
so you can spend on chain I guess. I don't
know. So I think overall it's obvious that
people believe that Trump is gonna be good
for crypto based on the price of Bitcoin
right now and some altcoins and...
But I think it's my jury's still out for
me, verdict's still out on the holistic
approach of how crypto is going to be seen
by the administration? Is it going to be
seen as this? Let's I mean couldn't say
Trump came out with his own token, right?
And it's 70% down like come the hell on.
Like they're obviously riding the same
kind of speculative market that most of
crypto is. So is it good for crypto? If
you ask me that question as in, oh, I
guess it's alt mining resurgence. We
totally missed the point of the question.
But in general, I think Trump is going to
be good perhaps for the speculative side
of crypto. Do I think he's going to be
good at real organic adoption of chains
that are actually making a difference in
doing something? Maybe that's a side
effect there. My opinion only, but we'll
get to see. He's not even in office yet
guys. Let's talk in January about proof of
work mining resurgence. I think all it
takes for a proof of work mining
resurgence is the price of Ergo to go up
and then people are going to mine the shit
out of it. Right. That's it.
All right, let's see. What else do we
have? Wombo says there's another fish in
the CQX, don't worry. Oh, Mark, because I
was trying to seduce Mark from Kraken.
Right, right, right. Oh yeah, FC, FC
CannonQ. MG, Palmyra going to launch a
coin or project, do you know any timing?
Oh, you're asking me, I can't say.
That's, is it on, it's not on, it has
what's it called? The IDO they did. People
don't have the coins in possession right
or the tokens in possession. They have
them just investing tokens.
It's just like a pre-sale or something,
right? They have rounds of that. So
definitely, I can say we're having more
pre-sale rounds. I don't know how many
more, but that's certainly available. And
again, I don't think it's open to US
citizens. You have to have different
passport if you want to participate, I
think, but I'm not completely sure. I know
the past ones were not open to US
citizens.
All right. All right. Let's see. What
else do we have? We won't comment on that
one. I think Kilver says quality content
right there when we were talking about
rule 34. Thank you, Kilver. Appreciate it.
Any news from Sky Harbor team about the
work on the marketplace? You know, Kilver,
I don't know if I said this the other day,
but I think mid last month I pinged Quokka
during the AMA and he didn't get back to
me till after, but he says the front-end
UI version 2 has finished and in testing
will be releasing the open source code
when deployed. The backend is being worked
on and there's not much work left, so the
dev is still slowly chipping away at it.
That was a report from Quokka. So that'll
be nice when that's up. As I said, when
it's up, we're hoping that we can organize
the Sigmanauts to kind of take it over and
manage a front end version of it from that
open source code and use it as a treasury
revenue stream as well as maintain it so
that we can have a dev that can
continuously work on it and make it
better.
Wombo wants me to do the dance QX. But
Dan, Dan does a great job at it. He's very
good at it. Kilver says that he's not,
he's moving into a new house, so he hasn't
streamed in a bit. He's going to start
again one to two.
Congrats.
Oh, yeah. I forgot to mention, guys, I've
been putting some liquidity into
TradeHouse on the Rosen side. I think I
put about only about maybe a couple
hundred ERGs worth on the Rosen side for
Rosen-ERG pair as well as maybe about 200
ERGs worth of CYPX in there as well. I
encourage all of you guys to go to
TradeHouse and just put your project
tokens in there or SigmaUSD or something.
Just get a little bit in there. That's a
great opportunity, that's a great place
for people to come and swap where they
want to be able to visually see and kind
of control their slippage. They can say
I'm going to set an order here and only
take it at this price. And then if it
matches then it's great. If not, then
maybe they'll come out to your price, but
it's a good tool. We're going to try to
push it more on the TradeHouse Twitter, as
well as try to retweet from the main
account and Sigmanauts account. But we
need to get liquidity. That's a big thing.
That's what attracts people to these
dApps. And that's what keeps things
pumping. So please, if you can...
Don't let that stuff burn a hole in your
wallet, your Nautilus or your Terminus or
your Minotaur. Go ahead and use it. Put it
out there. Even if you, so let's say
you're just like, I don't want to sell any
of my CYPX. I don't want to sell any of my
MewFinance token or Mew's not on
TradeHouse, but you get the idea. That was
a big thing for me too. So don't, then put
it at like 10% above Ergo. So remember the
way the order book works is when you put
in an order to sell, you're not selling
your CYPX or your Rosen or whatever for a
dollar amount. You're selling it for an
ERG amount, right? So you don't have to
touch that. Let's say the price of Ergo
goes up. Right? Your order in the price of
your token that you've matched it with
doesn't go up with ERG. Right? So now,
nobody's going to buy that thing because
it's way too expensive compared to the
price of ERG. Because you're still asking
for one ERG for a thousand tokens. And if
ERG goes up and the token doesn't go up
with it, you're asking for a higher valued
ERG for the same amount of tokens. So you
don't have to worry about switching it.
You don't have to worry about losing or
anything like that. You can take it off
and put it back there.
So the idea is if they both raise similar
which if anybody follows CoinGecko in
their portfolio or anything like that any
other portfolio. What's the Ergo one that
Louie made? Oh, Crooks Finance? Crooks
Finance, yeah. And it is a portfolio, too,
like that. You'll notice that most of the
time, on average, over a series of days,
these guys all raise, right? Ergo raises
up, rising tide raises all ships, kind of
thing. So your token rises up. The cool
thing is once in a while you'll get tokens
that go a little above, go a little below
and catch up. So that's where you'll get
those deals that people will come in and
buy. So if you're worried about selling
your project token then set it at 10%
higher because if it spikes or ERG dips
and the project token stays up then that's
a good opportunity that'll come in and do
that and you're not losing money
essentially kind of thing and then you can
always buy it back if you want to. But in
short use TradeHouse, use the order book
system, provide liquidity, yeah, provide
liquidity. That's the big thing. That's
why we look at these other chains and
we're like why is everybody using these
exchanges barely anything on there to do
kind of thing.
Well, they're using them because it's a
massive amount of liquidity in the
ecosystem, right? So you can do a swap and
you're not losing 5% on anything. So in
Ergo, we don't have that. We don't have
the big VCs that are going to be pumping
liquidity into these kind of things yet.
So it's up to us, right? In all it takes,
there's 10,000 people in chat, guys. If
everybody in chat, how many in the Ergo
chat? Do we know? Hang on, let's see.
11,435 people in the Ergo chat, just on
Telegram's side. If everybody puts in one
ERG and a thousand CYPX or a thousand
Rosen and a couple ERGs, that's just a
tiny amount in that order book. You're
going to have $10,000 or $20,000 worth of
depth in those order books. It just takes
a little bit from everybody. That's it.
That's it. And that's our weapon against
this kind of thing. That's our answer to
one dude or woman in Ethereum who puts in
a million dollars of liquidity somewhere.
We have to do this individually. It
doesn't mean that you have to put in
$10,000, just small amounts combined with
everybody's effort. And we have the same
effect, guys. That's all it's going to
take.
All right, what do we have? Well, we're
at 59:05. Since you joined five minutes
late, MGPai, that's the hour. Anything
closing? Are you missing class for this?
No, no, we're an hour behind our daylight
savings, right? So no classes start yet.
Nice, very nice, very nice. All right,
anything to close with, sir?
I don't know, we're going to the moon.
Good closing. All right. Thanks
everybody. And if you didn't hear what I
said, the last five minutes invest in the
ecosystem projects, play Cyberverse, list
things on MewFinance, liquidity into
TradeHouse, list stuff on Ergo auction
house, all that kind of stuff. Use the
ecosystem. There are plenty of ways to use
it without the fear of losing your project
tokens. If that's your worry. Cause I know
a lot of Ergo people are just, let's hold
it in our bags. It's so precious. We don't
want to lose it. So. Do it. I have, as I
say, I have about 50 liquid ERGs right
now. Everything else is tied up in
ecosystem projects, so do it. Don't be
afraid. All right, everybody. Thanks for
joining. We'll see you tomorrow for the
community chat. It's on Zoom. Everybody's
welcome. I'll post it on Twitter again.
Just come in chat. kushti will be there.
Joe might be there since, no, Joe might
not, Joe's not going to be there. But
we're getting devs. He announced it in the
dev chat. MGPai, you're going to try to be
there too. It's 3am for Dan, but maybe we
can get him there with the enticement that
somebody's going to yell at him. Dan likes
punishment. So we'll see. Come tomorrow, I
think, what is it, 4pm UTC? What was it?
And check our Twitter. You'll see the link
there. Thanks everybody. Enjoy your week.
Bye guys.