Good morning, everybody.
Or good afternoon, I guess, in your case,
kushti.
Hey, man.
Hello, everyone.
My pleasure to be here again.
And yeah, it's good to see you here
again.
And it is good that we are starting on
time after so many attempts.
Finally, everything is working smoothly.
from the first minute.
All right.
So what's new on your end, my friend?
What have you been working on?
A lot of things.
So finalizing 6.0.
Yeah, well, still there is need to check,
review something.
So yeah.
discovered some issues, well, versioned
issues, so I'm fixing them now.
Then, yeah, back to sub-blocks, so doing
some codes now, and yeah, hopefully this
month if no surprises, but they always
happen.
So yeah, hope to publish EAP reworked EAP
proposal based on the forum text which is
messy and now needs for polishing along
with some codes.
Currently I have just some stupid stuff
so some blocks being generated.
by local miner and then processing stops
here and there.
So now I'm filling this with real logic,
maybe of prototype quality, but still.
And then, yeah, we'll polish things.
Then what else?
So, yeah, so for Dexy, we have
Spectrum DEX pull request merged and
yeah, checking what to do next.
There is need for more developers, in
particular we need for UI maintainer.
It's a good idea probably to introduce UI
fee like done in SigmaUSD interface.
So, yeah, please reach, please join us.
So, yeah, that's the main limiting factor
for now.
Probably then, yeah, also would be happy
to see contributions with sub-blocks.
So, yeah, we'll check developers.
group today, so if there are guys willing
to contribute, I will make issues with
bounty and so on.
Then reviewing Sigma Rust.
features so just today reviewed and yeah
it seems to be done now support for
deterministic signatures which is needed
for keystone integration so yeah it seems
pgr456 now unblocked
So he was blocked with the need for
deterministic signatures since there is no
random generation API provided by
hardware.
on Keystone, unlike, let's say, big
operating systems like Linux, Windows, and
so on, right?
So there is need to work with randomness
differently, in short, and, yeah, so now
it's supported by Sigma Rust, so, well,
Keystone integration is going further,
then.
Then for ledger integration,
Unfortunately, my peer wasn't approved by
Ledger, so he is a former Kudelsky
security employee, but we were not lucky
in getting a Ledger team to get Kudelsky
quality from the former.
employees.
So yeah, I mean, currently, well, other
folks are, well, looking, actually talking
with approved entities.
So it's about Kudelsky and yeah, another
company, which name I've forgotten.
So Kudelsky is well known to me.
since they did some audits for some parts
of the Sigmanauts before, back in 2019.
So they did audit for inbuilt wallets,
for cryptography, for proof of work,
certain aspects of it.
So, yeah, what else?
So, yeah, also,
thinking about how to get more developers
on board, so on Saturday I'm giving a talk
at some local events.
I mean, it's mostly a developer's event,
just like maybe 50 or 60 folks attending.
But yeah, I mean, it's good still, right?
So maybe with just a few developers, we
can do more.
So I mean, there are a lot of ideas.
So just Bruno only has like, I don't
know.
like five or six new different ideas and
then yeah I also well published some
things on forum recently such as hashrate
coin random coin and so on and yeah there
is needs to improve infrastructure
still write a bit, then in core there is
need for some development, for reviews,
for documentation and so on.
Then published very recently an article
about, well, it's called Money Ownership
in the age of programmable money, right?
And based on that now doing a talk for
some events which is about art actually
and it will be it will take place in Italy
on December 21st and I'm recording video
and it will be about property rights in
the age of program money right because
well
It seems with tokenized real-world assets
and so on, with smart contracts in
particular, right, so this topic is more
broad, especially if we are talking about
such, well, blockchain.
let's say, friendly to, well, grasping
such ownership issues as Ergo, right?
But even if you are talking about
Ethereum, so I made a tweet recently about
another cash court decision, and yeah,
it's also about property rights recently,
right?
So the court actually decided
That Tornado Cash smart contract is not a
property, right, and then it cannot be
OFAC sanctioned, right, because of that.
So it's just an autonomous piece of
software and then, yeah, it's not quite
legal to sanction a piece of code.
Which is actually quite interesting
development and I think it also does sound
similar, but Yeah, well, so I'm doing a
talk for some events about art Digital art
in particular then.
Yeah, we have
A lot of interesting possibilities here
talking about property rights and
programmable property rights sometimes
maybe and so on for tokenized assets,
tokenized art and so on.
So preparing a talk about that, then also
planning another Asian tour and this time
hopefully it will not be Dubai because too
much Dubai probably for me.
So, yeah, thinking about visiting Hong
Kong around consensus conference and,
yeah, well, maybe some place around.
So, I know we have Sigmanauts in Vietnam,
South Korea, and so on.
So, yeah, well, we'll check with peers
there.
What's the possibility?
But yeah, it would be good to make
something in Hong Kong also.
So we had quite good meet-up there back
in 2019, which is available on YouTube, by
the way.
Let's talk from there.
Then, what else?
What else?
Now, what's new in terms of the dev
update this week?
I saw a lot of things from qx().
Yeah, well, it was quite an amazing dev
update.
So we have a new developer which made a
tool, actually quite an interesting tool
to encrypt and decrypt seed phrase.
to produce BEP-39 seed phrase and encrypt
it.
He claims that he is not a developer but
willing to do something on Ergo, so he
used AI mostly on that, but the seed
quality is checked with some Python
statistical analysis scripts and so on so
yeah that sounds interesting so well
please feel free to check the chat and to
check the tool and use it so I don't know
I mean it's getting more and more
interesting because well
I'm going to check developers which
joined recently or started to develop
something not so trivial recently, such as
HQx, right, with MewTooling, and then Mark
the Shark, this new guy with AI script.
I made a script and yeah, who else?
There are two or three other folks.
Yeah, Beene, some guy with a Discord
account, Beene somewhat.
And, yeah, so, my impression, is that,
these days, because, we have a lot of open
source, tooling available, open source
contracts, UI and so on.
So developers, mostly well combining,
taking existing functionality, right,
and, well, reworking it into something
new, right, some modifications for
starters, then deeper modifications, then
something maybe totally new.
So that was the path of MewFinance, I
believe.
Right, and that's actually
quite exciting to me so that's the power
of open source right so not just open
source but free software right so you can
take it you can modify you can run
modified version freely right and then
yeah the only thing is that yeah well do
your modification free as well right and
then people will develop
on foundations provided by you and then
yeah because of that we may have well
evolutionary development process right
with stable and solid contracts and yeah
also streamlined and easy development
cycle so
Quite good, but also talking about qx()
and so on.
I think still the Ergo potential is
uncovered by like 1% maybe.
roll-up schemes and so on.
So I'm thinking about some layer 2
constructions discussing some these days
even with very old folks.
Some with Cardano even since he has some
experience with Bitcoin layer 2.
The idea is that, yeah, well, it's fine
to, well, building on the existing ground,
but yeah, well, it's 99% of potential
still uncovered, so there is time to,
well...
open new horizons, right, for the
different developments possible to do more
writings, forum posts and so on.
And Luivatra, for example, Luivatra made
an excellent post recently about how to
use EAP5, so contract templates, which is
quite powerful to link.
actually which is allowing for using well
contracts within contracts so to to reason
about contracts within contracts right in
some not so hard and yeah pretty
streamlined way so yeah quite powerful
feature and i'm not sure any other
blockchain has it actually
Yeah, so that was also starting to play
with the mempool and voting, which is
awesome to see.
Yeah, that's probably all and probably
enough from me.
So what's on your side?
I was pretty excited to see Lithos
development, where I know that qx() is
starting to finish the NIPoPoWs contracts
and work on DevNets.
So I was trying to create more contracts
for kind of optimistic evaluations of
NIPoPoWs and working on kind of share
proofs.
The Sigmanauts mining pool this week was
hitting some big boxes in terms of storage
rent.
That was really nice to see.
I guess just based on like four years in
the past, they're starting to pick up more
kind of activity in terms of boxes
available that are, kind of stale.
So seeing those extra miner rewards is
pretty awesome.
I also saw that DuckPools is going to go
through their next round of kind of
raising.
If you look at how their roadmap is
laid out.
They said, okay, well, we're going to go
through periodic fundraising efforts and
have pretty clear
roadmap in terms of what they're going to
do for each particular phase.
I always support that.
I always throw my money at it because,
it's one of those things that I guess,
where your attention goes, you tend to get
more of, right?
Well, you pay for what you want to see.
So that's one of my favorite projects in
Ergo that, they do a lot of really good
documentation.
If you go through,
Everything that they do, which, circling
back to, kind of this idea of like a
natural evolution of, kind of the
development around open source software,
having that type of, not only complexity,
but like documentation detail is, is
really foundational.
So, I always have to kind of tip my hat
to, what crass is doing over there and,
encourage people to look into it, support
it, use it.
Paideia DAO is kicking off and I think
that's going to be really powerful
software suite long-term.
I think that, yeah, you do need like
direct management and engagement, which is
sometimes hard when people's mindset is
more like, I don't know, just speculative,
the main pointing or whatever in the
crypto space, but having like real world
tools that are useful is, is, fascinating
to me.
What else?
PGR, it looks like he submitted the whole
request for the, silver Oracle.
So, as Dexy moves towards, main net,
I've got to rethink with Bruno and the
team and see what options are available in
terms of kind of the natural evolution of
protocols where I guess we have enough
time now watching Gluon.
that we could potentially say, okay,
well, what have we learned based on
experience and what are the observations
and potentially improve or alter the
existing Gluon Gold a little bit, which I
think is a pretty neat step forward.
What else?
We submitted the Hummingbot requests to
the Hummingbot Foundation.
Which is going to lead to really kind of
a unique framework where, with Rosen
Bridge, we kind of unified trading
environments across, central exchanges.
But, one of the neat things about,
hummingbot for, trading on top of Rosen
Bridge or managing liquidity is, you now
have access to multiple,
environments to bot trade on KYC free.
So that's always a nice assumption for
users.
I don't know exactly how long that's
going to take for them to go through like
a review process, but that's kind of the
next order of operations in that kind of
development path.
And it's going to be interesting to see
what
evolves there because Ergo is kind of a
nice environment due to low fees, right?
So you always have like this, friction in
terms of the market costs of trading.
if you're talking like an AMM, you can
look at the pool fee, which is always some
balance between,
what liquidity providers, are
incentivized by as well as what, the
people buying and selling are willing to,
inherit, I guess in terms of costs.
And then you also have this execution,
cost, which, in some systems, if you look
at like EVM with gas, when, Bitcoin goes
through down or up,
there's always a race, and DeFi protocols
and gas goes through the roof.
And it'll be interesting to see how, I
don't know, kind of the efficiency of,
order execution, and Ergo makes it an
attractive, market for more active trading
because lower that friction a little bit
in terms of costs.
And then it's just a matter of liquidity
and opportunity, I guess.
Let's see with Rosen Bridge, yeah,
working on a Dogecoin integration.
We finally, pushed a more dynamic mobile
build, which is nice to see.
I'm not always the biggest mobile user to
be honest, just cause yeah, phone is
small.
It's easy to lose that kind of thing.
But, having a dynamic UI is pretty nice
to see.
And I hope people out there appreciate
that.
Also working with, Binance Smart Chain,
going through rounds of testing in terms
of integration, we're working on creating
a new watcher build that hopefully is a
little bit more, performant efficient, a
lot of upgrades in the background and up
and down the stack, and Rosen Bridge, I
hope that,
Yeah.
My goal is, we see, we see that live as
we roll through the end of the year, but
we always need to test and check and then
repeat.
So we're kind of in that phase.
Yeah, that's pretty much it for me.
You want to get into the questions?
My bad, was muted.
So, yeah, let's jump on the questions.
There is some topic to discuss, but qx()
is not here.
After a year spending a week with
students and getting probably totally
exhausted.
I don't understand him.
All right, so...
Yeah, well, we need to decide when to
make spaces and zoom calls.
But yeah, let's do that our telegram.
group which is bridged with Discord.
I mean the main Telegram group which is
bridged with a general channel in Discord
and yeah we can discuss such things after
the AMA.
So yeah let's jump on the questions.
All right so let's start maybe with Mr.
Whitecat.
Hello guys where is your PPJs?
Yeah, the most serious question probably.
I just woke up.
It's one of those things, I keep the
video above the chest.
Yeah, the same reason.
So yeah, you have to guess what PPJs are.
Let's see.
I'll go.
I think FC has a good question.
Tokenization is easy in theory, right?
Chop something up into small bits via a
good smart contract.
What are the standards for controlling
physical assets?
Seems right with fraud and mismanagement.
Yeah, there's a lot of
hyperfinancialization schemes around
tokenization that may or may not make
sense, right?
I'll drop some of my perspective, okay?
So like in Colorado, we have this area in
the middle of the state called the San
Luis Valley, right?
It's a kind of beautiful area, but it is
like this high desert, okay?
And so the infrastructure and the utility
of land there is not so great actually.
It's kind of interesting because there's
like some geographical like qualities in
terms of like deep water and stuff but
it's pretty popular for people to say like
okay somebody bought this huge track of
land and then they split it up into these
tiny little chunks
And they fractionalize it and then they
try to say okay.
Well, now we're going to sell these
little fractions of land that are absent
infrastructure and give them to people as
some sort of like speculative asset or I
don't know I guess sometimes people will
go up there in camp or whatever So I guess
there's some utility there but it kind of
can create a more of a financial scheme
than like a utility driven development.
OK. And it's really interesting if you if
you start to say, OK, well, let's take
like, I don't know, my car and you
fractionalize ownership of it across
people who gets to use it.
Is it something that's like being
driven for a utilitarian commercial
purpose that has profit distribution.
Who is in charge is always an interesting
question in there.
Who gets to use whatever the utility is.
You take a house and chop it into
millimeter by millimeter squares and say,
okay, well,
I'm going to sell these shares of the
house.
And what does that represent in reality?
Right.
does it just represent like some
fractional ownership of like an asset?
And it's interesting because maybe that,
is useful if there's like revenue and
profit distribution, but it also creates
some weird questions like who controls the
title.
Right.
Because when you're talking about
physical assets, you usually have some
regulatory layers that you have to deal
with.
And when you have centralized
counterparties, you generally need some
legal entity or a mechanism to deal with
those like friction points.
Right.
And then it's abstracted a little
further.
Let's say that you have a house that has
been put in millimeter by millimeter
squares and sold.
How do you come to consensus to actually
sell the house?
Or are you permanently stuck in this
weird notion of fractionalized ownership
that has no consensus to actually move the
asset?
And then, when that happens where it's
like you're stuck, there's usually some
party or entity that's taking fees from
moving around these little fractions.
And, it kind of creates, I don't know,
just weird schemes.
Right.
Do I think that having like.
physical real world assets on chain is
valuable.
Yeah, I think it can be super valuable in
terms of how money is raised and perhaps
how profits are distributed.
But you have to always remember those
layers of like regulatory footprint in
some jurisdiction and physical reality.
And that adds extreme complexity off
chain that makes like clean logic
hard.
I think it makes a lot more sense when
you have like, say gold, it's a bearer
asset, right?
It doesn't have a footprint in a
jurisdiction and a lot of those layers,
are less influential versus if you have a
house or I don't know, mineral rights or a
car or, something that is more grounded in
a single jurisdictions and laws, like the
level of complexity goes through the roof
completely.
So it's tokenization easy in theory.
Yeah.
But then when you look at like off chain
reality is messy and you kind of are
forced more or less to comply within
existing jurisdictions.
And that is not always easy to do in a
distributed or decentralized or trustless
way.
I guess.
what do you think?
kushti?
yeah so mostly but will continue actually
so yeah well it's quite complex when
you're talking nice something like a house
or a picture right so I mean if you have
some picture at some art gallery and you
will digitize
Well, so sell digital piece of it, right?
So like 1,000 pieces, then what does it
mean to own one piece out of 1,000, right?
So what are your property rights here?
But it's even more complex if you think
programmability, right?
If you're adding more complex
cryptography and if you're adding scripts,
So, for example, we have till 1,000
pieces, but one piece is owned by you,
another by me, third piece is owned by...
well, two out, two signature of yours and
mine and then fourth well, possessed by a
ring signature, so one key out of those
two keys here, so oh my and then let's say
tokens are possessed by some contract,
blocking one token a month and maybe
sending it to the last block miner.
At the moment, if this emission contract
has five
100 tokens, let's take maybe a more clear
example, 600, right?
Then yeah, at this point, well, majority
of tokens
if that makes sense, talk about majority
of tokens representing a picture.
So possessed by some contracts, but it's
hard to associate those tokens with some
ease, without this in the real deal,
right?
So, I mean, this session will be made,
gradually, token by token, by the
emission process.
So yeah, that is at this point when it's
still locked in the contract.
Well, who owns this picture, right?
It's quite complicated.
Yeah, it seems commodities is the lowest
hanging fruit, so I'm talking with Dan
about his Lithos project, right?
And then, well, in commodities,
settings so it makes sense to combine
physical and digital
like it's right.
So tokens representing physical lithium,
for example, with well, algorithmic
lithium stable coin, for example, which
would be used to secure which is not
produced yet.
Right.
So if you're buying lithium, then you can
get stable coin immediately.
Right.
Then, yeah, well, you're sick.
by that stable coin, but when physical
lithium is produced, you can exchange
algorithmic lithium to physical lithium.
to digital tokens representing physical
lithium for starters and then to physical
lithium, right, which you can hold in your
hands if you want to hold lithium in your
hands.
It could be toxic, I'm not sure.
Well, in regards with this, it's not an
issue, right?
Currently we have an issue with solid
stable coins such as SigmaUSD, Gluon also
probably, right?
Because of, well, over-collateralization
means you cannot mint a lot of tokens,
right, because you need a lot of capital,
right, reserves and so on.
But when you use algorithmic stablecoins
as a buffer, right, for physical assets,
then it makes sense that you are using
algorithmic stable coins to secure risks,
right?
You may have, for example, lithium may
not be produced, right?
There is a chance of that.
Or you can buy a brick of gold in
some vault in Dubai, for example, when
you're outside, but then you have a chance
of another COVID pandemic, right?
And then no flights, so you cannot reach
the vault.
And in this case, you can have, well,
your stablecoin-based insurance,
basically.
I made a forum post on that.
many months ago on well contracts which
is securing physical assets with digital
algorithmic twins so physical gold for
example with algorithmic gold
Yeah, there's a lot of financial products
that exist based on like the time friction
of delivery, right?
So it's like, you have, I guess, a lot of
paper financial products that first
started with that friction where it's
like, okay,
You own something that is in transit to
you or to somewhere else.
And so it represents a claim rather than
like a possession.
Like it's not really a bearer asset
because you don't have it.
Someone else has it, but you have that
friction in terms of settlement and
physical reality.
Right?
So it's like you have a producer that
fills a ship with oil.
And as that oil is moving across the
ocean contracts are constantly being
switching hands, every turn of the
propeller until it gets to the final
destination.
And then usually there's some notion of
like settlements.
and possession of the commodity once it's
physically arrived.
And that friction is never going to go
away in physical reality, right?
We're talking about things that do not
settle instantly because they have to move
in the real world.
And so having some
I guess abstraction of ownership that I
guess in some sense, there's like a layer
two where it's like a notion of like pre
confirmation and settlement that will
later happen once reality catches up.
That's constantly happening with
commodities.
And I think that is one of the more
interesting use cases of those type of
stable coins.
Right.
So yeah, well, a lot of interesting
possibilities here, right?
And a lot of complexities, especially if
we are talking about property rights.
In this age, we are already living in the
age of programmable assets, right?
Programmable ownership.
Probably good to answer this question
from Wombo.
Arm, can you speak a bit about your
experience over the week with catalyst
drama, what you heard and your thoughts on
it?
I don't know.
I don't, I don't really see it as drama.
So, the catalyst is built with, certain
parameters.
Okay.
And, and whenever you're going to deal
with things on chain, it's a good idea to
get some like notion of what the
parameters are and how things operate.
So like from my framework, I don't know.
It's essentially like a DeFi protocol,
right?
And so as a DeFi protocol, I guess if you
look at how it functions, it is something
that has an open attack vector for whales.
It always has, right?
So, we can look back in the Ergo
experience of like, SigmaUSD, for a while
had, had a, a certain whale that was
moving things around just based on the
weight of value that that whale could push
around, right?
That's always been a open vector for
catalyst drama.
And so, I've always kind of watched
catalysts and say, okay, this is
interesting.
Like if I were to go talk to Binance or a
bit, or, party that, has a dominant amount
of power in, Let's say ADA, they have the
ability to influence outcomes.
That's how the system is designed.
So then it's like, okay, there's some
logical path where unless that changes,
the most logical outcome is that a large
party can vote for themselves.
Right.
And, that is kind of a shitty form of
governance, maybe, but I don't know.
I didn't create the parameters.
It's not my game, but I went to the table
with that knowledge.
Right.
And so you had an entity that's actually
not that large of an entity and it was the
Cardano foundation, which I'm going to say
probably has more.
I don't know alignment of intent than
other potential whales right if we if we
look at the SigmaUSD and like how the bear
whale has his own incentive right and
that's profit I think probably the cardano
foundation has less of a profit incentive
maybe they're making a statement or trying
to get something I don't know exactly what
their intent was and to be honest I don't
need to care because
That's how the game is, right?
So if something happens in an open.
system within the parameters of how
protocol functions, that's called fair
game.
So I'm not going to sit around and cry
about it.
And, I know some people will talk about
philosophy and social theory and what is
good and what is, bad and what is right
and what is wrong.
And those are terrible security
incentives for DeFi.
And essentially that's how this system
operates.
So no crying.
understand your assumptions in the system
and try to do your best to navigate within
that.
And, like for Rosen Bridge, we've tried
to create partnerships with, when MensSwap
supported us in the past, Liquid has
supported us and they have, pretty large
power in terms of allocating votes.
That's just the game, right?
So it is what it is.
Things happen.
No crying.
You just, adapt, figure it out, move
forward.
I think that sometimes when you're
looking like DeFi, you just need to be
cold and look at the parameters of a
system.
This is how it functions and, operate
from that perspective rather than like an
emotional level.
Because, yeah, crying is not the type of
liquidity we need, folks.
why don't we go to the next question?
what did you pick?
Actually a lot of questions.
some comments.
Nice coffee cup, Joe.
anything to share about hack
participants, winners.
You want to take this?
I was not a judge this time.
I've been a little bit busy off-chain.
I do know that it looks like Satergo came
in first place.
I think Bruno got second.
The Shark and the Sigmanauts came in
third.
I haven't really dived into the projects
to be honest.
what are those things where you get busy
and then just external like bandwidth yes
so yeah the first place is not just
satergo but satergo offline world so yes
some solution for well increased security
Especially when we are talking about
sensitive amounts, right?
You shouldn't use mobile for sure, right?
I mean, that's quite a terrible choice
talking about security.
So, I mean, mobile wallet is just for
small amounts to play with, yeah, to have
some fun, maybe to buy a pizza with ERGs
and so on, but yeah, not for serious
holding.
One of the options for serious holding
would be better after certain reviews.
I would be happy to find time to take a
look at Satergo Offline World.
Then, yeah, well, the second place is
Bruno's, yeah, benefactory platform.
And, yeah, I'm in the middle of watching
the video, actually, so, yeah, well, I'm
posting them to ergochats.
When I'm starting watching, I've posted
Satergo and Brunos and I'm in the middle
of listening to it in the background.
Then the third place is Sigmanauts mining
pool somewhat project-wide.
And then there are other interesting
projects such as community, liquidity.
bootstrapping initiative so how well
people who don't know about Ethereum and
so on can participate in liquidity
provision on Ethereum so provide liquidity
for
Ethereum to ERG and USDT to ERG pools on
Uniswap.
So very interesting project, I think.
Yeah, well, we need to check other
projects, so I didn't participate this
time because of traveling.
Yeah, well, I didn't have time to take a
close look to all the submissions, to be
honest.
So, yeah, well, maybe next time we can
provide more extensive reviews.
A lot of things happening.
Yeah, then any question?
No, let me.
You want to prioritize a lot of
questions.
That's good.
A lot of good questions.
Let's take this one from Luke Graysmith.
Can government be separated from money?
Can money be separated from government?
For most of human history, the peg, the
least that fiat has been around the peg.
that kind of was the underlying base
layer of money was not necessarily
controlled by government then that would
be like gold and silver now to some degree
it's like okay was that physical asset
like controlled and through force yeah so
i guess i guess
Like on some level, even though like gold
and silver being like the underlying peg
for most fiat, still was connected to this
idea of like, I don't know, keep what you
kill.
And usually, governments and, groups have
always kind of been fighting for ownership
rights of various resources on this
planet.
So it's hard to say like, full
separation.
because government is just some like
abstraction of collective human power and
it's kind of hard to have like money which
is a human phenomenon separate from
like humanity is a collective.
But one interesting thing about something
like, proof of work assets or gold is it's
like it is globally distributed.
It just takes, work and energy to, in
essence, refine or extract these assets.
And there's a separation from the, let's
say,
And there's like hard, the ability to
hard code amounts in terms of money, which
I guess maybe like on some level, the
universe did that in terms of like
precious metals that are available in our
little biosphere or in like the case of
Bitcoin or Ergo, they launched from
Genesis with some finite amount.
So like, is it, can it be separated?
I think that the,
It's not exactly a clear-cut question
because, government is just like an
abstraction of collective human
consciousness that, creates some consensus
or order and, usually has some notion of
like projecting power.
So not fully, but you can certainly
restrict some of the parameters around
like money and how that operates.
And I think that as
Like you get away from centralization,
you generally get better assumptions.
What's your thought, kushti?
Yeah, so historically also, well, many
countries now also called free banking
when banks issued money without special
regulations.
So that was in the U.S.
Mostly from 1830s to 1864.
Then later it took place in Canada, Hong
Kong.
Yeah, I'm not sure about regulations, but
yeah, currency there is well issued by
private banks.
But yeah, I guess there are regulations
now, right?
So well, currently, I'm not sure any free
banking systems remain.
And so there are talks about getting back
to free banking, right?
And I think with blockchain it actually
makes sense because of transparency,
right?
So the usual issue was
well fractional reserve rights and well
improper reporting of reserves by private
banks then yeah in all the cases basically
governments use that to intervene right so
to take control but then they did
basically the same so well improper
reporting of reserves and so on
Well, playing with fractional reserve, so
it was back in 19th century even, right,
so a long time before abandoning gold
standard.
So back in 19th century there was no
government fully backing paper money
despite the claims.
Already right, but still some governments
used the same issues on the private bank
side to take control from private banks.
rather than to do the same, basically.
So yeah, now with blockchains, right,
with transparency.
possible transparency of reserves and
operations.
Yeah, it's possible, right, to get back
to free banking and actually I saw
ChainCash is some attempts, right, to
model the revival of free banking on top
of blockchain assets.
So the second presentation
of ChainCash is about that.
Actually, so the first one was more
technical, right?
And yeah, it was ErgoHack report.
But yeah, the second presentation is for
a general audience familiar with free
banking ideas.
But the idea is simple as that.
So it's when private banks can issue
money rights under the same units of
accounts.
Well, hey, if you're talking about the
US, for example, back in 19th century, so
it was dollar right, but issued by
different banks.
And well, on blockchain, now everyone can
be the bank rights.
Yeah, well and also Everyone well in case
of ChainCash is free to use full coverage
or fractional reserve And then yeah, it's
it's up to well agents accepting Not see
issued in this free banking kind of system
and
Yeah, going back to the question, right?
So yeah, I mean, it's a pretty well-known
environment, I guess.
And yeah, well, before 20th century,
actually, that was quite normal to have
private money, right?
Along with government's money.
Well, there were many countries,
actually.
not not having central banks and
government issued money at all.
So yeah, I mean, it's government's own
money is relatively a new phenomenon,
actually, historically.
Okay,
Hopefully enough.
I mean, we can talk more about when it
comes to such topics.
We can talk for a long time, but yeah,
probably enough.
I was thinking about that in relation to
stable coins, actually, as you were
talking.
Well, stablecoins are also a form of
private money, issued by Tether, for
example.
Yeah.
And there's always questions like what's
the backing or audit ability of it.
And like, on some abstract level, it's
like, okay, well let's say you have
backing and it's like, okay, I'm sitting
on this couch and this couch can be
denominated in dollars.
So then can I create my own, Joe's couch
dollars that's backed by this couch and
then say, Hey everybody, we're going to
spend, Joe couch dollars.
And it has,
Actually, why not?
It would still be better than most of
meme coins, right?
Because in case of meme coins, it's not
even claimed that they're backed by
anything, right?
I don't know.
Social energy.
Yeah, social energy, some information
phenomenon.
Yeah.
How to call it?
I don't know.
So some meme actually, right?
I think you just say that like there's
this weird
Phenomenon that's like where attention
goes I don't know energy flows and money
goes there, too So it's like memes are
constantly trying to be like give me
attention.
Give me attention and the more attention
they get then People throw money at it.
So I guess in some sense, maybe Joe's
couch dollars are a little bit more
durable but it's weird because like from
If you talk to somebody that's not
familiar with blockchain or free banking,
they'll be like, hey, isn't that
counterfeiting?
Like you're creating some abstract dollar
that's not quote unquote a dollar.
And so I think that's ultimately where
you get a lot of friction from government
anyway, is there's probably people that
have this mindset like you're creating
artificial dollars
That we don't have the same level of
oversight and control Versus like the the
original dollar so I think that is one of
the biggest pain points probably in terms
of stable coins peg to the fiat
specifically in the US like you're
inheriting their jurisdiction in their
mindset and that's dangerous and So I even
think we're gonna see like a more
more of a split than we've already seen.
It's like, okay, you have, USDC and they
have some, regulatory support and then,
ripple is coming and they're going to
have, better licensing.
So like, again, if you go back to what we
were talking about with real world assets,
it's like, you have to deal with these off
chain layers and different jurisdictions.
And
like at some point it unlocks potential
utility, but it also creates a single
attack surface.
And it's like, well, maybe there's value
in that utility, but your resilience maybe
doesn't, so much exist anymore.
And that's going to be an interesting
trade off to see how people deal with that
or, approach it or don't deal with it, I
guess.
I've always thought that dealing with
that layer of like jurisdictional
complexity probably makes the most sense
on another layer and the base, but that's,
that's my thought anyway.
See any good questions, kushti?
a lot of, so,
Let's start with some shilling maybe.
Where can we buy Ergo hats like yours
worldwide?
So you wanna show some store?
I'm not really, I have no idea.
The internet, somebody in the chat or did
a link at some point and I bought a hat.
So hopefully you can join like, I don't
know, telegram discord, Twix, whatever
they call it now.
and ask, what's the latest and greatest
place to buy Ergo physical merchandise.
And yeah, MewFinance is an option, but I
think MewMart has some steel, but they
have made mining great again, right?
But the question is about yours.
No, I have no idea.
Do you want to sell it maybe on you?
Well, do you have maybe some extra to
sell?
I don't know.
I bought a better one.
Wanna show your supplier maybe?
Oh yeah, I bought a better one like three
years ago, but I gave it to mgPai.
All right.
Yeah, then let me answer a question.
How can this Ergo network interact with
other blockchain networks that use
different consensus algorithms?
So there are many different options here.
So if we are talking about, well,
proof-of-work blockchains with, let's say,
simple consensus, such as Bitcoin with its
just SHA-256 hash function being used as
proof-of-work function, then you can build
even a trustless relay from Bitcoin to
Ergo.
And actually, the prototype was built by
me at some ErgoHack back in June, I
believe.
So yeah, you can check it and by using
that trustless relay so you can
trustlessly bring Bitcoin to Ergo maybe,
right?
You just need to consider locking
condition on Bitcoin.
You can use, for example, well, you can
burn
bitcoin on bitcoin blockchain and
presents a proof to get some tokens on
ergo blockchain that's a proof of born
idea maybe not popular now but back in
2014 there were some
kind of ICOs or token generation events
based on proof of burn, right?
And yeah, I guess a lot of Bitcoins were
burned, so they are proof of burn.
events.
Then you can also bring information from
Bitcoin blockchain messages and metadata
written in OP_RETURNs outputs.
The problem is that the opposite way
doesn't work, right?
So from Ergo to Bitcoin you cannot build
trustless relay really
Well, at least it's not known how to
build one because of Bitcoin limitations.
So, well, in this case, you can use
multi-signature-based solutions and here,
well, maybe Joe can tell us about Rosen
Bridge.
how it works with different blockchains
based on different consensus mechanisms.
Sure.
Well, you basically are kind of
abstracting that off the chain, at least
with Rosen Bridge.
So you're creating, scanners that are
reading and posting data between two
networks.
So you kind of have an intermediary layer
Yeah, there's a lot of different
potential ways to
Connect in different environments.
I would recommend that, if you want to
look at how Rosen Bridge works, we have a
lot of documentation on the website.
You can also join the channel and kind of
dive in to kind of the different chains
that we connect to and, how they operate,
what their assumptions are, because we
always have to have a footprint in like
whatever their consensus or finality
process looks like.
So it's it's a little bit different in a
way if you're looking at like the
assumptions of settlement from system to
system to system.
But there's a lot of different ways these
can connect.
I like Rosen Bridge's design because like
from my perspective, it treats assets more
like assets versus just information.
Like there's a lot of bridges that more
or less pass information or
proofs of something versus go through
like a redundant auditing process like you
would expect with money itself versus kind
of like information relaying any other
questions on there that that makes sense
to you kushti oh a lot of questions oh we
are out of time so
you think one question, one more
question.
Yeah.
Pick whatever's random.
Oh, there is one awesome question about
identity.
But yeah, it's about 20 minutes probably
to answer.
So ask next time.
Just copy paste this question.
Currently we are out of time.
Some questions about Rosen Bridge or
maybe let's pick something for both of us.
Yeah.
So yeah, please copy paste.
Well, paste during the next time, please.
Wait, wait, wait.
What's the answer?
How can we tokenize consumable
commodities?
Probably also quite involved, right?
How much Kraken is asking for Ergo
listing?
I don't know about any ask.
thoughts on aliens oh we don't have time
for serious questions even sorry ask the
hard questions yeah that's good hard
questions yeah we had some great questions
today
It's things that if you just kept talking
about it.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So government and money.
Yeah.
So it was really hard question among
others, but we don't have time for hard
questions as well.
So what to do?
Maybe, yeah, let's, let's talk if that's
time.
What's the answer?
kushti.
Will you be taken a well earned break
over Christmas?
How's about that?
I don't know.
Yeah, that's a good one from just a
little bit better.
Probably not.
I'll cook some food.
It's not that hard at least.
yeah do i take a break over christmas no
i'll i'll take a day cook some food have
family you're you're on the orthodox you
get to january christmas right january 7th
and yeah then also night of six but yeah
it's it's pretty much the same plan so
usually yeah i'm i'm going to church on
January 6th night and then yeah well
taking rest for half a day on 7th and yeah
that's it basically then you continue to
work yeah nice food day though hopefully
you got good stuff cooking over there yeah
so yeah
It's usually about, yeah, you can have
something like duck or turkey, so maybe
not very different even.
I'm going to smoke beef rib roast.
Yeah, sounds good.
So yeah, a lot of questions, but we need
for time to answer them.
So please repeat the next time and yeah,
well,