Hello, happy Thanksgiving to all the USA
Sigmanauts.
How you doing, kushti?
Good morning.
Doing well.
Hi, everyone.
Good time to share some updates, I guess,
and discuss some things in the AMA format.
It sure is, kushti.
Yeah, so we are trying different formats.
That was a good community call.
That was fun, yeah, the Zoom call, yep.
Yeah, a bit chaotic maybe, but yeah,
because for the first time I believe,
there were a lot of opinions and people
willing to speak, so it lasted for one
hour and a half instead of one hour, or
maybe not really planned, but I don't
know. I had in mind something like that.
And then, yeah, well, there will be
Twitter spaces tomorrow.
Do you know about that?
Which one's that, kushti?
One with House of Chimera, so it will be
announced later today.
Oh, it's the other one you invited me to.
Yeah, so you will be there, supposedly.
Awesome.
Yeah, and Joe also will be there. So,
yeah, three of us will represent and
uncover Ergo to House of Chimera community
and also Ergo community is welcomed to
jump.
Awesome. I'll look for that announcement.
We'll retweet it, get it out there too.
All right. Yeah. So we'll ask for an
announcement actually after the AMA. So
yeah, we are exploring different formats
with different entities around such as
House of Chimera, and there is one
proof-of-work merge mined Bitcoin
sidechain. We may have Twitter spaces.
Then, yeah, maybe some Ergo-only Twitter
space again, and then community calls. So
even the side of AMA, well, it's about
very tight schedule.
It seems before the new year if we are
targeting to have all of that, that's
about pretty tight schedule actually.
I heard some feedback online that CKB
wants to do another hosted space with us
as well kind of that space so we'll do
that at some point in the future this
year.
Maybe not this year, qx().
Yeah, because for this year, everything
is set probably already.
Yes. Well, maybe January then.
Yeah, cool beans. Well, what's new,
kushti?
That's a lot of new things, so finally
EIP-50 for 6.0 soft fork proposal
published, and the most, let's see,
understandable parts which are for general
public are also cross-published on the
forum. And then yeah so there's currently
just one pull request left and the first
round of reviewing already done so I'm
working on tests and I'm going to ping
miners to get good dates for start of
voting.
As a reminder, Ergo is not centralized
cryptocurrency if such term makes sense at
all, controlled by dev team so every
change is to be voted by miners with 90
percent, 90 plus percent of hash rate
voting for is needed for approval.
kushti, can you explain briefly how that
works? Like you publish a new kind of
change code for the node and how
specifically do miners vote on that, just
for the people watching?
Yeah, so basically they need to install
the latest version or a version of the
node which is supporting a new version of
the protocol. But then the voting is still
explicit. So they need to put concrete
value in settings, so they need to find
the voting section in the config file and
put certain value there because there is
no implicit voting. Before, there were
some pools which were asked for versions
of the node with implicit voting. When it
was 5.0, if my memory serves me well. They
did pre-voting, they didn't make a choice
until individually the miners voted on
their pool.
Was it GetBlock that did that?
So, GetBlock had the individual voting
for designers. Other pools just decided
whether to vote yes or no, and some asked
for a version with specific config, but
maybe after it was voted already to have
lock-in done. So I've forgotten actually
something like that. Well, in general, a
miner needs to put a vote for soft fork
explicitly.
For sure. And if some of the big pools or
the other pools, even small pools, don't
update their node to that, it's
essentially a totally different chain if
the soft fork goes through?
It's soft fork, so actually they will
continue to recognize blocks. They even
can mine blocks if we are talking about
upcoming soft forks. But there is a chance
that they can include invalid
transactions. So, well, 5.0 and actually
previous nodes will skip validations of
transactions with new features, 6.0
features. And then if 6.0 transaction is
invalid, for example, then there is a
chance that a miner not updated will mine
this invalid transaction and gets the
block rejected by 90% of the hash rate.
That's why voting is needed. You need to
be sure that even if all nodes are in the
network, they cannot mine invalid
transactions so that they cannot produce
long enough forks. That's why such big
numbers here in the wording for critical
things. Yeah, so there is forum posts
which is uncovering changes proposed such
as new features, opening possibilities for
actually a lot of applications, some
already shown such as trustless Bitcoin
bridge.
Then Lithos, then yes, certain roll-up
constructions are shown to be feasible.
Hash rate coin, so hash rate derivatives
would be feasible with 6.0. Yeah, well,
efficient at least, right, with 6.0.
Cryptographic applications. There is an
unfinished example of a range proof
validation. I've assigned a bounty for
that issue. If you want to play with
cryptography, ErgoScript and also get some
bounty, consider to finish this example.
It's a bit tricky, but definitely from
what I've checked, I've made half of it
and we found that the rest is using
basically the same operations which are
added along with a new unsigned big
integer type needed for cryptographic
applications along with modular
arithmetics.
Well, another thing aside of new features
and so on is the possibility in the node
to vote for new parameters without
breaking previous versions of the nodes or
maybe versions of the nodes not
recognizing such voting, so you can do
maybe some velvet forking kind of voting
from 6.0. And in particular, 6.0 nodes
also do recognize a new parameter, which
is number of sub-blocks per block. So,
yeah, well, with it, this parameter can be
used further in the sub-blocks protocol to
have miners having possibility to readjust
a number of sub-blocks per block, which is
quite interesting, I believe, when miners
would be capable to change frequency of
sub-blocks' pulsation, let's say.
When should we start pushing this out on
socials to get at least the miners aware
and the pool operators aware?
Right now, so I mean, it's finalized and
so what's not finalized is activation
details for mainnet. And yeah, so for
public testnet, I think we can do
activation like two weeks, literally two
weeks. So the testnet is currently not
that stable. So yeah, but when it will
become... Oh, we've got it there. We're
just waiting for your note, I think. It's
mgPai myself. It's also Explorer, so I
need to check with them what's going on
with the Explorer notes.
Right, you have to point testnet explorer
to the new testnet.
Yeah, but the testnet explorer is looking
at mine's not. And then there is need to
fix things. Maybe your peers are burning
the notes. Let's see. But yeah, I guess
it's about one to two days anyway. And
then I need to do some more tests in the
form of codes and also manual tests in
DevNets.
I'm running regularly 6.0 DevNets. Then
we'll propose public testnet activation
and then at the same time we can talk with
miners about mainnet activation details.
And as a reminder, after beginning of
voting at least three months would be
needed for activation. So first it would
be 32 epochs of 1024 blocks each for
voting and in case of supermajority
achieved not just supermajority and 90
plus percent - so supermajority is usually
associated with 66 percent plus and in
case of 90 plus percent support.
There is also a 32 epochs delay for
activation to give a possibility for
everyone to update. In total it's 64
epochs, 1024 blocks each, so about 3
months. Yeah and then we will have 6.0
activated and at the same time so during
those three months actually we can work on
sub-blocks because sub-blocks probably
would be deployed in a few steps and some
soft forkish update for miners would be
needed only at the last step, and they can
be deployed in kind of velvet fork way
before.
So yeah, and it would be good to consider
what to do after, so basically from mid
2025 and so on. So already a lot of talks.
A lot of proposals were pushed, but there
is need to consider what to do and in what
form. So I think the general vector could
be to decentralize development more.
Definitely as communities also definitely
becoming more and more decentralized in
regards with every aspect we can think of.
And then, yeah, so also, well, started,
so as I discussed, started Ergo book, and
now Joe is going also to contribute, so
hopefully some parts but I'm actually
thinking to publish like article by
article on the forums maybe the first
piece likely will be published this week
so just a few days after 6.0 proposal and
with Ergo book the idea is to get material
from different members of Ergo movement,
Ergo community, will become leader,
conceptualizing what we do know about
cryptocurrencies as a form of money,
peer-to-peer networks and so on.
And then how those concepts are realized
in Ergo, from philosophical aspects going
to technical. And then going maybe deeper.
And then to get some picture of what Ergo
protocol and ecosystem around is about and
maybe trying to achieve.
It looks like we got a sneaky guest when
you were talking, kushti.
Yeah, it's actually the spider that's
sitting on the wall there for the past
hour and a half. I don't like killing
spiders, so that guy's taking advantage of
the situation. So nice to see you, Charlie
Rose. AKA, qx().
It's great to see you too.
Yeah. For those of you who are too young
to know this, so Charlie Rose is a
journalist and old school journalist. And
he would conduct all of his interviews
with a black background like this. It was
very, it was very much like his brand to
always interviews with this black
background. So that's why I keep calling
qx() Charlie Rose and he's just like
looking to be like, what?
No, I know Charlie Rose. Of course.
Good. Because you make, give me this
blank face. Like I don't even know what
the hell anyway. Yeah. So, so, I mean, I
walked into this really interesting
conversation here. Now, you know, another
interesting conversation, actually you
mentioned Joe. And it just kind of, it's
kind of funny, you know, how narratives
and how people just kind of jump into
these, like, I mean, I don't want to say
just pure hype because it is quite a bit
of interesting tech behind BitcoinOS.
But, you know, the community and, you
know, our community as well as the Cardano
community, and of course, you know, the
communities are mixed, really jumped on
this, like BitcoinOS is going to bring so
much liquidity and it's just going to, you
know, just going to bring, it's going to
bring all of Bitcoin onto Cardano and
Ergo, and it's just going to be awesome,
you know, we're just going to be swimming
in liquidity. It's going to be so liquid
out here. It's going to be like, you know,
like Solaris, like the ocean planet.
Yeah, and it could but, you know, Ergo
already made something like this that
works really, really well. It's called
Rosen Bridge. And I keep talking about it
on socials. And it's just interesting
that, you know, like, I mean, we do get
quite a bit of recognition for Rosen, I
think. Rosen is one of the more popular
Ergo projects, I think, in the Ergo
Cardano ecosystem. You know, on Cardano,
many people know about Rosen versus, I
guess, you know, other projects that came
out of Ergo.
Maybe, you know, Splash, you know, is one
that rivals the popularity of Rosen. But
Rosen is this, you know, it's like pure
Ergo tech. And yeah, you know, I actually,
I see this question down here. I don't
know if you guys are, yeah, well, Jumeis
telling us to better learn how to swim.
Yeah, it's good.
Let's see. So Bobcat, and I think
actually Bobcat likes to ask this question
on every single AMA, at least that I've
been on, or maybe it's not Bobcat, maybe
it's somebody else, but we get this
question quite a bit, is actually I
selected it. I don't know. Can you guys
see it? I don't think you can see the
questions I selected. Can you see them?
I got you.
I put it there. Yeah, I don't know why I
can't see it. Okay, anyway. Yeah, no,
actually, I probably because I'm not
signed in. But anyway, select the one.
Okay, well, actually, this one as well.
This one is interesting. But I was
actually going to go to the one that just
what are you looking towards in 2025?
Bobcat asked that one.
Yeah. Well, so, but then we can go to the
BitcoinOS one because I actually, I'd like
to hear kushti's input on this and yours
too qx(). Okay. Don't feel like, you know,
in the conversation here. Okay. Yeah.
You're important too qx(). Okay. Don't
cry. Don't cry. Yeah, you know, what I'm
looking towards in 2025 is, you know, big
projects really realizing that it's
already here, it's already built. You
know, the tech is here. You know, there's
no new sensational type of thing. There's
like, oh my God, you know, this is going
to solve everything.
It's already here, but you have to start
utilizing. There has to be traffic. And I
think one of the big plays for 2025 would
be for some really nice, successful, and
successful dApps and platforms that have a
wide customer range, utilizing Rosen,
bringing Rosen just onto their stack and
utilizing it to serve between all these
different ecosystems. And now they got
runes, going to be bridging to Solana,
they're going to be bridging to
everywhere, bridging to the moon.
What was the newest one? I forgot, what
was the newest one for Rosen? What are
they going to be bridging to?
What's it called?
Binance, BNB, or Dogecoin.
Dogecoin and Binance, yeah, are the two
new ones.
Doge, yeah, Doge and Binance. Anyway,
it's here. You know, the tech is here.
It's time to utilize it. And I think our
focus is, and I think what's going to
happen in 2025 is more and more projects
will realize that, well, wait a second. I
need to do this now. Who has the tech now?
Rosen has the tech now. Right now you can
do it right now. I can move assets between
Cardano and Ergo and I can move assets
between Bitcoin and Cardano and so on. I
can do it right now.
And so that's why we're going to be
utilizing, with Paul Meyer, with Paul
McConaughey, we're going to be utilizing
Rosen, because we can do all this stuff.
We have the necessity to make it
cross-chain. We need to be able to move
these assets between Cardano, Ergo,
Bitcoin, EVM, because we actually have
some commitments to move some of this
stuff to EVM. And the tech is here, and
the tech is the most practical for it. So
it's all about really not just kind of
ringing the bell, look, here it is, but
actually getting these projects, the big
projects to look at it and say, hey, this
solution exists, we should utilize it, we
will utilize it, and getting to utilize
it.
And that's what I see what is happening
in 2025. More and more projects really
kind of getting it. So, yeah, I just
wanted to go to that question because that
was really on my mind after all this
stuff, BitcoinOS, because, you know, I
mean, I guess, yeah, I mean, people want
to see liquidity, and you want to see
liquidity, you want to see, you know, life
on chain.
And they think that, you know, Bitcoin
will bring that more of that life on
chain. Whether it will or won't remains to
be seen, but, you know, they think it
will, you know. Actually, I would like to
get kushti's, well, and yours qx(). Okay,
yours qx() and kushti's input on the
difference because I'm sure that people
have asked, how is it different? Is it the
same tech or is it different tech?
So I don't know which one he wants to go
first, but maybe he should answer that.
Right maybe. Sure, well first of all in
the social scene my tribute I attribute
that BitcoinOS hype and then pretty quick
what's the opposite of hype? I don't know
but that happened all in it like a week
drama drama on Twitter I attribute that to
you know, everything's experience of pump
Cardano and Ergo both recently and
experience quite a quite a pump in there
in their sex and their sex value at least.
Everybody's frothing in the mouth and then
along comes this other promise of you know
the promise of more liquidity flowing in
and higher values there so people
immediately jump on the train for that
without even thinking or looking or
reading into it or anything and then they
come out with a they come up with, oh
yeah, we're going to fundraise here as a
token, and everybody's like, oh, that's
awful.
You know, you guys are awful, that kind
of thing. So that was funny to watch with
popcorn from the sidelines, that's for
sure. But from what I understand, here,
I'll give my stupid explanation, and
kushti can correct everything that I'm
wrong. So, Rosen's a bridge, essentially.
You lock tokens on one side, you release
them on the other side. And Rosen's unique
and special because it uses this two-layer
approach with watchers and guards.
Watchers first see the transaction,
report it, guards verify that transaction,
then do a consensus and release it on the
other side. There's never any minting of
tokens. It's not like a live mint. The
tokens, the supply is minted and locked
right off the bat. So there's no way you
can continuously leak and mint more tokens
on Rosen like that. Whereas BitcoinOS, I
believe, is more like a programmable
layer. I mean, it's its own thing where
you can have kind of trustless relays
like, I think kushti, you made one
recently as a proof of concept back in a
couple months ago to be able to report
transactions on another chain from
Bitcoin.
But that's my understanding of it.
kushti, please correct me.
Yeah, so you can use trustless relay to
bring Bitcoin to Ergo. But the other way,
it doesn't work because you cannot build
Ergo relay on Bitcoin. Bitcoin is too
limited for that so then you can do
different tricks such as BitcoinOS way to
verify ZK snarks. But, yeah, it's
complicated. And, yeah, it's not audited,
it's not well tested and so on. And it's
also not even quite new. So Bitcoin
community is considering using snarks in
Bitcoin along with Bitcoin scripts in form
of contingent payments, for example, since
2015, so the first presentation was done
at Financial Cryptography 2015.
But then it's stuff quite complicated, so
the original scheme presented at Financial
Cryptography 2015 was shown to be insecure
in some paper from 2017. That paper
proposed a fix, a paper by Alexander
Chiesa and others. I've forgotten its
name. But then the proposed fix even was
corrected in another follow-up paper. So,
yeah, and about this BitcoinOS, they wait
to optimistically verify snarks. Yeah, I
personally would wait for I don't know,
another five years to have dust settle
down around all that.
I mean just from my observation of
previous attempts to build stuff like
that. Yes, so contingent payments were
used even in simpler context like, so the
original showcase was paid for Sudoku
solution, so payment for proving, for a
proof of some computationally hard
challenge solution. But, yeah, even in
that simple setting, things are quite
complicated and BitcoinOS is more
complicated and the white paper is not
that detailed, let's say. So it's just
very briefly touching details and
efficiency is not quite clear and then
execution in the presence of network
congestion and so on.
And then about how all those things are
implemented from snarks to scripts,
Bitcoin and what are possible attacks and
so on. So yeah, it's still not quite clear
to start with. And yeah, in the Rosen,
it's just a multisig on Bitcoin side. And
it's maybe not that fancy, but it's quite
clear how it's working, at least, on the
Bitcoin side. And then on the Ergo side,
there is another layer of protection,
which is about watchers.
And guards.
Guards, but guards are co-signing on
Bitcoin?
And in case of anything happening there,
so you have second layer on Ergo, second
layer.
Oh, I see what you mean. Yeah.
So, yeah, I mean, it's simple and working
at least.
Speaking of Rosen Bridge, Armeanio and
the Rosen team are getting near their
Hummingbot implementations, and they're
putting out a channel soon on Telegram and
they're going to use it as an educational
kind of thing where people come in, they
learn about it, they run it, they test it,
and they get very knowledgeable about how
to run your own hummingbot. I mean, that's
one of the things that I mean, everybody
wishes for some big angel to come in and
dump liquidity everywhere and trade
everywhere and hold our hands and make us
feel good like some savior or messiah. But
when it comes down to it, guys, it's us.
Like we have the power to take, even if
you have like 200 ERGs, it doesn't matter.
grab this hummingbot, jump in the channel
when it's made, learn how to use it,
arbitrage across the ecosystems, across
exchanges, and make a couple ERGs along
the way, you know, just from running
something easily on your computer. And
that will provide liquidity, that'll help
provide liquidity across different
pockets, different enclaves, whether it be
Ethereum, Binance, Doge, Cardano, Bitcoin
anything like that, so it's up to us guys.
I mean I feel like we're sitting
Sometimes I feel like we're sitting in
this advanced cathedral with all these
amazing scientific tools in front of us in
the year 4000. And we're sitting there
looking at these tools and being like, oh,
that's cool. Let's poke it. That's neat.
But when's somebody going to come along
and build this for us and do this for us?
It's like, the tools are there, guys. We
have everything we need. And there's
plenty of us. There's 12-some thousand
people in the Telegram chat alone. There's
plenty of us to be able to pick up
something and use it and make a
difference.
So, I mean, we're talking hundreds of
people run these hummingbots for Rosen
Bridge with their implementation of it,
and you're going to see a big difference
in liquidity across exchanges and DEXs.
Yeah, so watch out for that guys. Please
join the telegram chat when Rosen Bridge
sets it up Don't be afraid to jump in
there and use hummingbot Ask questions.
I'm available for I'll be running one I
just got some loose ERGs from a
reimbursement for running some servers. So
I have those I can put in and We can
provide liquidity across the spectrum
guys. So don't be afraid We're here to
hold each other's hands.
You're that liquidity provider that's
going to just come and provide liquidity
everywhere.
No, I just... I only have like 300 ERGs.
Just go around and liquidity everything.
I only have like 300 ERGs, but I'll put
it all towards HummingBot. No problem.
Yeah, 300 ERGs times 300.
No, no, everything else is in ecosystem
projects.
I also think to provide some more
liquidity. Yeah, it seems there are some
options which are not realized yet. Even
SigmaUSD to Dexy Gold liquidity pool. But
yeah, it's very natural, I guess,
liquidity pool to profit from arbitrage.
Because, depending on crypto market
conditions, you have independent movements
of gold price against USD.
It's kind of crypto-independent way to
profit from arbitrage. And yeah, it's
still not there, surprisingly. So yeah,
well, I will do that. So I even tried, but
got some errors before because of
something with Spectrum DEX chainbots.
There was something when trying to create
liquidity pools on certain clients, but
yeah, well now it's probably resolved. So
yeah, need to try again.
All right, what else we got here? All
right. Well, yeah, we actually got a so
this is a actually a term that's been
floating around We would love we love to
say demurrage The mirage. The mirage.
Yeah. Yeah. So we'd love to use the word
the mirage, but I think a lot of people
are missing context here. So why don't you
qx() explain this like you would to a five
year old.
Awesome. Demurrage to a five-year-old.
Let's see. Demurrage, well, first of all,
demurrage is one of the coolest things
about Ergo. Super, super cool. It's also
one of the most misunderstood things about
Ergo when people come in. So explaining
like a five-year-old. Okay. Let's see.
Okay, let's say that the five-year-old has
a bunch of toys. And you like to play with
your toys. You have your trains, you have
your Legos, you have everything. All
right.
So, you put those toys in, every time you
put it away, you put it in a little
baggie, and you throw it in your little
protective coating, and you throw it in
your chest, your box outside. All right,
every time you want to play with it or do
it, you have to get it out of that little
baggie, play with it, put it back in the
little baggie and set it there. But let's
say you don't play with toys for quite a
while. They take up space in that chest
and it's hard for your dad to move that
chest around and put it in the basement or
put it upstairs for you and do that. So it
gets heavier and heavier and heavier.
So, what you can do to help prevent that,
there are two things. You can either take
all the toys out and put them in one bag
and maybe store that bag in an easier
place. And then there's more room in the
chest. Or you can, your dad can get really
pissed at you for having so many toys. And
he can take a few of those toys in the
small bags that you haven't touched in a
long, long time and essentially throw them
out. So that's maybe a five-year-old could
understand that. I don't know. That may
have been too simply and missing a little
bit of the point. But here's a
12-year-old's explanation.
So blockchains get bloat. We know that
from watching other chains who lost their
history and struggling to find it and
chains that get massively bloated. And
bloat leads to centralization. You have
Solana nodes that are so massive and
require so much throughput that people are
running them in centralized clusters like
in Amazon or Azure. So that is not
decentralized. That's not somebody like
Dan or kushti or myself who could just
spin up a node in our basement or on our
spare computer. So keeping a node pruned
and small is going to encourage
decentralization on small devices.
OK, so in order to do that, Ergo in the
base code says that, hey, if you have
these boxes, where UTXO, so every
transaction into your wallet goes in its
own little box, you can never add to that
box. If you want to use the tokens in that
box, you have to spend the box, which then
takes money and puts it in somebody else's
wallet in a box and brings a change back
to your little another new box in your
thing all right so in order to make sure
the blockchain is small excuse me anything
after four years of just sitting there not
doing anything and when i say four years i
mean four years in block time Just sitting
there not doing anything will be able to
allow to be collected a small amount of
rent from it all right and what this does
is if not necessarily it's two factor
right you're collecting rent from people
who aren't doing anything who are just
storing things on chain and not moving it
around so it could be a miner that has 10
000 boxes of one ERG that they've been
mining for a long you know and just
sitting there for four years.
Or it could be dust from something,
airdrop, or tokens that were distributed,
or even a miner that just has too much of
a too small ERG sitting around. Okay, so
that takes a bloat on the blockchain. So
demurrage, at that point, if the amount of
ERG in the box is too small for the rent
cost, the whole box is taken and
destroyed. So now we've cleaned up the
chain of all this dust that's just out
there. That amount is called storage rent.
It goes to the people mining it. They can
wrap it in a transaction and spend it and
bring it to the mining pool or the person
mining it.
If there's enough ERG to cover that rent,
then the box is just recreated with a
change with the storage rent taken out of
it and it's put back there. But overall
goal. ELI 12 is that It's meant to prevent
bloat on a blockchain which helps with
decentralization essentially My wife just
brought me a sandwich Look at that
homemade bacon egg sandwich guys Are you
gonna storage rent that sandwich?
It's gonna take some storage rent off it
right now guys Yeah, you're gonna take
storage rent.
Oh, you're actually going to eat while
you're doing an AMA. You, you college
student.
People get afraid, people get afraid of
demurrage or storage rent because they're
like somebody's taking stuff from my
wallet. I hear a lot of FUD sometimes from
like two specific people on Twitter.
That's like, Oh, I don't like Ergo because
the devs can just take all my money. What
they don't understand is that you need a
90% consensus to do any sort of that kind
of change in that consensus mechanism
there to do that absolutely insane
thought. I mean, why would miners vote
against their own interests to be able to
rape everybody's wallet that way? It makes
no sense.
FUD in misunderstandings. It's one of the
best tools out there for a chain to reduce
bloat. I know, kushti, you said Ethereum
had thought about it for a while or
somebody other chains have thought about
implementing in a while, but...
Yeah, so actually Ethereum community
started to discuss storage rent and
actually the term was taken from the
Ethereum community, not demurrage, which
is well known in the theory of money and
economics, but storage rent, so it was
taken from the Ethereum community and
they've been discussing it since 2015
actually. Because it's quite clear that,
you know, it's not fair and quite a broken
economy in Ethereum. Yeah, also Bitcoin
and basically every blockchain when you
can create some object on the blockchain
such as unspent outputs or smart contract
in case of Ethereum and so on and then it
lives forever so it lives on thousands of
computers in peer-to-peer network but it's
been paid once and then living forever,
which is totally unrealistic and also
unfair.
There is no example, I believe, where you
can pay once for storage and then occupy
it forever. It's simply contra-economical.
And yeah, also, when we are talking about
real-world assets such as gold, any
commodity, so you are paying for storage,
it's basically the same. There is some
cost to hold your gold. A brick of gold in
a gold vault. To store any commodity you
have in a warehouse, such as, I don't
know, wheat, coffee, whatever. So you need
to pay for storage. The same in the
digital world. So you're occupying bytes
on the thousands of machines, bytes of
their memory, then you are not paying
anything.
Yeah, in Ethereum it's even worse because
that smart contract is living forever,
it's occupying memory, some critical
indices and so on. Then they will ask for
using suicide command. There is such
instruction when contract is not needed.
You can free. You can mark that it's not
used anymore and free memory basically.
But as you need to pay a gas for such
command, it's not being used. So it's like
a nice command in Linux. So it's nice, but
no one is using it.
And then, yeah, that nonsense about devs
capable to charge, I don't know, that's
completely nonsensical. So in comparison
with all the proof-of-work
cryptocurrencies, but Bitcoin actually,
it's harder in Ergo, because, well, again,
90% voting is... Well, it's not even
possible with soft fork. So you need to do
hard fork, because I don't see any way to
do this soft fork. Well, as we are not
doing, we are avoiding hard forks,
especially such controversial. I mean,
it's the least issue in Ergo in comparison
with other proof-of-work currencies, but
Bitcoin, because I'm not aware about
changing protocol by avoiding anywhere,
but Bitcoin and Ergo.
Because in Ethereum, it always was about
dev's team setting something in the code
and then just ordering miners to update
the nodes and participate in that. Or
else. Yeah, so in that way they even fired
miners after all. But the same is all
other proof-of-work blockchains. So it's
usually about developers just providing a
new version and telling miners to install
it. And that's why it actually was quite
hard to work with miners on all that stuff
voting and so on to ask them to provide
the information and then wait for the
action because usually you know what they
do expect is basically the same as
happening everywhere so developers just
coming and providing a new version and
they're just running a new version of node
software for another shitcoin you know
without thinking much for what's going on
there.
I mean, who cares about some shitcoin,
you know, and what's happening there. I
mean, the only reason for them, for
miners, for mining pool to be there is
just to mine and then dump and then jump
on another ASIC, mining Bitmain controlled
shitcoin. And so, yeah, I mean, because of
that attitude, it's quite hard to push
miners to make decisions about what stuff
they're working on so that's quite weird
so when you push people around to get more
power, usually people are grabbing power.
And here is the opposite situation.
I think anybody looking on from the
outside to the in would see demurrage
storage rent as proof that Ergo has been
created and thought of for the long term
and sustainability. So that's my number
one thought when I think of storage rent
and when I talk to other people about it.
If you're serious into crypto and you see
it as a financial power tool for the
individual, and you look at how these
things were built and thought of, you look
at Ethereum and you're like, how the fuck
is this supposed to sustain for this
thing, or Solana even? My goodness,
they're going to have countries running
these nodes kind of thing.
And you look at Ergo and you're like,
this was really thought out, and this was
thought out for sustainability, this was
thought out for decentralization, and
storage rent just proves that right there,
right off the bat, that that was the case.
Yeah, actually, I love that cathedral
analogy very much, and also, well,
thoughts about writing a text on that,
because cathedrals considered as example
of something, well, thoughts. I believe
Linux community maybe is using the same
analogy, but need to check actually. So
it's something when you can build for
centuries and you are not breaking what
was built before. You are just building
new parts nearby and connecting with
existing parts and with centuries it's
becoming even more solid and even more
beautiful.
So yeah, that's what should be the goal
here. So building a cathedral, not
speculative spec mining or whatever
speculative one-day story. So that was the
goal always implicitly. But yeah, maybe
there is need to also somehow explicitly
state it at some point, I believe.
All right, Dan, what else we have? Is
there any other questions that pique your
interest?
Yeah, let's do one more. So this is
actually, you know, I think this kind of
aligns well with what you were saying
about, you know, the 90% of the time it
works every time with the devs. So here's
a question. Bitcoin is not set in stone
for max supply. Do you think Ergo max
supply will ever get voted to change?
Well, so let's start with can it be voted
to change? Can it?
Not quite, actually, because it's not
part of the protocol even. It's not a
token. Ergo emission is set in the form of
contract. Other cryptocurrencies, you
cannot just change some constant in the
code, like, for example, Ravencoin did,
Ethereum did. And many cryptocurrencies
actually did. So here you need to somehow
change how contracts are executed and
change, I don't know, in a very deep way.
So it would be harder than in Bitcoin,
definitely.
But even in Bitcoin, as far as I know,
they are considering very tricky ways to
bypass emissions. There are different
proposals, but all of them are doing some
tricky things to avoid breaking
everything. So, and in Ergo, yeah, the
first question is whether it's needed at
all, considering that there is storage
rent. So maybe, yeah, if storage rents in
like 20 years wouldn't play out that well
to provide enough rewards, or if there
will be problem with smoothness of rewards
and so on, maybe it would be better to
tweak storage rent like was already
proposed by a community member to put
storage rent to some pool and then pay
from that pool, like from emission
contracts, so just pay certain fixed
amounts of per block.
There are also proposals to have
automatic auctions for tokens collected.
And then, yeah, well, put ERGs raised from
auctions to the same pool, for example.
There are different DeFi tools for
financial schemes, which can be used to
provide smooth rewards to miners when
emission is out. Storage rent probably
would provide enough, especially
considering tokens and so on, in like 20
years when the emission will be finished.
But, yeah, in case of any issues here,
because it's hard to plan such things in
the first place. You don't know what will
happen with UTXO state in 20 years. And,
yeah, in this case, there are many tools,
like repurposing storage rent so instead
of miners just charging it send it to some
pool which is paying miners a fixed amount
of ERG per block doing those auctions well
storage rent parameters can be changed but
only within some range so miners cannot
raise storage rent significantly, the
maximum rate is just 2x of default current
value. And so on. So there is enough
tooling to avoid doomsday scenario which
is about changing emission I believe but
there are different opinions here for sure
so Ethereum guys changed emission I don't
know two or three times already and
probably will do for more but to me it's
you know, a very critical thing which
shouldn't be changed because when you
change such things as total supply, then
you're kind of breaking markets around,
which are already operating on well known
public information about emission.
And that's what makes cryptocurrency is
beautiful. So you have perfectly known
public information about total emission,
emission schedule and so on. And so when
you're breaking such things, it's not that
good story. It could be needed maybe in
some cases and some communities decided to
change emission. Monero, for example,
introduced tail emission, and then
Ethereum changed the reward per block a
few times. But yeah, it's better to avoid
such things at all costs.
Right. I mean, it's changing the
assumptions of a chain. I look at it the
same way as other chains who are talking
about implementing storage rent. You're
changing the assumptions and agreements
when miners started mining your chain and
started, or users started utilizing your
chain. You're changing all the agreements
on the smart contracts written that don't
take into account any sort of future
storage rent or anything like that. So
it's a huge, huge like rug pull, I would
say, on those members.
Yeah, so in Ergo, it's there since day
one, so if you ever used Ergo, you've
agreed to storage rent already. And yeah,
it's not changed. Even parameters are
still the same as five years ago. But
yeah, if you are going to introduce
storage rent to a blockchain which doesn't
have it, then it's also a huge deal. It's
breaking a lot of things on many levels.
But yeah, so in the Bitcoin community,
there are discussions about the
possibility to introduce storage rent now.
Maybe the next civil war in the Bitcoin
community would be about that. So what
would be about? So like previous one was
about just one constant block size.
Whether to set it to 2 megabyte, 4
megabyte, 8 megabyte, unlimited size, do
what's Bitcoin core. Did some magic with
Segwit and so on.
So yeah, then the next civil war could be
about what to do with emission or storage
rent or tail emission. Introducing
changing emission schedule basically by
introducing tail emission. Or just leave
things intact. Yeah, there are maybe other
options. So yeah, the next civil war
probably could be about that.
No, we don't need no civil war.
Yeah, but in Ergo, actually, one of the
motivation to have for all those warnings
for parameter block size for that sort of
for capability was to avoid civil wars in
the Ergo community. So, well, if you don't
like block size, then just reach miners
and tell them towards maybe they will
listen to you. Maybe not, but there is no
need for drama in the community, so just
work with miners and try to change the
protocol in the way you like. I mean, it's
always possible and no one is preventing
that. But also there is no need to push
others to do changes you would like to
have.
So just work on your own or find friends
and work with them.
Dan, you've been very quiet and Wombo's
noticed that. I think you have a question
right here. Wombo's got a question. Dan,
could you speak a bit about your video on
Catamarca Lithium Facility?
Yeah. Well, I can speak a lot about it.
And I think he said a little bit, a little
bit, Danny said, yeah, a little, a lot of,
a little, I'll speak a lot about it in the
coming days. I'm actually going to
Argentina on Sunday again for two weeks
this time. And so there's actually going
to be a continuation of this work. But, it
was an interesting experience, very
interesting. It's one of those things
where you talk about all these things that
we can do with blockchain, especially in
an RWA sector and IoT, RWA and
traceability and all this stuff.
And then you go there and you see that
they need it. I mean, bad. It's a huge
facility and You know, it makes, I mean,
the thing, I think they put like a billion
dollars into it or something like that.
It's some obscene amount of money. And
there are such inefficiencies and not just
there. I mean, it's just in general,
there's such inefficiency, such
opaqueness. And it hurts, it hurts the
production. I mean, it hurts profits
because opaqueness is bad for efficiency.
And when you don't have efficiency, you
get bad ROI. You can get more ROI.
And yeah, just seeing all this really can
open my eyes even more to the fact that
this could all be, like Winter Protocol,
for example, again, built on Ergo, for
those of you who still don't know, because
every couple of weeks I'll get one of
those questions where people will ask me,
so are you building anything on Ergo? Like
we literally built everything on Ergo so
far, like literally the whole platform is
on Ergo so far. So yeah, kushti knows
because kushti has seen it, you know.
Yeah, I mean, I'm reviewing contracts
currently and yeah, they're definitely on
Ergo. I mean, my eyes, yeah, I mean, the
work more or less. So, yeah, it's
definitely about Ergo.
So, you know, and going there and seeing
how we can really help the real world with
Ergo tech, I mean, that is, I mean, to me,
that is actually just really cool and
validating, you know, it's kind of
validates the whole thing that we are on
the right track. So yeah, there's going to
be a lot more actually coming out from
there in the next week or so. You'll see
we got a big unveiling happening next
week. So again, this is another asset that
can be potentially that will be utilizing
Ergo for tokenization.
So yeah, yeah, it's just it was a very
interesting experience and I hope to And I
know we will have an impact over there
with the technology and with what we have
to offer.
So that was a little bit. That was a good
ELI response.
Yeah, I hope that was a little enough of
bit.
Perfect. Oh, we got another question. I
want to answer this one. What would you
guys do when Ergo hits $50? Happy
Thanksgiving. So personally, you'd see no
change for me. I'd still be doing
everything that I'm doing here. All my
Ergo and project tokens would still be
sitting in my wallet. It would make no
difference to me. What it would make a
difference to is the Sigmanauts Treasury,
allowing us to have more reach, have more
function, have more, be able to hire more
people, be able to do more promotions. It
would turn our, you know, literally what,
50 times our treasury.
So that'd be amazing for the Sigmanauts
Treasury, the decentralized DAO there in
our outreach and our ability to function.
Personally, it'd make no difference in my
daily function here at all. So I don't
know about you guys If you're bringing you
bring you sandwiches during during AMAs My
wife brings me sandwiches at a dollar 50
or a dollar 70 dollar 85 My wife will
bring me sandwiches at 50 dollars,
correct?
All right, so for me probably, well, just
remembering when it was about 20, so
probably my ass would be grilled a lot
around those days because yeah, I mean
during price appreciation. Yeah, you just
have more issues to resolve and also
communication channels are getting busier
and busier, you know, so like...
Oh, the social, yeah.
Yeah, well, not social, I mean, a lot of
people are reaching to DMs, so, well,
yeah, I don't know, so, back in 2020.
Yeah, it was kind of a disaster, but yeah,
I mean, just recently I found some
messages, not from $20 a day, but later
during the Ethereum merge. You know, Ergo
is invited to get listed on some exchange,
but yeah, there is need to discuss some, I
don't know. And yeah, it's for free, but
there is need for some marketing budget,
you know.
It's free, but... Yeah.
Central machines are the Rumpelstiltskins
of the world.
Yeah, I just discovered that, I don't
know, weeks ago, so two years after, so
yeah, and I guess if it would be 50, then
yeah, Telegram would be not quite usable
because of such wonderful offers to
discuss anything with 100 exchanges and
marketing agencies and whoever. Then a lot
of new developers willing to come and just
sending you DMs for some reason, instead
of, I don't know, reading documentation
around and so on. Maybe reach public chat.
So yeah, I mean, I'm pretty sure that,
yeah, the ass will be grilled a lot.
Simply.
But yeah, I mean, that's part of life.
Yeah. I you know, I mean nothing would
would change except for You know have some
gold chains i'd be sitting in my own jet
You know, of course a couple more wives a
couple more wives I hope your wife's
asleep right now Yeah, she's not I would
be sending question pizzas with
questionable topics to qx()'s house COD
Yeah, I mean that's that's about it Yeah,
I get I get kushti a wireless version of
those headphones.
Oh That's nice. Yeah. Yeah, that's
Everybody knows why it is better than why
it is much better
If you say so grandpa, anyway, yeah.
Well, anyway, I think this is a good place
to leave it off. So everybody's, you know,
we're, we're, we're, we're full answering,
you know, bull, bull questioning. So yeah.
Um, good AMA guys. Um, well, good AMA
kushti. Okay. I'll take them. Okay. Yeah,
you know, it's like, it's like if you
share that sandwich, it would have been
better, but you can't and you won't. Don't
forget guys anyway guys everybody who
celebrates happy happy thanksgiving out
here we don't celebrate so they but but
they did in the in recent in in recent
years they have assimilated the commercial
side of thanksgiving black friday so now
we actually have black friday in japan but
no thanksgiving just black friday people
die like they do in the u.s black fridays
Not like that, but you know, they do.
But actually, we have this. So Black
Friday is kind of like, you know, the
Japanese retailers. Oh, Black Friday. Oh,
people are buying lots of stuff. We make
two. You know, it's like, it was like, but
actually out here we have a, so on January
1st, they're always, it's called
Fukubukuro. So it's basically like a gift
bag and all these stores have these
special fukubukuro which is basically like
something that's I don't know, like
limited edition or super cheap or
something like that.
So you have that in the U.S. with Black
Friday where people line up at like 2 a.m.
to get like $100, 50 inch TV or something
like that. Out here, they have the same
thing. They line up for these fukubukuro
from all these stores and they'll spend
like 200 bucks on fukubukuro and
supposedly it's like all this stuff that's
worth like a thousand bucks or something
and it's always limited. So we already
have that, but now we have Black Friday,
but we don't have Turkey. Except for
Costco and then the problem with Costco
turkeys is that most Japanese houses don't
have ovens and you can't fit a turkey in a
conventional oven.
So like I always, I always see them and
they're expensive as shit too. They're
about like 60, 70 bucks.
That's why you deep that deep fry that
stuff out on your front yard or the
sidewalk.
Yeah, well, you know, I think my
neighbors would have something to say
about that but Yeah, it's yeah, it's an
interesting experience. So like I said
Everybody happy Thanksgiving for those who
celebrate for those who don't celebrate
happy whatever Yeah, and so until next
time same place same channel same people
Friday is coming, right?
Tomorrow Friday.
Yeah. Yeah, that's that tomorrow. Yeah
tomorrow
Yeah, so Black Friday is everywhere here
as well. But yeah, I mean, now it's going
to be quite strange because it seems that
the whole November is now going to be
Black Friday because some sellers are
starting sales.
This is something they do. This is
something that you can get on black friday
actually I was digging the reason why I
got the blur background on here is because
my sugar gliders, Went loose in my room
and just like trashed it So but wait, how
does a five ounce?
How does a five ounce animal trash your
room dan?
indeed indeed i mean the thing is as big
as a hamster four of them like and i came
in here i'm like what the hell happened
like what happened in here it looks like a
freaking cheetah went loose in here it
just it was crazy so i haven't had a
chance to clean it up that's why but in
the process for some reason i now remember
that i have it i found this so this is the
soviet medal of labor It was given to only
the finest factory workers of the Soviet
Union.
Wow. Where'd you get it from? Okay.
So I got it from Georgia, actually. I was
thinking about it. It's randomly in a bag
with a little booklet, with a little
Soviet booklet. Yeah. Oh, wait. Yeah,
there it is. Yeah. It says veteran of
labor on it. And so this is from the 80s,
actually. I bought it in Georgia, in
Tbilisi, years ago. And so I found this.
So if you work hard enough, maybe someday
you'll have this. But for the time being,
I am keeping this medal.
You should put it up on the, you should
put it up on the MewFinance physical NFT
site and sell it.
There we go.
You know what? Speaking of that, maybe,
maybe if you guys are lucky and you check
out MewFinance tomorrow, maybe you'll see
some black Friday deals on a few token
packs. Maybe if I remember from
Sigmanauts, my own thing, I'll put some up
there. Let me, let me shake my loose
wallets and we'll see what's in there.
Maybe I can sell some discounted project
tokens.
Right. All right. All right. Well, maybe
I think maybe it's time to go. So I guess,
yeah, same time, same place, same channel.
Don't forget the spaces tomorrow with
House of Chimera. And we'll announce that
on Twitter in a bit as soon as we see it.
Yeah. Going to get details. Yeah. It will
be announced once I've got them.
Great. All right. Happy Thanksgiving
everybody. This is Dan from Japan signing
off.