All right, here we go, fellas.
Welcome.
Mark, good to see you.
Wade, thanks for coming on, man.
Thanks, guys. Yeah, good to talk to you.
Yeah, for sure. So I'm just now meeting
you, Wade. My name's Tim. People in Ergo
know me as tmr.erg. And I've been here for
like maybe three years now. I'm kind of
following along. I am relatively new to
crypto. I don't really have a background
in it. My background is in education. I
grew up in a rural place, so I didn't have
exposure to a lot of tech. But I was
generally good at math and stuff. And so
as I got older, I'm fine. I can manage.
But I'm not an expert, not a coder,
nothing like that. But yeah, I stumbled
into this community and just thought it
really lined up with my values and then
met Mark and me and Mark get along. So we
started doing this, I guess, several
months ago now. So I'm curious, what is
your background and your relation to
technology and finance? How'd you end up
talking to us?
Yeah, so I've had actually a pretty early
exposure to crypto. Hold on one second,
I'll close the door and we can start that
over.
So my background actually comes from I
went to a magnet program with technical
aspects to it. I can definitely talk about
that at some point too in the future on
this, but the program I went to was the
Center for Advanced Technology. You can
look that up and you can find out where
that is, and I still live down the street
from them.
All right, here we go, guys. Deep breath.
All right, so I went to a pretty technical
high school called the Center for Advanced
Technology where we were learning computer
programming, a lot of math and science
classes at that point in time too. And
that was actually my first exposure to
cryptocurrency. And I heard about Bitcoin
in the early 2010s. Oh, wow. Because I
have programming friends and programming
classes that they were all a bunch of
nerds on the edge of tech in a lot of
ways. We were pirating sites with music
and things like that were very prevalent
in that period of time. File sharing, the
whole school had networks with computers
in the classroom. I think before that was
a lot more prevalent in schools nowadays
with individual logins connected to LAN.
And so I was exposed to that type of stuff
from an early age, and I've always really
been fascinated by computers and
technologies, to be honest, and I've built
a couple computers over my life since
then. I think from that experience on,
though, it was something I kind of put in
the back of my head as something that
still seemed pretty niche to me, or at
least didn't click along with the people
that I was hanging out with, the things
that I was involved with, like sports. So
I almost dismissed it for probably a very
long time. Since that point, going through
college and focusing on more production
related sides of technology and media. And
I've continued that through my career
right now with my business. And I've
always talked about with friends different
types of cryptocurrencies and I've
probably traded a little bit on Robinhood
just for fun, never holding anything
seriously. But again, I've been more
interested in, through college I got a
business degree, so definitely interested
in finance and the workings of a business
and all those types of things that go
along with that. So I've had a lot of
traditional investments through that
period of time, individual stocks, IRA
plans, things like that. And I've just
been pretty conservative focusing on those
aspects, but still always interested in
the technology of crypto and maybe some of
the future use cases of it, but still kind
of discovering more for my personal risk
tolerance. And besides that, the true
utility of it in a lot of ways.
Yeah, I think that's important whenever
you think about crypto as an investment.
It's like if you're already set and you're
already going to retire and you have a
plan, like it's fine to be conservative.
Like you don't have to just roll all your
money into Bitcoin. Like that's not
responsible. And I mean, I'm the same way,
it's like I evaluated my own risk
tolerance and allocated accordingly and
just like I'm not going to over invest in
something that I don't control. So totally
get it. And that's something I tell
people. It's like, yeah, okay, if you're
already retired, like you don't need to
invest in Bitcoin. But if you don't want
to, it's fine.
Yeah, absolutely. But even now, so in
current times, Bitcoin seems like still
the most flourishing, most popular, most
gains to be had in crypto in this way too.
So I know there's a lot of subsets that
you guys know better about than I do in
the world, but I think my knowledge kind
of stops at like the first couple highest
market caps in crypto. And then besides
that, I think my knowledge drops off
pretty fast of what's available out there
and the differences between each of those
blockchains and coins and stuff.
Yeah. So Mark, what about you, dude?
When's the first time you heard of crypto
or blockchain or Bitcoin?
I would say probably around like 2018.
That's when I first bought Bitcoin. I was
actually just looking the other day. I'm
like, how much Bitcoin in my lifetime have
I ever bought? Just to have that sort of
FOMO, right? And it was nothing crazy. But
yeah, I would say actually, though,
thinking about it 2016, maybe 15, someone
was mentioning how they're mining
Ethereum. I'm like, what? This is weird.
Like, you got a GPU. And at that point, I
was just so focused just in my life and
all that sort of stuff didn't really give
it any sort of glimpse or look. But I have
a background in, I guess, mechanical
engineering and then software engineering.
And so kind of going through life, one
thing led to another in terms of
entrepreneurial type of ideas, built my
own computer similar to Wade, and then all
of a sudden I could find out, hey, I can
use my GPUs to mine. From an investment
perspective, my parents come from real
estate. And so my dad was always kind of
instilling that idea of just like, you
need to buy assets instead of leaving it
in the dollar. And so but on that same
token, I don't really like the idea of
working with tenants and things like that.
And so that's where crypto and even stocks
where I kind of come to play in my
mindset, or even mining. And so instead of
buying a stock or crypto, I can buy the
asset that is the GPU miner. And then from
there, I can continually rely on it on a
reward more indefinitely for the most
part. So that's kind of, I guess, my story
there.
Yeah, that's cool, man. I, I guess, for
me, probably like 2012, I heard about
Bitcoin. And I remember like a really
specific conversation with my mom. Like I
came home from college, just visiting and
like, hey, I heard about this thing. I
didn't understand it. I was like, it's
like money for your computer and you like
use energy to get it. And I didn't like,
didn't click, didn't understand. And then
I just like blanked it out for a huge
portion for like the next nine years or
something. Didn't understand at all. And
then I recently told the story to Mark
about my mom asked me to explain Bitcoin
to her and I couldn't so then I like did a
deep dive and I was like, oh, this
actually makes a lot of sense now that I'm
like, I don't know what made it click this
time that didn't happen before but I think
maybe I just had a better understanding of
finance and like the world economy and I
could kind of see a place for it. So yeah,
that's my story. So next, I was gonna ask
Wade, where are you in your understanding
of Bitcoin and crypto? How would you
describe Bitcoin? What would you say if I
asked you to explain it in one minute?
I'll do my best guys. Anyone else out
there listening, go easy on me. It's
written on a program that creates a
blockchain, which creates a ledger, which
is mined at certain intervals based on the
difficulty of the state of the program, it
rewards bitcoins after certain amounts of
programming input to a processing power
from GPUs. And then it's something that
was created with a finite resource and it
was meant to be mined over a certain
period of time and just slowly being
chipped away by all the GPUs out there. I
understand the idea of the blockchain with
it can be traced back through the program
through that and for what I understand
also is made by a fairly anonymous source
that's kind of like up for debate who it
was, a few people trying to claim who it
was at the same time so. It's
decentralized, it's not controlled by a
federal government or anything like that
and it's stored in digital wallets on
computers that keeps track of the certain
keys of what's what, how many coins you
have, or you can protect it with the
encrypted with the password and exchange
that between users for a certain fees on
the chain as well. And basically send that
all over the world then that way. And
yeah, it's a digital currency.
Yeah, absolutely. That's pretty good. I
would say you're like already in the 99th
percentile.
All right, so I would. Okay,
understanding of programming. When I
learned it, to begin with, I learned
C-sharp, C++, HTML. I've done some small
programs before. Mark and I have even sat
down and we've messed with some of the
data that I have from the drones that I
use and gone over some programs. He's way
more adept at it than I am, but I at least
through my school understand the language
of computers in that way. I don't think
it's something that I could sit down and
just come up off from the top of my head
right now today, but I understand the ones
and the zeros as in the if then, the input
and output of a program like that. So I
could at least have some sort of
foundation to to build off of at least for
comprehension and understanding.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I think you showed a
pretty good understanding right there. I
guess if I were to like critique anything,
it would just be like little tiny bits
like some of them use GPUs. Others use
application specific circuits and CPU also
or just GPU. I'm sure be way less
efficient with the CPU. Different cryptos
use different things. And I think I want
to say Bitcoin started with the CPU. Is
that right, Mark?
Yeah, totally. So that was like the
initial but as the difficulty increased,
then smaller and smaller likelihood of
finding a block on CPUs and then people
quickly moved over to GPUs. And then
finally, like you're saying, Tim, the
ASICs.
Yeah, when I talk to new people, like
zero or very little understanding, I just
try to get out that it's a distributed
ledger that you have to use energy to
change. And so all these people are
competing with their energy use to make
changes to the ledger. And then the other
part that is point where people maybe make
an assumption is like the coins are in
your wallet like it's really just the
blockchain and the blockchain associates
coins with your wallet like that's not
quite it's not quite accurate.
The wallet stores the keys to that part
of the chain. Yeah, the addresses to the
chain where it's where you got the box.
So the wallet, I think, has the private
key to which gives you the ability to
spend a given box and within that box is
your specific asset. So your wallets that
are tied to your private keys can be you
could have a bunch of different boxes, but
consolidated, they could have whatever
summation amount of crypto is in that box.
And then in order to spend that box to
create a new box, with UTXO so unspent
transaction output. So if I wanted to send
you say 10 ERGs or like however much
Bitcoin I have to burn the boxes that are
in my that are signed by my private key
and only by my private key and then send
them to you and then that's the only way
you can send it and so like what Tim was
saying it's the wallet is sort of a view
within the blockchain, then the subset of
these blocks are only spendable by you
with this specific protocol.
Yeah, that's a really good point to bring
up too is like the public private keys. So
one of the concepts in cryptography is
like a puzzle that is hard to solve, but
easy to prove, right? So I have a private
key that only I know. And it's like
cryptographically matches my public key,
but you can't go from the public to the
private. I can go from private to public
and that allows me to send keys or send
coins rather, but people can only kind of
see where it's coming from through the
public address and they're not able to
derive my private key.
And then that brings in a good segue for
what smart contracts are. So
traditionally, when you get sent tokens
into like the boxes in your wallet,
they're only spendable if you sign that
transaction but now smart contracts are
another layer to that to where you can
sign and say hey i'm going to send this to
tim but or this other condition is true.
So for example, say you have some type of
delayed dispersion. So like in 10 minutes,
I'm going to send this amount to Tim, or I
can send it right now. But otherwise it
can get spent by Tim and then you can run
what's called off chain bots to then
collect those boxes are then spendable.
And then they send that to Tim
automatically. And so then that's where
the programmatic sort of idea comes into
play.
Yeah, and pretty much every real world
financial asset or application. You can
think of borrowing, lending, derivatives,
baskets of things. You could build all of
those things to be done automatically with
a smart contract. So Mark might want to
borrow some money because he wants to go
short or long some other asset and the
contract would enable that as well as like
a ton of other things.
The idea of smart contracts really seems
fascinating to me too and something I've
talked with people about for a while would
help in my business to automate certain
things when it comes to collecting
payments from clients. Again, I think
you'd have to see a lot more mass adoption
of, I think, the underlying assets by
clients of mine that are a lot less tech
savvy than I am in some cases. But I think
the concept is super promising.
And even from a security standpoint,
right? So, kind of differing from chain to
chain, we have different smart contract
languages that are able to write these
contracts. So Ethereum is notable for the
languages escaping me. Anyways, but they
can be not hacked but people write in
within so on Ergo it's called a Sigma
prop. And so the Sigma prop if true that
box gets to be spendable. Now on Ethereum
I'm not sure what the case is but people
are able to put sort of an or statement so
then if that becomes true, you can then
spend that on Ethereum and that's how
people get hacked for like millions of
dollars because they put so much money
into a proxy contract. So another entity
kind of holding these funds, these boxes,
I guess it's different on Ethereum. But
then because of that sort of flaw within
the smart contract is then able to leak
funds from that contract unexpectedly.
Speaking of adoption and losing your
money, what doubts and reservations do you
have about crypto broadly, Wade? You're
what we call a normie and a no-coiner.
What gives, man?
I mean, yeah, full disclosure for the
audience right now, I'm not holding any
coins or anything, any crypto. Yeah, puts
me kind of on the outside as someone who
is interested in it. But I think just my
risk tolerance for this point, I've done
pretty okay and stock investing over the
last six, seven years of my career, we had
a pretty bullish stock market as well,
which has enabled me to buy some real
world assets too with that. And I've kind
of just been taking the tortoise or the
hare philosophy a lot when it comes to
that, the slow and steady wins the race.
But I am interested in the technology
itself of cryptocurrency and its future
use potentials. And I think we're getting
a lot closer to a point where I think
enough people have heard and understand
about it that it's making more and more
sense as time goes on, especially with, I
think, the positive outlook that we're
going to have over the next four years in
the US and how a lot of people are now are
even more bullish about Bitcoin because of
this new administration that we could have
a lot more adoption of it, which makes it
more inherently viable and makes more
sense for people to hold when there's a
lot more hands that it could be exchanged
from. I think more reservations I have
about it is if, I was talking to my
brother about this concept a little bit.
We're talking about, well, the idea of
investing in something like gold, for
example, not even Bitcoin, but gold said,
okay, well, if I want to invest in
something like gold to hedge against a
downturn in the market, I could buy a gold
that the point would be to buy a gold bar,
not just a gold exchange fund, because
then you're losing the utility of that. If
the stock market goes down, if the
networks go down, you don't even have
access to that. So you want a gold bar,
but then if you have a gold bar and now
you want to exchange that for food it's
kind of hard to break that bar up for food
right so then i think of i the closest
thing i can compare bitcoin to and this
might not be completely accurate would be
gold it's a great store of some value and
some proof of that energy expenditure i
think if i wanted some other form of
reserve besides the stock market in case
the stock market would crash or the
network fails or weren't even worse
scenario in the world, is thinking of like
a prepper mindset, then I probably
wouldn't be able to access that or
exchange that between people either, I
fear. So if it came down to the apocalypse
or something like that, I'd probably
rather have a pack of cigarettes to try to
trade people, or a can of food or gas in
that way, because that's what I think of
people would have some sort of value. I
watched some prison shows talking about
the currencies that they've developed
there between them without actual other
physical money and come down to bartering.
So if it was the end of the world, I'd
probably rather have a gas can than a
million dollars of Bitcoin in my digital
wallet that I can't even turn on
potentially. But I don't think it doesn't
have value today, but I think just to me,
and I'm not even that much of a doomsday
property to begin with, but I think until
that scenario happens that I still have
lights like my traditional stock
investments as a place to fairly safely
keep some savings.
Yeah, I mean, everything you said is
totally reasonable, dude. So I guess I'll
go back like from the beginning. So you
said it's funny how the bigger it gets,
like the more valid it kind of becomes,
which is a little bit inverse to some
stocks, right? Like we see Nvidia and the
chart is like going like this and you're
like, that's probably a bubble. But now we
see Bitcoin doing that. It's like knocking
on the door of 100K today and like, oh,
that means it's more valid and it's
probably safer to invest in than it was at
$15K, which is just inverse. It's like a
different mode of thinking about Bitcoin
versus stocks.
Yeah, absolutely. I mean, I think it also
just the volume of trades at any way. And
the fact that it's still with Bitcoin, as
far as I know and understand, you don't
have to trade a full coin like you do with
a full stock. You don't have to buy one
share. You can buy a partial.
Divisible to a million parts. Yeah.
Right. So another thing that you said that
was good, there's a good analogy. You're
like, oh, if I have the gold ETF, I don't
actually have any gold. We say not your
keys, not your coins. So yeah, man, like
if you don't have the actual asset, it's
like you're trusting somebody or some
system to uphold your value that you're
trying to save. And that's a risk. It's a
counterparty risk, for sure.
Yeah, like having I also thought that too
about cryptocurrency, I think in a point
to where, and like I said, I've traded
some on Robinhood in the past when I was,
I think, kind of popular in its own way.
And then I realized ultimately that I'm
not holding that true asset, I'm just
buying their holding of it basically. So I
think it would be important, I think, for
my future self to obtain crypto assets to
actually have it in my own wallet as well,
like you're saying.
Yeah. So your last point was about kind
of like that worst case scenario. How
would crypto actually be useful? Which is
actually a good thought exercise. I think
like real worst case scenario, yeah, like,
internet's gone. Electricity is only
available if you have a solar panel.
That's like a real problem. But I think a
lot of people would be really messed up in
that case then too. And then I'm also kind
of thinking about Bitcoin as probably the
most resilient money there that's digital.
So as we approach that limit, everything
is going to fly to that safety. And so in
that process, it would become more
valuable. We still have things like
Starlink and every other satellite
internet provider or whatever. That would
be online for a while. And then also
thinking about some technologies that are
developed on Ergo, it's like you could
make transactions with email and flip
phone. We were even talking about could
you program it to use radio waves? Like a
ham radio, could you put out a signal that
somebody would be able to interpret as a
transaction? Which is pretty low tech in
terms of hardware requirements and energy
requirements. Cool to think about.
Scary. You still need a node, I guess, at
the end of the day. As long as there's one
person that can kind of broadcast, hey,
connect to my node and we can facilitate
this transaction for you. But what's
interesting about Bitcoin, I guess, also
would be the fact that as more people
flock to it, it becomes probably more
resilient, right in the price. So probably
less volatility kind of over time,
similarity, I guess, to gold in some
sense, because, and especially if there
is, I guess, some sort of apocalyptic type
tragedy that would happen. then
effectively the less people would be
mining it right and so less people mining
it then the fixed supply just gets just
got really more fixed in some sense and so
would probably protect the value of it.
Whereas other currencies, like the idea
with gold is, well, there's only so much
gold. And then back in the day, they were
trading seashells or they were making
these stones and things like that. Well,
until new tech came along and was like,
oh, well, I can collect seashells faster
now. And so that just crashed the currency
and things like that. I think with
Bitcoin, it kind of protects that, right?
Because of mining, mining protects that
new supply coming in. So this is going to
be a limited amount of stock relative to.
Yeah, no, that's a good point, Mark. I
think the supply would be fixed then and
demand would, the demand, I think part of
it is what, the supply is a good argument
to make. And I think that's extremely
solid. The demand part of it, I'm not sure
would be there because I wonder what the
minimum equipment requirements would be to
exchange hands of it then because if I had
a dollar in my hand, for example, I all I
have to do is hand that to you. If I have
a coin, do I have to have a and again, I
know this is like the worst case scenario
and probably not going to happen. But I
did just live through two hurricanes in
Florida where I lost power for five days.
I tell you what, there was lines around
the corner, gas stations waiting for gas
and my generator was extremely helpful to
be able to use here. So I might need a
generator, I might need a laptop or a
phone to power that and maybe some sort of
Starlink or cell service for internet. In
that case, it's probably the minimum you
might need to exchange crypto in that
case. I think again, I think that's just
an extreme case of that. And I think most
of my investing philosophy is just way
more cautious, but I again, I do think the
technology has crazy potential. And I'm
here talking about it, because I do think
it's very interesting and could have a lot
more value in the future as it does today.
And not only just to us, but future
generations might find more value and I
think it's ultimately up to the masses
like that to decide what direction we want
to go in and I think people are betting
with their money right now that this could
be one of those avenues.
Yeah, and I think relative to stocks,
right? So Bitcoin is very much this hard
money asset, whereas stocks is kind of
people, I wouldn't say it's hard money,
right? Because if you think about it,
people say there's a fixed supply of like
Tesla or Nvidia, but that's not
necessarily true, right? Because every
five years, every three years, they do a
stock split, and it's effectively adding
10 times more of the stock supply, and
they're just essentially printing stock,
whereas Bitcoin and even Ergo, it's less
so and then specifically bitcoin and ergo
the hardware requirements to set up this
sort of stuff is a lot cheaper and easier
people are selling these miners and then
they break within like the first few
months and they cost like ten thousand
dollars not super ideal and in a similar
case for some of these stocks in order to
buy like At one point, what was it,
NVIDIA, it was like $1,300 or something.
That's a little outrageous, but of course,
Bitcoin's 90 something thousand now and
that's, so that's not really ideal, but
the idea that you can be divisible by like
all these different sort of units of time,
but then also Bitcoin can't go bad. You
can buy a million dollars worth of gas,
but probably will go bad in a few months
or you could buy a million dollars worth
of cigarettes, but if it rains on the
cigarettes, that's a lot of cigarettes to
buy, and so from Bitcoin is able to
translate over time but also space but
then also corruption in terms of like the
environment and not political corruption
but just you can't corrode Bitcoin just
like gold right and so in a similar sense
right you can see that sort of split
between all the different gold silver
copper within the coins transfer of those
assets they're able to translate space go
across the world sort of thing and still
kind of maintain their value and that's
something I think a lot of people want,
right? I would say it's less so of like
number go up, but more of just like, let's
preserve my value, because right now the
governments, who knows what they're gonna
do, and I just wanna preserve my assets,
whatever those assets are, and not have
them go down, or just like slowly go down
over time, right?
So something I say is the point of crypto
is not to make you rich, but to make you
free. So we're at the beginning of that
adoption curve, and so the investment
potential is there, but that's not the
point. The point is to give people another
option that's not controlled or
manipulated by others, and the supply of
dollars or stocks is controlled by people,
and the supply of Bitcoin is controlled by
code. And so it's not up for debate about
what it is and what's gonna happen. So
that being said, I like to talk to people
about why having a hard cap supply is
important. I don't necessarily think that
Bitcoin would be the world's reserve
currency. I don't know. That's not like my
base case. I kind of think the main
benefit is just having another currency to
compete with all the other currencies so
that it holds them honest, right? Because
I think something like 70% of all the
dollars were printed in the past like five
years. So like, that's mind blowing,
right? That's a lot of dollars. And who
knows what the effect is going to be like
they just did it because they felt like
they had to. And so as somebody who's
forced to use those dollars, I should have
a choice to like have this other thing.
And I feel like Bitcoin and cryptos that
are specifically proof of work. They kind
of just give me an option where I know the
outcome. I know what it is. I can verify
all the parameters. And whereas the
dollar, I know that it's going to be
accepted. They just changed the definition
of M2, which is like the money supply in
the past few years. You look up M2 on the
chart and it's like, and they're like, oh,
we don't use this anymore. They're like,
yeah, I bet.
That's a great point, Tim. Yeah, you
don't have control over that other lever
then that's so important to economic
supply and demand that that other lever
gets pulled in the wrong direction for
majority of people that are forced to use
this currency. I think you make a really
good case when you cite examples of
hyperinflation in some South American
countries if you look at what's happened
down there in certain places where they
have just inflated the crap out of their
currency to where the spending power has
just become so insignificant in some ways
that it's millions of dollars in whatever
currency that is for a loaf of bread or
whatever that may be. So I think there's a
great case for crypto that you're making
in that way. And then one that I think
principally, I do believe a lot. And I
think maybe if I'm allowed to segue this
into another category, we talked about the
top one a lot, Bitcoin, that's obviously
the biggest market cap. How does that
trickle down? And what need for other
blockchains have come out of that or have
been invented after that and maybe help
explain to me some of the other use cases
of different coins or maybe especially
Ergo in your guys case.
Yeah. So I think Mark kind of hit on it a
little bit previously where originally
Bitcoin was really just a tool for
transacting and sending and receiving
those coins and had to do that manually.
It didn't have that smart contract
functionality that we talked about. So in
2015 or 2016, Ethereum came out and that
was really the first smart contract
application that arose. And just kind of
being the first one, it had a lot of
flaws. We found that there are more
efficient ways to do things, more secure
ways to do things. And that has led us to
Ergo, where it's kind of, it's doing a lot
of things, right? So when I introduce
people to crypto, I tell them there's a
lot of scams. A lot of people are just
trying to make your money and they're not
very transparent about what they're
selling you and so Ergo one for me was
just a line with my values like everything
is open source like there is a team that
they received very little money in terms
of like the whole coin allocation they got
like 4% of all the tokens and they they
publish a verifiable budget and like
expense everything like you can see every
dollar that they've spent. So that to me
just made a lot of sense and it made it
really clear. And then overall the goal is
to reduce the technological requirements
as much as possible so as many people
around the world can access it as
possible. And then with that, they don't
take any technological risks. So they only
use cryptographic principles that are
proven, starting with Bitcoin. So they
basically took Bitcoin's code and took the
most the safest, most proven aspects of
that and then kind of built on top of it
without inventing the wheel again and
trying to accomplish something that's not
proven. So it's like, no, if we don't know
that it's secure, we're not going to do
that.
and and then like from other tokens right
so you have litecoin you have doge those
are just mere copies literal copies of the
same so it's a fork is what it's called so
you can have the same consensus and then
some miners can then say hey we're going
to go over here in this lane But we're
going to call this Litecoin. And so then
they facilitate Litecoin, new miners stand
up, new mining rigs for here. And so now
you have a new blockchain kind of
entirely. So Dogecoin was done, I think
was the official first meme coin. Litecoin
was to be like, hey, or like silver, so to
speak. And then you have all these other
sort of paradigms that kind of switch to
where Like we were talking earlier,
Bitcoin was the CPU miner. Then we moved
the GPUs and then quickly moved into
ASICs. So application specific integrated
circuit. All they can do is mine Bitcoin,
literally nothing else. And so as that
quickly started to get stood up, it's like
10K now for a Bitcoin miner. Not really,
like Tim was saying, like not really
accessible to the general population,
right? And so what is really cool about
crypto or Ergo is the fact that you can
buy a A GPU now for like a couple hundred
bucks right you can put up maybe hook that
up I saw somebody hooked hooked up an AMD
GPU to Raspberry Pi and then you can be on
your way start collecting mining tokens
and things like that and so from an
accessibility perspective super important.
And then just the smart contract layer
compared to Ethereum to Ergo, Ethereum has
what's called gas fees and these gas fees
can be like maybe 20 bucks to a hundred
bucks and you're maybe trying to send like
five. So you're spending more in
transaction fees than you are actually in
what you're trying to transact. And then
an additional note is that you can try to
send this and it can fail and then you
lose everything. Like you don't get that
back. I'm not really sure where it goes,
but like, so it, and that sucks, right? If
I want to send you some money, I want to
know that you're going to get it. Not that
it fails and then it doesn't work. So
talking to Ergo, if it doesn't send, it
doesn't send. There's no like, oh, is it
not, is it? And then additionally, for one
transaction, it costs, one, 1000th of a
ERG. So it's 0.001. And ERG right now is
like $1.40. And so super cheap to
transact. So if you wanted to send a
million dollars, it's going to cost you
0.01 ERG just to send it to a given
address. And then other things, you can
see there's more copies. Or there's
different consensus protocols. So we have
proof of work. That's what we're actively
talking about with all these tokens that
we are coins rather that we've talked
about. But then there's proof of stake,
which is a different consensus mechanism.
So Cardano is primarily proof of stake.
Ethereum moved the proof of stake. And so
basically what that basically is is you
need to buy a specific asset. You need to
hold that asset. And then those, you run
some code by putting those assets in
there. And then that is sort of
facilitates the consensus protocol. And so
you have what's called stake pools. And so
you have stake pool operators and you can
stake your ADA onto those stake pools. And
then those find the blocks and then those
facilitate the transactions. There's some
key to debate sometimes between what's
more secure, proof of stake, proof of
work. I like proof of work because, again,
it goes back to that accessibility
perspective. So if you wanted to set up a
mining pool, Wade, all you would have to
do is just run some code. You don't even
have to be a miner. You don't have to run
any type of mining equipment, but you
could set up your own mining pool. But if
you wanted to be a stake pool operator,
you need millions of ADA. And so ADA is
like, 70 cents right now. That's a lot of
fucking money. Excuse my French, just to
get so it's like, it's art, so if you
wanted to be a stakeholder, you need to be
on it from the very early on. Whereas
right now, if you wanted to be a mining
pool operator, it's easy to do and will
always ever be easy to do. So I think kind
of going back to why Ergo, why we like
really Ergo is like the principles, it's
for the people, it's not really like, oh,
if you have a lot of money, we're going to
favor you like other chains might, we're
really for like that accessibility
perspective and kind of putting that power
into the people and having, I guess, less
attack vectors to that, right.
Accessibility is huge for more adoption
of these ideas.
The critique of Proof of Stake that I
like the most is just that you have 10% of
all the coins on the proof of stake and
you stake those, you're always going to
have 10% of the coins because you earn
interest for holding, for staking those
tokens. And so it's not really a level
playing field for people entering the
space, like Mark said. So for a group of
work, it's like you might have all these
miners set up. But difficulty increases
over time. Technology increases over time.
And so new entrants kind of really get the
edge. They get the advantage. In five
years from now, the quality of solar
panels and graphics cards and just
literally everything is going to give that
person the advantage over whoever's been
mining for the last five years. They might
have more coins, but their production
capability is going to be way higher.
Right. It's kind of like easy money in
that sense, right? Where the idea, I
guess, of easy money is, there's these
people, select few, right, who have a huge
pile of this given asset, a huge
stockpile, and then they're selling it to
these newcomers, right, at a higher price
and then versus hard money, right? It's
it's fixed. It's easy to get on board. If
you haven't read the Bitcoin standard, I'd
read it and read it again. Really great
book.
The book I recommend people is Broken
Money by Lynn Alden. That was really good.
She kind of goes through the history of
money and talking about seashells and gold
and then credit systems and fiat and all
this stuff and the challenges with each
and how crypto can solve those challenges.
I thought it was great and she has a lot
of content online. Yeah, that's who I
recommend Newton's to.
I'll check some of those out.
So Wade, maybe just to end, I'm
wondering, do you have any advice for us
about how to talk to people who aren't
interested? Because, I don't know when
this will come out, but Thanksgiving's
coming up and people are gonna be like,
Hey, am I bitcoins doing awesome? How do
we talk to people who aren't into crypto?
Like, did we do a good job? Or do you have
any any recommendations?
That's a really good question. And you're
right. There's probably a lot of
Thanksgiving conversations happening
around who's doing really well in this and
who's upset at other things. Maybe my
ideas or perspective is making it less
seem like an exclusive club. And I don't
think it necessarily is, but I think there
is some technological facade to some
people when no one questions holding or
having fiat currency, people might be more
or less savvy with it, but no one doesn't
understand having the value of a dollar to
food to X, Y, and Z. So I think making it
more analogous with other types of
currency maybe seeing more transactions
happen with this type of currency, instead
of something that's maybe outside of that
realm altogether seems really helpful. I
think there's certain words to or certain
lingo when it comes to things like that
that make it seem with crypto that makes
it seem a little more complicated than it
has to be to probably ones that we've even
discussed today that I might understand,
but to a bigger audience, maybe such as
even just the blockchain or wallets and
digital wallets in that way, maybe, maybe
not. Digital wallet does try to do a good
job of equating what that means. I think a
good- Still seems like a club in some
certain ways that, I understand there's a
big community aspect to get things off the
ground, like that too and what it's taken
to get to this point, but I don't really
think it has to be, and none of it is to
me inherently exclusive either, to adopt,
to buy, to exchange. in those ways, but
there is just some really benign
observations on, on my end, but again, I
could be far off from what other people
think or dismiss about it too. So I'm just
here to offer one other perspective on it.
No, that's super helpful, man. And I
think a goal that we have is to make the
application so that people don't even know
that they're using crypto or a blockchain.
It's like when we send money on Venmo or
whatever, I'm not thinking about code or
there's no lingo that I use. I'm just
like, no, send me 10 bucks for this pizza
I bought you. And that's it. So once we
get to that point, I think that'll kind of
alleviate what you're saying there.
Yeah, completely. Yeah, it doesn't even
think you don't even see physical money
when you send stuff over that online. So
there's no reason to me why that couldn't
also be done on a different sort of
exchange in that way that could involve
crypto more than more than likely in the
future.
Would you say even to it's maybe more of
a or not more of a but it could be kind of
an educational thing to where kind of
understanding the pros and cons of certain
like money systems, like you were saying,
like, why did the South American countries
sort of fail with respect to, I think
there's a lot of sort of things happening
in the country and the world, so it's kind
of hard to tune into specific things as
well, right? So especially on the day to
day live too, right? So, I don't know,
what do you think there?
Yeah, it's hard to spread any idea that
far. It seems like there's a lot of other
noise that happens in the world right now
with gaming content or anything else. I
think just finding ways to use it in
everyday life that would be applicable to
people to be able to see how this actually
applies in certain ways, instead of just
conceptually, but practically as well if
you go to the store and I use, Apple Pay,
touch to pay, then you don't see any go
across even your credit card, for example,
it's just happening somewhere else, being
able to do that on, potentially another
currency, even having gone to Europe and
using an American credit card, it's
possible to do that. There's just a small
fee that comes off. There's an automatic
translation that happens there, a
conversion between the currencies. And I
don't know what the technological
capabilities of that are right now. I'm
sure it's possible, but be able to
integrate that with normal everyday life
at some point for people.
We already got it, brother.
They call it Babel fees. So you can
choose to spend whatever currency you want
and then it'll make the transaction on the
back end and you don't even know that it
happened. It'll just tell you how much it
cost.
Yeah, cool. Yeah, see, that's something
that I haven't experienced with Paul and
I'm sure it would be really cool to see
used in person. And if I saw, Mark using
that in person, other people around me,
then I think just seeing being able to see
that firsthand, too, I think, would make a
lot more people comfortable with, with the
ideas and other currency.
So I think, Wade, what we'll have to do
is I'll have to come over at some point
and we can set up your GPU to maybe mine
at night so we can start getting your Ergo
coming in.
old gaming computer here that I'm not
using right now. It's sitting on the
floor. So there we go.
Yeah, let's do it, man. Let's get you
some ERG.
Definitely interested. I would be
interested to the difference of the energy
cost verse, the outputs, but I think that
might be very region specific to in a lot
of ways. Yeah, definitely. At least worth
to experiment for me.
All right, we'll have you on in the
future and you can tell us your experience
as a fresh set of eyes.
Yeah, that'd be great. All right, good
talking to you guys and good to hear what
you guys are up to and some stuff I
learned today too that I wasn't really
sure about, but I think the best way would
be just dipping your toes and learning
something new.
That's it, man. I feel the same way. I
just like learn. I love to learn. And so I
meet people like Mark, and they can
explain one little thing at a time. And
over the years, I feel like I've opened my
mind to a lot of things and just learned a
ton. So it's a cool place to kind of just
spend some free time.
Yeah, and our community is just so great.
I really enjoy talking with Tim.
Obviously, you as well, Wade, and if you
join us in the Telegram or Discord groups
and ever have a question. people are just
so overly helpful and willing just to kind
of clarify certain points, which that's a
common reoccurrence within our community
that we hear. And we're not really gonna
point you to, oh, hey, go buy this token,
you're gonna make a million bucks or
whatever, right? We're not really trying
to do anything like that, but if you need
to understand a concept or anything,
really, people are just so, so, so
helpful. So hope to see you in the chats,
bud.
Thanks, guys.
Have a great day.
See you, everyone.