presentation.
I'm pretty excited about it.
This is Mining Rights Protocol.
And so what is MRP or Mining Rights
Protocol?
It's a mineral rights inspired system for
blockchain mining.
It's a rights-based token distribution
mechanism, has an NFT enhanced mining
privileges, and allows for sustainable
token emission as a protocol.
And so it kind of in short is essentially
what we're doing, we are minting tokens.
And these set of tokens are going to be
our rights tokens.
And so we can have five of these rights
tokens.
We can have 10, have 20, we have 10
million.
These would be sort of, I guess, akin to
specific GPUs.
And then we have the actual admission
token, which would be akin to ERG.
And so basically what we're doing is you
buy the rights tokens and then that gives
you the right to then run a block and to
be able to emit the given token.
So we can say maybe the token here is
MRP.
So say, for example, we have 10,000
rights tokens.
and you buy one, you can then buy or
rather emit the MRP token as long as
you're mining.
And so again, you have to be mining.
This is essentially a mining protocol
kind of on top of the Ergo blockchain and
allows for sort of dual rewards.
And so what we're doing there
specifically is going to be proving that
the miner did find the given block.
We can take a look on the chain, like
which miner found it, look at an explorer.
Oh, they did find it.
Great.
And then from there, they can claim that
token.
And so kind of looking at the specifics
more closely, we'll have two proxy
contracts.
We'll have the rights token and then the
MRP token or an NFT token to be able to
emit it from.
And so we'll put in all of the TX fees
that we need or even protocol fees.
Because this whole thing can be sort of
gamified like traditional other things.
But it might make sense for a given
protocol to pay people who run bots that
maybe just aren't miners.
So then they get a little bit of reward.
That's awesome from them, but they're
also keeping the protocol.
The emissions essentially running.
Aside from like you or a couple other
people.
So more incentives.
So just like with GPU purchases, you want
to say, hey, can I buy this GPU?
Can I buy the rights?
Fantastic, you do buy the rights and then
from here we can have an NFT bonus that's
maybe a commemorative bonus or maybe they
buy so much or within the first 100 XYZ
they get a lifetime of 1.2X rewards.
Again, could be gamified, could just be a
receipt.
From there, we want to check, does the
miner have the rights?
Oh, look, they do have the rights.
Fantastic.
Did they find a block?
They did find a block.
Fantastic.
Let's make a claim.
Now that we made a claim, is it a valid
claim?
It is a valid claim.
We can then dispense the MRP token or we
can generate an NFT based upon parameters
at that given time.
So like block height, the size of the
block, things like that.
And then this is the entire sort of
action flow from this perspective.
And then quickly moving along, we're
looking at our technical requirements.
So what is this, what was, what is it
gonna take for users to set this up?
So we'll have a user interface for the
protocol owner to set these tokens up with
the specific details and that sort of
criteria.
From there, we are going to also have
distribution bots.
Those distribution bots will use Ergo
nodes to facilitate the smart contract
layer that we're facilitating here.
And then that's essentially it.
So the user is going to access the
dashboard.
They're going to request status and say,
hey, what's going on?
All right, we're back.
And so just to kind of wrap up this
section, we'll have various GitHub repos
to sort of show how to do this, maybe even
some sites that are running this, and
it'll be really, really easy.
I have prototypes of this specific setup
right here, and it works great.
Super easy to run, and all in Python.
So here's our protocol owner UI sample we
have right here.
And so we can kind of see, from top to
bottom, total number of NFTs, tokens, the
distribution pattern, rights token price
per ERG.
Everything will probably add some more
here, because this is sort of a prototype.
We have some details right here.
How much it's going to cost to fund all
this.
And so thank goodness it only cost 0.001
ERG per TX and so we're going to need that
by the total number of tokens divided by
the distribution amount.
And so we need to have enough inside the
boxes to be able to emit.
And so the owner, they're going to create
the token.
They're going to set up the initial sale.
They have the rights distribution next,
and then the protocol management.
And so that's just collecting the fees.
The reserve management in this case so
they're going to reserve for some reason
2500 but again the gamification you don't
have to do that you can do whatever you
want.
Adjust the parameters.
Not actively.
But set the parameters and kind of go
more of a thing.
Because once it's in the emission
contract, you can't change it.
Initially, on testnet, we do have some
things to be built in that whoever owns
the protocol can spend the boxes.
That's getting your money back.
But obviously, we'll take that out on
mainnet.
So people don't rug.
And so then we have the rights holder
experience.
So they can purchase rights.
They can have a minimum of one token, say
max.
Again, max.
You don't have to.
You can do NFT bonuses.
The mining operation will have the block
discovery, the reward claims, and then the
collection of the token or NFT.
And then we can even do staking, things
like that.
Again, a bunch of different options.
From here, we have the bot
infrastructure.
So it's gonna do the real-time block
scanning.
And then users can set this up to be like
every minute, every... And so there is
incentive to say, to have really good
software to be, if you're gonna be the one
say collecting most of these.
Or have multiple bots set up because
there's baked in the protocol for you to
get say the MRP token.
But they're going to do the rights
verification and then calculate the
rewards.
This is the distribution system
effectively of the emission tokens.
Instead of mining, we're running these
bots.
Instead of GPUs, we're buying and selling
rights tokens.
It's like a synthetic GPU mining system.
So this could be an initial release.
I am playing around with the idea of
launching one of these, but this is a
sample for 10 years.
And so we can see how much of the token
supply is emitted over 10 years.
We can see the yearly emission rate on
both plots here.
It's pretty easy to see.
Because we have the halving sort of
happen.
So we have 100 and 50 to 25, the half of
25.
And then here kind of wrapping up again
this is more of a white paper, but we do
have some prototypes.
I've been moving across the country so
didn't have a lot of time to code as one
would imagine, but kind of a roadmap here
is to start and build and continue to
build on this foundation that we have.
And that foundation is a system that
generates tokens very similarly to our
emission token, say MRP.
And then from there, it is dispensed to a
set of users, hard-coded at this point,
but distributed at those users, like, say,
one every block, or every other block,
rather.
And then does that until the box is
empty.
And then again, I'm running various bots
to facilitate this.
So we do have prototypes, that stuff does
work.
And then we can start to slowly
transition over to this sort of core
protocol we're calling.
And then once you hit that core protocol,
continue testing on testnet, validate sort
of the boxes, try to attack it, see if I
can spend these boxes and make sure that
the Sigma prop is accurate for what we're
actually trying to launch here.
And then maybe we're gonna launch the
actual tool set, sort of an SDK, so to
speak, and then we can actually launch a
specific token.
And then from there, I want to move into
this NFT system to where this could be
utilized, for example, for token minting.
This is an alternative to token minting
and then puts the tokens, I'm sorry, NFT
minting, NFT minting into the hands of the
miners and miners can do whatever they
want or even the pool operators.
Maybe we would do something for this for
the Sigmanauts mining pool.
But the idea would be to buy a rights
token or essentially the rights to buy an
NFT or however many NFTs and maybe there's
like say a limit like 10k there's 5k
there's a thousand.
And then per one, you'll get a specific
NFT, but only when a given miner finds the
block.
So then we're using this sort of mining
randomness whenever they're going to find
a block to then mint a NFT.
And then that could go to some sort of
marketplace like MewMart.
And then the last sort of step I would
like to do.
And maybe we'll wait to launch a token
once we have all of this but some sort of
staking opportunity because it would be
really interesting to be able to have
rights to these tokens and then be able to
stake these tokens for other rewards in
sort of a synthetic sort of GPU mining
environment but maybe it doesn't make
sense and I'd be curious what the feedback
we get for this because maybe there's
something that I'm not really thinking
about and might not be a good idea.
And then, of course, partnership with the
communities and then governance, if this
continues to take off, especially if we
launch a given token, we'll probably have
a Paideia kind of DAO and use that.
So let me know what everybody thinks.
We're excited to submit this and see what
happens.