Everyone, my name is Bruno and I'm going
to present Beene, a proof of funding
platform.
The goal of this platform is very simple.
It's to enable projects that want to raise
funds to do so and to allow contributors
who are providing funds to those projects
to be rewarded with tokens.
These tokens, we call them contribution
accounting tokens or proof of funding
tokens.
So what are the rules of this protocol of
this platform?
So it works like this. Project owners
deploy a funds vault with the following
parameters: The funding token that should
be provided as funds into the project. A
minimum amount of funding tokens that need
to be raised for the fundraising to be
considered successful and for the project
to start.
A deadline, the proof of funding token
that will be used to reward the
contributors, and the rate of proof of
funding tokens that will be given to the
contributors per funding token provided.
So after this funding vault is deployed,
project owners may add or remove proof of
funding tokens from the vault at any time.
For as long as there are proof of funding
tokens available in the contract,
contributors can provide any amount of
funding tokens to the contract and they
immediately receive a proportional amount
of proof of funding tokens to account for
their contribution and serve as proof of
funding.
At any time after the minimum amount has
been reached, project owners may withdraw
any amount of funding tokens from the
vault.
And at any time after the deadline, if
the minimum amount has not been reached,
contributors may return any amount of
proof of funding tokens to the vault and
withdraw the corresponding amount of
funding tokens that they had provided to
the vault before.
These rules can also be displayed in this
more graphical form.
So in this chart, we have the time in the
horizontal axis and the amount raised in
the vertical axis. And as you can see, at
any time, if you have raised more than a
minimum amount, those are the actions that
project owners may perform and that
contributors may perform.
And if the amount raised has not reached
the minimum and the time has passed beyond
the deadline, then contributors may give
back their proof of funding tokens and
withdraw the funding tokens that they had
provided.
Okay, so let's have a look at some
examples.
So this is an actual example that we had
and that we used Ergo Raffle for this. But
with Ergo Raffle, then we had to manually
distribute the proof of funding tokens,
the contribution accounting tokens
afterwards. And with this platform that we
have built, this distribution will be done
automatically.
So this Stable Order needed 5000 ERG to
develop an SDK for Gluon Gold. And with
this funding platform, a vault with 5000
Gluon is created with a rate of one Gluon
per ERG and a deadline in two weeks. And
yeah, 5000 Gluon are added to the vault.
Then let's suppose that after 1.5 weeks,
the goal of raising 5,000 ERG is achieved.
The contributors will have received their
Gluon as soon as they have contributed and
this Stable Order will be able to withdraw
5,000 ERG immediately after the goal has
been achieved.
Here's another example. Let's suppose
that a group of Ergo community members
wishes to produce from five to 20 articles
about Ergo at a cost of 100 ERG per
article. They create a new token, let's
say EAT, Ergo Articles Token, and they
create a vault with 2000 of those tokens
and a rate of one EAT per ERG.
The minimum amount is set to 500 ERG and
the deadline is set to two weeks from now.
So then let's suppose that after one week
the minimum goal of raising 500 ERG is
achieved. So at that point the group can
already withdraw the 500 ERG and start
producing the minimum number of articles,
like five articles.
Then as time passes and the community
sees that the group is delivering the
articles, more contributors may provide
more ERG and be rewarded with the
remaining EAT that are there in the vault,
up to 2000 EAT.
Now, if this initiative happens to be
working really well, the group may decide
to increase the number of EAT in the
contract to 10,000 and to allow the
community to continue contributing to the
production of up to 100 articles in total
now.
Now let's have a look at another example.
So let's suppose that the dev team
promises to use the latest technologies to
do something extremely amazing and they're
asking for five million ERG with a
deadline in two weeks and those who
contribute will be rewarded with a proof
of funding token that is now called Super
Duper Blockchain Tokens at a very
preferential rate.
So it's a very great bargain and nobody
should miss out.
And let's suppose that after one week,
things are looking really good, right? And
the team manages to raise 3 million ERG.
But then their too good to be true
promises get exposed as just a huge soup
of buzzwords and the community stops
funding.
So after the deadline, those who had been
lured into providing funding for this scam
can safely give back their SDBT to get
their ERG back.
So, with these very simple set of rules,
we can cover a wide variety of use cases,
such as, for example, donations. These
proof of funding tokens, they can serve as
proof of donation tokens, right? Something
that doesn't have like a monetary value,
but they are still valuable as a proof
that you have made something good, right?
That you have donated to a certain cause,
to a certain project.
They can also be used for crowdfunding.
So in this case, the contribution
accounting tokens or the proof of funding
tokens could later be exchanged for goods
produced by the crowdfunded project.
This platform can even be used for
traditional startup funding, you know,
traditional sale of tokens for a fixed
price. It could be used, for example, for
sales of event tickets, where the tokens
represent tickets to an event with a
minimum and a maximum capacity.
And the original use case that made us
develop this platform is this use case of
benefactions that we have in Stable Order.
This idea that we are working together and
contributing to our projects and these
contributions may be both in the form of
labor and capital and both of these types
of contributions are treated equally and
they both receive tokens to account for
their contributions.
So yeah, I hope you enjoyed the platform
and I hope everyone will have lots of
success raising funds for interesting
projects. And yeah, thank you. Please get
in touch and contribute to our projects.
These are our social media links. Follow
us, join us in our channels. Yeah, thank
you.
Hey, it's Jossemii. I'm going to show a
demo of the Beene Foundation platform.
So this is the available projects list.
All of these projects can be funded by any
user. Contributions page is the project
where the user has contributed, my
projects is a list with all the projects
that the user owns and there is a
formulary to submit a new project.
So the idea is to select a token, but
actually for the demo we are going to mint
a new token. So, for example, set the
token amount to 1,000, 1 ERG per token,
this will be max 10 ERG token and a
minimum of 1 ERG token and let's say 9
days until the user funding deadline.
You might, for example, add this project
link. So this is the content of the
project. And this is a description,
description, description.
So this will execute a transaction and
we'll mint these tokens so then we can see
the transaction was submitted and we need
to wait but now I'm going to contribute to
another project so for example to this
project.
In the detail page we can see all the
info of the project how much time left -
the time left is in block number of blocks
but it's translated to time - and this is
a progress bar of the current amount of
tokens, the maximum amount of tokens and
the minimum amount of tokens to make the
refund if it's not reached.
So let's contribute. Well currently I'm
the owner with this wallet so this is
another page with the other browser with
other wallet and if I - yes, I only see
the user actions.
So I can contribute. I can't refund
because the deadline is not reached yet.
So I will contribute with one token, for
example. Eight tokens was sold for now. So
I will submit it. That's the transaction
ID.
And that's it. So, well, that's it. This
is the demo.