Mark, what's up, man?
Hey, Tim.
Good, man.
Long time.
How's it going?
Dude, I'm doing very good.
I just moved and got my life in order.
But happy to sit down for a minute.
This will be episode two.
We had a little hiccup with our episodes.
And so this is episode two.
And today, we kind of wanted to talk
about some current events.
First thing was just like a big thing.
I think it's super cool.
Like just the emission reduction just
happened.
Do you want to kind of talk about that?
Like where are we at and where are we
going?
Yeah, absolutely.
So I think we're at 21 now as a block
reward.
And so I think I counted this morning, we
have six more steps from a decrease of
three to get to three.
So sometime in 2026.
So I think the miners are definitely
starting to feel it.
I mean, especially from earlier this
year, we were at like 30, really like 33
or something like that.
And then now we're... What does that make
sense?
Anyways, we're at something like that.
And then now here we are at 21.
Next one's about to be 18.
So less and less are being mined, and the
price is still sort of consistently the
same.
So it's an interesting sort of trade off
from a mining perspective right now to
where we're getting even less ERG.
Essentially the same electricity costs
around the same sort of cost to sell it.
So hopefully start to see some pressure
one way or the other, hopefully up, to
kind of alleviate some of the mining
struggles at the moment, but kind of
exciting, nonetheless, another sort of
halving but not so.
I mean, honestly, it's more than a
halving since when I started, I think when
I got in at 21, it was 72, right?
That's a lot of ERG right now.
And it was a lot of ERG, and we were at
$10 or something.
Yeah, absolutely.
When I think about that I just learned so
much about like trading and stuff like,
oh, I should definitely have taken
profits. I knew it was gonna happen.
And it was actually more aggressive.
The emission was more aggressive.
Before we changed it.
Do you want to talk about the emission,
the contract, the new change that
happened?
I'm not too familiar, I guess.
So yeah, why don't you go ahead and take
it away?
Sure.
So there was an initial emission curve
that had all of the ERG being emitted, I
think in like eight years.
So like before 2030, like all the ERG
would have been emitted.
And so it was like really aggressive.
And then they voted on this via mining,
which is sick.
So they had people indicate their
preference with a setting in their config
file.
And they got 90% consensus, which is
sick.
And so now, that's all.
Yeah.
Yeah, 90%.
I'm going to take an aside.
I'm going to skip the story.
I'll come back.
Anyway, so now some of the ERG gets put
into a re-emission contract.
So that initial emission is split.
So some of it goes to the miners, some of
it goes to a contract, and that contract
is then delayed.
And so that is how we've created a longer
tail to 2045 or something.
Yeah, so after we get down to three ERG,
it's all going to be coming from the re
emission contract.
Okay, right.
Not very much ERG.
And it's just a lot of pressure.
And kind of like you said, one way or the
other, it's going to go someplace.
Yeah, absolutely.
And it's, I kind of remember now, now
that you're saying that where it's like,
it was kind of a big deal in the ecosystem
at the time to where I think Coastal
Crypto made like a video to where it's
like, the devs are like stealing your ERG,
basically, it's like, oh, they're changing
something in the blockchain.
And in reality, you could shape it how
you want, but in reality, it's like, it's
for the longevity of the chain.
And I'm looking at it right now, it looks
like actually 2044, this month on the
27th, it looks like it'll go to zero right
after that.
So I mean, yeah, that's quite a long time
to be mining ERG from then.
And then we have storage rent as well.
Because we're starting to hit it now
within our mining pool within the last
four years, but there just needs to be
these incentives for miners to stay on the
network.
And even Bitcoin has that sort of kind of
built into their protocol too.
But like you were saying, it's, I think
it's even way further out, right?
Isn't it like 2144?
Yeah.
Right.
So that's an extremely long time that
they're going to be slowly, slowly mining.
So it will be interesting as well.
Like we're sort of approaching these
limits.
So like very early on, a lot of tokens
will be distributed on our network,
Bitcoin's network.
And it will be interesting as I guess
we're approaching some sort of like a
limit with respect to that.
And we'll see how that actually gets to
play out.
It's like these sorts of parameters that
we get the change now.
We'll actually get to see those end
results and how well Ergo's protocol
worked out compared to Bitcoin and vice
versa.
So that'll be kind of interesting.
And like in 20 years, man.
100%.
And I'm also just really excited to see
how adjustable fees and the storage rent
and also things like fair initial mining
offerings can support mining in that
really low emission environment.
Like once we get to three, I feel like
it's gonna make other things quite
valuable.
It's like, you're gonna need to be paying
attention to the storage rent, to like
what can be scavenged and collected by
your mining pool.
And if your mining pool's not doing that,
it's probably not gonna be profitable.
So it's going to really incentivize
innovation and people finding new ways to
identify things faster or offer rewards to
the miners for starting their projects.
Yeah, I mean, that's a great point.
Because people are actually doing that
now where they're able to get these, the
UTXOs with storage rent, but without hash
power for some reason.
I don't really know the nuances of it,
but somebody is able to essentially run a
script and gather those UTXOs, I think
without hash at least.
And qx() would be the better person, I
guess, to explain that to myself.
And so I think, yeah, just continuing to
push innovation with this sort of thing is
interesting.
But then you brought up fair initial
mining offering.
So would that be more of like a just a
token on like a network to where it's
like, would that be a side chain?
Would that be sort of like a layer two?
What would that sort of be, I suppose?
Yeah.
OK, so I think it could be either.
I guess when I was talking about it, I
was imagining, let's say you wanted to
come up with a new protocol, like a
lending protocol or whatever, and you
wanted to distribute your governance
tokens or something.
You could offer them as mining rewards to
be collected.
So you could just add, oh, I'm going to
input 10 tokens every block to be mined.
And I'm not sure if that's done through
some sort of script, maybe like mimicking
the re emission contract, or if you would
just like set the block height to whatever
you want it to be.
So it could be collected like garbage.
Probably either way.
Totally.
But yeah, and then it's just like,
whoever gets it gets it.
And they're not like paying you, not a
security. Howey test.
Yeah, absolutely.
And you brought up side chains and layer
twos.
So I think also it's like those are
getting mined also, right?
And so if you're running your miner and
there's a side chain going on that's the
same algo as Autolykos, it's like you're
kind of getting both of those rewards at
the same time, I think.
Okay, interesting.
Because I think it's an interesting
concept and there's a lot of, I suppose it
depends on like the security aspects and
what you're trying to do with it.
Because I think from like a token
perspective, it would be interesting
because I feel like that would be like the
lowest hanging fruit.
And if you had like all you would need to
do is essentially if your mining pool
supported it, you could just say, hey,
look at my participation when we find a
block on Ergo.
Oh, you found that block on Ergo.
Here's the reward you get from like Mark
and Tim smart contracts, and then you get
10 tokens for that block reward and then
that distributes.
But then I guess you'd have to build in
some like why I guess why would you want
to do that, aside from like the fair
initial mining offering standpoint.
Would it make sense for just one pool to
support it or do all pools need to support
it?
So it's kind of an interesting, how fair
do we want it to be?
Because fairness is in some sense
subjective.
And so it's like a spectrum even, I
guess.
So I think when you get into like, when
you get into a side chain, like you might
have an application specific side chain,
right?
So it's like a chain running, kind of
leveraging Ergo security, but it has a
specific purpose.
Like maybe there's like one dApp that
just has its own little chain.
And then maybe it's like, they kind of to
your point, like they don't want everyone
to get those tokens.
They might want their tokens to be
distributed under certain conditions.
So I think it just allows a lot of things
to be possible, which is super cool.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
It'd be fun to work on something like
that.
I saw I think Armeanio posted that as
sort of like an idea for the next coming
ErgoHack for somebody to work on.
So hopefully somebody picks that up.
That'd be cool to see.
Yeah, for sure.
So dude, did you see NiceHash is starting
to require KYC?
Yeah, yeah, that makes me somewhat
nervous as like the mining pool operator
for, and even qx() right for the
Sigmanauts mining pool.
We've talked a little bit about it and
what we're going to do and stuff.
But yeah, I mean, it's cool for a lot of
our tools, right?
The whole point is to be permissionless.
I don't need anybody's permission to join
the network.
So I think it's like, in some sense,
bullshit, right?
If I can say that here, but I don't know,
what are your thoughts?
Oh man.
Like, so every time something like that
happens, I just, it reinforces that I've
kind of made the right choice to associate
myself with Ergo.
Just my values align and it's like, no,
like just we're trying to enable freedom
and have a open permissionless transparent
network for anyone to participate in.
And like, oh, I have to register with you
and give you my personal information.
Like, dude, I honestly I hate doing that
because I've gotten four notices in the
past, I'll say 18 months that some
organization has been hacked and lost my
data.
And like, right, like what, like, stop,
stop doing that.
Stop asking.
Yeah, and then you have to give it to
them for free.
They're not safeguarding it.
There's no protocol in place to where
it's like, hey, I'm going to give you this
information, and I don't necessarily have
to trust your own security and privacy.
Let's let the blockchain do it for us.
But here we have all these people in the
way with their sort of, I guess, systems
that are hackable in some sense.
And then here we are where it's like,
yeah, then all your data is distributed.
which is crazy because like even from
like a business sense, you can come up
with LLCs and trusts that obfuscate your
own name away.
So like, so in theory, like that could be
a legitimate way for somebody to maybe
avoid like you are tied to like this
mining rig, like come up with an LLC or
trust, I suppose.
But so then at least it's tied in some
like entity, I guess, and things like
that.
But but yeah, dude, so something really
interesting about LLCs in the United
States.
They just made a law that you have to now
associate your LLC with your legal name.
So there's KYC on LLCs now, so that's
going away.
Oh, really?
Interesting.
Yeah.
I think at the start of 25.
OK. Well, I better get mine ready to go
then.
Yeah.
So I mean, then it comes back to like the
first principles of Ergo of just like,
again, why, like being permissionless
privacy is important.
Like, I'm getting ready to move to, I'm
going to rent out my house.
Like I don't really want my renters
knowing what I own, knowing what I have.
I want them to know my name.
So like privacy is like extremely
important especially when you're doing
just like day-to-day sort of like deals
and then then there becomes like all these
attack vectors as you could say once you
actually know somebody's like who they are
and where they live you know there have
been like home invasions because certain
people have found out where they live they
know
their YouTube personality like on, or
something like that, right?
And then they try to steal their crypto
keys or, it's shit like that.
It's crazy.
So I mean, to be tied to that.
It's just like insane.
And the whole thing around KYC and
blockchain is it's kind of funny to me,
because it's like, I think through zero
knowledge proofs, like you could you could
absolutely prove that it's not you without
giving away your identity.
That's the magic of ZK.
You can prove that it's not you.
So then what?
Why do I have to give you all my info?
Totally.
Well, I think it's just maybe like
regulation trying to catch up with crypto
and they're trying to do their best.
They're like, oh, I don't really
understand this.
And they don't, I guess, maybe understand
like why certain things are so important.
But I think on the other hand, because
it's kind of like, if you think about it,
like, it's sort of like this predator prey
sort of like kind of mindset and model,
you can model it as to where Bitcoin to
say this prey in this example, starts to
come up, there's a lot of like Bitcoin
people, we need to get regulation starts
to come down some more predators.
So there's like a balance between this
sort of ecosystem model, I guess you could
like sort of envision.
And then eventually, I guess wondered
depending on the I guess the ecosystem
right you know what the predator or the
prey becomes extinct right and so
hopefully I guess in this case neither
because they really the game is to
continue to play the game and so hopefully
you know we create more tools to kind of
get around certain things that we
essentially want to get around from a
legal perspective and the legal systems
like oh I see.
this is really important for that reason.
Okay, let's adjust this over here and
kind of vice versa.
We need to, I think, have the talks, but
the way they're doing it is not the right
way to kind of go about it, I would say,
it's very, very much a lot of control.
Yeah, yeah, totally, man.
And it and it's like, just reinforcing
how much they don't get it.
Yeah.
Right, right.
Like, bless his heart, Trump is starting
his what's it called, like, freedom,
finance or something.
And it's like, oh my gosh, right.
Yeah, one KYC, like, right.
Yeah.
But lucky for us, the ethos around Ergo
is leading to like some really cool
solutions, Lithos coming online,
For those of you who haven't heard of
that, Lithos is like a distributed
permissionless mining pool, kind of run on
the blockchain.
So you don't, it's not like a centralized
thing, like NiceHash where like somebody's
responsible for all your stuff.
It's actually run on the blockchain.
And so that's coming online as 6.0 gets
finished, Node 6.0.
I don't really know enough about it to
talk about it.
But I think that's a sign for us to get a
guest on here who has something to
contribute there.
I think, I bet kushti would come and tell
us about 6.0.
Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, that'd be a lot of fun.
I mean, just to, cause I think with 6.0
comes a lot of things just from, so yeah,
we have Lithos, I think Sigma protocols.
So I think that's side chains, so really
sort of like, it's a door and potentially
a pretty big door from like ecosystem
perspective.
So then once we have this, there's a lot
of little, not little, I suppose, but
other things we can sort of tie and attach
to and then more applications, more
applications mean more real world
applications.
And that's gonna be really cool to see.
Yeah, man, I think side chains are one of
the things that I got most excited about
when I started learning about Ergo.
I remember, what was it called?
Ergo.meta, right?
And it's like a sidechain cookbook is
what I remember kushti characterizing it.
So it's like, it's just like a dev kit,
right?
But for these like, here's how you make
your sidechain.
And my imagination kind of goes wild.
Like we talked about application specific
side chains, but I also like to think
about building like Monero on top of Ergo.
That way it's like kind of capturing the
more, I don't want to say extreme, but
like the more maximal viewpoint of like, I
really get why people like Monero.
It's, I think that is maybe the most
valid maximalism in my view, it's like I
see Bitcoin maximalism as like being
conservative and not wanting to like risk
all your money on some like brand new
shitcoin.
I get it.
But I also think somebody who's like, No,
we need to have an unstoppable tool.
That's Monero.
That makes sense to me.
And it just needs some legs.
Like we need to have DeFi, you need to
have lending and borrowing and stablecoins
and all this stuff and if we can we can
put that on Ergo on it as a sidechain or
somehow bridging it I don't know I'm not
the guy to give you the technical details
but if we can give Monero some legs like
now we're cooking with gas
Yeah, yeah, that would be huge.
And isn't Monero mined with CPUs?
I think, right?
Yeah, so I mean, that's just so
accessible, like everybody for the most
part has a CPU in their mining Ergo, so
you could probably dual mine in some
aspects.
And it would be cool opportunity for the
Sigmanauts mining pool to kind of stand up
other pools on these side chains to kind
of support that and
Yeah, I mean, especially just with this
whole KYC thing having that privacy aspect
that privacy buffer just to be able to
say, hey, no, I hear what you're saying
government, but I'm still going to do
this, and protect yourself, right?
Because like, ultimately, in some places,
it is against the law.
I'm not trying to get arrested.
I have a little one at home.
So it's like, let's make sure and so
having those tools building for war so to
speak is gonna be very important that you
have the proper tools right so if you're
going against war against somebody who has
bullets and all you have is a shield that
can't stop bullets or something like that
that's not really gonna do too well versus
having like so we need the proper
equipment to be able to say hey no I hear
what you're saying but we're still gonna
do this and it's like you're saying
unstoppable so yeah it's a powerful idea
Yeah.
So I think this means we need to get
somebody smarter than the two of us to
teach us about side chains, about 6.0, all
that.
All right.
So I'm going to move us forward.
We wanted to talk a little bit about
something that happened a few years ago,
just like a little story about something
that Ergo went through and was hardened
by.
I'm going to share my screen, and
hopefully this doesn't mess up Andy's
beautiful work.
All right.
There we go.
Nice.
The bear whale.
Yeah.
So these are so that bear whale.
All right.
First of all, it's an awesome drawing.
Absolutely.
Bear whale, the bear whale saga.
This was in 2021, where a large holder
was draining the SigmaUSD account or the
bank, specifically attacking the RSV
holders.
And so just to kind of give an overview,
some prior knowledge, SigmaUSD is our kind
of flagship stablecoin.
And it works by having two tokens.
So the SigmaUSD here and SigRSV.
So USD is obviously pegged to a dollar.
And that peg is maintained by allowing
volatility in the RSV, which is like the
reserve token.
Okay, so there's the bank that holds all
the ERG, and then the value of these two
tokens is, well, one of them is held
stable, and then the other fluctuates
based on the value of the ERG that's held
in the bank.
All right, so these are kind of the rules
that it operates under.
So you can always redeem your SigmaUSD,
but you can't you can't mint the USD
unless there is 400% of the value in the
reserve.
So if there's not enough reserves, then
you can't mint the USD.
And if there's not enough reserves, you
also can't redeem your RSV.
So you can kind of get locked in.
And so these are the rules.
The bear whale was able to manipulate the
rules in this first version in SigmaUSD
version one.
Okay.
What he was doing was like super clever.
Sometimes when I'm in blockchain, I'm
just like, man, I'm just not that smart
compared to all these guys.
So he was taking advantage of the Oracle
speed, right?
So he would jump into a position of
SigmaUSD and then the Oracle is reading
the markets in, I don't know, we'll say
TradeOgre or whatever.
And he had enough ERG to sell all the ERG
and that crash the price the Oracle would
read that price and then so his SigmaUSD
position would actually be able to be
redeemed for more ERG than he bought it
for, right?
So then he would, so he would buy
SigmaUSD, crash the price, the Oracle
would see that crash, and then that would
be reflected here.
So let's say he paid 100 bucks or 100 ERG
for 100 SigmaUSD.
Then the value of the ERG goes down to,
let's say it's now his SigmaUSD is worth
120 ERG.
He switched back in and then bought his
position back to raise the price.
And so he was able to like slowly collect
ERG, not slowly, but over time he
collected a bunch of ERG just by gaming
this little system.
And so there's a cool article in, in the
ergoplatform.org.
If anyone wants to read about it, you can
see how the community was like learning
about it, tracking his wallets.
People started writing scripts to kind of
try to get around this and not let it
happen.
And eventually what the team had to do
was slow down the rate of change that the
Oracle could report.
So I think it's now, they limited the
update to 0.5% every 30 minutes, up or
down.
And so now if the bear whale tried to do
it again, he would actually have to hold
the price down for longer and for more
than 30 minutes if he wanted a 0.5%
change.
And so it might not be really worth the
risk.
And actually when it happened, I think he
lost, this article says he lost 170,000
ERG trying to keep doing it after they
patched the protocol.
Which I just thought was like a really
cool story about, finding an attacker who
had, it's just like a, not like a clever,
good on him, but ended up prevailing in
the end.
How long was the whole saga?
Like from, like, when I guess from the
initial attack to when they patched it.
Cause I would imagine once they kind of
figured out like, Oh, wow, I see what's
happening.
We need to kind of act now, I'm curious
about that.
I'm not sure.
I'm not sure how long it was.
It says something about between $2 and
$4.
So probably not that long.
I bet it was like six months that the
version one was going.
And then they updated it to version two.
I mean, thankfully that happened now,
honestly, versus like, imagine if we had
like multiple bear whales attacking at the
same time, just essentially attacking the
network in that aspect.
And especially when it was like so, so
high in terms of price.
And even some people now say the price is
being manipulated in some sense.
And maybe, maybe it is.
With all these guys with all these, like
a hundred thousand or he lost like, so he
must've been using a lot more than a
hundred thousand.
That's a lot.
I mean, I don't know how I feel about
like, okay.
So I think the term manipulation is a
little bit funny because to me, if it's
just like a market, and people are selling
and buying and like, you could do whatever
you want.
Absolutely.
I think the only time it becomes really
unethical is like, if the founders are
doing something, like if the Ergo
Foundation treasury is being used to like,
do the bear whale thing, like that, that's
messed up.
But if it's just like some rich guy, like
it's what it is.
Yeah.
So take as much control as you want,
right.
So I mean, the rules are there.
If you can do it, then send it.
I totally agree.
But yeah, something's happening, I guess.
But in any case, it's interesting,
though.
It's like, how does somebody even figure
out that you can even do the thing that
the bear whale did?
Like that must've taken some serious, or
maybe not, I don't know.
I mean, I haven't really played too much
around with it, the idea, but sounds
pretty complicated and complex to be able
to kind of sort through.
And then obviously they had some pretty
confidence in doing it, especially since,
even after it was patched, they kept
sending it and sending it and trying it
and trying it.
So then realize, oh wow, okay, maybe they
fixed it or something like that, right?
Yeah.
And even more to my point about like,
it's like, whatever, it's just like how
the world works.
This ended up hardening the, not just the
SigmaUSD protocol with the changes, now
it's stronger, but it led to like, oh,
like, we could come up with maybe simpler
designs or other more secure designs for
stable coins.
And that's led us on to Dexy and Gluon,
which are super cool.
I'll just share the gluon design.
It has these two tokens that are kind of
like SigmaUSD and SigRSV.
This is the stable coin that's not really
stable.
It's just pegged to gold.
And then this is the reserve token.
But you don't just buy one.
You have to mint both, which is pretty
cool.
And that allows for a lower reserve ratio
requirement.
Since everyone's like simultaneously
minting both of these and then and then
they have to sell, if you actually just
wanted gold, well, then you have to sell
your guac over here.
I keep calling it guac, G-A-U-C. You have
to keep selling this and then you get then
you get all gold or only gold and that
leads to the protocol earning fees.
So that it can kind of maintain that peg
by, super cool.
Just like another, another version of it.
And then this, Dexy Gold.
So Dexy Gold is, I think maybe even
simpler, where it's just an auto,
arbitrage mechanism, right?
So there's like a bank.
So when this came out a long time ago, I
tried to make like a visual of it and this
could be totally wrong.
So I would love for somebody to just kind
of make fun of me for not understanding.
This is a long time ago.
Okay.
So the Dexy I think works like this.
There's, there's like the bank where, it
can buy and sell, tokens out of this AMM.
And that is reading the Oracle price for
gold.
And so that's how it decides what to do.
If the price needs to go up or down to
match the price of gold, then it takes the
action in the AMM.
And then users are able to interact with
the AMM.
So they're buying and selling.
And then the fees go to the bank.
So the bank's value is going to grow over
time and capacity will increase as users
use the protocol.
That's awesome.
Yeah, I thought it was cool.
So what's, I guess, the difference then
between Dexy and Gluon?
So Gluon, it has that reserve.
You're sending your ERG in and then
receiving these two tokens.
And then the algorithm kind of balances
the value of those two and it has that
reserve token.
Dexy doesn't have a reserve token.
It's just, yeah, it's, how did he say it?
It's one token with like two protocols.
So instead of two tokens with one
protocol on Gluon, interesting.
Yeah.
So in Dexy, it's just like gold and ERG.
And there's the bank doing stuff.
And then there's the AMM doing stuff to
balance the price.
That's what I think.
And I'd love to like, get some nuance.
So maybe that's another episode in the
future.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think so.
Because I have like a lot of questions
like, why would you want to have a reserve
like who who makes the reserve?
So do you have to do like, initial
funding of it?
And then there's builds the reserve
versus like, Dexy is looking at the bank,
in terms of gold.
And then I would imagine, right, because
of the reserve token, there's probably
nuances to where you could do arbitrage
between these gold stable coins back to
back, because of how their mechanisms kind
of increase and decrease their prices.
Yeah, so I think, I think Dexy might
actually, I think you're right, like you
would have to kind of fund that bank.
But it eventually is like a locked
protocol.
It's a protocol owned liquidity there.
Nobody owns that.
It's non-custodial.
It's just locked in a contract that
operates autonomously.
It's not like somebody's ERG is sitting
in that bank.
That's what I think.
But then how does the gold, I guess, work
into the play then?
Because then, I guess, technically,
you're buying gold, right?
But then where's the actual gold I
suppose, come into play because wouldn't
in theory the bank buy real gold in order
to have, right?
In a real life thing, yes.
So this is minting those tokens and the
value is represented in the AMM.
So it has ERG and the gold tokens and the
bank can mint gold tokens and buy and sell
those in the AMM.
Right.
I guess I'm confused on just like what
it's backed by.
Like, well, how does it inherently hold?
Yeah, just ERG and the Oracle.
Okay.
Interesting.
It's well, I think it's similar to like
SigmaUSD, where it's like, it's just
algorithmic and like, yeah, is this worth
a dollar?
It's just a token.
Right.
But since you can sell your SigmaUSD for
$1 worth of ERG, that's what makes it
valuable.
That's what like ensures its value.
And so the same thing here, you're
getting this token that's like, yeah, it's
not real gold.
Which would be really interesting.
I would love to have like some warehouse
actually selling tokens that you could go
get.
Right.
Yeah.
But in this case, it's like, no, it's
just this autonomous protocol that will
give you the oracle price of gold in ERG
when you want it.
So it's more of like a synthetic gold,
per se.
So would the same be true for Gluon in
the reserve token?
But it would be more of like a synthetic,
but like with a reserve, I guess.
And then that has its own, I guess,
inherent properties relative to, I guess.
Yeah, so Dexy, I think, uses the users
mostly and the bank to buy and sell things
to maintain that price.
And then Gluon uses the algorithm to kind
of tell you how much you can purchase
these for or redeem your reserve token
for.
And that reserve token is going to go up
and down, kind of like exaggerated
movements of the ERG to BTC price.
Right.
No, that's very fascinating because I
mean, imagine like, being able to do this
just for and I think that's kind of almost
where like, ChainCash comes into play to
where it's like, kind of take these models
of where it's like, okay, let's just get
rid of gold, it's abstract away.
And then like, let's put like my house.
And then you can like tokenize your house
and then sell certain aspects of your
house or whatever real world applications
actually make sense, I suppose, like
actual gold would be sick, like, Yeah,
here's my my warehouse of gold.
We've got 10 bars or whatever it is.
And then that's what kind of how they're
doing with the which would be very similar
to the ETF, what they're doing with the
Bitcoin ETF, in some aspects.
Dude.
So funny that I've admitted this right
now.
On Twitter, I actually I spam Peter
Schiff and tell him that he should be
tokenizing his gold on the Ergo
blockchain.
He could sell it and earn.
I mean, you could earn a 1% fee.
Like, why don't you do that?
And just every time someone needs to buy
or redeem their their gold token backed by
his gold, he owns a gold company.
It's like, okay, but there you go, bro.
Like you hate Bitcoin.
Right?
Yeah.
Does he like blockchain though?
I don't know.
His whole position is weird, because I
think like, the gold and Bitcoin value
proposition is just so similar.
Like, yeah, like, why hate one or the
other?
Totally.
I was actually just thinking the other
day, I'm like, I should buy some gold,
like, that should be something, buy some
of those assets and silver, and uranium.
like.
Okay, uranium.
That's why you have to let me know how to
buy that.
Oh, just stocks, bro stocks.
I don't actually own any uranium.
Tim's building nukes out in Arizona.
My kids are gonna be weird.
You actually work for the CIA.
So it's cool.
All right, brother.
Is there is there anything else you
wanted to talk about today?
No, I think that we definitely talked a
lot and hit a lot of good, exciting
topics.
So I mean, maybe we save it for the next
episode.
Yeah.
So just a disclaimer to everybody.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
I'm just a guy and I like to read a lot.
I don't understand everything perfectly.
So if me and Mark get something wrong,
I'd love to learn and you can be a guest
and come and drop your knowledge on us.
Yeah, please do.
I mean, for sure.
Correct us and let us know how it is,
please.
Yeah.
I'm an idea guy.
That's it.
Right.
I like that Rick Rubin clip where he's
like, no, I'm not good at music.
I don't know anything.
I know what I like and what I don't like.
Right.
He's just this hit producer for all these
bands.
It's like, cool, cool, cool.
I mean that and that's honestly that's a
good takeaway just in life it's like and
even with Ergo right it's like well if you
really want to get excited and do
something you just got to be excited and
do it you don't really need to know like
whatever here we are we don't know
everything about Ergo we're talking about
it so and it's fun having a blast doing it
yeah all right brother i hope you have a
great day stay safe out there cool see
everyone
you