Hey guys, I'm Gvuldis from the team
Kropli and we are here to introduce you to
On-Ergo.
It is an amazing tool that we are
building here on Ergo and I hope that you
guys enjoy and find it useful.
So let's start our presentation by
talking about the problems that we are
going to address.
I'm fairly sure that most of you guys
have seen what has happened with Cardano
over the last few years since it is of
course our testnet. It started well with a
wallet and then boom, it was overwhelming
so quickly and it was basically impossible
to stay updated on most developments.
This was at least my experience, I don't
know about you guys, but we believe that
Ergo, though considerably smaller right
now, is going to end up on the same path
and face this same problem.
And we believe that it is better to solve
this problem sooner rather than later. And
Cardano, as far as I know, still doesn't
have the solution for this. That's why we
are here right now.
One more problem that inexperienced
people face in crypto is that things are
much more complicated than we as
professional community members think. The
reality is that most people investing in
crypto will never withdraw their coins
from centralized exchanges because, well,
it is simply too complicated at this stage
of time.
As of now, there isn't really a clear,
consistent guide for navigating the
ecosystem and exploring all the
opportunities that it provides or will
provide in the future. And newcomers are
just scared to make mistakes with their
money. They need to be encouraged somehow,
in some way. And marketing, when?
So on Ergo, our solution to these
problems that we started to create during
Ergo Hack 9 will provide both new and
experienced users with an event calendar,
an educational platform, a Discord bot,
and with some very nice incentives to get
people to discover new possibilities
on-chain.
Let's take a look at them separately with
more details. First of all, an event
calendar. Whether it's community meetups,
dApp launches, updates, or special events,
everything gets listed here. And it's
super easy for projects as well as
community members to add events
themselves.
We are still polishing the details and
permissions for adding events. However, we
want to make those rules as decentralized
as possible. For now, possible solutions
include a Discord bot integration or NFTs,
granting the possibility to post. So
you'll always know what's happening, when
and where.
Imagine not having to dig through 10
different channels or announcements, it's
all here in one place, and you don't have
to miss anything. We are aware that this
might not be as useful at the moment,
however, as I mentioned before, this can
become very useful with several project
pre-sales launching at the same time
during Ergo's exponential growth.
Here you can see a small preview of the
very early stage development that we have
done so far on the event calendar.
So, besides just keeping you informed, we
want to help everyone learn about Ergo
too. That's where our educational platform
comes in. We are creating a quest roadmap.
It's kind of like a game where each quest
is a learning opportunity.
For example, your first quest might be
something as simple as creating a wallet,
then maybe sending your first transaction
or integrating with the app. Each
completed quest brings rewards. So you're
not just learning, you're playing a game
and earning along the way.
Our goal here is to build confidence and
knowledge, guiding you from a newbie to a
Sigmanauts, step by step. We have made
some of these roadmaps, however we don't
want to reveal too much so that we can
make the launch even more exciting.
Here's a small preview of a start of a
potential quest roadmap on the educational
platform about the Cyberverse game. Each
new quest unlocks after the previous has
been finished. And this is basically how a
start of such roadmap could look like.
Our Discord bot is like the backbone of
this whole experience. It's integrated
with the platform and acts as an assistant
for the community. Let's say you're
curious about upcoming events. Just type
slash events and it will list everything
that's on the calendar.
Projects can also use the bot to add
events directly with a slash add event,
making it instantly accessible to the
whole community. As I already mentioned,
we are thinking of possible solutions for
adding events, and one more possibility
would be to integrate this Discord bot in
Ergo ecosystem's Discord servers, make
them follow the announcement pages, let
the posts go through AI check, and
automatically add the event mentioned in
the announcement to On-Ergo's calendar.
We are exploring many options and we will
make sure to choose the best one with the
help of Ergo's community and its feedback.
Now, what's a community platform without
some incentives, right? We are going to
have leaderboards, raffles and rewards to
keep things fun and engaging. So, if
you're completing quests, attending events
or just actively participating in the
ecosystem, you'll be recognized for it,
and who doesn't love a bit of friendly
competition.
These incentives are all about building a
healthy, active community where everyone's
excited to contribute and engage.
On-Ergo is more than just a platform.
It's an innovative approach to managing
and navigating the Ergo ecosystem. We are
combining event management, gamified
onboarding, and DeFi accessibility all in
one. We're creating an ecosystem hub that
doesn't just give you information but
actually helps you experience the
ecosystem hands-on.
This innovation is all about making Ergo
user-friendly and accessible from
beginners to seasoned pros.
Our community is at the core of
everything we are building with On-Ergo.
This platform is designed to grow and
evolve with community input. We want to
hear from you, your ideas, your feedback,
your events. On-Ergo will make it easy to
organize and promote community-led events,
building a central hub for the entire Ergo
family.
Together, we'll create a thriving,
connected ecosystem where everyone can get
involved.
So who will actually benefit from this?
First of all newcomers, because On-Ergo
simplifies the entry into Ergo with guided
learning and easy-to-find events. Then the
community, because the platform helps by
summarizing all updates and events in one
place.
And projects, new projects especially,
can gain visibility and engagement with a
simple way to list events and updates and,
well, On-Ergo strengthens the entire Ergo
ecosystem by making it more accessible and
pushing people to use the ecosystem more.
So, what's next? We're starting with the
essentials, the event calendar and the
Discord bot to get the foundation in
place. Then we'll expand with more
educational quests, enhanced incentives
and user-driven updates.
We are also planning to open source the
project later on so the community can
contribute directly. This roadmap is
flexible. As we grow and get feedback,
we'll keep adapting and improving to make
sure that we are meeting the needs of the
community.
In summary, On-Ergo is here to bring the
Ergo ecosystem together, all in one place.
Whether you're looking for events,
educational resources or community
incentives, we want On-Ergo to be your
go-to hub. Our mission is to make Ergo
simple, accessible and engaging for
everyone.
One ecosystem, one platform, that's
On-Ergo. Thank you for being here and
let's work together to make the Ergo
ecosystem the best it can be. Thank you
for letting us participate in this Ergo
hack and thank you for attention from
On-Ergo.