Mark, what's happening, man?
Hey, Tim.
Good, man. Good. Warm and sunny in
Florida. How about you?
Dude, it's cold over here. It was, I
think, in the 20s this morning when I woke
up. But you know what is heating up,
though?
Yeah, the bull run, right?
Oh, dude, I gotta say, the other day, I
saw that dumb bird just like going up and
I was the worst employee. I checked my
phone like 30 times, I swear to God. I was
like, holy shit, 90,000.
What a great Monday, you know, it's just
like, geez, and then I see people on
Twitter. It's like, okay, we don't have to
post every $1,000. You know, it's starting
to get like that. It's exciting. You know,
it's just like, oh, man, you know, texting
the normie friends like guys, it's
happening, you know, the conviction. Yeah,
we have it's finally, you know, it's
bearing fruit in some sense, right?
Yeah, dude, I gotta say, when Bitcoin was
down, I told 50 to 100 people, like for
sure, at least that many. I even did a
presentation in my doctoral program
because we had this assignment where it
was for an evaluation class, like how to
structure formal evaluations. And so my
like little side project or like mini
project for this class was is Bitcoin a
scam? And so I like conducted a formal
evaluation. And clearly, it's not a scam.
I don't know if it's going to be the
reserve currency of the world, but it's
not a scam. And so I gave this whole
presentation. Everyone was like, didn't it
just crash? I'm like, yeah, that's why I
told you about it right now. I told all
these people, probably 100 people in that
class and otherwise, the only person that
listened to me was my mom. My mom bought.
My mom bought Bitcoin and is now like,
yeah.
That's awesome. Yeah, good for her. So
how did you convince your mom? I feel like
my parents, at least my dad, he's like,
you know, I should have bought it or like,
you know, but then doesn't get the go
ahead, I guess, you know, what was your
argument, I guess, right?
Okay, so really, I wasn't like convincing
my mom, my mom asked me kind of a long
time ago, like, Hey, like what's Bitcoin?
And I was like, I can't give you a really
good answer. Let me like read and learn.
And you know, like two months later, I was
like, Oh God, Bob, we need to, we gotta
like, look at this. So like her and I both
kind of like went a little bit in and then
that led me to, you know, Cardano and then
Ergo.
And then you know the crash and everyone
was depressed and all this and my mom
honestly like forgot about it and then you
know when everything was super low. I just
like kind of brought it up again I was
like hey mom you need to like get back
into Coinbase and like you should buy a
little bit more now because you're gonna
have twice as much buying power and it'll
be worth it.
Yeah. It's funny too, like you were
saying, right? Some people are like, well,
didn't it just crash? They weren't saying
that, right? In 2008, 2009, when the
housing market crashed, you know, people
were buying up a bunch of houses. If you
have the liquidity, of course, a lot of
people were hurting, but people weren't
going to say, oh, are you not going to buy
a house? I mean, of course, it's a little
bit different from an asset perspective.
But I don't know. I think it's
interesting. Maybe it's just so new.
People are still kind of, I mean, we're so
early even too, right? It's just so,
people are still just not really sure
about it, right?
Yeah, man. It's really funny. Like
whenever you start saying your honest
opinion about this to people, like how
early are we? Like you feel kind of crazy.
You know, it's like, yeah, no, it could
legit be in the millions. If, if Bitcoin
hits half of gold, that's like 400k.
That's crazy. Half of gold. And why not?
Why not?
Yeah. And then with the current
administration, or not the current, the
next administration kind of coming in, it
seems they're suggesting, right? It could
be an indicator that's positive for
Bitcoin. And then also other people are
maybe starting to come around. I don't
know if you saw a tweet from Peter Schiff.
Peter Schiff's like, I'm starting to come
around. Maybe we can fix the social
security problem. He's like, if we buy 25%
of all of the Bitcoin, that would shoot it
up to 20 million. Then we would just hold
and coming up with all this stuff and that
would be amazing. Obviously good price,
but even for social security, like I would
love to retire and get social security,
you know?
I think he was being sarcastic, but the
further he went along, it's like, dude,
you're making the exact point. He's like,
well, then you have to sell your Bitcoin.
And I actually posted the meme. Dude, I'm
going to actually show this meme real
quick. I won't show the meme. It's the one
where Neo is talking to Morpheus. And he's
like, so you're saying I'm going to be
able to sell my bitcoins for millions of
dollars? He's like, no, Neo. When you're
ready, you won't have to. I sent that to
Peter Schiff, probably didn't see it. But
whatever.
No, absolutely. I mean, and if what are
you saying, you know, right, maybe it will
be a reserve currency, and then you won't
have to sell it. And you know, there will
be all of these financial mechanisms to
where it's like, you can leverage your
Bitcoin without selling your Bitcoin in
some sense. And we're starting to see
different vehicles with the stock market.
You can buy the ETFs. That's been doing
really, really well. Micro strategies. I
don't have you paid attention much to
micro strategies. That's a crazy volatile
index relative to Bitcoin. It's like, it's
hotter than Bitcoin. I bought some like,
when it first not micro strategies, but
when the ETF came out, and I'm up pretty
good. And it's just like, it's crazy, like
to see.
Yeah, dude. I saw when Grayscale,
remember when Grayscale was that just like
a deep discount? It was like nice little
discount, you know, and then...
Yeah. So it's a wild time. So when do you
think a hundred K is going to happen? You
know, right now, what is it around 90
something 92, 93?
I think it said it was at 91 and then I
saw it at 89 dude, for all I know, it
could be like three o'clock. I don't know.
It wouldn't surprise me. It also wouldn't
surprise me if it went down and tested 70
K again. Just, you know, that's how it
goes. Like why not?
Absolutely. Yeah, I think people are
going to probably start taking profits.
And I mean, it's just been a super hot
week these last like three days. And then
now it's, you know, I would imagine maybe
some cooling down. But, you know, I'm sure
a lot of people are just bullish with this
new administration coming in from a crypto
perspective. And, you know, Bobby Kennedy
has even mentioned like, you know, some
things that he wants to do with Bitcoin
and you know, paying off the debt with it.
And like, so I think there's gonna be a
lot of positives relative to, but of
course, we're biased because we've been
exposed to so.
But overall, dude, super exciting. And
hopefully it kind of becomes normal. I was
starting this business with my wife and
was looking to use some of my funds to
borrow against them rather than sell to
start this business. And none of the
Bitcoin anything, nothing related to
Bitcoin is eligible in the stock market at
least through Schwab or whatever. So all
the stuff I have in Bitcoin, I would
actually have to sell it that could borrow
against it unless I go through like, you
know, third party or whatever. So I'm
learning more about that kind of see how
realistic it is.
That's interesting. Yeah, especially with
the stock market, right? Because it takes
because it's cool that's in the stock
market, but we actually lose a little bit
of applicability within the asset because
it sort of locks it, you can't move it, we
lose control. But of course, there's
certain vehicles why you'd want to do
that. Like I have my 401k, you know, I
don't really need to take it out and do
anything with it.
So yeah, same. That's what I had it in a
sheltered account. And so it's like, you
know, doing all this tax free and I can
like make these trades without
capitalizing, you know, having to pay
taxes. So yeah.
So hopefully this bull market kind of
carries over to Ergo. I've seen some
people, you know, like, oh, are we going
to see above all time highs? Some people
are starting to say, oh, I don't think so.
I'm not really sure. I haven't really
given it too much thought, but it's
exciting. I think nonetheless, these next
six months.
So I actually put this in a tweet
yesterday. If you look at the price, it
looks bad, like per coin, right? But if
you look at the market cap, it's not as
bad. So market cap, we're one eighth of
the way. So we're at a hundred million
right now. And all time high was at like
800 million. Right. So, but price is like
$19 to $1. Right. So that looks bad, but
it's because all that heavy emission in
21, 22, and then now it's like pretty low,
the emissions pretty low. So per market
cap, like, I think we're okay right now
and ready to participate in the bull
market. Like, who knows? Are we gonna stop
at 20 or like send it to you know, $10
billion market cap one of these days.
Yeah, that was a great tweet that you had
because you were saying something up to
the effect, right? Basically, the lower it
stays or the longer it stays in that sort
of level, the more sort of springboard to
sort of shoot up, right? And I could
probably see that too, you know, because I
think we've seen that, like, if you look
at Bitcoin, Bitcoin was trading in those
trenches for such a very long time like
you're saying right very similar Ergo the
emissions were extremely high people were
spending 10,000 bitcoin on a pizza you
know like very similarly here you know
with Ergo you know people are spending
hundreds of ERG right for for certain
things and so I don't know I feel like it
could probably it just needs time and it's
just inevitable right and so we'll see
what happens absolutely but I think we've
got a lot of good things confluencing kind
of together from an ecosystems perspective
to a community perspective the chain
itself.
Oh, yeah So we'll see what else is going
on. We've got ErgoHack. What do you know
about ErgoHack? That's just finished up
and judging is about to start. Is that
right?
Yeah, yeah, I think Glasgow said in one
of the chats it started. I think it was
either yesterday or today. Yeah, ErgoHack
9 so that's pretty sweet. What was it?
It's about UI and mining so great theme. I
think. You know, Ergo is poised to be, you
know, one of the best proof of work chains
out there. So of course, highlighting that
to outsiders, I think is extremely
important. And then of course, relative
from the user perspective, you know,
harnessing the UIs and making our UIs a
lot better. Because I think for some, a
lot of people don't really like, I guess,
UIs in Ergo. But I feel like, to me, that
doesn't really mean much. And so like UI
is user interface. So like, what about the
UI? Does it make sense? And you brought
it, I think, I think we might've talked
about this on the last podcast where it's
like, well, what do we mean when we say
this is a bad UI? And I think you were
kind of saying like, basically know your
assumptions. What exactly does it do? What
it doesn't do FAQs, things like that. So
it would be cool, kind of interesting if
like there was a standardization relative
to UI. So like someone that's coming new
into the ecosystem could say, Hey, I want
to make something we could point them to
Hey, this is sort of the standard. And
then we can kind of continue to build up.
Yeah, for sure, man. I think there's been
a lot of good things to come out of these
ErgoHacks. And even if it's not
necessarily a project that comes out, it's
like, just a culture that kind of develops
over time or people just kind of want to
help others learn. And a lot of this stuff
is open source. So like things, you know,
even if something doesn't work out or a
project dies, you know, like, I think
ErgoPad just shut down, right? But like,
it's okay. All that stuff is still there
to get reused. All the vesting contracts,
that's super useful. And somebody is going
to take that and use it. And same for all
these ErgoHack projects. Though, of
course, I hope they succeed. I saw some
cool ones on the list of the present
ErgoHack. One of them I was super excited
about was Minotaur. We've kind of been
waiting for a good multi-sig. I saw the
video. Looks pretty simple. You know,
that's exactly what we want.
Yeah. Well, so how does it work then? I
guess is it basically because for
multi-sig need multiple people, right?
Maybe four out of seven keys. So how does
it handle that? I guess.
So the video that I watched, it was
really just showing like several wallets
being open at the same time. And when one
like submitted the transaction, it
appeared on all the wallets like you need
to sign this transaction. And then so all
the people would be able to fulfill that
obligation and then the transaction would
go through. And I think that's like super
necessary as I don't know, let's say
somebody got a million bucks in ERG in a
few years. You really need to think about
your security and ensuring that you're not
going to lose that. Like myself, I use the
steel plates. That's what secures my
funds, but I also give incomplete plates
to different people. And so they know,
like, if something happened to me, they
could talk to these other people and
figure out how to get my funds, right? So
they could like put their thing together.
But that, you know, that's a multi-sig.
But it's a little tricky. And so this is
just like taking all the work out of that
and all the sketchiness where I could
actually just like set it up and do it
legit, like thank goodness. Thank you,
Minotaur.
Right. And I think too from like, like
you're saying, like, you know, I see some
people who have like hundreds of thousands
of ERG in a given wallet. That makes me
nervous. You know, I have multiple wallets
set up. But if you have a multi-sig and
you hold all the keys, you know that
that's kind of a reinforcement of like no
one's going to hack you because they have
to hack you maybe four out of seven keys
for example or whatever the case so I
think that's definitely an extra security
benefit security blanket makes you sleep a
little bit better at night with that's you
know if you're especially if you have if
it's a hot wallet right because I mean
that's eventually going to happen say you
take profits and you do have that much
it's like that's going to be nerve
wracking. You know what I mean? And
putting that all in a hot wallet and you
know, maybe some guy has your keys, just
doesn't know it waiting to see, Oh,
100,000 just popped in there. They run
their script or bots just waiting. I mean,
hopefully not right. But I'm just, you
know, thinking of the worst sort of
outcome that would be devastating. You
know what I mean?
Yeah, man. I mean, keylogger is probably
the easiest thing to happen to somebody,
you know, just they get your password,
remote access, gone.
Right. It's like, dude. Yeah. And then
that's what's, in some sense, cool about I
guess it's more of more institution type
stuff because it adds like that security
blanket, I guess. But I don't know how
from an insurance perspective, like if
they were to lose your keys. But I think
at the end of the day, you got to take
accountability. If you're going to put all
that money into that sort of stuff, you
need to make sure you know what you're
doing. You know, like, for example, there
was somebody in Rosen that got scammed,
like, I don't know, 16,000 because he gave
his keys. But it's just like, dude, you
have 16,000 or like, how do you not know
that you don't do that? Like it's just
money growing trees for you. Like how do
you know what I mean? It's just like, it's
a weird concept that people sort of, I
guess, ape into something and then don't
do any like due diligence. So certainly a
wild west, but of course a certain level
of accountability needs to be in place.
So let's see what else we got. We got a
cool one. 3D Ergo. Bro, you wanna talk
about 3D Ergo?
Yeah, so it looks like it's a, what would
you call this? An explorer for, I guess
not an explorer, right? More of like a
visual explorer, in any case. Yeah, like a
visual explorer. Looks at a specific block
and then you can zoom in on the given TXs
and see where they're going and coming
from. I got it pulled up, let me see if I
can share this. And like this would be
really neat, for example, if like you had
one input and like 10,000 outputs, I would
love to see something like that, you know,
or like where people are trying to stress
test sort of the network. That would be
kind of really cool to see.
Mark, while I'm doing this, do you wanna
look for the block that had the MiGoreng
drop?
Okay, yeah, let me see. That one had,
let's see if we can, okay. So I'll talk
about this. So here's, these are the
transactions that are in the current
block. Oh man, I did this like 15 minutes
ago. Oh, there we go. All right. Now we're
cooking. So you click on it and you can
really see what each block is doing and
what it's connected to. And there's like a
starting point and an ending point and you
can, oh yeah. Look at this. Oh wow. Yeah.
I just think this is so dang cool. Like, I
think you would have to be doing this like
kind of purposefully to like really, oh,
look at that, there's a SigmaUSD.
I think maybe a next step with this could
be from an analysis perspective to where
it's like maybe you put in your wallet and
then you can see all the different wallets
from a networking perspective that they're
connected to. So then you could, if you
were like, Hey, this guy has like, you
know, 10 million ERG, but he's doing some
weird sketchy stuff. You know, you can
maybe analyze all his wallets that he's
interacting with, and then kind of figure
out maybe what they're doing. Maybe it's
like the Silk Road and you can kind of
follow that a little bit more closely.
Yeah, that's a cool idea, man. I was also
thinking about it like you could see if
your privacy was broken, you know, like,
like, oh, did I make a mistake in my
wallet? Am I screwed? Do I have to like
mix all this again or whatever? You could
just put your wallets in here and see if
they connect. And if they don't, you're
good.
Right. Yeah, absolutely. See if it's
traceable back to you. I mean, yeah, that
would be really neat. I mean, especially
from a mining pool perspective where we're
sending out, you know, transactions every
day, it would be cool to see like, based
off our sort of node, just the branches
and like how that sort of like ripples, so
to speak, throughout the ecosystem, people
switching stuff, moving it around. I
couldn't find the block. I found some
article on Reddit, but they didn't give me
that.
Well, we'll come back to it. We'll throw
that up next episode. It sounds good.
Probably crash there. They can pull it up
20,000 times. And so what else we got? You
have a project in this ErgoHack. Tell me.
I actually know very little. I saw your
tweets, something about NFTs and swapping.
So no swapping. That was my last one. So
I'm calling it the Miner Rights Protocol.
So MRP for short. And so essentially the
idea is to, it's similar to kind of mining
in and of itself nowadays. And so in order
to mine at a given mine shaft, you have to
buy the rights if you don't own the land.
You have to buy the rights to be able to
mine that. And so the idea here is that
miners would then buy this token, buy the
rights to this token, and then the
protocol owner of this token can then set
up various mechanisms for emission. And so
call it MRP as the token, for right now
and say we have 10 million for a given
Ergo block maybe there's a hundred
thousand or I guess a thousand are
released and then we can then tie the
emission to the miner that found the block
on Ergo so then we can essentially
bootstrap the Ergo protocol on top of a
token and then we can then emit this token
through the mining system instead of an
IPO or ICO initial coin offering. And
then, so then this way, whoever has the
rights will then, in essence, sort of
restrict sort of, I guess, the difficulty
in some sense, right? Because if only five
people have it, it's going to be pretty
difficult to mine. But if the entire
ecosystem has it, then pretty easy. But
again, allow for the miners to control
rather than so so then yeah another idea I
guess kind of with that is you could mint
NFTs with this and let the miners mint the
NFTs sort of programmatically and so then
the given block that a miner found could
be then used within the algorithm that
generates the NFT to then make that NFT so
it's driven by the sort of parameters and
so in essence it helps with rug pulling in
some sense because you can't the only way
to rug pull this is no miners are running
it and so so it's based off the miners and
so I can make one but they could be like,
oh, well, this is stupid. I'm not going to
run this. Oh, but I like this other one.
Or the mining pool could do it. And then
the mining pool could facilitate it. So
it's basically putting the token emissions
back into, specifically for tokens, into
the miners' hands. And then they can sell
them to whoever they want. But also, we
can gamify this, kind of developing an
idea within the game to where miners
finding blocks is gamified and then if
they find a block something happens like
so for example maybe they have some
probability of finding some given reward
and then if they get it then they get that
token. I don't have anything. I have some
of this coded out, but kind of in short,
we set up the emission contract and miners
will then verify that they found a given
block. They will then run off chain bots
to then collect this UTXO because then is
now spendable for that miner. And then the
person who's running the bot will then get
a little bit for themselves. Again, based
off the protocol, you could maybe not
incentivize people to run bots. But why
would you do that? It would make sense.
Like, for example, if you're not a miner,
you maybe want to run a bot. So then you
could get a little bit of rewards for
giving a miner that given token because
they found the block and then you can kind
of facilitate it from there but of course
only mine it if you have that given rights
token and then the rights token can help
with I suppose the price because say you
have I don't know 10,000 rights tokens and
only one miner and one rights token is I
don't know one ERG and doesn't make sense
to have more than one, you know, then
you're kind of, and that's 10,000 ERG. So
then that could be sort of the market cap
for this given token initially. And so, I
don't know, so kind of playing around with
some of like the specifics, right. But
from a conceptual perspective, that's what
it is.
Dude, that's so sick. So I think maybe
previously there was something about like,
a specific mining pool. If you are in this
specific mining pool, then they can
distribute tokens to that pool. But yours
is not a pool, but it's whoever's holding
that token.
Right. Yeah, exactly. And then it has to
be a miner. Yeah. So just somebody,
anybody mining who has that token would
then be eligible to earn your tokens if
they find a block.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Exactly. And then
again, we can like build upon this. So
where it's like, say, you're not a miner,
but you want to like invest in my mining
company, right? Because so then you could
buy mining rights tokens for me and then
stake your mining tokens on my rigs or
something like that and then you get a cut
of my rewards when I find a block because
you can like maybe within the protocol the
more mining rights tokens you have that's
as a multiplier for how much is emitted
you know and so but then you can also,
that's true. Maybe in six months, the
general emissions are cut in half. You
know, so you could have halving, you can
have a logarithmic curve, you can have a
linear, you can do whatever you want. The
idea is really kind of sort of to kind of
create this putty and then we can stretch
it kind of however we want it to fit the
sort of space that we need. So it should
be pretty flexible in terms of what people
like. So I'm hoping to make an entire user
interface. So then if you wanted to make
this, you could do that. And then people
then just put in the proxy contract
address in terms of off chain bots, and
then they could just be on their way. And
then it would just kind of work together.
Sounds like you need somebody to create a
new project and wants to distribute some
tokens.
Yeah, right. Otherwise, I think I might
try to release the first one. But yeah,
it's going to be fun. And then if I create
it, right, I don't get any money from
this. Right. I mean, unless I put it in
the protocol fees, but people will be able
to see that. So it's not like people can
just create something and it's not obvious
a rug pull. You know what I mean? So it's
just a different way to make miners more
income potentially. Right. Cause it's up
to them if they want to buy the tokens or
not.
Yeah, I can imagine a lot of different
uses like one way or the other, you know,
yeah, but you have a good point. You know,
not everything needs a token. That was
something I read very early on in Ergo and
kushti was maybe criticizing Chainlink a
little bit, like, why do you have a token?
Like, you're an Oracle, you could use the
ETH of like, what's this for? You're
clearly just trying to get some money
here.
Totally, totally. So I think for this,
kind of on that sort of, like, yeah, I
guess, in some sense, yeah, definitely
don't need to, but I think from an
educational perspective, it's kind of cool
to see because then people are running off
chain bots, you know, and maybe people
aren't privy to what that is. And so, you
know, that's kind of a cool mechanism to
kind of explore. So maybe some
educational, but even what's really cool
in my mind is just bootstrapping the Ergo
protocol on top of this. So then, you
know, we're essentially kind of, it's not
a side chain. It's not like a layer two, I
guess, but it's, I don't know. It's like
a, it's like an in-between layer on Ergo,
I guess. And we're just essentially using
those tools and kind of creating our, and
now you have wrote this, I'm glad you
thought of it. So it's like a synthetic
GPU mining. So the miner rights are
essentially synthetic GPUs. You buy those
synthetic GPUs to be able to have the
access to mine this given token, just like
how Ergo is. Right? I'm buying a GPU and
that gives me the right to mine Ergo. So
pretty interesting. I think at least dude.
Yeah, that's a sick idea. Congrats.
Thanks. Yeah, we'll see what I'm curious
what other people think. So I'm super
pumped to get this developed and out the
door.
Right on, man. All right. Well, what
else? What else do you want to talk about
today? We've been going for about 30
something
Yeah, I mean, we can definitely, I'd say
so we talked a little bit about maybe some
standardization with UI, right? And maybe
why that's important. So I think kind of
pivoting back to that, we have the Ergo
improvement proposals. And that's, to me,
is kind of like the shows the topology of
the chain and sort of how it works, why we
do certain things. So why do we have proxy
contracts or why do we do certain things
like with Babel fees or. So if you haven't
looked up at the EIP, I'd say definitely
kind of take a look. You know, there's
there's artwork standards. There's I think
the most recent. I know that's not true,
but like there's a collection standard for
NFTs, you know, so maybe you've heard
that. So I know Cyberverse has its own
collection. For the NFTs and maybe you
thought well, why is that a thing? Well,
we can read on the Ergo improvement
proposal of why that was a thing There's
probably a problem that was looking to
solve right and this is the solution for
that. So I think it's kind of like for
lack of a better word it's like the Bill
of Rights of the chain in some sense of
like, you know of why we're doing certain
things a certain way I guess
Yeah, okay. That's super cool. So maybe
let me say it back. So an EIP is like an
agreement among the users of Ergo that
this is the way we're going to do
something specifically and it's like
limited to whatever the EIP says or is
like the topic that they're talking about.
And the purpose of that is to just make
sure that we're a little bit more
organized and can like kind of agree upon
like a procedure for this specific set of
actions like NFTs or whatever. We had
talked previously about the emission
reduction. That was one EIP that got
proposed and passed. Let's say I have an
idea for an EIP. How do I propose an EIP
and how does that get approved?
That's a great question. I know there's a
repo and I'm looking at it right now and I
think you essentially just put in a pull
request because there's a bunch of
different EIPs that are I guess being
voted on and I'm not sure who votes on
them. Maybe the miners vote on them. I'm
not really too sure. Maybe we can get
kushti on here and he can help us out with
that. I think he'd be a great person to
talk to on that. Yeah, because we have,
there's like 26 pull requests right now in
the EIP. And I know one of them, right, it
was written by qx() with like ephemeral
tokens. And so I think the general
generality of the idea is just kind of put
a good use case, kind of explain the
problem, right, and then why we kind of
need this sort of standardization. So
like, kind of going to an example here is,
would be EIP-5, so it's a contract
template. And so you might be able to see
in some of the ErgoHack submissions, a lot
of people are using this template to
facilitate the explanation of their given
contracts. And so, let's see, does it say
anything specific? So, I mean, it just
kind of tells you, right, just the given
formats or maybe this is the right one. In
any case, definitely worth checking out
and then even comparing to like Bitcoin's,
proposals and improvement proposals and
other things, and things like that.
Because again, I think it's important to
kind of take a look at and for a while I
didn't really, wasn't really aware of
this. And so, I mean, EIP-27 is the soft
fork, emission retargeting soft fork. So,
it's definitely, you know, something to be
with the ecosystem, right? So.
Yeah, yeah. I wonder, like, if some
things are voted on and others aren't, or
does everything need to be voted on by
miners? It's like, I kind of wonder, you
know, what's the scope of an EIP, you
know, like is an EIP always, cause it
sounds like the contract template. Like
that's not something that's in the core
protocol, you know, that's like something
people are just kind of agreeing on using.
So like, does that get voted on by miners?
Or is that just like, did we just talk
about it in GitHub? And everyone's like,
cool, right?
Yeah, you know, what's the consensus
mechanism, I guess, for accepting the
social layer? Yeah, I'm not too sure, to
be honest. So I would imagine for forking,
miners need to approve that. There's
probably a vote. But if there's no fork,
so EIP-6, Informal Smart Contract Protocol
Specification Format, that is the one I
was actually referring to. But that didn't
need a fork. maybe some of the core devs,
maybe from EF, that sort of thing, we're
like, hey, this is a really great way to
facilitate that and let's accept that and
then becomes an improvement proposal. So I
think the heart of it is, like you were
saying, it's not part of the core
protocol, but it's an improvement. And if
it makes sense to, I guess, the core devs,
and I think, it's always subject to
change, you know what I mean?
Maybe that's it right there. If it
requires a soft fork, it requires a vote
by miners. Right. I bet that's it. Oh,
look at us. We're learning.
But yeah, definitely it's interesting.
And so when I was writing some contracts,
I kind of stumbled upon this and I was
like, oh, I need to kind of pay attention
to this. And so if you're a new dev to the
ecosystem, I mean, a great place to start
to understand Ergo and the topology is for
sure the EIPs.
Yeah. And I think I think even not devs
should should kind of understand you know
just like know your assumptions you should
know a little bit you don't have to be
like super technical I don't think I'm
super technical but I'm like aware of
these decisions that are being made that
are going to affect my bag, you know, it's
like, yeah, you got to know, you got to
know. And if you don't know, it's your
fault, because it's all public.
Yeah. And then from a, you know, bag
perspective, like, maybe why should I
invest in this? What are they proposing in
the future to be an EIP? Maybe they have
something that's like, very critical, and
that could be really interesting. So like,
I know, right now, sub-blocks are kind of
on the hot topic right now. So I would
imagine there's probably an EIP kind of
coming up or in the works potentially for
that. There's one on storage rent, right?
So it's very interesting. Yeah, definitely
worth taking a look at and kind of diving
into just to kind of be more of a bull, I
suppose, for Ergo, because there's a lot
of stuff happening. And this is a great
way to see that, right?
So maybe I'll share this and we can talk
about it and then wrap up. I made this
yesterday, and your talk about EIPs and
all this stuff is in the GitHub, and it's
all right there. It's here for everyone to
see. And when I go through that exercise
of really understanding Ergo, I could just
kind of see where all these things are
just falling short. It's like, if anyone
who's in these anyone outside of Ergo is
listening to this and you're involved in
these projects like like take take a
second and look at what we got man like
it's just so clear how none of these
things are going to stand up like none of
these things stand up dude I actually saw
a tweet from somebody from Luna Classic
yesterday and I just I couldn't I couldn't
believe it like what are you doing what
what are you doing
Right. What did they, what did they say?
Oh, just like, I don't know, they were
just like, hyping it up. Like, are you
serious? Like, are you serious?
Yeah, I'd say, you know, it's hard to,
you know, be, I guess, unbiased,
especially if you got so much money. And
maybe that's the case for them. And I
think it's important to I mean, and that's
a great what you did there. It's a great
you know, exercise in validating your own
sort of ideas on Ergo, right? Because it's
like, well, is it the best or, you know,
is this a good idea? And, you know, we're
able to kind of run through those specific
other chains, kind of see where they fell,
you know, and it seems, right, Ergo is
kind of, you know, kind of this top dog in
the sense of its protocol and, you know,
everything it kind of stands for compared
to these other chains where they've in a
sense fell short, right? Because I'm sure
they had a, yeah, go ahead, sorry.
No, to your point, I think when you kind
of get married to a bag, you get in some
blind spots. And I was trying to be a
little bit funny with some of these. But
also, I don't know, maybe illuminate some
of these things like Litecoin. You're all
in on Litecoin. That's it. That's what
you're doing. And maybe a few people would
kind of just reflect and be like, oh, it's
been 15 years and maybe something is a
little bit better.
Right, absolutely. Yeah, especially from
a tech perspective, because it's just
like, you know, Litecoin is just a copy of
Bitcoin. There's not really anything
inherently special. So I guess with that,
you know, when do you think Ergo is going
to get a fork? And we'll start to see Ergo
get forked in the sense of like light Ergo
or like, you know, Doge Ergo, in a sense
of like, it's a copy of it, just like how
these other coins have, you know, do you
think that'll happen?
I'm sure Ergo will get forked. I mean, I
am surprised it didn't happen with the
mining reduction. Very easily could have
happened. Ethereum forked when they
started messing with their mining and got
rid of their mining. Totally. Yeah, it
wouldn't surprise me if there was some
update that a substantial amount of people
didn't agree to. But that's why we do soft
forks. Ergo kind of is committed to not
having hard forks because we recognize the
value of a coherent social layer where
we're kind of all on the same team. And if
the majority of us don't agree to
something, well, then we're not going to
do it. Totally. And I just appreciate
that. And honestly, I wish that our actual
government had some sort of function
where, like, if somebody makes a proposal
and 90% of the population votes for it,
that should be a law. Right. That should
just be a law. And I don't know. Maybe
that will happen sometime, but probably
not.
Yeah, I mean, I think it's a good
indicator in some sense of like, you know,
the ethos of the community that we haven't
had a hard fork for like Ergo Classic or
some shit like that, because it's like,
you know, we are true to our values. And
so because of that, we're still on the
same lane as we've always been versus like
something like Bitcoin. OK, we're going to
fork to Doge just to make a joke. Oh,
we're going to fork to Litecoin because,
you know, we'll be the silver or whatever
their original, you know, whatever it is,
you know, kind of going after money.
Right. They're doing it for the wrong
reasons. Bitcoin Cash, same thing. You
know, going after the money. Whereas, you
know, that's not necessarily the case
here. So people are kind of in it for the
core values, for the everyday people, kind
of that sort of thing. And that's kind of
cool to see. Hopefully, after this, we
don't see the hard forks take place. I
think it's a good sign from a community
perspective that that hasn't taken place
yet.
Yeah, 100%, man. Totally agree. I think
this might be a good place for us to wrap
it up. So thanks, Mark.
Yeah, thanks, Tim. Have a great time
everybody. See ya.