I'll take the blame if it is. Yeah, I
don't hear any sound on the YouTube. Let's
give it a second. Grayman entered, let's
allow Grayman in while Andy's fixing the
sound. Let me hit live here. Let's see.
Unmute. Yeah, yeah, we are here, we're
good, we're live. All right, back to - oh
no problem Andy, we're gonna flog you
after the show. All right, starting again.
Good morning everybody. Welcome to the
Ergo AMA. We have kushti, Benzel, and
Grayman with us this morning. You saw us
go through the visual of the Ergo update.
We hit it all, actually. There's three
updates this morning. So I'm sure you read
it exactly as we were saying it. You
probably read it in kushti's voice, right?
Actually, sorry. Yeah, hello everyone.
Because yeah, it seems greetings also
miss. So yeah, also yes, him is a game of
proms. So yeah, also. Oh, what do you see
that was down here? It's about for Lisa
sexually.
Oh nice. I haven't finished the contracts
in front in for game of proms yet. Just
sharing a tell you a few weeks ago.
Oh, yeah, so there is telegram group
where game of proms can be discussed and I
love it. It doesn't really have any use at
the moment, but if anyone's interested,
feel free to use it.
Nice Josephine, that's awesome. Yeah, and
back to Lithos as well. Guys, if you
haven't seen the videos, I split up all
seven or eight videos from the Ergo
meetup. I ran them through AI and got
summaries and bookmarks and all that kind
of goodness and put those in the
description of YouTube and I posted them
in a series in YouTube in a grouping so
you can go to that whole group. Joe starts
it off and then I think I didn't pay
attention to the order after that, but Joe
starts it off and then everybody else is
after that. But if you have a chance go
see the Lithos chat - that was a very
popular, very popular talk. Cheese always
does an amazing job breaking things down
simply so you can understand him. And he's
got that ASMR cheese voice, which is
fantastic.
So check that out. Also with Lithos I
believe they will need some test net
people firing up their rigs in November at
some point. So that's really exciting to
see that going. Amazing. All right, let's
kill the dev update here. What is the news
today, guys?
We've got some big news in the crypto
sphere, right, lately. And kushti's coined
a term for the season. kushti, what's your
term for the season?
So it's the rug season.
The rug season. Oh, man, you know, with I
think something the other week too I
forget what it was. Oh, Amazon, right?
Going down and this kind of stuff
happening. It really shows how important
real decentralization and peer to peer
networks are for resiliency, right?
Right. Yeah, but now we have like, so
yeah, this Amazon outage. Yeah, it's
showing well, kind of decentralization we
have, right.
Yeah, it's like Amazon's a canary in the
coal mine there, right? You don't know
who's attached to it until it actually
dies. Then you're like, oh, really? You
know, your entire back end was relying on
the centralized service, you know, kind of
thing. The only thing we noticed is the
same day one of our load balancers for
Cloudflare was banning one of our
redirects for the GraphQL. I don't know if
it was related or not, but it doesn't
matter. It's fixed momentarily with that.
But yeah, really, really telling, I'd say,
of the industry for those kind of hangups
there. And about Kadena, man, that's
absolutely bonkers, eh?
I think it's expected, actually, and we
should expect from all that. Actually, for
many years, well, over the span of many
years, it's now kind of standard, right?
When we have a blockchain, which is run by
a single company without community,
basically, or with fake community, right?
Which is basically existing only as
mercenaries right? So some I don't know
well projects which are only milking
grants around, then yeah paid shillers and
so on. But well, it's all working right
when the markets are fine, but well, if
they are not, then we see what we saw like
yesterday, right?
So, well, and we will see more of that.
So all those, well, company owns
blockchains, well, whether they will
transition to community control, but it's
very unlikely, right, so one control is
grabbed. There is a little chance to
become normal. And then the second option
is it would die probably. So, well, it
would be good to help the Kadena
community, but yeah, we're the first
place. We need to find their community,
right? So, I joined their group just like
yesterday. And yeah, well, I haven't seen
any seeds, you know, of community action.
So, for example, back in 2016, when we
had Ethereum, proof of work, proof of
stake. No, it wasn't. Yeah. So it was,
these, the DAO hack rights and yeah, chain
owners had chosen to roll back the chain,
right? After selling, the court is low.
And then, yeah, there was active community
disagreement, right? And that's how
Ethereum Classic got appeared. But then,
even, no, it was like a few days maybe
after Ethereum Classic was born. So me and
Charles Hoskinson, so we appeared on some
podcasts and defended the Ethereum
Classic.
So yeah, but back then it had just a few
supporters around the world. And yeah,
well, now it's doing quite well, more or
less, I believe, right? But yeah, back
then it wasn't quite clear whether it will
survive coming weeks or not. But yeah,
well, we got some traction around. Yeah,
well, these days it's much worse. So
basically we have all those companies
controlling blockchains and then crowds
running from one blockchain to another
while waiting for pumps, right? And then
usually they got scammed everywhere. Then
yeah, well, running away from the whole
space, claiming that crypto is scam. I
mean, of course it's scam if you are well,
chasing scams. So no, no, no, no surprise
here.
So, yeah, basically, no any community
action. I witnessed just some shilling.
Yeah, you're usually done by the same
company, blockchains, right? The shillers,
maybe paid shillers mostly. So that they
just shoot the same company block chains
in the Kadena group. And yeah, the
shilling was like just trust me, bro. So I
mean, well you're saying they're shilling
new block chains in the Kadena group that
you saw? Some existing some existing block
chains, but from what I've seen here on
only the same company owns rights. And
yeah, the shilling was basically like,
trust me, bro. So I mean, like, then our
team was bad, but our team is good. Trust
me bro, all that nonsense. I would be
surprised if anyone is buying that in
2025.
Yeah, you will be prepared to be
surprised, right? Once you're used to
those kind of things, trust me bro as part
of being part of a community to be part of
the exit liquidity or just be there to
bolster the price of a project. It's a
quite different experience than being part
of a community of something that you
believe in that's going to make a
difference and is fair in all those
matters. It's much harder, I would say, to
do what we're doing here with Ergo and
what you've done with Ergo over the many,
many years to build that community and
have that community stick around as
opposed to somebody that doesn't, and it's
centrally run, and decisions are always
coming from the top instead of, you know,
from the bottom up or the side out kind of
thing. So it really becomes apparent in
situations like these where, you know, the
top crinkles and dies, and then was there
ever a root system to actually sustain new
growth? So, I mean, that's a question,
yeah.
Yeah, so then what can we do here? I
think, well, if some community action
would be seen, so, well, what can we
propose is to switch from ASIC mining to
ASIC resistant, right? So basically,
Autolykos, and in this case, we would have
trustless pegging with Kadena, which would
be good for Kadena as well right. So now
it seems to be a smaller blockchain well
by market cap probably not only right
because well if the chain would survive
well so somehow something would then yeah,
well, it would be small, right? Because,
well, I mean, this company, Blockchains,
it seems, yeah, I mean, they're always
talking about good tech, good tech, but
when you know that the company is
disappearing, no one is interested in good
tech. And that's quite clear in this
Kadena case, right?
Yeah, there are 20 million market cap
right now, unfortunately for them. Yeah,
that's rough.
Yeah, so CannonQ told our telegram that
they raised 200 million, was it? Yeah, so
absolutely bonkers, where's that go?
Where's it? Where is that where to go
salaries?
Where is that where to go salaries? Maybe
next time in Las Vegas, you can do some
search around under the couch cushions at
the Bellagio by accident.
Yeah. Oh gosh, yeah, it's interesting.
You know you sit back and you think you
know, what would what would Ergo be right
now if the community was given money for
development funds beyond that kind of
thing that much at least? That'd be
absolutely insane. I think I think you
guys have quoted and Joe's quoted many
times that the number one expense in Ergo
has been exchange listings. Yeah, it's
like 70 percent maybe of all the time and
most of that's wasted, actually.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Done. Wasted. I mean,
even before, so from exchanges I got
listed back in 2019, only probate, I guess
still alive. So heartbeat disappeared.
Yep. And well for others I don't remember
their names even well so some were free
some not but yeah basically most of 2019
expenses just disappeared somewhere with
those well guys, let's say politely. Then,
yeah, well, other listings, yeah,
basically. So, yeah, the biggest article
and yeah, well, also our long period quite
useless after all, right? But well, we did
what was requested by community after all.
That's what I can say.
Yeah, a lot of community feel that that
kind of access is necessary. But honestly,
I think we're at a, not a crossroads, but
I think we're at a parallel intersection,
if that makes sense. I think still the
people who are interested in a project
like Ergo, fair launch, peer-to-peer,
decentralized, may be running parallel
with us because those people that are
actually interested pretty much should
know how to access us, right? I'd say the
people that are jumping on chain right now
for things like corporately centralized
projects through central exchanges, that's
maybe more their cup of tea. I think we're
still a bit away from the overall adoption
of, you know, slowly, slowly you can see
that kind of thing eroding, but it's
interesting.
You see, in my eyes, I see this corporate
structure of crypto, like half of Solana
going down when Amazon goes out. I see
things erode, right? You see these central
entities erode, but in the end it also
reveals those central entities that can
continue to sustain and stand up because
they have so much money pumped at them. So
instead of this large island of
centralized bullshit, now instead you have
maybe several pillars of huge tall
skyscrapers of these centralized
bullshits. And so there's less of them,
yeah, but there's still main strong ones
that are there and in your face. So it's
not like, I don't feel like, you know,
while we're losing these, you know, as it
goes along, which is great, it's the big
ones are still going to get taller and
taller. So it's not, we're always going to
have that to deal with, I believe, and
always fight against, in my opinion.
Everybody else asleep? Grayman? HQ?
Benzel? They're all great here. Here we
go.
He's awake. I am awake. I'm here. I love
the rents. I'm in agreement with with
everything that you've said so far. I got
into crypto late and fortunately landed in
Ergo via Cardano and the eloquent Mr.
Hoskinson.
Cardano is a gateway drug to Ergo. He
should make a t-shirt.
Well, so I think I managed to, you know,
Bitcoin, Cardano and, and Ergo, I think I
managed to avoid corporate scams, but
there's a phrase that I used to hear a lot
back in the day. I mean, we've been
talking about this shit for years. It's
not like this is a new thing. What was the
regulatory arbitrage? And essentially the
concept being that if you want to make a
bunch of money by being a scammer, you're
going to have to do that in a way that is
not regulated by the current system. And
so what do we have? We have Binance owning
effectively 70% of the transaction base of
the industry or something like that,
something way over 50%. And where are they
even based at this point? Like they've
hopped around.
I mean, the chair of the board, I guess,
CZ, spent some time in the US jail. I'm
not sure about all the details of that
stuff. I know he's free now, but it's just
a mess. I mean, this is anything but
decentralized, especially if you're
keeping your coins on their exchange. But
also in terms of the way that they control
the order book and the flow of
transactions, it's crazy that people think
of this as crypto and get excited about
it. And that's sort of like another
trading account, another exchange for
them. And it's their favorite one because
it's totally lawless. But then the end
result is that 95% of people get
completely rugged, especially the ones
that engage in any kind of leverage
trading, because somebody else is running
the train, and they say when it stops and
goes, not you, and it's not about
guessing, it's about them maximizing their
profit, and it's a corporation, guys, and
it's not a well-regulated corporation.
So to me, it's insane to watch all this
happen. I think it's going to get worse,
unfortunately.
Yes, such huge transfers of wealth
happening, you know, with these dips and
these shorts and everything. Absolutely
mind boggling how much money is
transferring to more wealthy people here.
Yep. So I don't know if there's really
much more to say than that. I feel blessed
that I never really got involved in that
part of the so-called industry. I mean, to
me, it literally is just a scam. It makes
no sense. I mean, they do sell Bitcoin and
they do sell Cardano, and that's great.
But that's fine. If 99% of what they sell
are tokens that they extract hundreds of
thousands of dollars from the community
and team and then get a bunch of tokens
and then as soon as they get listed they
dunk on them and they drop off I mean,
it's like a vampire. I can't believe
anybody participates in this but there you
go. Like they say the path is littered
with bodies.
So Ergo is walking a different path. We
aren't even like, I mean, I think that at
one point there was a negotiated position
with Binance US and the Ergo Foundation,
which at the time was maybe, let's just
say more well endowed entity than it is
now as time has passed. They voted it
down, wisely so in retrospect. And we
never really had that much money in the
till as a community because I think the
Ergo Foundation was founded after the
chain got started and funded by less than
5%, more than 4%, but less than 5% of the
coins as they were mined. And so initially
that led to a lot of ERG but not worth a
lot of dollars, and so there was never
really an opportunity for Ergo to play in
that space unless some whale decided that
they just wanted to underwrite it. And
surprise, surprise, none of them did,
because they recognize that that whole
game is rigged and that it doesn't make
any sense to play it to just hand your
money to somebody that's going to come and
insist that you give them more to keep
playing. It's worse than a casino.
So I don't know what else to say. I feel
bad for everybody that got hurt by that.
But at the same time, you know, some of
those people just need to get washed out.
They're not here for the right reasons. To
the extent that we see some of that in the
Ergo forums, I just sort of shrug and
it's, it's, I mean, I'm sure there are
some people that look at whatever I post
as being painful to read through or, or a
skip over.
Oh, it's just painful to listen to you
talk, Grayman, even for me, you know, I'm
just kidding. Love hearing you talk, sir.
I don't know. I don't know what to say.
It's, it's hard to, it's hard to see.
It's, it is people saw complaining about
it.
I just I can't I can't really even
understand their motivations. So they get
sold this, you know, put your money in and
you'll get 20% 30% 40% rich. I mean when
you go to a central exchange and they're
advertising to hold a stable coin and get
like 10% returns or whatever that bullshit
is. I mean in a normal person's head that
would like, how is this sustainable?
What's going on here? So they're roped in
by these kind of things of absolutely
ridiculous returns, and then this kind of
stuff can't be sustainable. The liquidity
providers, and when I say liquidity
providers, I mean the fools in their
money, dry out.
Yeah. I mean, to be fair, I also, when I
first started trying to learn about all
this stuff, I was also led to these
exchanges and whatnot. All of the talk of
here's where you go to get this and
whatnot. And it just seemed like it was
such a broad and crazy space that the only
way to get involved was to just grab some
close by piece and start doing stuff. But
it was pretty quickly, pretty easy to
figure out that this is crazy town, like
this is worse than a casino, and I have no
interest in doing that. I could just play
the stock market.
I mean, I guess a lot of the way that I
think about it might be privileged by
being an American, especially an older
American towards the end of my career, or
last third, let's say. So I have a little
bit of time and money and wisdom and I can
see you know, what's obvious bullshit. I
think a lot of the people that get trapped
are people that were just out of college
and you know, they're just trying to get
out in the world and swim and somebody's
got a good comment in chat.
That's related to this. Mobius says fuck
profit, can't think like that. And I think
that's the problem, right? I think people
need to be able to understand that there
are many profit opportunities in Ergo.
Many. There's SigmaFi, there's arbitrage,
there's SigmaUSD Bank. There's a lot of
profit opportunities in Ergo. There's
MuShop, you know, for physical goods for
profiting off that. A lot of profits,
okay? And that's a sustainable profit.
That's a profit that actually can sustain
itself. What we're talking about here is
obvious scam profits where it's a pyramid
scheme where the idea is you make a profit
because somebody else is there to lose a
lot, right? That's the difference that
we're speaking about here. Profit is fine.
Nobody should shame anybody about profit,
right? And there's plenty of opportunities
in Ergo to do so. There's a huge
difference between that and what you're
seeing at central casino exchanges. Huge
difference, Mobius.
Yeah, but profit that's made from a hype
machine is just at the expense of the
losers. Yeah, exactly. And it's not going
to be sustainable. So it doesn't make any
sense. Yeah, you have to build slowly but
surely tools that can be used and
eventually the exponential turns the
corner and starts being faster than you
can even get ready for and eventually
becomes an asset.
You can't build a foundation on balloons.
One of them pops, you're done.
Yeah, so Ergo has been slow and steady.
It's getting better and better. It's sort
of the Kaizen mentality. Every we just
got, you know, node six has just come out
already starting to think about the
repercussions of that and how to turn it
into sub blocks and getting back into
finance online. There's a lot of stuff
that's cooking and it didn't start cooking
yesterday, right? It's been going for a
while, consistently working on building
and making it better as a tool, not as a
toy or as a fad. And that feels like what
all of this pumped out fun shit is. It's
just let's try and make a fad.
It's like Ergo is perpetual soup,
Grayman. It's always been cooking for a
long time and you come back a year later
and it might taste different, but it's
been cooking the entire time.
Right, yep.
Yeah, HQ's got a question in chat. A good
question, actually. A good for HQ, that's
for sure. Question, what would be the
outcome when EF publishes similar
announcements as Kadena, as they are
running out of funds, etc. Should we be
sharing on socials why EF actually isn't
behind the core Devon, etc. ETC nowhere to
go. I think we've been preaching that as
often as we can, HQ. I think everybody out
here on the AMAs has made it very clear
that EF's overall goal was - kushti's
gonna jump in with this. I said EF. EF's
overall goal is to fade into some other
part of existence. You know, their goal
was to bootstrap in that sense. Sorry, go
for it kushti.
Yeah, so well as a guy who actually
founded EF, I'm finding all those talks
strange. So it seems well at some point
well the EF got perceived as a kind of
main entity, maybe establishing entity.
But actually it was established a month
after the main at launch. It was November
or December 2019. And yeah, to that
moment, well, Ergo was listed on like five
or six exchanges, right? So, well, the
development went well without EF and so
on, right? So, well, I mean, things were
made without the EF for starters, right?
So for many months and yeah, well, then
basically since 2022, I believe, so Joe
and me and others, I believe also, well,
pushing the idea that EF is well, by
definition is not around for forever,
probably right. I mean, no one knows,
maybe it can find some ways to exist
forever. But to the best of my knowledge,
that there is no any human made
organization, which lived forever. Right.
Even to survive for like 20 years for a
foundation or a commercial company is
already quite exceptional. I know such
corporations, companies, but we simply
don't know. Thousands disappeared, right?
So, well...
I think kushti, I think you should...
They've handed off a lot of their
important duties already to the SIGs and
to the Infradow, and there's still more
that they retain, but those could be
handed off as well. I mean, one that's
really stand out for me is ErgoDocs is
just spectacular and updated and it's very
in depth and it's going to be sad to see
that sort of official duty of the EF
disappear along with everything else when
that time comes. But presumably the
community will pick it up and maintain it.
We just need to get to that point. There's
also the website, which I think is quite
good as is, but apparently there's a new
one coming at some point and that's great.
But, you know, that's also something that
in the future, I mean, what's Bitcoin.com?
It's whoever owns that domain. We're going
to have to move past the idea that that
like, what's the website for Linux? I
mean, it just, you know, there's something
that just needs to go away.
Get some onion links for the Ergo hosted
website. That'd be great.
Makes a little too exclusive for the
website. So another one is coming. Well,
it's coming. Yeah. For many, many months,
but they can't push because it's just
volunteer some volunteer. Yeah, well not
paid by any party and well, I've seen some
drafts a few months ago and recently, I've
got a message that it's basically ready.
So wow, I can check it in days and and
then, yeah, let's see when it will be
launched. But it would be different from
EFs. And I think it's also good, right?
It's OK for diverse.
We could actually launch that directly on
infra for now, if we want to, at least for
the, you know, just launch straight to
that. And then you can live side by side
for a minute and we can make sure it works
and go from there.
That would be interesting. And yeah, so
that's another website is more sci-fi
punk-ish. And yeah, well, it's made to the
guys' preferences. And yeah, no one can
judge here.
I do hold .erg. And if we guys want to
release something .erg, so maybe we can do
platform.erg and release that on there.
You bought the entire endpoint there the
entire what's it called? How much was
that?
It was gifted from from handshakes. Yes.
Oh you bought the handshake. Yeah, I got
you. Okay. I was gonna say cuz dot Ergs
gotta be some country in Europe or
something, right? Yeah. Let's see, .erg
is, I don't know. I don't know. But I was
back to community guys, when you're
talking, I feel like, I feel like, a good
community in, like Ergo is, should be,
yeah, HQ3rr is going to start a country. A
good community is, like the ship of
Theseus. You guys familiar with that?
So that's a thought experiment that says
if you have a ship, a wooden ship, right?
You guys, we'll save for everybody online.
If you have a wooden ship and over
hundreds of years you replace every single
board, you know, one at a time or every so
often, and after many, many years the ship
is totally different boards. There are no
original boards in the ship or sails or
anything. Is at the same ship, right? And
I think a lot of people say, yeah, it's
the same ship, right? So I feel like a
good community is like the ship of
Theseus, right? You have, you know, the
community back in the day, it's still the
Ergo community, the community in the
future is still the Ergo community, but
it's changed so much, might not even be
same members, right? But the mission
remains the same, the experiences, the
experience, the historical knowledge base
remains the same. All that kind of stuff
moves with the community as it comes
along. So I think that's an indicator of a
good project that has something like this,
not something that's just a captain that
runs around on whatever ship has the
biggest sail. And then if the ship sinks,
he's like, fuck off, I've got my treasure
chest, goodbye. And then it goes down for
good. Whereas this kind of community is
very resilient.
I wanted to add to that prior question of
how would that situation be perceived by
the community? I think it would be
celebrated even from the tone of the
organization themselves releasing it,
wouldn't be in the tone of how Kadena
released it. The EF will be glad to say,
hey, this has already been the plan. So to
answer the question directly, I think it
would be a good thing, a good sign for
that announcement in our community versus
how it was accepted in the other one.
I think you're right, Benzel. I think
you're right, because we saw this already
pre-played out with Joe leaving the EF,
with kushti leaving the EF. It was like,
oh, you know, this is expected. This is
what's happening. It's like kids going off
to college. It was a sad day, though.
Yeah, it's sad, but it's like, oh, this is
what's supposed to happen. This is
evolution of what's supposed to happen. I
love your sweatshirt. Did you get that at
the meetup, sir?
This is my physical airdrop. This is how
I got the claims of free stuff right here.
This is my airdrop. All right. Did you
get a hat?
This is the only free airdrops we do is
physical in person.
Did you bring a hat back with you from
Colorado?
Oh, I didn't. I think Chris got them all,
so I might have to ask him to ship me one.
Chris took them all?
No, no, no. He grabbed them because they
were left there. I guess they could have
been in that church for a bit.
I think he posted on socials like, I
don't know how, but I have got these. So
maybe he was drunk and he took all of
them. I got a shirt too.
Oh, the mining shirt. That's awesome.
Fantastic. I'm wearing my sweatshirt that
I stole from Joe at Vegas a couple of
years ago.
He was supposed to give me his Rosen
Bridge sweatshirt, but it's the only one
he has so I didn't want it. But he still
have to steal it like you have to steal
it. I can't take the only one you have I
feel bad.
That's what he does. That's Joe's MO.
He'll bring something leave it on a chair
and expect somebody to take it. You know
take as much control over Joe's
merchandise as you can. I think it's the
same. You know, I still haven't washed
this in two years. It still smells like
Joe.
It's perfect. You know this disc that's
awesome.
Old-school cool.
What's that?
Old-school cool like steal this disc.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yep. Yep. Those are
the days, right?
No, overall I'd say my sentiment towards
Ergo always remains the same, right?
There's no external factors that make me
think, oh, you know, I'm worried for the
future of Ergo. It's all that, yep, this
is like watching a play play out that we
know the ending to. This is exactly what
we expected to happen to this centralized
entity, you know, and here we are just
trucking along. Sorry, Grayman, go for it.
But that sounds like a godlike
perspective. I'm just in the soup. I don't
know how it's going to end, but it gets
better and better for me. So I know we're
going in the right direction. I mean,
there could be a wave that goes and
smashes the entire thing apart. But I
doubt it, I think there will be a wave
that'll smash almost the entire industry
apart at some point, sooner or later. I
mean, if nothing else, a decade from now
when Bitcoin's halving takes it to the
point where there's no security budget
anymore, that's going to be a hell of a
wave. And when that happens, it's going to
be a question of who can survive that
tragedy. And I think that we're aiming in
the right direction.
I mean, if you say fuck Binance, sorry,
bleep that out. But if you say that you
don't want to deal with Binance or any of
these other extractive exchanges, well, we
have ways to deal with that. We have Rosen
Bridge. We have very soon we have Machina
Finance, which will make it so that we
have long chain liquidity that's
constantly running and that can be done
with Rosen bridged assets. And so to be
fair liquidity bootstrapping is always a
problem and one of the biggest complaints
about a smaller blockchain or community.
But there's something where you can
literally put your money where your mouth
is and allocate a portion of your holdings
to trading and liquidity according to a
robot that you set up to do it. And you
can rest assured that it's still going to
be self custody within your wallet and
that you have ultimate control over the
whole thing without dealing with Binance,
you know what now, right? It's there. The
ball's gonna be in their court in the long
run when that wave crashes and destroys a
lot of stuff. Hopefully it destroys them
too but we got to have a way for people to
interact and I think we've got it and I
think we lead the industry in that sense.
There are other tools on other systems
that are close to this, but not the same.
I think Ergo is extremely well positioned
for the rug season. For starters, is
Binance now available in the US?
I don't know. I don't touch that.
It's a Binance US domain that the
government kind of made them give up
ownership of that.
Yeah, it's different things though,
right? It's quite a bit limited compared
to the other Binance, if I recall
correctly.
Separate, but probably run by the same
crowd of crooks and so therefore not so
separate.
But the Binance Smart Chain is the bridge
between the two, I believe.
Well, anyway, probably it's worth to
consider to withdraw from it, especially
in the US, because I think at some point
we may see maybe the second term or
another crackdown. Well, because, yeah, it
seems now, well, crypto Twitter are full
of accusations, right, towards Binance,
hard to say. Well, well, so some are
definitely real, because, well, the
exchange is scammy, as well as its owner,
right, and people around. Well, but, yeah,
well, as usually in such things, well,
maybe it's kind of preparation, right, for
some actions also. Hard to say at this
point, we'll see. But yeah, it's better to
stay away from all CSAT related. So it's
actually much worse than Kadena and so on.
All his assets, like DEX tokens and so on.
They are not even pretending to be proof
of work like Kadena and so on, just some
tokens printed by the guy to his own
pockets then yeah well partly distributed
but yeah for BNB still more than 70
percent in his pockets so he is simply
controlling the market and the...
Well, another thing is, well, why I'm
thinking about rug season. So many people
in this crypto space did await for all
season, right? Well, and they provided
some probably valid arguments that markets
are cyclical and so on. Right, and I
think, yeah, those arguments are
convincing, but only in the presence of
markets, right, so more or less free
markets. So in the case of, well, markets
like we had in 2013, 2017, so mostly proof
of work cryptocurrencies, well, mostly.
Well, also proof of stake cryptocurrencies
distributed through ICOs, right? So, well,
quite well distributed after all, in
comparison with today's nonsense, like
oligarchs tokens. So, yeah, well, if
markets would be similar, then, yeah,
maybe we would care for all season. But
with tokens, which are dominating in the
market now, we simply don't care for
markets, right? So, well, it's not markets
when supply is basically controlled and
can be changed for free at any moment. The
owner of a token can just send a portion
to an exchange and liquidate everyone. In
this environment we don't have markets, so
it's quite about manipulations,
multi-level manipulations. Instead of alt
season, we have rug season, so it's not
cyclical markets behavior. It's not about
markets after all this crypto space at
this point. So we need for all these dots
to be washed out somehow and that's what
we are starting to see maybe.
Yeah, I think too, going off what you
just said, kushti, I think people also
flock to familiar, right? So that's
exactly how the fiat world works, right?
You know, it's always them against the top
against retail, right? And cryptocurrency
was supposed to, and is supposed to, and
what Ergo is doing, is balancing that out,
right? It's making it so that it becomes
apparent who is the person that holds most
of the things and can just manipulate as
they like. So, you know Ergo follows that
but a lot of other chains do not and just
mimic what they see in the fiat world. So
when people flock they are looking for
somebody to be a leader. They're looking
for some organization to own something so
they can feel safe. When in reality there
were never even safe in the fiat world
when that happens, right? It's a classic
example of the walrus and the oysters,
right? You know, you're led to a table for
dinner.
This would be a good time to plug Joe's
talk on the Meetup.
Yes, great. Go for it, Grayman. You plug
it.
I mean, you're basically just stating
what a third of the talk was about, was
that, you know, we just need to not look
for leaders, but look for solutions. Yeah.
And, you know, that's, it's worth
watching. All the talks are worth
watching. That Meetup was a spectacular
event for me. I haven't worked my way
through all of them, but I did rewatch
Joe's and it stands up everything about
it's perfect. It was off the cuff and
spoke from the heart and it anticipated
what we're witnessing happen right now.
So, you know, I don't want to gloat and
watch all these people suffer from the
market falling apart. I hope nobody takes
it that way. But yeah, I mean it seems
inevitable to me. So on that level, I hope
people get out before they get hurt and
find a safe place to be and that could be
Ergo. I hope it is but it could be
whatever land precious metals, you know,
whatever you can do to secure your your
your future and your you know your your
treasure is worth doing because sticking
around in the crypto system where people
can rug you at any moment is not a good
place to be so?
Yeah, I would say don't look for leaders.
Don't seek out leaders in this space. Seek
out, lead yourself and seek out peers,
right? You know, I mean, it's perfect if
you want to, you know, like, it's amazing
to be like, Joe's amazing, kushti's
amazing, Grayman's amazing, it's great to
hear them talk. And that's great. But, you
know, like, we could have somebody that
fucks up big time, right? Like, let's take
Cardano and Charles Hoskinson. What if
something is revealed that's absolutely
awful? Right? There goes the chain. Done.
Right? There's a whole leader of the chain
it's looking at. Right? And whether that's
due to the community looking to Charles to
lead or Charles not letting go, you know,
fully, I don't know. But that's dangerous.
Right? So trust yourself. Lead yourself
and seek out peers. It's 10 o'clock.
I got to go, boys.
Yeah, there we go. Hold on, everybody.
We've got to roll out the outro. We all
need you. Hi, everybody. Good morning.
All right, everybody. Let's say some talk
for next week. Amazing for everybody to
join us. We had Benzel, kushti, Grayman,
hq3rr, and meta. Sorry, go for it kushti.
What are you gonna say? Benzel?
Yeah, so as always let's continue our the
text chat. So Grayman I will jump on chain
cache basis chat a bit later with silver
sense and so on. Then yeah, let's continue
to discuss. So if we can find something
like a Kadena community, then yeah, let's
try to organize space with them. But yeah,
we still need to find community. So they
have a group of 35,000 people, but I
haven't found any community there. Tourist
base? Yeah, so we can do Twitter space
once they somehow self-organize to discuss
what to do with development and so on,
right? So we may offer them to switch to
ASIC resistant proof of work and so on,
right? So to do some crisis management
and... So, but see also in regards with
community organization, we can share a lot
of experience, right, because we have a
lot of experience got our the six years.
But well, there are a lot of companies
that own blockchains around and we need to
educate the users before the blockchains
get collapsed.
I have a question. Why not set up example
and just bring them, adopt them to the
Rosen Bridge and bring the whole chain and
use the wrapped assets on Ergo instead of
giving them another solution to adopt to
it, how to like us and that.
So what's the community there? It's a six
community miners, right? What are they
going to do on Ergo? Sell their ASIC for
GPUs? What community is that? I guess,
yeah, yeah, good. Where's Joe? Get that
shit together, Joe.
Yeah, because we have, we already have
and we need a test. We need to test it
with something. And if we have opportunity
to show someone that they can do it here.
So if it happened today with Kadena,
tomorrow it will happen with another
chain, which are run by VCs or they are
run by companies. So they have a pathway
to join and go and see how they can have a
more decentralized and everything more
controlled. how to do it and we will learn
how to run the sidechains also.
Yeah actually a good idea right so well
if for some reason well usually for having
big losses and well inability to fix them
so someone is still a stick to a company
owned blockchain right so we may offer
well, just to try Ergo for starters as a
plan B, right? Because, yeah, well,
inevitably, any company like 99% will go
bankrupt, right? And then, yeah,
blockchains associated with them will be
collapsed as well. So, I don't know,
what's the statistic for commercial
companies outside crypto? I think in 10
years, like 99% of companies.
It's big, yeah.
Yeah, and I think in crypto it should be
even more, right, because this space is
crazy.
Well, plus, in crypto it's global, right?
In crypto, it's global. So, you know, it's
not like a small company in Arkansas that
jumps up is going to have an effect on
somebody in China, right? So, but in
crypto, you could start up a chain and
it's immediately 100% global right off the
bat. So yeah, I agree, kushti. It's more
than 99%.
It's also global on Amazon, maybe. Yeah,
it's not just geographic distribution,
though. It's also distribution of
applications and industries that we can
support. So we are a platform, not a
company. It's a cathedral. It's a place
where many different types can come to
worship and participate in our little
religion that we're growing here. It's a
cathedral, and we need to think of it like
that, something that's going to last for
hundreds of years. Mistakes will be made,
but they'll get ironed out before hundreds
of years, something's for sure.
Plant a tree so your children can sit in
the shade, right?
Yeah, exactly. So I think, yeah, it
should be promoted as kind of a cathedral
or Unix, right? Because well, Unix at some
point also adopted this cathedral
methodology, right? So just to build in a
composable way. So we are composing simple
tools, right? Something impressive, our
decades, maybe centuries to come.
Guys, that's a good place to end it. I
really have to go. So great talking to
everybody here today. kushti, do you want
to end it?
Thank you. Bye. So let's continue. Yeah.
Continuing checks to everybody. We'll see
you next week. Same time. Thanks so much
everybody. Bye bye.