Hi, everyone.
Thanks for joining.
Today we will explore Game of Proms, or
GOP.
The main idea is summarized by our
slogan, AI challenges, blockchain
solutions.
GOP is a new platform designed to help AI
development become more open and
collaborative.
It's built on top of two technologies,
Celaut, that is a system ensuring that
services are unchangeable, immutable, and
run in a safe, separate, isolated spaces,
which is vital for fair and trustworthy
competitions.
and the Ergo blockchain, which provides a
transparent system for rewards and
verifying results when training and
testing AI models.
Celaut can also be used to execute
services in a distributed manner, where
the interaction of processes is occurring
in Ergo, but this property is not relevant
here in GOP.
So today we use AI more and more, but its
development is often centralized.
This can limit broad participation, make
it hard to see how things work, and hinder
collaborative efforts.
How can this be improved?
How can more people globally contribute
to solving complex AI problems and
building better AI?
These are the motivations behind Game of
Proms.
So the main idea is to make AI
development more like an open competitive
sport.
The system runs as follows.
First, creators can define specific AI
problems or challenges as game services.
For example, a creator could design an AI
challenge for the game Snake.
And the game's service will be the snake
game itself, its rules, and how it
measures the AI's score, like the snake
length.
These game services provide the
environment, any necessary data, and
clear, objective ways to measure AI
performance.
Then a global community of developers and
AI enthusiasts can then create and submit
their solver services for the Snake
example.
This would be their AI designed to play
Snake.
So these solver services run inside the
game service.
Celaut ensures that this happens in a way
that is safe and isolated, protecting both
the game and the solver.
We will see this later in the demo.
And finally, the scores, performance
data, and prize distributions are all
managed transparently and fairly on the
Ergo blockchain.
So GOP aims to get more diverse solutions
by opening up challenges to everyone.
It makes building and testing AI models
more distributed, transparent and
accessible.
So this platform isn't just about simple
games.
It's about building a framework to
improve AI collaboratively with incentives
for innovation.
Let's look at the key components.
So first, the game service.
Think of this as the AI benchmark or the
controller test environment.
It's a Celaut service.
This means it's packaged so it cannot be
changed.
It's immutable once it's defined by the
creator.
and it runs in its own safe, separate
space, so it's isolated.
This is vital so everyone can trust the
test environment and its fate exactly how
the creator specified it.
And it defines the problem that provides
the context and includes the logic to
evaluate any submitted AI model, any
solution.
Probably it will be executed by the
participants on its own local nodes.
And it's capable to do that.
Second, the solver service.
This is the model or algorithm created by
a participant.
It's also a service.
So it's also immutable and runs in
isolation.
This ensures the game service can trust
the solver hasn't been tampered with.
And the solver is protected from
excessive interference during the
execution.
It's their proposed solution ready for
evaluation.
Then the GopWeb portal.
This acts as the central hub.
Creators can publish their AI challenges
here, and developers can find these
challenges to download game services and
later submit their results for on-chain
validation.
And it can be as a local service or not.
And finally, the Ergo blockchain.
This serves as the highly secure and
transparent ledger.
It's used for registering AI challenges,
tracking participation, cryptographically
validating AI model performance, and
distributing the rewards fairly.
This structure, particularly with Celaut
immutability and isolation, ensures a
trusted execution environment, allowing
complex AI tasks to be broken down into
verifiable and competitive challenges.
OK, so let's see what creators and
players do.
A creator who designs an AI challenge.
First, they design the game or a test.
It needs a score that can be measured.
It's also very important that the game
has a variety or changes each time it's
played.
This stops players from just finding one
fixed answer for a game that never
changes.
Then they generate a unique secret code
for their game.
This code is a key for securely verifying
scores on the blockchain later.
Then they package their game as a service
with the inside, with the secret inside,
make the service unchangeable.
And finally, they publish it, they
publish the service.
This involves creating a game box on the
Ergo blockchain, which stores hash of
their secret code, the competition
deadline, the participation fee, and the
game service hash and other parameters.
And on the player side, the player is who
builds an AI solution for that challenge,
for that game.
So the player first finds a game or
challenge on the GOP web portal and
downloads the selected game service.
The download can be done across the
Celaut node if it's available in some
peers or in a centralized repository like
Mega or Google Drive or something.
Then they can design their solver service
their AI model or strategy.
package the solution as an unchangeable
Celaut service.
Then they run the game service with a
solver on their own Celaut node.
Because they are Celaut services, they
run in their own separate safe spaces,
ensuring a fair test.
When it finishes, they get their
performance data, a cryptographic
commitment, a list of scores, the real
score is hidden among these, and a hash of
the game logs.
And if they are satisfied with their AI's
performance, with the score, they submit
their entry to compete into the
blockchain.
They do this by creating a participation
box on the Ergo blockchain and paying the
entry fee.
Now how are scores kept secret during the
competition but still proven to be correct
and fair at the end.
This is done using these commitments on
Ergo.
So let's explain it.
First, when a player tests
the game locally, the game service, which
knows the game secret, the game secret is
inside of the game service, generates a
commitment.
This commitment is a special hash code,
like a digital fingerprint.
It's made from the solver ID, the real
score, the log hash,
the game record code and a secret game.
The player submits this commitment and a
score list, the real score plus some
decoys.
to the blockchain, we use a list of
scores because publishing the exact score
directly could discourage later players
from submitting their own items unless
they were certain they could beat all the
current scores on the blockchain.
With this way, their actual score isn't
public yet, but it's on the blockchain.
So after the game's deadline, the creator
reveals the secret code.
And then the Ergo smart contract, the
script on the game box, does the
verification for every participant.
It uses a valid secret, their solver ID,
their log hash, and tries each score in
their score list to calculate the
commitment.
If this commitment matches the real
committed commitment in the participation
box, the player originally submitted, that
score is confirmed as the true and
validated score for that AI model, for
that solver.
Then the contract automatically
identifies the participation with the
highest validated score and that player
wins.
This entire process is transparent,
verifiable by anyone and enforced by the
blockchain code.
Okay, enough talk.
Let's see how the system works.
So first of all, we need to install the
Celaut node.
So let's go to the node github page.
It's an alpha version, so this is
important.
It's actually an alpha version, it's
recommended to use a virtual machine.
I'm not going to use a virtual machine,
but it's recommended.
So first we install this.
OK, so the node is installed.
Let's check info.
OK, the key up.
Yes.
And we can see this is the address of
this node, the conversion.
And it's connected to an Ergo node.
was created two wallets, two Ergo
wallets.
You can check how it works on the node
documentation, but actually it's data
doesn't have ERGs.
But this is not important for Game of
Proms.
So first of all, we need to implement our
game service.
We have implemented it, but it's
It's in games.
This is our folder with the game service.
So it contains all the logic to make the
score, commits, and all of this to manage
the solvers.
So inside of the code, this is the secret
that we should previously generate
So we are going to use this secret to
submit the game service.
First of all, we need to pack it into a
service.
So for that, we need to do node pack.
And wait, because this could take like 20
minutes maybe.
So I'm going to break the video here.
Okay, so the service game package process
is finished.
So we have the service on our Celaut
node.
We can check it with this command or we
can inspect it.
this other command.
Here we see all the information about
this service, the metadata that these
hashes, the hash of the service, the hash
of all of this content, and the reputation
proofs of the service that are
on Ergo, but this currently doesn't have
anyone.
And here we see that the service can't
connect to outside sources.
So it can't submit information to other
servers or something.
So it's for privacy or things like that.
So now let's, as game creators, we are
going to... We are going to submit our
game to the Ergo blockchain.
So we will need...
Okay, well, this is not the browser, is
this?
Perfect.
Okay, so here we see the games and we are
going to create a new game.
Snake demo video.
The game service is this.
We should add the type of the hash, maybe
here.
And our game secret that is in the code,
internally in the game service.
So the participants can't see it because
it's obfuscated.
Actually, it's not obfuscated, but it
should be.
participation fee, we are going to put
the minimum and two hours maybe.
The game creator will receive 20% of the
total amount that is accumulated in the
contract.
We can put a link and snake
and use an image and this should be like
the URL where the user can download the
service game if his Celaut node can't take
it from other peers.
So create a game.
Okay, sign the transaction.
OK, so the transaction is done.
So here we have the game.
This is the time to the deadline.
And I can submit my score.
This is the same wallet that created the
game, but could work too.
So here we have the NFT of the game, the
token that identifies the game, me, the
creator.
This is the service game, the game
service.
A link with more information, the
participation fee, the creator commission,
the stake that the creator puts on the
contract to ensure that he will resolve it
at the end after the deadline.
And some URLs, a list of URLs that a
participant could use.
to get a game service if the Celaut
network can't provide it.
Because maybe it doesn't have any peers
with this service.
This could be a centralized service
provider or like Mega or Google Drive or
something, or IPFS or other centralized
solution.
So let's play now the role of
the role of developers.
So now, as developers, we want to
participate in this game.
So we need to implement our solution that
is here.
There are two solvers, but actually we
are going to use the basic solver that is
a very basic AI algorithm with A-star.
It's very short.
So the other one, it's a language model
solver that creates a prompt to control
the snake.
But we are going to pack this.
So for this, we need to do the same.
And this could take 20 minutes too, maybe
less, but we need to wait.
Well, our basic AI snake, our robot to
play snake, it's packed, actually.
here, you can see.
So pack means that we transform from the
source code to a service, OK, specifying
the Dockerfile to create all the file
system, specifying the interface of the
service,
and these things.
You can read more about it on the Celaut
Project repositories.
So now we need to play the Snake game.
we need to execute locally or in one of
our peers, the snake game.
We have it actually on our node, but if
we downloaded it from a mirror URLs, we
should make this command import, like for
example, snake game, that would be,
and it should be imported to the node
repository.
Well, the node registry of service.
So actually we have one peer, I think,
that it's running in another computer of
my local network.
So we don't have ads.
This is the information of this node.
I'm talking very much about this, but
each node has its own Ergo wallet.
So they transfer ERG one to each other
for rent gas, where gas is the
representation of resources of a node.
But yes, actually, they give to each peer
a default amount of gas free.
So they don't need to transfer ERG.
Okay, so let's execute the service game.
So here, the node has decided to run the
execute the snake's game on the other
peer, but if this peer doesn't have the
snake game service, so it will take from
this node then, but it's running on our
computer.
We can read it here.
This is the instance ID.
The service is the snake game.
And the parent is the client that
represents all the execution from the
terminal.
And the gas that has this instance.
So we can access to this.
So the Snake game, it's hosting a simple
webpage to control it.
That allows you to play games, to play
participations with your solvers, and to
reproduce
solvers from other participants.
If they share their solver logs of the
game and seed, game seed to allow
deterministic reproduction.
So we need to get our solver with a
Celaut service extension.
So we need to, for that, we need to
export it.
Export, what's the name?
Sorry.
So we export the basic AI snake.
Actually, we have this on the desktop, so
we can run the game.
We load it on the game service and start
the game.
So actually, the game service is
receiving the solver in a file using a
library that allows the service to
interact with its node.
The game service will be able to request
the execution of the solver to the node
that is executing it.
If you are interested in how Celaut works
or how Celaut manages services or things
like that, you can check the demo videos
that are on the Celaut repository.
It has the repository.
Okay, so we can see actually that the
game service has sent the solver to the
node.
The node is building it.
Building it means that it's taking all
the file system and creating a virtual
machine for that service.
But this is only needed at the first
execution of a service in a node.
Okay, so actually the node, it's running
actually the solver.
So we can check these.
Checking other instances.
So actually, both services, the game
service and the solver, are running on the
local node.
This can be seen here in location.
But if the other peer of my network takes
the execution here, where my node says,
okay, where I should execute this.
And it's only considering itself because
the other peer doesn't have the service.
And as we can see here,
The game, the snake game, the game
service loses some gas, spent some gas to
execute.
Our solver has dependency.
And yes, so this game snake game, the
game service, it's controlling, it's
executing the solver service.
So here we can see the progress.
So for each time, the game service sends
the state of the snake,
and the environment to the solver and the
solver returns a position like up, down,
and so on.
This time was only length three.
It's a low score, but it's valid.
And this is the seed of this game.
We need these two.
to allow reproduction for other
participants to check our solver if they
want.
Here, now we need to download this
participation data.
We could replay it more times.
This solver can get to a 50 score or
things like that, but we are going to
participate with this.
So here we need to...
to download the data packet so this
contains all the information that we need
to add to the Ergo blockchain it contains
the solver ID our solver ID that is this
the hash logs that basically add all the
logs this log file that is here this
contains all the information about the
The game?
This is the commitment that contains
internally the secret, just the game
secret that only the game creator knows.
And this is a score list where this is
one of them, it's all real one.
And these other, actually, these
parameters are not going to be loaded to
the Ergo blockchain.
They should be in other versions of the
protocol.
this is the seed that reproduces the game
and determinism index says to the others
how many times you need to reproduce the
solver
to get the same logs.
So for this example, for this solver,
it's very deterministic.
But if it's a language model, for
example, solver, probably it needs a more
high index.
Maybe.
modify these scores if we want, but it
must contain the real score because if not
contain the real score, the contract will
not add our participation on the code.
So, okay, we can download this and we are
ready to participate, to submit a
participation with this data.
so okay 30 minutes only i have made i
have repeated some parts of the video so
Okay, submit my score, so I can put all
the input forms manually or submit a JSON
file.
Downloads, yes, this.
So here is the commitment code that
contains the service, the service secret,
the hash logs, the hash of the logs, the
service ID, the real score.
This is the solver ID, hash logs, yes,
hash logs, and scores, where this is all
real, but other participants will not
know.
Confirm.
And we need to wait now to this.
So we can reproduce if we want the logs.
Here, yes, this.
Play, and we can reproduce our game, for
example.
Or we can play another time, if we want.
OK, so the transaction is confirmed.
So participation was submitted.
OK, there's one participation and there
are 22 minutes left.
OK, so this is our participation.
We can see the score list, but the
reality is encrypted.
And there are this amount of ERGs to the
prize.
So we are going to stop the video and
resolve the game after the deadline.
Well, so after the deadline, the
participation is closed.
So now the participants need to wait that
the game creator resolve the game.
Because for resolve the game, the game
secret is needed into an output of the
transaction.
of the transaction that will spend the
game box and all the participation boxes.
So, as the role of game developers, the
game creators, are going to take the
secret that is inside of the game service,
we are going to resolve the game.
So this transaction, the script of this
transaction will loop all the
participations and all the scores of each
participation and select the correct score
for each participation and will allow send
the prize to the participant with the
highest score.
The transaction is done.
It's completed.
We can see now that the game was
resolved.
This wallet is the unique participation.
is the winner.
So we received the transaction with the
ERG.
And yes, and we can see here the real
scores of each participant.
And that's it.
That's it.
So why
Why is Game of Proms good for making AI
better in the future?
Well, it ensures fair and trustworthy AI
tests.
The rules are code.
A model performance is only openly
validated and prizes are given out by
smart contracts on Ergo.
Unchangeable and isolated services are
are okay for this trust, so everyone
knows the game and the AI players are
running exactly as intended without hidden
modifications.
It rewards innovation when prizes are
given for the best AI models.
It encourages people to try new
approaches and find breakthrough solutions
to AI problems.
It fosters decentralized collaborations
and provides the trust layer for results
on payments.
So GOP can help break down traditional
silos where AI work might be stuck with
one group or in one place.
It opens new kinds of challenges.
The platform can host competitions for AI
models in many advanced areas like
algorithmic trading in simulated markets
or scientific discovery like
like protein folding, for example, or
complex resource management problems,
like, for example, energy optimization on
installations.
There are a lot of challenges that can be
done.
It empowers both creators and developers.
Creators can design and monetize unique
challenges, and developers get a platform
to test their skills, gain recognition,
and potentially earn rewards from their
innovative AI models.
Then the AI models that are
shared between the community are open not
not source open maybe could be but not
necessarily but they are on
are isolated pieces of software so anyone
can use in its own local computers or
other computers but without the censorship
resistant of other AI solutions where are
hosted only on the developers' servers.
So as we say in the last slide, the snake
demo is just the start, because Game of
Proms is designed for a much wider range
of AI applications.
I'm going to mention some of them.
learning to navigate and control things
like a more advanced version of Snake Game
or Pac-Man or other retro games or that
can be to a simulated robots in complex
environments, complex and simulated
environments.
And then these same solvers can be
executed in real robots in the real world,
for example, and algorithmic trading bots
where AI agents compete to achieve the
best returns in simulated financial
markets.
There is an example of trading game
implementation on the code base too.
We could have scientific discovery, AI
challenges for tasks like protein folding
or discovering novel material properties.
AI for strategic planning or resources
optimization, games that test an AI's
long-term decision-making.
AI for making or fixing computer code,
where AI writes or optimizes software, if
the rules of these challenges are well
specified.
And natural language processing task,
where AI are scored on their ability to
understand, interpret or generate human
language.
That is the trending topic, actually, in
AI.
So if an AI's performance on a task can
be quantifiably scored, and if its
environment can be built as a third-party
game service, it can be a Game of Proms
challenge.
OK, so vision and future plans.
So the first version was built for
ErgoHack.
The first version was built for ErgoHack,
showcasing the main idea.
Looking ahead, the vision of GOP is to
make it a significant platform for
advancing in AI in a new open and
trustworthy way.
So for that, I'm going to enumerate some
points.
that could be necessary or important.
With the community, the aim is to attract
AI researchers, developers, and
organizations to both create compelling
challenges and zoom into innovative AI
solutions.
Develop advanced game mechanisms and AI
evaluation metrics so the platform can
support increasingly complex AI tasks.
provide better tools to simplify the
creation, testing, and deployment of game
and solver instances.
This is more a task for the Celaut part,
so the Celaut layer, maybe.
and explore possibilities like
multi-chain support and integrations with
other AI platforms to expand reach and
impact.
Particularly the multi-chain support can
be, it's more detailed on the
documentation of the ErgoHack proposal.
You can read it if you want.
So basically, this opens a big
opportunity for a worldwide incentivized
and transparent platform for finally
making and testing AI models.
So that's Game of Proms, AI challenges,
blockchain solutions.
It's a platform designed for people to
compete, collaborate, and advance AI in an
open, distributed, and trustworthy manner.
So thank you for listening, and I'm happy
to answer
Any questions on Discord, Telegram or the
YouTube comments of this video?
So, thanks.