Welcome, welcome to the second weekly
Community Ergo AMA.
The new format that we're hosting
involves everybody here, which means if
you show up, be prepared to either ask
questions or listen or be asked questions.
Because it's an AMA for everybody and
it's a community and that's how it works.
We've got a nice crowd today with
Dimitri, kushti, Byron, and our next
Anthony, Grayman, Blake, Starkenberg,
Faku, and Odi Bocha.
So this is gonna be great that
everybody's here. Thanks so much for
coming.
What's new, guys? Anybody?
kushti, you're muted.
A nice company here, yeah. A lot of new
face also.
It is great to see. We've got, Odi
actually just took over, if you can see,
where is he in this chart? He's over
there, way over there. There, my finger's
pointing.
He just took over the Sigmanauts Twitter.
So hopefully we see some activity back out
of that Twitter. It's been dormant for a
little bit. So very excited to see what
he's going to bring to the table there.
Hopefully some spiciness.
Some people don't like spiciness, but I
think that's the purpose. I think that
account can handle some things like that
that the main account potentially can't.
So looking forward to seeing what's coming
out of there.
How's your week been, guys?
Yeah, also nothing bad in spiciness,
right? So it's actually attractive. Yeah,
that's at some point creating dramas, but
the dramas unavoidable anyway, probably,
right?
It is, it is.
Why to have boring dramas if you can have
spicy dramas.
Oh boy. We'll see what Odi does later
today. He's just going to delete the
account like Joe does, just done.
Oh, boy. Yeah, no, that account could use
some dusting off, that's for sure. It's
always been through the hands of several
people. And everybody that's touched it
has done a great job and brought something
different and new. And I think everybody,
last I checked, everybody that's used it
still has access to it. So there's about
five people that can post at once and have
different voices. And it's a community
account. It perfectly fits that bill, so
looking forward to that, Odie. See what
you bring to the table.
What else? What's new on my part? It's
been a busy week here around. We've had my
Ergo bots actually went offline for a week
or two. And I had to bring those back up.
There was some NGINX issue. But infra
machines are in the back of my car, all
boxed up that I showed you last week, and
ready to be shipped out. I just have to
swing by USPS on the way home today,
tomorrow, Friday. So those guys should see
that. And we'll get an increase to the P2P
infrastructure.
I spoke with Mark Glasgow over the week
and I think the next target is to infra
the ergoplatform.org website completely,
ergoplatform.com, simply because Google
charges us right up the ass for hosting.
It's pretty bad. So if we can infra that
and get that off that, that'll save a cost
to the EF and move it to the community,
which is fantastic. Slowly moving in that
direction.
And on a side note as well for the
educational stuff that we were talking
about last week, I've further integrated
more LLMs into at least my school side
here. So getting more practice to what
it's going to be like in automation when
we finally move on to doing that with Ergo
platform content and videos and all that
kind of stuff. So really looking forward
to that. But I'm pacing myself. I don't
want to start another task before we
finish up and get the infrastructure down
fully stabilized. So yeah, trying to pace
that up.
What about you guys? kushti, what's new?
So busy, as usual, composing some text
also will post in the main Telegram chat
just after the call. So other than that,
yeah, so busy developing and managing
developers in different ways, different
projects. So yeah, that's more or less it.
Let's bang through the dev updates that
were yesterday real quick. I'll read them
off and maybe there's something to chat
about there. All right. Incoming screen
share, folks. There we go.
All right. So kushti yesterday, 9.06 AM,
Ergo protocol and reference client R&D. We
reviewed 6.0 changes in Node, made PR with
some minor improvements, polished and
proposed for review second PR. Towards
sub-blocks now in Sigma SDK, will be
merged after design doc discussion and
approval. Next for Sigma, plan refactoring
and extensible context to reuse our
programmable money engine and side chain,
off-chain environments, et cetera. And
testing along with Potato and improving
P2P layer for sub-blocks.
Is Potato running a DevNet, kushti, is
that what it is?
So I'm running seed nodes and he is
joining and then reporting. Yes, some
issues. Yeah, well, the last one. So I'm
also joining with my notes. So sometimes
it's about three notes, sometimes two. And
yeah, well, so issues he has sometimes not
reproducible on my site.
kushti, how far away geologically is he
from you? I'm wondering how that affects
node synchronization with faster
sub-blocks.
Yeah, but I don't know. Oh, wait. So
Sydney is in Hetzner, the German data
center, probably. And then Potato, I don't
know, probably late in America.
But yeah that's a good span that's a good
test. That's my guess. So but also our
devnet is kind of extreme so it has blocks
every 30 seconds and 60 sub-blocks per
block so yeah it means two sub-blocks a
second even so it's quite intense.
Oh wow so you kept the 30 second devnet
when you moved to devnet and applied
sub-blocks there that's pretty extreme.
Yeah. Yeah. So, yeah, but that's good for
testing also.
Yeah. All right. Then you got GitCircles.
You reviewed and merged a poll. You've
agreed to use Ergo addresses instead of
secp256k1 and WishYouBalance is improving
implementation. Who's WishYouBalance?
Yeah, so a couple of new developers, so
yeah, BroEtiquette and WishYouBalance.
Yeah, so WishYouBalance is actually a good
cycles idea author, and yeah, BroEtiquette
is, well, some contributor. So yeah, I'm
actually just reporting what they are
doing, mostly. So yeah, it's the project
after all.
And so GitCircles is a project to create
kind of community currencies, but for
digital development communities where you
get tokens for committing to some
repositories. And yeah, so we will start
testing, creating well, talking manually
and doing some testing transactions
manually also, just like few days. And
then yeah, the development is going on. So
there is Git bot already done as well as
persistence layer. So the next step is
some GitHub application and the Ergo half
chain site.
And you think this would ever be able to
implement something like a DAO integration
into GitCircles to where if something is
approved on a DAO, if a merge request from
a GitHub repository is approved on the DAO
vote, then an off-chain bot executes a
push or a pull for that GitHub PR request
automatically kind of thing. Yeah, so PRs
are then voted on in the DAO, and then the
off-chain bot executes that push, that
change.
So actually, open source communities
already acting as DAOs, right, just
off-chain. Usually some rules, some
maintainers, which are accepting what's
going to be merged into the main code
base, right? And then everyone can come
and propose a pull request, but not every
pull request would be merged and so on.
Then, yeah, well, it's kind of like hard
topic rights, governance and open source
communities.
For example, Linux rights, it's hard to
imagine still 30 years after its
development without the single leader. So
it's a big question how Linux would be
developed without Linus Torvalds. And so
on. So yeah, the same dependency is
typical for many open source communities.
Yeah, sometimes even programming languages
and so on. But yeah, well, in some cases,
it's more or less polycentric like Bitcoin
rights where there are like five
developers yeah maybe the different number
now which can merge.
And yeah, there is no single leader
officially, right? But yeah, in practice,
it's about one or two guys, after all, who
are making the most major decisions.
That's typical for DAOs, on-chain DAOs
also, right? So when you have DAOs
usually, yeah, there are some opinion
leaders, right? So it's actually a quite
interesting topic. So would it make sense
to bring already existing kind of DAO
structures like open source communities on
chain, right? And to try to build on-chain
DAOs or not? Maybe off-chain options are
more flexible actually.
What was that, Grayman? Grayman was
saying something.
I was just saying they barely get
anything done. I mean, look at all this
debate over the OP_RETURN issue. It's not
like they're significantly changing the
structure of the thing. When is Bitcoin
going to get to 1.0?
Yeah, but sometimes I think people are
dramatic there just to get a feeling of
importance right and also get recognized
for more and then charge for consultancy
and appearances at conferences and so on.
So yeah, well, I witnessed the first
OP_RETURN drama a little bit back in
2014-15. And yeah, it also was more or
less the same, so a lot of unnecessary
dramatic talks and yeah, so some guys
heating the discussions on purpose, I
guess, in order to get more recognition.
There's also just the drama of the big
blocks and the schism, right? And it's all
just over one little parameter. It's not
like it's substantially changing the
nature of the technology. Before NIPoPoWs,
Ergo was different than it is now. That
changed things in a very substantial way
because it enables light clients that have
full security. So now my phone can be used
without the same assumptions that come
from spooling up a lightning channel. And
so how is that going to, how would
anything like that be implemented in
Bitcoin given their current governance and
way of developing things?
Yeah, probably no chance. So in Ergo,
yeah, so we have NIPoPoWs support from day
one, right? So just, well, support and
clients was lagging for some time but yeah
the core structure was there but yeah well
for Bitcoin there are talks since like
2012 about doing UTXO commitments right
which are allowing for actually a lot of
protocols and yeah well blockchain pruning
and support for lite clients right even if
they still have to download all the
headers in the absence of NIPoPoWs but
yeah still because all the interest spent
on some constants.
It feels like we're still in our age of
heroes part of development and that it's
very hard to put that into a box of
governance. And you know, eventually
you've got to get there. I hear what
you're saying. Ultimately, the goal is to
write yourself out of a job so that you're
no longer necessary, but.
There are a number of people in this
community that are really carrying a lot
of water up the hill. And that kind is the
way it has to be. It sort of self forms a
government and people ask each other for
help because we don't have VC funding. So
we don't have daddy that we go to and ask
to keep handing out dollar bills for us to
go and buy some new machine or do some new
approach. We just have each other. And so
the governance kind of self-forms.
But in the long run, if you end up like
Bitcoin, it's just ossified. It's
controlled by a group of people that
everybody agrees are sufficiently
undemanding and unchallenging that you can
just argue about things like OP_RETURN and
not have the thing grow or change. And
they'll say that that's because they just
want to be conservative. But Bitcoin is
unfinished and getting pretty old.
In early years, 2009, 2010, they actually
were quite radical even, right, about
changes. But then, yeah, well, endless
wars started and they ended up with the
current state where it's not possible to
change anything in the protocol,
basically. Especially if not proposed by
certain developers like one or two of
them. So yeah, so it's quite interesting.
But yeah, in case of VCs, I think it's
simple, right? So I mean, there is some
organization, which is paying developers
and making all the decisions. But then,
yeah, it's not about community, right? So
if such term is used, so it's a little bit
fake community, I think, right? And yeah,
it's always controlled by who is signing
checks.
Hey, guys. I wanted to add something a
bit about community. First of all, it's
super great to talk to you all because I
have been following for a very long time.
And now it's super great to speak and at
least to be a little bit more in person
with you than usually on Twitter or
somewhere else.
The project that I've been building is
MindHealer. And what I wanted to point out
is that building was one thing, and now
the most important part is marketing and
community. And it's a whole different
story, and it has its own challenges. And
the challenges are pretty unexpected, not
what I was thinking it would be. Provided
that I'm also a therapist and I have lots
of connections and friends, and I thought
it would have been much easier.
But people are very reluctant because of
this impression, because of this, you
know, what people usually think about
cryptocurrencies, like scam or something
else. And those who don't have any
experience, they are very reluctant to
join and to try.
And so what I'm currently thinking of is
that we have one-to-one calls at
MindHealer. So people can have one-to-one
consultations. And what I'm doing right
now is there would be group calls as well.
So they could have like seminars or
something like that. And my goal is to
make maybe some three educational classes
about Ergo for specialists who would come
so they will have understanding how it
works etc etc and over time they will
start using it more and more.
But something that the community could be
really interested in is that I was
thinking, since there is such huge demand
on money that is decentralized, that is
not attached to this or that country,
maybe we should try and accelerate some
adoption because, for instance, I'm
currently in Brazil, but I've lived in
several countries.
And it's super hard when you move to a
different country because you have to buy
a different SIM card. Work with banks. In
Brazil, banks can close your account
anytime without any without anything, they
just close the accounts. Maybe you didn't
pay your taxes. Maybe something else. So
we close your account. Why? Well, I don't
know. Just go to the bank and ask them.
And that's the way things are. And when
you move from country to country over
time, it's a really huge, huge difficulty.
So what I thought, maybe we could try and
again, with the community, try to increase
the community. So there are some bloggers
who could potentially be very helpful, who
could work for us the way, who could do
the same job for us that Roger Ver did in
2012 for Bitcoin. So they could be
ambassadors filming how they onboard
people into Ergo, something like that.
Again, it's for community to think about
it. But I really like the idea, and I
suggest that in the Russian Telegram
group. And people are kind of interesting,
not sure. So currently I'm asking, and
let's see how it goes with the bloggers, I
mean.
You're suggesting hiring bloggers and
that kind of thing?
Maybe hiring, maybe inviting them to join
the community so they would promote Ergo,
kind of like reality shows.
So things that I found that those people
have zero interest unless you feed them
funds and money. That's what I've run
across with actually every outreach. There
are a few, like when we started the, when
dev updates a couple of years ago, I
started trying to just get influencers as
interviewers. It was kind of a tactic to
be like, hey, come talk about crypto in
your sphere and what it's like, and also
try to educate them on Ergo in the
meantime. And it was interesting talking
to some of these people.
And most of the people, or actually all
of the people I talked to, were more on
the up and coming kind of thing. You know,
from the Cardano side at least, to try to
get that kind of exposure. Even, what can
I say? There's very little time or
interest that they have unless there's
something in it for them. I guess there's
a kind way to say it, right? So it's hard
to convince somebody like that to be
altruistic and come to a project that is
altruistic and open source, right? And
peer to peer, where there's no upside for
them in the future to potentially make a
ton of money off it. That's what I've
found. So it's a tough balance.
Like look at how much Cardano paid SNEK
or whoever on Cardano paid, SNEK paid,
what's that guy's name, that influencer
with the long hair that he cut short
recently. Like they paid him, I think the
number is 40 grand, I think I heard
secretly that the number was $40,000.
Yeah, exactly. They paid him 40, 50 grand
to start promoting SNEK and probably gave
him a bunch of SNEK as well. So is it
worth it? I don't know.
But that's about so-called crypto
bloggers, crypto KOLs, right? And usually
those are totally retarded and greedy
bastards. They are not creating valuable
content even, right? But if I understand
Dmitry's idea, right? So the idea is to
have some, I don't know, like borderless
enthusiasts, also bloggers, right? And do
some videos like how I make my money with
just GPU, right? Then how I can bring it
to Africa, right, Latin America without
any control and then use there.
And yeah, well, I can mine my digital
gold, but yeah, I can also convert it to
stable value, right? Using stable coins,
well, gold packs, SigmaUSD. And yeah,
well, also it's possible to do
crowdfunding, right? For a blogger.
Because, yeah, well, many of them are
actually doing something like day trips. I
mean, they're like travel bloggers.
The issue isn't necessarily all with
KOLs, it's that the popularity for KOLs
exists, right? So the issue is 90% of the
communities in crypto, and I don't know,
maybe even more, they're of the mindset of
we're playing with casinos, right? I mean,
look at this. It's so disgusting that look
at the incident that happened yesterday in
the US with the assassination. There were
gosh darn meme coins that were tripping
off at $1.5 million in volume with this
guy's name on it that just got
assassinated. That's what these KOLs are
targeting. They're targeting get rich
casinos.
But the point is that there is no need to
spend energy, time and money on those
so-called crypto people. The idea is to
get ordinary people to trust some
decentralized money. Because the issue is
that those KOLs, well, aside of some,
well, Bitcoin maximalists, right, with
like big experience, right, some of this.
So usually they are getting checks from
VCs rights to promote some, well, not so
decentralized, let's say politely, kinds
of assets, right?
So, yeah, the idea is to avoid this at
all and yeah, attach to like ordinary
people. Because, well, we cannot fight,
right, with so-called crypto. We can just
build some alternative or original,
actually, vision, right?
Right, right. So that's a thought,
kushti. When you get a baseline with what
Dmitry is talking about, you have to try
to understand right from the get-go who
we're trying to attract. Are we trying to
attract more like buying people like us
who are in crypto for the decentralized
peer-to-peer nature of what Ergo is and
what crypto should be. Or are we trying to
attract people to pump the price of Ergo,
right? So if that's established at the
beginning, then you can target who you
want speaking for it.
I wanted to tell you about the audience
that I was keeping in mind. So I dropped a
link to one of the guys that I got in
touch with and why I got in touch with
that guy. Because there is a huge, I mean,
I just was thinking about one community.
I'm Russian, so I was thinking about
Russian community, Russian speaking
community. What's very particular about it
is that there is a huge, several hundred
thousand people who want money that is not
attached to any particular government.
They just want money.
They sometimes want to sell an apartment
here and buy it there. So their needs are
very basic. And all they know is they know
about Binance and how to use it. That's
the best case scenario. Sometimes they
know even less. They don't know anything
about decentralization. They don't know
anything about this. So they basically
want money. And I was thinking about the
audience and those travel bloggers, they
really don't know the difference between
centralized and decentralized.
We can basically showcase Ergo to a new
audience. And to show that it is cheap,
people can make money transfers. They can
use it. And then little by little, we can
educate them through those bloggers.
Again, we can do it differently. We should
target bloggers that are not exposed to
crypto at all. So they might have a wallet
for donations, but nothing more than that.
And we can make competition for bloggers,
because people who travel, they are not
usually very. So their prices are not very
high, let's put it like that. And we can
make a competition, for instance, best
explanatory video of how to install an
Ergo Wallet app and how to pay for
something on the road or something like
that.
Yeah, that stuff works well, I think. And
kushti also spoke a little bit about the
other method, too. And you were touching
on this, too, Dimitri, where you're not
necessarily getting an influencer, but
you're finding a leader of a project
somewhere in another country that could
utilize decentralized finance and then
maybe make them a mouthpiece for it
online, not just for Ergo, but for
utilizing decentralized peer-to-peer
finance to accomplish what they're doing
and using Ergo in the meantime to do it.
So I think, yeah. Those are great. Those
are great ideas.
Yeah, but also, so, yeah, had a talk
with, wish you balance, again, GitCircles,
guys in the, so yeah, what's the plan,
right is to, yeah, first to test it and
then, to do kind of airdrop to existing
developer communities, right? So in the
first place to some Rust framework
building communities for frameworks used
in GitCircles and so on.
All right, so the idea is to issue token,
right, and to invite people to get them
for at least a contribution accounting
kind of tool, right? But then, yeah, it's
not that hard to start to attach
economies, right? Well, invite sponsors,
draw some sponsors and so on. I'm willing
to put some money maybe into liquidity
pools just, right? Well, you can just
reuse existing tooling. And so on. But
yeah, the idea is to target developers,
right? Not crypto people because, well,
what's the point in dealing with so-called
crypto? I mean, it's just.
You know, when you are dealing with
people in crypto, it's mostly like a
competition who is louder, who is shouting
a marketing buzz at the most noisy level.
And yeah, it's better to grab people from
outside, right? And bring to build,
especially developers, right? Bring to
build new economies.
Ben, you don't have to raise your hand.
Just jump in, man. It's community.
Well, so I don't necessarily want to
change the subject, but I want to shift
the focus a little bit. When I'm on X and
I see an Ergo raffle for trying to do a
Maxi listing, which I think was one of the
ones that was up there the last couple of
months, there's something in maybe this is
because I'm not crypto enough. But I think
being here is something. But if I was able
to Apple pay $10 from my bank account to
an Ergo raffle, I would participate in 10
times the Ergo raffles that I already
participate in right and it's also like if
I could just apple pay to an Ergo raffle
it kind of turns into more of a go fund me
thing rather than hey I need to see this
raffle I need to remember this raffle then
I need to go to Coinbase I need to buy
some sort of coin and then I need to go to
another exchange to swap that from
whatever coin I chose to ERG and then
finally I need to shift that from the from
the exchange platform to my Ergo wallet
and then get that money to the Ergo
raffle, you know, so if like.
In one, this is a, it's more of a, hey, I
want to support the Ergo community, but I
don't want to go through 30 minutes of
problems to be able to donate $10 to this
raffle. So is there a way that you can.
And once again, I'm not a super dev or
anything. I can't do this, right? But is
there a way that we can make it so that
you could kind of turn Ergo raffle into a
GoFundMe type platform, but also have it
have Ergo branding to increase brand
awareness?
Because the problem in crypto and
particularly with Ergo, is nobody knows
what it is. I mean, there's a few of us
who, I mean, for me, it was in 2021, I
heard the Charles Hoskinson Lex Friedman
podcast. He mentioned Ergo. In about 2022,
I started really getting into Ergo and
believed in the mission. So I got my first
set of Ergo I've been a part of the
community in the last few months i've kind
of fallen off because you know sometimes
real life gets in the way of you know my
crypto journey but it's like the issue
isn't with.
The community size, it's too complicated
to be an Ergo user, simply put. Back in
the day, I was buying ADA on Coinbase
sending it to KuCoin, swapping my ADA for
Ergo on KuCoin, sending it to my wallet.
And then it's like, am I really going to
go through all that effort and then donate
my Ergo? Maybe I'm just speaking in
circles. I don't know if anyone has
anything to add off of that, but it's
simply put, it's too difficult to be an
Ergo user.
So you're in the US, I assume Ben?
Yeah.
Yeah. So when I first got into Ergo as
well, Ergo felt like a scarce resource,
right? Because it was a pain to get in the
US. And I'm from New York, which is even
more restrictive, right? I had to use a
Florida address from my wife's account to
purchase Ergo from Coinbase early on, or
ADA, and then do the same path you did
until they cut us off KuCoin. So there's
an accessibility issue right there. I
agree. But my question is to you, what do
we. How are we framing that?
So there's no accountability in raffles
where there's something like Apple Pay
link with cash, right? So let's say, let's
take, for example, that Ergo raffle set up
where you could donate ERGs or here's an
Apple Pay link to a cash account, right?
On Ergo piece, we can see exactly what
happens to the Ergo after the raffle
finishes. It goes to a wallet, it's used,
it's locked, whatever, who's using it kind
of thing. And with raffle two, we'll see
tokens be able to do that as well. But
with the Fiat, there's no trail
accountability or anything, right? I guess
you could demand that you see it appear on
chain after that, or what it's used for,
some accounting piece.
And I appreciate your sentiment towards
transparency. But at a certain point, it's
like, we trust that GoFundMe is going to
send the funds that we send to GoFundMe to
the user. And I know this is a big thing.
You shouldn't trust. You should verify.
But at a certain point, when does
verification become an inhibitor towards
growth of a product.
Right, so I can see immediately when you
were speaking, ideas came to mind, like,
if we want to reach the broader community
as a Sigmanauts and we're fundraising for
something like the Ergo Meetup, I agree.
There could be, you know, here's a raffle
to fundraise this and here's a GoFundMe as
well for people who want to donate fiat.
So I think that's a great idea, for sure.
But here's the problem. The base of your
idea is accessibility, which, you know,
it's always been a strain, a rough thing
for Ergo, for sure.
Yeah, I also think. Yeah, sorry. Go
ahead, man.
No, go ahead. Go ahead. So I think this
is the perfect example, actually. And
yeah, it makes sense to maybe make a list,
right, of such like tests, right, for
accessibility. And then, yeah, so for
Raffle, in particular, also, what's
doable? So I think, well, not sure when
but this is achievable so first we need
for raffle version 2 right to have stable
coins and then yeah some bridge where you
can get stable coins supported on Ergo in
exchange of Apple Pay payments, right? But
as Grayman said in comments, so yeah, that
there is HodlCoin already with the
VoltPay. So maybe is it supporting Apple
Pay? Probably not, right?
No, it does not. Yeah, well, and you can
get gift cards out. But yeah, it's to go
from the conventional financial world and
into Ergo. then Banxa is our best bet in
the United States currently. It's not
outrageous the way that they operate, but
setting up something so that you could
just click a button and have your $10
Apple Pay go into a raffle.
I mean, it's just UI, UX development. The
fact that the backend is a raffle is good
for traceability. That doesn't need to be
in conflict. In fact, it could just be a
value add, but it's not being added to
anything right now because in order to
participate in an Ergo raffle, you have to
be an Ergonaut. You have to hold Ergo in a
wallet and understand how to use it. I
think Ben's making some good points.
And I applaud you for going out on a limb
and doing that, Ben, on video, because we
need somebody to stand up from that
perspective and say, hey, look, this is
not about the latest technical nuance so
much as it is about making it super easy
to get people involved. Also, like what
Dimitri was saying earlier, at first I was
sort of dismissing it, but then I got his
point. Let's talk to communities outside
of Ergo and get those people to be
interested for a variety of reasons and
that'll you know any any way that you can
connect the real world and other
communities into it that's great but then
Ben said hey look that's all well and good
but then they're going to have to go
through this process of setting up a
wallet and all these other things it's a
friction that we need to overcome and the
only way to overcome it is to.
Apply lubricant, right? And that's a UI
UX dev issue, and that's hard to do. You
know, kushti's given me the thumbs up here
because you can't push a rope. I mean,
he's developing, you know, the next
innovations in the core and the node. It's
hard for him to switch from that into
being somebody that writes a bot that
works with X to press a button and then
suddenly you get an Apple pay that goes to
a particular, oh, you have to do a sign
it, right? That would be nice, but it has
to be done.
Sounds like a skill issue for kushti.
We need to get HQ on this call. Where has
he been? He's probably with his little
one.
He's in Pakistan probably still.
Interesting.
Yeah, helping some victims of floods.
The floods there are outrageous. Yeah,
outrageous, crazy. Himalayas are some of
the newest mountains in the world, and boy
are they unstable. When it rains hard, it
is hell to pay.
So I'm interested to do a test, really. I
think there's probably some fundraising
opportunities and the things we can do.
Oh, sorry.
No, no, I think it'd be neat. I think,
Ben, I think we're gonna, I think I'll
integrate that into at least the tech side
of the Next Ergo Raffle that the SIGs do
is do a side GoFundMe for it for fiat
users. And we'll see what happens. I think
it's a good idea. See what happens. I
mean, I'm ready to take criticism by like,
oh, you're a crypto group and you're still
using fiat to direct fiat payments kind of
thing. So that's fine, I think, but yeah.
Well, it's also like, the fact of the
matter is crypto is great, and I love the
idea in the community, but God is it a
pain in the ass to use. If I could, I'd go
to the local pizza shop and pay with my
ERG. That'd be great. But that's so many
steps. That's why when.
I haven't kept up with this, but Tabi
POS, that was super interesting to me. It
was like the first real, and I don't know
what the deal with Tabi POS is currently,
but it was the first real blockchain
product that I saw that was like, oh, this
is actually useful in real life. It's
like, you know, dexes are cool, kind of
useless to a regular person. A lot of
these things are really, and I understand
that DEXes are important on the backend to
make a lot of things work. I get that. But
to a regular user, to a regular person, no
one cares about a DEX.
Like, my dad, for example, isn't going to
be like, oh my God, look at all these
features that this really cool DEX on Ergo
has, right? That's not taking away from
the quality of these things, right? But
it's just a fact that
60-something-year-old people who see
Bitcoin and they're like, oh my God,
Bitcoin's a way for me to preserve my
wealth over time. Great, but then you get
like, that's like layer one, and then
like, Ergo's down here at like layer
seven. And I appreciate Ergo for being at
layer seven, but the layman is just like
money Bitcoin, money Bitcoin, money
Bitcoin. And they're never going to use
their Bitcoin in real life.
Right, Ben. So, Ergo's had that
agreements and good reality check. I think
Ergo's slightly aware of that and Devs
are, and you'll see that in some of the
products that come out, is that they are
transparent to the user, right? So, like,
Machina's team was originally working on a
ticketing system that allows concert
tickets and things. So that you could have
on-chain governance of your ticket system
and the normal user wouldn't know. They
just download an app that had an
integrated wallet that passed the tokens
back and forth kind of thing.
So I agree. I think when developers
develop, they should keep that in mind,
especially in Ergo, that people might not
want to know that they're holding Ergo per
se, but they want to know that they're
holding a product. They're using a product
that uses some crazy stable security and
peer-to-peer network. that their data and
their value is safe.
Yeah. And once again, I'm speaking out of
hand because I don't have the experience
to implement any of this. So if any of
this is bullshit, I'm sure some of it can
be. But it's, hey, you get them in with
the Apple Pay GoFundMe type thing. And
then that gives you the opportunity to
educate people, meeting them where they
are, rather than trying to, it's like if
I'm in New York City and you're in, I
don't know, Woodstock, New York, it's
like, how am I going to get you from
Woodstock to New York City? It's, I don't
even know you, right? Like, I'm not gonna
be like, hey, come to New York City and
you're gonna come to New York City. That's
not gonna happen.
Well, you brought up some really good
points, Ben. Likewise, Grayman about the
stuff he was saying. But I think it's more
or less a product of the time, because if
you rewind time, older people kind of had
a distaste for the internet. Now, if you
log on to Facebook, that's where they hang
out. So I think it's more of a UI thing,
like what Grayman would say is the ease of
access, and then also to what QX was
saying about the criticism from going from
fiat real to dual purpose. I don't see
that as a valid criticism at all, because
for us to even get into Ergo, you have to
go from your bank account to dual purpose,
right? So it's like, using Ben's point,
which is a good point. That's not a
criticism because people are They already
if you're donating to a GoFundMe. It's a
purpose.
All right, so we got our first plot
scanner of the Of the show luckily we have
his face. We can post it somewhere and
shame him. What an asshole anyway moving
on that might also just be some video that
he put up there.
Oh yeah, yeah, it's not his asshole, I'm
sure. I know. He was white. He was white.
The person in the video was not white.
Why is there a video on his phone?
I think maybe we ought to cut the feed
for YouTube before we get in trouble.
I don't know.
It's already there. Andy can clip it.
Andy can clip it. It's not a big deal. All
right. So before I was distracted, I even
forgot what the hell I was going to say.
Demetri, what were you saying?
Oh, yes. So some, yeah, so cross-chain.
Yeah, so as long as the liquidity is
available on both sides, Dmitriy, so let's
say you want to do a raffle and broadcast
Ethereum, Binance, all those things, but
you want to use the funds on Ergo. As long
as those liquidity pools exist, then Rosen
could develop, essentially, except tokens
in Ethereum. It goes into a wallet and
then automatically transfers across the
bridge at the end of the raffle once it
knows that it's a certain amount. So yeah,
development-wise, it's totally possible
and would be totally neat. Or you could,
yeah, yeah, that would be really neat.
Yeah. I'm still a little shell-shocked
from that. It's 10 o'clock.
Maybe we should end on a good point. No,
don't end it yet. I want to do an
advertisement that will tie it all
together.
All right, go for it, Grayman.
It's for the Autolykos DAO and Venture
Capital Collective, which is formed
recently on Ergo. It's a project being led
by LifeOfIFA. And it's an experiment in
doing governance on chain in Ergo in a
sort of standard corporate form. And it's
a situation where there's a token, which
is called Lykos, which essentially
represents a share in this enterprise. And
it's been through the seed round. The next
round is the sow round. And then the round
after that is where we start funding
projects. And the first project is a
payment gateway.
And I think there have been a number of
things that we need to take into account
when we end up developing a spec for that,
one of them being that mixing would be
involved. But I think another would be
that it would actually be a way to accept
and process payment from Fiat into any
other currency, I guess, again, assuming
that you've got the liquidity to support
that. So that's my little advertisement
for Autolykos. It's permissionless, so you
don't need my permission to join, but
maybe some encouragement. The Sow Round's
coming up soon, so keep an eye out for it.
Awesome.
Very cool. And I think we missed those
two things I just want to mention as well
that we missed on the dev update. Nautilus
wallet has some stuff that came out.
FleetSDK upgrades. Nautilus is
investigating ledger connection issue.
Machina Finance is finishing limit orders
on unit tests. Also, with speaking of
spam, like we just had spam troll just
now. Ergo's had a couple airdrops recently
of fake tokens or tokens that lead you to
a fake site that want to try to get you to
connect your wallet to.
So just a reminder to everybody that
Nautilus has those baked in, ignore spam
tokens, ignore NSFW tokens because those
come as well. So if you have those clicked
and I think they're clicked by default,
the Sigmanauts and Ergo Explorer
communities mark tokens as spam as they
come in and they're automatically hidden
from your wallet so you'll never even see
them if you utilize Nautilus for that and
then you can use Terminus wallet a mobile
wallet to burn them if you want to as well
which is great and I think HodlCoin has a
burn option on their site as well if i'm
not mistaken so just keep in mind that too
that.
Nautilus is also going to integrate on
that community list, we're going to start
putting addresses there that are known
scammers so that when you send, when you
try to send funds to a known scammer
address that the community's marked as a
known scanner, Nautilus won't stop you per
se, but the idea is to pop up a little
message that says, hey buddy. This address
has been marked by the community as a
known asshole or known scammer or
whatever. Are you sure you want to do
this? And maybe a default check to no and
then you have to yes and confirm it kind
of thing. So that's a new thing coming out
of Nautilus at some point in the future
with these community lists.
If you are up at 3 a.m. and you recognize
that a spam token went out and nobody else
is awake, go ahead and submit a PR to our
GitHub or go to ErgoExplorer and find that
token and mark it as a scam as well or pop
it in chat. Someone will take care of it
this morning. We're a community and it's
up to us to keep each other safe for that
kind of thing.
All right, everybody.
Actually, there are more updates. There
is also a reworked basis contract and we
have some new developers contributing
there as well. Yeah, well, let's discuss
during the next call maybe.
Yeah, yeah, there's basis right there.
There's a Cyberverse update report as well
came in.
Cyberverse and maybe. So yeah, let's
discuss during the next call.
Yeah, sounds good.
So we'll just talk about it. Every week,
Ben. I hope to see you every week, man.
Come in. It's awesome to have your
opinion.
And join Autolykos, Ben.
Come talk to us about the idea. Dude, I
have to find my Ergo seed phrase first.
Uh-oh.
Create a new wallet and send your shit to
it. Well, that requires me finding my seed
phrase first. I think I got logged out of
Nautilus. I think I got logged out of
Nautilus.
Oh, okay.
No, I'm not logged out of Nautilus.
Great. So make a new wallet and send it
ASAP. Yeah. Yep. Yep.
And everybody go to Colorado if you can.
Yes, I'm going to announce the first two
speakers. I'll announce maybe today or
tomorrow, the third speaker, three out of
three out of the six speakers or seven
speakers we have. Please come. It's going
to be a lot of fun. We're going to live
stream everything, but we'd love to have
you guys here in person.
The Twitter stuff.
Yes, thank you, Adi. October 11th then.
So people are showing up Friday, October
11th is Saturday, and then there's a
breakfast, community breakfast thing on
Sunday as well if people are still around.
Yeah, it's gonna be fun. Later.
And everybody check out Dimitri. Oh, he
just left. He was developed. Oh, he's
right there. Your picture. I'm here.
MindHealer as well. I've poked around it
kind of thing. But super, super
interesting idea.
Thanks, thanks. Yeah, so let's discuss
MindHealer maybe also.
Yeah, pop into that chat, Dmitri, and
talk about it as well. Yeah, Grayman.
Grayman will bring it down. There's not
enough ERG in the world for Grayman
sessions.
All right, everybody, it's been awesome.
I love these community talks. I think
they're a step up in what Ergo is, so
fantastic. kushti, any closing words?
So awesome atmosphere. Yeah, very
pleasant talk. So yeah, let's continue
next week.
Great. Ciao. Thanks, everyone.