Hi everyone, it's Josemi and in this
video I'm going to present Beene, a proof
of funding platform designed to support
projects in raising funds and fairly
rewarding their contributions.
So, Beene enables any project to receive
funding from the community and
automatically distributes proof of funding
tokens to contributors in real time.
These tokens serve as contribution
accounting tokens, providing who
contributed and how much.
Here's how the platform works.
Project owners create a funding vault and
define the funding token, for example,
ERG, a minimum funding goal, a deadline,
the proof of funding token to distribute
and a rate of how many proof tokens are
given per funding token.
Once a vault is created, project owners
can add or remove reward tokens.
Contributors can deposit any amount of
funding tokens and they immediately
receive proof of funding token vouchers
that represent their proof of funding
tokens.
So if the funding goal is reached, the
project owner can withdraw the funds and
contributors can exchange their funding
token vouchers with the same amount of
funding tokens.
And if the goal isn't reached by the
deadline, contributors can return their
proof of funding token vouchers and
recover their contributions.
So let's visualize this on a chart where
the horizontal axis is time and the
vertical axis is the amount of funding
token raised.
So you can see the actions that become
available depending on whether the goal
has been reached or the deadline has
passed.
So let's see a real example. We used
Beene to raise funds for Gluon Gold.
So the team needed 5,000 ERG to develop
an SDK. A vault was created with a goal of
5,000 ERGs at a rate of one Gluon per ERG
and a two-week deadline.
Once the goal was met, contributors had
already received their Gluons and the
project owner could immediately access the
funds.
Another example could be a group that
wants to write between 5 and 20 articles
about Ergo, where each article costs 100
ERG.
So they might call their token the Ergo
Articles Token and create a vault with a
goal of 500 ERGs, a rate of 1 EAT per ERG,
and a deadline of 2 weeks.
And after reaching 500 ERGs, the team
starts writing articles. And if the
community is happy, more people contribute
and more tokens get distributed so they
can even increase the vault capacity to
support up to 100 articles, for example.
Now a cautionary example. A team promises
something revolutionary and asks for 5
million ERGs with a flashy token reward,
called SuperDuper Blockchain Token.
And after one week, they raise 3 million
ERGs. But the project is exposed as
nonsense because it's only a soup of
buzzwords.
So thanks to Beene's rules, because the
minimum amount of 5 million ERGs was not
raised after the deadline, contributors
can return their proof of funding tokens,
the SuperDuper Blockchain Token, and get
their ERG back.
So Beene can be used in many ways. One
can be donations, where proof tokens
represent your support to a cause.
Another use case can be crowdfunding,
where proof tokens can be exchanged for
goods later.
Startup funding, selling tokens at a
fixed price. Event tickets, where proof of
funding tokens act as tickets to an event
with a minimum and maximum capacity.
And collaborative projects or
benefactions - that is the original use
case that made us develop this platform.
So this idea of working together on
different projects and where labor and
capital to these projects are both
rewarded equally with contribution
accounting tokens.
Okay, so this is the landing page for the
project. We have implementations on
Ethereum and on Ergo.
There is some basic information about it,
links to social media. Both projects are
open source and available on GitHub.
So the Beene on Ergo implementation is a
web app. It's only running with observers
only in the browser and connecting
directly to the Ergo blockchain.
It makes it slower but more fault
tolerant too.
There are some projects. This is the
Gluon Gold security audit that we realized
a few months ago.
Okay, so let's create a project to show
it. So for example, this PFT project will
be our PFT. Let's put this amount of PFT,
the exchange rate of this, the minimum of,
for example, half and one day limit, so
the deadline will be tomorrow at the same
time.
Test project. So for the creation it
needs two transactions.
Okay, now we can sign the transaction,
the second transaction, and this
transaction will create our Beene project.
Okay, so the transaction is confirmed.
Now we can check it, reloading the
projects.
Demo test project. So it's only 23 hours
for the deadline. So we are the owners of
this project too.
So we can see these actions. We could add
PFT tokens or withdraw them. So for
example if we want to block more
contributions we could extract the amount
that is currently on the contract. But now
as users, as contributors, we are going to
contribute.
So there are 0.6 PFTs, so we are going to
contribute with 1. We are going to get 0.1
contributions, sending this amount of
ERGs.
And we will get an auxiliary token, the
PFT voucher. This token will serve to us
as the voucher to get the PFT token after
the deadline if the minimum amount is
raised.
Okay, the contribution transaction is
confirmed. So we can reload the project.
Perfect, so we can see now that there is
some contribution and it's not at minimum.
So for now, when the deadline is reached,
we should be able to refund our ERGs.
And that's it. So follow us on social
media, join our channels and get in touch
if you would like to work with us. Thanks
for watching.