Good morning, everyone.
How are you doing?
Doing well. How about you?
I'm doing good. It's a good day to be an
Ergonaut.
Yeah, like every day.
Every day. Every day is a good day to be
an Ergonaut.
kushti, congratulations on 6.0 release
and 6.1 release. That's fantastic. Amazing
feat.
Right, so everything released. I'm
working with miners and yeah, everything
is good at the moment.
Yeah, I mean it only brought the chain
down for what? Two hours, right?
Sorry?
It only brought the chain down for about
two hours with that new release. It's a
joke, kushti, Ergo doesn't go down, come
on!
Yeah, I mean, no any downtime, so yeah,
we are good with everything, and yeah,
let's see how our voting will go. So in
case of success, we will have activation
of 6.0 around October and well we can
actually have hopefully sub-blocks more or
less ready by the time, right? That would
be awesome.
Mid-October, late October, let's see, but
we start... We can start injecting nodes
in the internet. Someone here hired some
spots here. I think in somewhat stats into
the public.
All right. You should be able to, you're
glitching a little bit, kushti. You got
some bots running.
Shut down the mixer shut down the other
stuff I think seconds
Yep, yep, yep. So with 6.0, with the
mining pools, they do not need to change
any parameters if they vote yes, right?
That's how you wrote this one. So if they
want to vote no on it, they have to have a
parameter into the node. If they want to
vote yes, then they just run 6.0, and
they're good to go. And voting should be
done on, what is it, October? Is that
October? No, sorry, not October. July 12th
or July 11th, something like that?
Yeah, beginning of the warning and then,
yeah, well, if there will be enough votes
in one month and a half, right, like 90
plus percent, then, yeah, we will have
then delay for activation for another one
month and a half for everyone to better
update, but it's not necessary for this
update. So it's really soft. So if you run
5.x nodes or even 4.0.100 something, then
yeah, well, everything will be fine. So
for 5.x nodes, yeah, your nodes will just
skip validation of new scripts and that's
it. So it will validate all the current
scripts even.
So no, no sub-blocks on 5.0 nodes at all.
They will just ignore them.
Yeah, and they also ignore the new
parameter, the voting for changing number
of sub-blocks per block on every chair, so
this is the new voteable parameter
injected into 6.0 logic, consensus logic,
but yeah, well, thanks to the art of soft
fork ability, 5.x nodes will just keep
this parameter and watching for changing.
Have you ever had a soft fork that was
close? Or has it always pretty much been a
landslide? Like, you know, something where
it was going to be close whether something
would pass or not?
So we had a couple of soft forks before,
right, so EIP-27. which yeah was quite
soft like this one so it's nothing
controversial where where 50% of the
miners had it one way 50% the other or
close to that oh but so it was about 90
plus percent as well so soft forks require
for 90 plus percent oh 90 percent for soft
forks. Yeah. So, 50% just to change
non-critical parameters like size and so
on. But yeah, for soft forks, you need for
90 plus percent to avoid appearance of
Ergo classic, something like that, you
know, so Ergo classic.
Even if you have like 20% disagreements,
15% initially it was for Ethereum Classic.
No, it's better to avoid. And yeah, so for
Bitcoin Cash, I believe it was also
something like that. So yeah, we require
for 90 plus percent agreements for soft
forks, not just one half, because then you
may have, I don't know, even 60 versus 40
split, right? And such split is still kind
of annoying, probably, right?
Yeah, 40% is quite a few better people,
yeah, for sure.
Very divisive, but yeah, well, if you
require for 90-plus percent, then yeah.
There is a little chance, well, another
fork will survive.
Well, if Mark's listening from the SIGS
mining pool, we've got a double job there.
We've got to do a Paideia vote first, and
then you can implement the 6.0 node on the
thing. So it's a double vote, essentially.
First and then to implement.
So, what's going on with Sigmanauts
mining pool? Is it open to more
experiments like FIMO and so on? Yeah,
FIMO, right.
Yeah, yeah, 100% fair, a fair initial
mining offer. Yeah, that'd be amazing.
Right now we are working on, Chi's got us
a new build of storage rent, and Mark's
spinning that up on testnet just to make
sure everything's going to go okay. Just
be, you know, storage rent tool is, you
know, sometimes it takes a little nudging
to get it going great, but we don't want
to put that on the main pool until we're
sure. So he's firing that up on the
testnet. We have to ask Chi to build us a
6.0 node for storage rent as well. So
we're going to work on that. But yeah.
It's going well, going very well. I love
the SIGS pool. If anybody's mining out
there, join the SIGS pool. It's more than
a pool, kushti, it's a community, I should
say.
Well, it's truly Ergo-oriented, so we can
try some new things with Sigmanauts in the
first place. Well, with 6.0 there will be
better support for sidechains, including
trustless two-way pegged merge mined
sidechains. A lot of words, but yeah, it's
a really cool thing. Not quite possible in
the world of Bitcoin or Monero, but
possible here. Then there will be support
for efficient trustless relays for Bitcoin
and Bitcoin-like blockchains and so on.
As Ergoversary is coming. Yeah, some
announcements also coming in regards to
that and yeah, well here I think sigma
mining pool also can help with
experimentation right and getting the
ecosystem to the new frontiers
Andy wanted us to remind people, speaking
of that kind of stuff, that the Ergo hack
videos are being released today,
yesterday, tomorrow, throughout the day.
So make sure you check up on those. You
watch everybody's hard work on the Ergo
hack. If anybody's ever done an ergo hack
before, it's a lot more difficult than it
sounds. You have a limited time to do
something and so basically you ignore your
family and your life for how many ever
days it takes just to get something done.
You know, typically in a normal coding
experience, you run into always something
that sticks you, right? That you can't
figure out or it's just not working like
you think it's going to work. So in a
normal environment, I just set that aside
and go into something else. But in an Ergo
hack, you're like,
Nope, got to finish this to make deadline
or else it's just not going to work kind
of thing. So it's a lot of work that all
these developers put in to ErgoHacks to
get things rolling. So go ahead, watch
their videos and see what they're doing.
And hopefully, since this one is based on
AI, you might get some ideas that says,
hey, you know, if people that aren't devs
or they're hobbyist devs can do these
complex apps that interact with the Ergo
blockchain, maybe you can too. Kind of
thing so don't shy away from that and
check out those videos, but Ergoversary I
just got done recording a video with our
own Dan the man from Japan How he praised
Ergo blockchain for enabling
You know his winter protocol which can do
on chain... What are they called? Oh W...
Something assets. I can't remember. I was
a plate last night And how Ergo enabled
something like that And why they chose
Ergo. So that was a lot of fun to
interview him a quick 30 minute interview.
So please check that out. On July 1st is
the Ergoversary. We are going to do a
special AMA two days early on July 1st.
It's going to be myself, kushti, Joe,
and... Who was the fourth? I've forgotten
who the fourth was, Andy. Maybe Andy can
text me. But I'm pretty sure there were
four of us. So that's going to be a lot of
fun. Who was the fourth, kushti?
Maybe Dan? I don't know.
No, what's her name? I can't remember. It
was Dan. It was Dan, yep.
Okay, so it's me, Dan, Joe, and qx().
I think we reached out to CW. CW,
reaching out to CW as well, but he's in
Australia, so poor guy needs some sleep, I
guess.
It would be funny to have five or more
people on the table, but I'm not sure
about connection issues. We can try at
some point. Yeah, Ergoversary is coming,
so yeah, well, be ready to spend some time
on July 1st to watch videos, watch AMA. I
guess we will have some community chat
also, our Telegram Discord.
Oh, that's a good idea, yeah. So, yeah,
prepare your drink, like tea, I don't
know, coffee or coffee.
Call in to work that day just so he can
watch all the things. Focus on Ergo only.
Yeah, and be ready to have fun around
July 1st, like we had a lot of fun,
actually not really, six years ago.
Six years, that's crazy, kushti, six
years old.
Yeah, yeah. But yeah, it's actually quite
amazing. I mean, living through all those
six years, and I will think that's, yeah,
I mean, new people are coming all the
time, right? Proposing some things you
haven't thought about even, and yeah,
they're doing something.
I just, I think it's commendable that
Ergo has stayed true to her thesis for six
years amongst all the crap that's come
down the pipe and all the temptations, I
would say. I mean, how tempting is it to
do back-end deals with you know token
supplies and those kind of things and I
know it's hard for Ergo just because you
know, we were a fair start and the only
good place to get stuff is exchanges right
or from directly from miners So it's a
little harder for that kind of thing to
happen But I think it is commendable and
it speaks to Ergo how in six years It's
only gotten stronger and it's resolved of
what it is and how it functions and what
it's supposed to be
Yeah, and how well basically all the
issues got resolved somehow, right? For
example, if there are some issues with
centralized exchanges, basically hate
fairly distributed assets these days,
right? Well, they simply prefer some,
well, straight rugpulls, memes, scams,
fart coins.
Well, it's hard for... It's hard for
central exchanges to extract value and
liquidate shorts and longs if they don't
have a big chunk of the supply themselves,
right?
I think, well, they will get into issues,
right, because of that, especially, well,
when we have more and more, well, straight
rugpulls, even, not from, like, small
scammers, but, yeah, I mean, pretty big
so-called blockchain projects now going
through VC rugpulls, like Mantra and
recently RWN Rowan somewhat, I don't know,
so it's got minus 90% because kind of
owner of the project, I mean, which is
already, that sounds pretty horrible,
right? I mean, among all the marketing
gimmicks in regards to decentralization
and so on, yeah, so we have some owner.
which is dumping straight like minus 90%
in a day. And yeah, before there was
another VC rugpull when it was like 95% in
one hour because of coordinated VC
rugpulling. So, yes, centralized exchanges
love that and getting back to the initial
point.
Well, the Ergo community then went to the
road of bridging rights to blockchains
with some liquidity already there are like
Cardano, Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain,
and they will be more and more. And then,
yeah, well, Rosen Bridge is going to be, I
believe, its own vault, right, with
multiple blockchains connected. It would
be kind of a saver for many blockchains,
actually, right? So these days if you
are... for many blockchains, actually,
right? So these days if you are...
We had to be mostly paid to centralized
exchanges in case of a fair launch. We had
to do with Ergo because back in 2019, it
was quite obvious that you cannot get
listed for free. You need to pay all
those. So, yeah, I guess most of the
treasury actually was paid to centralized
exchanges. It wasn't avoidable, right? But
yeah, nowadays you can launch a blockchain
and the only thing you need is to
Basically, the Rosen Bridge integration
rights, and you can do it for free.
That's what I was going to say. That
should be a clear indicator to projects,
right? When they look at how to spread
themselves over other ecosystems or access
via exchanges, look at an exchange, right?
Even a project like Ergo, who says, look,
not Coinbase, Kraken, look, we will we
have devs community devs core devs that
are willing to do all the work, right? The
exchange is like yeah. No, thanks. No,
thanks Whereas somebody like Rosen Bridge
has released documentation that says oh,
hey You want a bridge to all other
ecosystems that were connected to you want
back doors to exchanges? Here you go.
Here's how to do it. So, I mean, I think
once, you know, that hooks on to people
and they see that, at least devs seeing
that, or chain creators, I think that's
going to be the obvious pathway to
adoption there.
Yeah. And then, especially when Rosen
starts doing vaults and fast lane and
direct on ramps, I think that's a game
changer for sure.
Right, so for new chain you may have
cross-chain and liquidity pools everywhere
since day one and it would be good for
first month at least, quite enough, so it
is definitely better than what we had. In
the first one year, actually like 14
months before GATE.io, what we had is just
terrible exchanges with drunk support like
Tidex.
Drunk? Did you say drunk support?
Yeah, so I mean the the the support in
the force Just drunk I mean, I don't know
if it's good