Cool, cool.
Hey, welcome, everybody. We're just going
to be going over Why Mine Ergo? A guide to
profitability, sustainability. Probably a
lot of this stuff you're very familiar
with, but we're just going to go through
it at a high level, as well as talk about
Sigmonauts mining pool.
Cool. And so what we're going to cover
today is understanding Ergo, why it
matters, the basics of mining, the
Autolykos algorithm, the technical setups
- so setting up the rig, the design of the
rig, heat and power - as well as the
economics, so costs, breaking even,
various analysis, emission schedule
impacts, and then as well as the
Sigmonauts mining pool.
So who is this for? We have whoever's new
to crypto, experienced miners, maybe
post-ETH merge. I think generally if
you're interested in crypto, it's probably
worth looking into proof of work and then
at a minimum maybe potentially even mining
it.
And so what is Ergo? As I'm sure most
people know, but in case you don't, it's a
truly fair blockchain launched in 2019. No
pre-mine, no ICO, no VC funding. Built by
experts, so former Chainlink and Cardano
developers. We have the max supply around
97.7 million. Strictly capped. Mission is
decentralized finance accessible to
everyone. Philosophy is fair launch,
community driven, and proof of work
secured.
So Ergo is a blockchain done right, by
the people for the people.
And so what is mining? The basics: Mining
is securing the blockchain network. You
provide computational power, hash rate,
and the network rewards you with ERG
tokens. Think of it as getting paid to run
security for a digital bank. Your GPU
solves complex mathematical puzzles. The
more puzzles you solve, the more you earn.
Without miners, the blockchain can't
function.
So we've got to secure the transactions,
validate the transactions, secure the
network. And so you're not just earning
rewards, you're supporting a revolutionary
financial system that is Ergo.
And so what makes this so special? So
it's ASIC resistant, memory hard, proof of
work. It's very GPU friendly. It's very
cool. And so a lot of those factors, for
me at least, as to why mine Ergo make it a
lot easier on the cards. I know ASIC
companies aren't necessarily going to come
into Ergo and sort of rug us.
So no ASICs, like we say, right? Maybe
potentially true decentralization because
essentially anybody can go off and buy a
GPU. Anybody that generally has probably a
desktop computer potentially with a GPU,
maybe a gaming computer.
So it's more accessible than potentially
mining Bitcoin.
And so a critical factor here is the
emission schedule. I believe when I first
started mining, it was probably about, I
think, 75 or 60 ERG was the emission per
block all the way down to 12, I believe.
The block time is still static, two
minutes. Going to be changing here soon, I
believe. And then our reduction schedule
is going to be next.
So every three months it reduces by
three. So nine to six to three should be
interesting as things sort of move in that
direction.
So decreasing supply is going to enable
scarcity. And so as miners start to mine
more and more of this asset, there'll be
less and less from a daily perspective
being emitted into the ecosystem.
Understanding mining costs: you have your
initial investment, but then you have
operating costs. Your initial investment
is going to be your GPUs, your
motherboards, your CPUs, your power
supply, the frame, everything that you
need for the complete compute unit. Then
your operating costs are going to be
something to the effect of your
electricity, which is going to be your
biggest operating cost. Your internet
connection, cooling - I think ventilation
is definitely underexplored here, at least
from my experience when I first started
mining. Maintenance and then of course
pool fees, which generally is around 1%
depending upon which mining pools you go
to.
So yeah, as we say here, electricity is
the key determining factor for
profitability. A secondary, I suppose,
might be price itself, right? Because if
the price is like, for ERG at like $100,
that's going to be a little bit different.
But of course, the difficulty kind of
changes.
So what you need to know about mining:
your hash rate - so how fast your GPU
mines, that's going to be relative to how
much ERG you actually earn. Your
electricity rate, the network difficulty -
so how hard it is to find these specific
blocks. GPU power draw - so how much
electricity you're actually going to be
physically using.
And there's differences whether you
measure it from the actual device or is it
from the software? Obviously, you want to
measure it from the device, so that's the
most sound measurement. Then, of course,
current ERG price and then the block
reward. And again, the block reward is
going to change every three months or so.
And so here is calculating cost to mine
one ERG. And so why do you want to even
calculate the cost to mine one ERG? So the
idea here is, say it costs $1.50 to mine
ERG, and the current cost is, I think,
like 70 cents or even 60 cents, you are at
a loss. Cost to mine ERG is say a dollar,
but ERG is $2. Well, then now you're
making 100% more.
And so this is what this formula is going
to be calculating. And I think as miners,
we need to sort of look at it as like a
business perspective and potentially even
at a minimum pay off your electricity
costs. But I think additionally, miners
are also looking at a speculative bet. So,
hey, maybe one day ERG is going to go up
to this mythical price. And if that's the
case, then sell everything and go down and
move to the islands or something, right?
Whatever other people's dreams are.
And so here it is. So it's your hash rate
divided by the network hash, multiplied by
the block reward and then the blocks per
day. So that's how much actual ERG you're
going to be getting. And then your daily
electrical cost. And then once we have
those two specific numbers, right? So your
daily electrical costs and then the daily
ERGs mined.
And so, for example, we have here 150
mega hash consuming 150 watts. I think in
this example, we're just using kind of
nice numbers. I think 150 watts at 150
mega hash is quite high. So with the - and
I haven't validated these numbers, so -
but in any case, network hash rate 50 tera
hash, the electricity is 12 cents per
kilowatt hour, block reward is 12. And so
your daily ERG is about a quarter of an
ERG. Your daily cost is going to be 43
cents. So then your cost per ERG is going
to be $1.67. So you're instantly paying
more for your ERG.
That is that calculation. But again, this
could be more of the speculative play. And
so, hey, maybe in 10 years ERG is going to
be, $100, $1000. And I'm just going to sit
on this kind of like the idea of Bitcoin
and miners back then.
Yeah, you're good to go. Pay a little
premium.
Yeah, exactly. And that's the key
takeaway, right? And so then if your ERG
price is greater than your cost to mine,
like we were just saying, it's profitable.
Otherwise, you're at a loss. And then
breakeven is also nice.
So yeah, variables change. So the price
is going to fluctuate. That's why a lot of
miners, like Son of a Tech, he's always
saying to pay off your electricity first,
because that first and foremost, it's a
business. And then if there's any extra,
then just hold on to that. But everybody's
game plan, I would say, is sort of
different.
You can certainly gamble by mining. You
could say, forget it. I'm just going to
pay the electricity bill because I can pay
that electricity bill and just gather as
much as I want and just kind of see what
happens.
So yeah, other variables, right? The
network difficulty increases, block
rewards. And then, of course, the
electricity rate. They may come knock on
your door and say, hey, you're using way
too much electricity. You're going to
start paying more prices, which I've heard
is a thing.
So yeah, so we have long term
considerations. Beyond daily profit, we
have hardware depreciation over time.
These things are running 24/7. They're
going to be collecting dust, inherent
entropy within the system. ERG
appreciation potential hopefully. Resale
value of the mining GPUs - that certainly
has been the case.
I have seen that maybe less and less in
the future. Like for example, I bought
these AMD cards and they were about $750
in 2021 and now they're like $100. And so
maybe the resale value of mining GPUs,
that could be the case, but currently I
don't believe it's the case.
Tax implications, of course, in the
United States. So yeah, hodl strategy -
really just mine at the low prices. Forget
your electricity costs, just pay that. And
then you have potential 10x returns,
hopefully, we'll see. And then mining is
in a sense, right, dollar cost averaging
into ERG.
And so, but I think there's certain
byproducts potentially as a result of
that. So if you live in a colder climate,
you could recapture a lot of this energy
that is the heat. You could then put that
back into your house. I know a lot of
people do that. I used to do that when I
lived in Colorado, kept my garage very
nice and toasty when it was close to zero
degrees or 20 degrees.
And that's just kind of moving into here.
Emission reduction impacts, so right now
we have 12 ERGs as the block reward, so
8,640 ERGs a day. Then we move into nine
ERGs, so 6,400 ERGs a day, six ERGs,
4,300, and then three ERGs forever is
going to be 2,160 ERGs.
And so there will most likely be some
sort of squeeze in the amounts of just
scarcity, right? So early miners, we're
saying here, have a massive advantage,
especially when we were mining at really
high rates like 70 ERGs or 65 ERGs for the
block reward.
And so talking about the algorithm, it's
a cool algorithm. So it's very good on
your specific hardware, which is great for
longevity, because again, talking about
buying equipment, you potentially want to
just buy this equipment and never have to
buy equipment again, but most likely
you're going to be buying secondary used
GPUs that have been running for a very
long time anyhow.
And so you want to run it on something
that's going to be running 24/7, running
that's not really stress testing these
GPUs who have already been most likely
abused.
Power efficiency, I think, again, is very
critical. I used to mine, and I used to
say, oh, I just want the highest hash
power. But in reality, especially with
economies of scale, you can start to get
at maybe one or two GPUs, no big deal. But
you get 5, 10, 15, 30 GPUs. This economy
of scale with the specific rigs and all
that electricity cost, it doesn't really
make too much sense.
And so running cooler means your GPUs
last maybe two to three years longer, 10
to 20% less power. You might have some
less rewards within Ergo, but I think,
again, it's like we want to be able to -
mining is like a game that you want to -
it's not like to win, you want to just
like play the game. And so like, that's
like the goal here, not necessarily
winners or losers - just want to keep
staying in business.
And so right, so that talks about
longevity - thermal stress, fan longevity.
So if there's any inherent noise that you
don't necessarily notice, that's inherent
entropy within the system. And so maybe
something's off kilter. And so maybe every
six months it's good to have a plan and
just take off the rigs apart, clean them
all off, put some isopropyl alcohol, get
all the dust out of that, especially for
the fans, right?
Because if you have more mass, that is
the dust spinning, they're going to have
to work harder, those motors are going to
have to work harder, and that's just going
to put more inherent stress on the system.
Not good for longevity.
So the, we have memory intensive mining.
So how Autolykos works is a memory hard
computation, GPU core sits relatively
idle, but we focus on VRAM - 6 gigabyte
minimum. 8 gigabyte plus optimal. Of
course, different tuning. So underclock
the GPU, overclock the memory, reduce
voltage. Again, highly recommend.
Efficiency is key here.
And so yeah, you want to find that
optimization sweet spot. So you can get 80
to 90% of that max hash rate. So you can
get 60 to 70% power. And that even kind of
talks about too, again, the longevity of
things.
So if you've got a really nice electric
rate and you're using less power, you can
actually put more cards on top of the
entire electrical network that you have.
Because then in theory, instead of using
the total capacity, you can maybe fit one
or two extra cards on there to make up for
the lowered hash rate because of the
clocks.
Totally. Yeah, Ken was just talking about
the efficiency of the cards compared to
something like Kapow and you really just
want to take care of them. But you do have
a good point to where it's like, you want
to maximize for this three month period,
because in the next three months, you're
going to be getting arguably less. So then
you could even think about it as of like
right now hey I'm just going to mine until
it hits the three. So then your electrical
rate is essentially fluctuating because
now you're actually getting more. Like a
year from now you're going to be getting
less and so you can recalculate what the
actual cost would be to mine in the future
and do some weird accounting I'm sure.
Yeah, I don't know, maybe I'd push back
on that, because NVIDIA came out with a
card solely for mining, and when they
first came out with it - so it's the
CMP-170HX. It was five grand for that
card. Now you were just showing me today,
it's like $300. So it's like, and that was
maybe two or three years ago, and that's
like 400 mega hash for that one card
versus I don't know what the newest cards
are pumping out, but...
Right. Yeah, it could be.
Right. But what's really nice about
mining is we were kind of talking about it
a little bit yesterday in one of the side
discussions - virgin coins, a virgin
wallet, where it's like, it's literally
only ERG coming in here that's mined. So
there's no sense of - nobody knows where
you're at. You're on your own island
except the mining pool, but there's no
other transactions tied to that.
I kind of like that idea to where you
build up a nice stack and then nobody can
tie that to me. I mean, you can use a
mixer, I'm sure, but people can then see
you use the mixer. It's a very anonymous
way to just dollar cost average into ERG.
You can even move to - they have hosting
farms where they make deals with you and
you just send your stuff to them and
they're like, oh, we'll give you this
electrical rate and then in return. But
I'm seeing less and less GPUs do that -
more and more ASICs for sure.
So, but there's an opportunity, I think,
with solar renewables. Great opportunity.
I think they're relatively cheap. You
could build a nice solar farm, and the
next thing you know, you have free
printing of ERG because then say all the
equipment's all paid off. And then if
you've got all the other equipment for the
solar paid off. And then you're also
routing that heat to heat your house - you
have this really nice efficient energy
making machine where it's just printing
ERG, everything else is paid off, and then
the heat is going back into it.
Definitely.
So ASIC resistance - fair mining, and I
think that's a huge aspect because I came
into certain cryptocurrencies and then
it's like, come to find out, you need to
buy so much to sort of be able to - in
Cardano, if you want to create a stake
pool, you really kind of need so much ADA
to create them and mine blocks.
Versus Ergo, you can just say, hey, I'm
going to buy this GPU setup, just point to
the pool, and you're making money ready to
go. And it could be even used as a burning
mechanism. You could be like, OK, hey,
this guy needs some ERG, and just turn on
a rig, and then anonymously fund them, or
something like that.
So fair competition - your GPU competes
on an equal footing. True decentralization
- so mining power stays distributed
globally, ideally. Dynamic protection - so
scheduled memory increase, brick any ASIC
attempts. And then community focus - so
mining rewards stay with individual
miners.
And I think that's a huge one. I think
with the whole ASIC thing we really want
to - I think we've seen the rise and the
fall of various chains that have then
said, okay, hey, we'll allow ASICs to come
in. Here we have a hard...
Well, I think it's the algorithm, right?
So it's like, we decided to use this
algorithm and then we'd have to fork it, I
guess, to change the consensus layer that
is the algorithm.
Yeah. Only time will tell, I suppose.
Hopefully. Yeah. Right. Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, we can see all these things, but
we'll see what comes out in the wash, I
suppose.
And so here's some of the hardware
requirements at a minimum. I think we were
at four gigs for the VRAM, maybe a few
years ago, and then it went up to six. And
so I had a couple of four gig cards that
obviously wouldn't be able to support this
anymore. But I think that's an opportunity
for some sort of side chains that's been
talked about.
So then we have single GPU and multi GPU.
So yeah, your single GPU really is going
to be like your gaming PC, maybe your
workstation, testing the waters, low
barrier to entry, ROI potentially 12 to 18
months - we say typically, but who knows
in this market.
So it's sort of a smaller investment,
depending on what sort of setup you have.
It could be zero because you could have
already potentially have it.
Now your multi-GPU setup. This can be
somebody - it's like, all right, I really
want to get into this. You have the
electricity cost. That's one thing. It's
one thing to be like, hey, I'm going to do
all this. I'm going to run five giga hash.
But then it's like, well, do you have the
electricity to do it? Do you have a 30 amp
outlet? Can you pay for somebody to
install the 30 amp? Do you need 50 amps?
What's the safe wattage to run on 30 amps?
Knowing all that stuff.
Even the cords is extremely important
because if you say, hey, I want this
specific card to run at 300 watts, but the
cord is only good for 250, you're going to
start a good fire. Or even you're using a
specific 3D printed hanger. So one time I
3D printed and created my own hangers and
so they'd hang and you have an open
airframe kind of going through it.
And I was actually just at breakfast with
my wife and I was looking at the camera
and then as I was looking at it one of the
GPUs fell because after a couple months
and I was using PETG but after a couple
months of just being warmed up, warmed up,
warmed up, the screws started to sort of
create the hole a little bit bigger and
bigger and then eventually just would fall
out.
So it's always good to have those sort of
backups and cameras and things because it
would suck to put three to ten thousand
dollars down into this, get it all set up,
brick a machine, brick a motherboard,
create a fire for all of this sorts of
stuff. So definitely do the single GPU
setup first. Get your feet wet.
Typically, right, yeah. Probably a lot
longer now as of yesterday. These were
made a few days ago.
But yeah, I mean, I think that it's a
good point. So Graham had mentioned
college students, they don't have to pay
for their electricity. So that's a great
vector or even Airbnbs. I've heard people
get Airbnbs. They see that they have a 30
amp outlet over their entire setup, get
free electricity. It's a way to do it for
sure.
And so let's break down the different
mining components. So we have open air,
which is nice, but it has a lot of
different moving parts. And so I think
again, kind of going back to that idea of
entropy, if you have a lot of components
moving within the system, something is
bound to break and you're sort of as
strong as your weakest link.
So if a PCIe board riser goes out, well
then that's down, but then you've got to
move everything. And if you've got - I've
had at most 13 cards in there, and you
have the cords managed very nicely, it's
kind of a pain in the butt to take one
card out, switch that out.
I prefer the server cases. On Amazon, you
can get them, I think, for like $500. You
can put eight cards in there. It comes
with fans. It runs Windows, but you can
put in, of course, HiveOS or anything like
that. Highly recommended. And those are
stackable, then you can move them
anywhere. Versus the open airframes,
definitely not the case.
Right. Yeah, a lot of aftermarket parts
out there right now, probably for cheap,
you could just put something. Right. Yeah.
Definitely. The thing I think you'd need
to worry about potentially with mining,
with that sort of approach, is there's a
lot of move to LLMs being moved to local.
So I think before the video game group was
getting upset with crypto people because
they're buying all the GPUs.
But now I think there's going to be a
move to where now all the crypto guys are
going to be upset with the AI guys trying
to buy all the GPUs, because I think there
really will be more of a privacy sort of
thing with LLMs and being like, hey, I
want to run it on my stuff. I don't want
people knowing what my prompts are and
things like that.
And I think the tools are generally
moving more towards open source and being
able to run them sort of locally. And it's
kind of pretty easy to do. We've done it
with a couple of websites. So just some
sort of food for thought there.
And then I think that even kind of goes
into the idea of like, hey, I could create
my own LLM setup. And then when my
family's not using it, maybe from 10 PM to
6 AM, it's just mining Ergo. And it just
has that script that's running. Okay,
cool. Turning off into offline mode. Now
I'm just going to mine Ergo, turn it back
on. Now back to the home LLM or whatever
the case.
Yeah, right. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, home LLM
or whatever LLM you want to call it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly. Because I
think as we move further down with LLMs
and I know kind of varying off a little
bit, but like, you could have your camera
set up with different MCP servers and your
cameras in your house, you maybe want to
access that LLM to have that. But then now
maybe Google or OpenAI or all these people
sort of have this data that is your kids
or your family.
And so I think that's where the privacy
is going to maybe potentially come in or
listening to you. And you just want to be
able to say, Hey, home LLM XYZ, you don't
want it to...
Right. Yeah. Totally. And then it's like,
cool, we have our own little LM setup. It
does whatever that needs to do. But that
same infrastructure can then be flipped on
its head when we're not using it to then
run at night and mine Ergo. And then plus
they're both are going to generate heat.
So I think there's opportunity there to
create heat, especially for things like
hot yoga - makes no sense to just have a
heater when you're just constantly going
to be purposely heating something.
So it kind of maybe makes sense to have a
bunch of miners running, even if you
are... And that's where I think the heat
perspective, you could even flip the
electricity cost on its head because then
it's like, well, I don't really care.
We're going to burn this electricity
anyways. But now we get another asset to
go inside of it and we just get that and
then we just actually get a discount now.
So it's I think a lot of the mining stuff
is really kind of how you look at it. So
maybe one way it looks like a circle and
then the other way it looks like a square
- sort of that kind of famous example,
right? Just depends on how you're looking
at it.
So yeah, understanding the problem. So
each GPU generates 100 to 200 watts of
heat. Six GPUs could produce 1200 watts of
heat, equivalent to a space heater. And of
course, we're not even talking about
noise. Noise is also a big problem.
So, I'll just continue here. So, single
rig heat management, we're just talking
room positioning. So, keeping away from
walls. I think one of the big things with
mining, people don't really think about is
this concept called heat transfer.
And so really, it's the idea of you have
something generating heat, but we're not
really thinking about how are we going to
actively move that out of this system. And
you can think of this room as a closed
system, I suppose. And if you have heat,
how is it going to generate and eventually
assimilate to the main temperature?
So if you think of it like water, so if
you have water that is room temperature
but then I pour a little bit of hot water,
eventually it'll take some amount of time
for this whole water to be the same
temperature. And so that's sort of what
heat transfer is. And you want to be able
to effectively - especially if you're
trying to minimize the effect of the heat,
you want to be able to understand - so
some people will create a rig room and
then they'll create heat isolation and
then they'll create their exhaust. So
they're kind of creating some insulation
sort of to help slow or help this
translate the heat in some manner.
So yeah, multiple rigs, definitely a lot
of heat. The challenge scales up. So 10
GPUs, almost close to 2,000 watts of heat.
It is very hot, very loud. The
infrastructure needs, I mean, and that's a
serious setup. Even 30 GPUs, it's like
sometimes they go down, you gotta turn
them back on.
Some months they can run like no big
deal. And then other months it's like,
dude, every week I gotta, all right, I'm
messing with it. And it's like, hey,
honey, I'll be right back. I gotta do
something to the rigs. And it'll be like a
few hours later. And it's like, okay, I'm
finally done. There's a lot of problem
solving, but for me, I really enjoy that
because it could be a bunch of different
things.
So yes, we have smart solutions. So yeah,
maybe you got basement mining. So warm air
rises. So if you're gonna mine, put it
into the lowest point that you can. So
eventually the heat will actually rise.
Garage with ventilation. So I was mining
in my garage and so the warmer months I
was actually able to open up both garages.
And so I was able to just draft that heat
super fast, which was really, really nice.
But the problem with that is inherently
that's a warm area. So bugs are going to
naturally attract to that spot. So for the
open air sort of cases, I'd have to go in
there and get some air in a can and just
clean that all up because otherwise that
organic matter will just collect up,
create dust and eventually could catch
fire. No good.
It's one thing to get involved with
mining and tell your wife, hey, we're
going to put 10K into mining, do all that
stuff. It's another to cause a fire. How
stupid would you look, I guess?
So in hot climates, AC costs are going to
probably kill a lot of profits. But I
think that is kind of where you need to
put your engineering hat on and sort of
see how can you - so the idea here is you
got to keep the actual cards cool, not
necessarily the exhaust.
And so if you can keep that airflow,
what's called laminar, but also over the
card at that same temperature, whether
it's 80 or 90 degrees Celsius, then that's
fine, as long as it doesn't skyrocket up.
But it's definitely a hard problem to do,
so maybe mine at night.
Again, it's all about your specific where
you are, where you're located. Maybe
there's an opportunity to build some sites
on land. Maybe you can dig down in the
ground. You can actually build up vents
and off gas that heat to some sort of
greenhouse, things like that.
There might be an opportunity, especially
out here in Colorado. They grow a lot of
cannabis from my understanding. They
probably spent a lot of money on heat. So
what if they had a bunch of Ergo miners
underneath somewhere then off gassing that
heat and back into the grow house? And so
that would be a huge net positive.
There was actually - I went on a tour to
one of the dispensaries and they actually
built the heating mechanism outside of the
property, which makes no sense because now
it's not even insulated. So now you have
hot air leaving the building, going
outside to where it's cold, and then going
back in. It's like, no, you should have
kept that inside. So again, it's all about
efficiency, efficiency for the cards, but
then also efficiency from an environmental
perspective.
Yeah, right. When we do Chain Cash, we'll
buy a bunch of property and then maybe a
barter system to be like, okay, who's
going to build the deck? Okay, Mark's
going to build the mining setup, and so on
and so forth. We need a senior design
project or something, right?
So, electricity rates definitely matter
the most, right? So, 5 cents to 10 cents.
I got 11 cents. I was okay with that at
the time. And so I was running like five
giga hash, probably about a year ago. And
I was probably about like three to 400
bucks a month. I don't remember how much
ERG it was, but which is irrelevant, I
suppose now just because of the
scheduling.
I don't know if that's a typo. So what
are the rates? Many utilities charge...
oh, I see, right. So different rates. And
so off peak times versus peak hours.
And so again, going back to that sort of
LLM sort of concept, maybe it makes sense
to run it cheaper at night, the weekends,
when not using it. So it's going to be a
lot cheaper versus peak hours. And then
additionally, it's like a note about peak
hours. Peak hours are also correlated most
likely with peak temperature hours.
So it's like, if I'm in a hot environment
anyways, and then I'm also getting charged
a lot for electricity, probably doesn't
make a lot of sense to be mining during
that time anyways. And I think it's okay
to turn your rigs off. Sometimes maybe
you've had a bad month.
Yeah, so for most mining pools on Ergo,
it's PPLNS, so it's pay per last N shares.
And so N is set by the mining pool, and
ours right now is one half. And so you
could just think of this as a window. And
so say the last 12 hours are all the
shares you're going to get calculated for.
So if you just started, you're not going
to have a lot of shares within the last 12
hours. And so you get penalized for that.
But if you get onboard to the pool after
those 12 hours, you now have the maximum
full amount of shares that you could
possibly have.
But then if you onboard another giga
hash, your shares amount potential then
increase because now you have more
potential shares to be able to submit
within that 12-hour window. So if you turn
it off, and it really depends, on
Sigmonauts mining pool, it just depends on
when we find blocks.
So say for example, you're maxed out on
your 12-hour window. We find a block and
that was high difficulty. Then we have
high effort. Then we find another block
within an hour. Then we find another block
- you're going to have a high
participation because you have the maximum
amount of shares.
Let's say between the second and third
block, you are turning off for the night,
you're still going to have, say, 90
percent of that window covered because you
have one hour less, call it, or wherever
the math works out to. But then it goes
from one hour to six hours. Well, now you
have six hours left of those last shares.
And it really just depends on what the N
is. And so again, ours is one half, but
you could put like four, which could be
weeks. You could do months. So then, but
those are obviously really old shares. And
it's like, we don't really care about
that. We just care about these more recent
shares. So that's a way to do that.
So then we have solo mining versus pool
mining. So you mine alone. If you get a
block, you get all the rewards. Very
unpredictable, but really it's only
unpredictable in the sense of if you have
a small amount - I mean, I'd say it is
predictable, but it's just, you're not
going to get paid soon, because if you
have 100 giga hash, it's going to take 30
days, but you could have luck within the
first hour.
That happened to me. I was like 500 giga
hash and I found two blocks. And I was
doing a test pool and it was just me on
there. It's just like, oh, well, that
works out.
And then pool mining, depending on the
fee, you sort of split your hashrate and
then whenever anybody on the pool finds a
block, then we all split that with respect
to our participation, which is calculated
by the PPLNS calculation. And then we also
have the small fee.
So then we take that ERG reward. We
calculate that fee. The pool keeps the
fee. And then from there, the PPLNS gets
added to the shares of the database.
I thought I'd fix this, but at one point,
the Sigmonauts mining pool was 1%. It's
variable. So if you want to vote it to 2,
and it passes, we'll vote it to 2. If you
want to vote it to 0, we can vote it to 0.
Any miner on our pool, if they want a DAO
token, we'll give it to you.
So we're distributing storage rent. We
have bonus tokens, doing a bunch of other
different things. But then we also, of
course, have Herominers, which I believe
they're also distributing or I know
they're collecting Demarage. I don't know
how exactly they're distributing it.
Right, okay. Well, the way we do Demarage
distribution is we do it one for one
participation. So, for that block, we'll
calculate your participation. We'll then
take that same - we back calculate it, but
we grab that value and then we multiply
that by whatever the ERG amount we got
from Demarage.
So, if it's 10 ERG, and your
participation was 10%, then you'll get
one. And then that's paid, traditionally
that'll be paid every Tuesday, but there's
some sniping wars sort of happening.
Sorry, say that again?
Yeah, for sure. There was an opportunity
a few months ago where there was this,
CannonQ can correct me, but I think there
was like 1000 SigmaUSD in Demarage. Wasn't
it something like that? Or there was like
a thousand in token value. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. So definitely the incentive is
there. Okay, that's what it was, yeah,
SigRSV.
Okay, yeah.
Yeah. So let's see, it says Herominers,
it's 2%. I think they do - does anybody
know what their payout is? It's not PPLNS,
right? It's like Bitcoin. Isn't it like
Bitcoin pools do it? No? Okay. Fair
enough.
Okay. So yeah, talking about the
Sigmonauts. So we have a DAO run on
Paideia. Everybody has a say in the pool.
We actually have 10,000 ERGs in our
treasury, which is awesome. Only pool
right now distributing - well, that's not
true. Sorry, I thought I fixed the storage
rent. But the only pool distributing bonus
tokens to our miners.
I think at one point we had 60 tokens
that we'd airdrop all at once to, I think
at most we had 60 people. So that's kind
of cool. We're supporting the ecosystem,
so fees fund Ergo development and
community projects. All decisions voted on
by the community are all open, active,
Discord and Telegram.
We have a bunch of different alerts. So
every time we find a block. Really good
group of guys, if you're interested in
mining, people are there from all over the
world. So if you have a question,
generally somebody's on there to answer,
whether it be about mining. And something
I really like about our mining community
is I like to think that all the miners are
devs in hiding.
They just don't know it yet. They have
the technical ability to be able to spin
up a miner, put up the OS, that takes some
noodling within the terminal and things
like that. And so we were actually able to
get two of our miners to join the last
hackathon. So that was pretty neat.
And so storage rent is Ergo's unique
feature. So rent, this is also Demarage.
It's collected from unspent boxes older
than four years. Prevents the blockchain
bloat and provides additional revenue for
the miners. And so here's just some sample
current revenue. This is free money for
the most part.
It's just there. It blows my mind that
people don't consolidate their boxes that
are more than four years old, but maybe
they left the community. And so yeah, on
Sigmonauts mining pool, I wrote a script
that will distribute it all proportionally
to the Sigmonauts miners based upon our
participation in the database.
It increases your effective earnings. I
guess we're the only  well, I guess
Grayman said they're distributing it, but
equally. I'd be curious to see how
exactly.
Right. It would be good on us to put a,
from a transparency perspective, be like,
hey, this is exactly how we're doing this,
all the FAQs and stuff. I'll have to take
a note of that.
But yeah, our fee is 1%. So sorry for all
the spam of the 0.9. Our minimum threshold
is 0.5. We did create this protocol. I
don't know if it's really a protocol, but
essentially you could mint an NFT. You
could then inscribe in this NFT your
minimum or your payout threshold.
And then our system would then pick that
up based off our collection ID. And then
from there it would automatically change
your payout threshold without having to
message me or anything like that. So a
little bit more permissionless sort of
payout thresholds.
Because we have some miners, right? They
might have 50 giga hash and they might be
making 10, 20, 30 ERGs a day. And if it's
0.5, they're just getting a lot of spam.
And so from maybe even a tax perspective,
it's nicer to have it in one transaction
as opposed to five transactions a day.
Plus from the mining pool perspective,
I'd say we don't want to make five
transactions a day if we can just make the
one to save on the TX cost, I suppose.
So, yeah, if you need to get help, we're
pretty active on Telegram and Discord.
Let's see. Mining with Sigmonauts isn't
just about profit. It's about supporting
the true decentralization and being part
of the community that believes in Ergo's
vision. Mining fees fund ecosystem
development, not just corporate profits.
And then, of course, we can vote on those
specific developments. Something like,
hey, I want to do this and we're going to
spend this, it needs to be voted on by
everybody.
So if you want to get started with mining
Ergo, you need a mining wallet. So
Nautilus is what I would recommend. Get a
mining software. Really kind of depends if
it's NVIDIA or AMD. Mine to the Sigmonauts
mining pool. Check out, I think it's
ergo-miners.com is our dashboard.
Configure the miner within your wallet,
start mining and monitoring the pool
dashboard. Again, join our socials.
So here's a couple of different mining
options. Just kind of for the sake of
time, kind of get through these. So yeah,
optimize again for efficiency here.
So yeah, why Ergo? So we've got the
cooler algorithm, better for GPUs,
declining emissions, so scarcity. So I
think that's been a big thing for a while.
And so now we're actually like in the next
year, we're going to see that play out.
And is that sort of narrative true? I
don't know. We'll find out.
ASIC resistance, storage rent income, an
active ecosystem, no pre-mine or ICO.
We're gonna be mining until 2045. And
expert developers.
So resource and links. Start your mining
journey today. Comments, questions,
concerns.
What is my - yeah, I think it's pretty
cool. I think, Sigmonauts. I think we
probably have - I'm thinking about it.
We'd have two separate options and I'm
still sort of fuzzy on the entirety,
aspects, but I think we could probably
have Sigmonauts mining pool is how we run
it today. But then also...
Yeah, I think we could do that,
irrespective, but we could probably have
to do a DAO vote if we want to do one or
the other or do both. I'm completely open
with what the DAO wants to do. So, kind of
open to. So, absolutely.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, that'd be a really -
I'm not sure if mining core does that. I
mean, Geez, do you know? Like is this...
Okay. Sick. Right.
Totally.
Yeah, some guy named Oliver.
Yeah, that'd be a really cool idea. Can
you overstuff the transaction? So if I'm
in the pool and you're saying, hey, I want
to make the transaction, could I put as
much as I want in there? And then that
would essentially push out...
Right, right, right. Yeah, that'd be a
cool idea because right now for our bonus
tokens, we're doing that once a week
and...
Okay. Yeah, that's definitely a good -
I'll be relying on Geez there to help us
out.
Sweet. Alright, cool. Any questions
online? I don't think so.
Alright, cool.