Welcome to the Ergo Proof of Work
Community AMA, today hosted from Sunny.
Ithaca, my house.
I decided to come in late to work today
so we can host it from the house with us
today.
We've got a couple people joining us
right off the bat.
We've got Kushti, we've got Aberg, which
reminds me of that Hamilton song, A.burr,
right?
Aaron.burr.
Then we've got Byron as well joining us.
Good morning, everybody.
And Kushti, how are you guys doing today?
Doing perfect so 6.0 activated
successfully so it was totally a flawless
experience so yeah I had the chance to
sleep well and so on so yeah it's very
well around them and so yeah well we are
discussing talks on what to do next so
sub-blocks development and so on maybe we
will share some thoughts and yeah a lot of
talks around now is about marketing
community marketing efforts so let's have
the call maybe focused on that
specifically if there is demand to discuss
that specifically because about that
Yeah, I mean, that's always needed. It's
always hard to kick start something in the
community from the grassroots with
marketing when you don't throw thousands
and thousands of dollars at it, right?
I think it's actually maybe easier
because when you throw money, then yes,
some marketing agencies creating some
ordinary crap, right? Like, I don't know,
Super Booper Web3 project. AI slot kind of
stuff doing not known what's but super
cool by talking and Yeah, I agree.
It's not lasting.
That's kind of a short that's like
throwing That's not creative, right
because there is no skin in the game. So
yeah, I think Well, community efforts can
easily help perform that especially in
2025 because well
Paid marketing did work well. I think, I
don't know, maybe my personal fantasy is
just, but it did work well back in 2017,
18, something like that, right? When even
some paid slope in coin telegraph, coin
desk. It worked quite well, but these
days, I don't know, so we have like
thousands of different blockchain
projects, let's say, claiming somewhat
decentralization, but yeah, usually having
concentrated distribution and so
possibility to throw printed money.
basically right on paid marketing but
then yeah I mean it's just Totally
tasteless flow of low quality content
basically, right? So it doesn't make sense
to read cryptocurrency media in 2025,
right? Because of that, you just can check
buzzwords density in headlines just to...
well get the idea what's popular now and
that's it so yeah well I think community
marketing can do much better just because
of skin in the game and yeah it's more
creative by nature right
Yeah, yeah, I'd say so. I think what I
was trying to say is, while community
marketing and grassroots marketing is
difficult compared to throwing $1,000,
$2,000, $5,000, $100,000 at a marketing
firm, it is definitely more sustainable.
It's harder to kickstart that right off
the bat, whereas the big marketing firms
are, you just throw money at it, you're
done. But those are not sustaining. Burn
bright for a second catch some fireflies
even burn the fireflies with your project
and then go away, you know, so community
marketing I think it's for sure the way to
go and what Ergo has been doing forever
now people that believe in the project
come in do their part pitch in and It
spreads naturally. So yeah.
Yeah hundred percent Well, let's jump
right to let's get over the couple dev
updates that you have today And then we
can go into more talking more about
marketing after that sound good
All right, no objections. Here we go.
Let's see if this works.
The main thing is 6.0 got activated.
Check your notes if you are running. So
both 6.0 and 5.0 should be in agreement.
So I'm running a few notes of both
versions and yes everything seems fine. So
yeah it's working as expected and yeah now
we have a new parameter which is workable
by miners. So number of sub-blocks per
block to be used In upcoming sub-blocks
protocol protocol Right.
And so yeah, currently i'm working on
sub-blocks white paper What's that take to
what's that take to change how many votes
how many what percentage does that take to
change the number of sub-blocks?
So just 50 so it's pretty much like block
size so block cost limits, right? So it's
just like ordinary parameter so you can
change a little bit so by one maybe even
right so if it's 30 sub-blocks per block
on average this epoch and miners are
wanting to raise it then next epoch it
would be 31 right and then 32 so yeah it's
pretty much like block size or block cost
limits.
But yeah it's relative so one percent and
here it's absolute if my memory serves me
well yeah so it's absolute one sub-block
you can change so up or down so it could
be 29 or 31 next epoch going from 30.
Cool. Cool. It looks like you got Sigma
SDK examples recently done. You want to
talk about that and GitCircles as well?
Yeah. So, but basically it's what was
discussed one or two weeks ago. So, well,
as we have kind of treasury of different
designs, ideas, and so on, expressed on
the Ergo form back in 2019. 2020. So now
I'm basically using AI agents to generate
codes right along with tests. So sometimes
it's like pure garbage. So AI is
generating just some nonsense especially
when it comes to cryptography. But yeah
when it's possible to generate something
useful so I'm rechecking contracts.
Manually, then yeah I'm publishing and
sometimes it's working well so then yeah
I'm publishing and well I'm also checking
that tests generated are actually testing
useful for testing and testing real
properties of contracts and that contracts
are not flawed at least trivially so
Yeah, then they would be useful, right?
So there are a few examples already
published, such as whitelist transfers,
right? So global transfer policy example,
made in Pure ErgoScript. So in a sidechain
implementation, could be more efficient,
like in proposed braid design, but it's
possible even with ErgoScript, and the
example is now published. Then Stealth
Address, which is already used in some
wallets, such as Desktop ErgoMixer,
probably the only one, not sure if
Minotaur or any other wallet. is using it
but yeah now there is also contract
published along with tests. Then wallet
with daily withdrawal limit which could be
quite cool for cold wallet implementation
right if you for example having
centralized exchange then yeah you can put
funds in this kind of
a contract-protected cold wallet and then
have max spending at like 1% a day, for
example. So yeah, it could be quite useful
for centralized exchanges to use such
techniques in a transparent way instead of
what they are doing Perpetual token is a
token which can be earned. I don't know
how useful this idea is these days, but
back in 2020 there were some applications
which had need for this perpetual token
pattern.
You can use a combination of those
things, so you can combine Cold wallets
with withdrawal limits, I don't know, with
maybe even white listed transfers, right?
So you can have cold wallets with only
white listed exit options and so on. So
yeah, those contracts can be considered as
building blocks also, right? So more
complex. financial machinery.
Then GitCircles, maybe the guys will
starting to provide updates by their own
soon, but currently there is just some
small telegram group and I'm taking
updates from that. So yeah, well, we wish
you balance is now working on the website.
started today even and, yeah, he made the
last issue before deployment and, well,
Brough Etiquette is working on
implementation of state issues towards
deployment and testing. So after this
issue number 11, so the plan is to start
onboard different developing communities.
maybe for dependencies heavily used in the
Ergo ecosystem, such as Rust libraries and
so on. And yeah, that would be quite an
interesting experiment to onboard
different developers, developing
communities on Ergo.
Alright, then I made some progress with
basis Chain Cash. Some actions like
issuing debt nodes, working, but other
things are buggy, so I'm polishing things
now. Another developer started to work on
wallets, so soon probably we may show some
prototype transfers.
Did you say that Chain Cash is going to
need some agents running, I mean some
batchers running, or is that just
interacts fully with smart contracts on
Chain, no need for any batching machines
running?
So for Chain Cash, it's fully on chain.
But yeah, currently we are working on
basis, which is off chain cache, right?
Using some trackers. Yeah, you need to use
some Parties which track state of debt
nodes issued off chain, right? But Yeah,
it's open source solution. So it's kind of
like a BitTorrent, right, so you may
connect to different trackers, right, you
may choose tracker freely, you can run a
tracker and yeah, to trust in them can be
minimized, so it can be federation like
Oracle Pool or Rosen Bridge, right, so it
can be maybe done as an
something like Rollup maybe even but yeah
it's still quite an early idea to be
researched further. So yeah a lot of
options to reduce trust there but we are
starting with the simplest option right so
the idea currently is to show well working
financial systems where Money can be
created using a combination of trust and
blockchain assets. So the same idea as
Chain Cash. And yeah, so there is also
updates maybe not published even towards
USE stable coins. Well, I've published the
proposed parameters in the Telegram group
today and we are discussing them. So the
Oracle pool is running smoothly, the new
USD Oracle pool. So yeah, there is a
chance to see
deployments of the new stable coin quite
quickly. Let's see, so it's not well about
technical issues at this point mostly, but
yeah, rather discussions, politics, all
that stuff. And once done, yeah, so we
will have a new USD stable coin and the
idea of reaching and other whales around
is to use it for bringing efficient
unstoppable algorithmic stable coin
liquidity towards other ecosystems, such
as Binance Smart Chain, Cardano and so on.
But yeah, also we can use those things in
combination, right? So once you have
algorithmic unstoppable dollar, you can
use it in basis, right? So for off-chain
payments for local trading, AI to AI
payments and so on.
Kushti, what's it going to take to get
the current Oracle updated to the new one?
Just a little priority kind of thing at
the moment?
Yeah, so I think, well, so the plan is to
update the bank, right, towards using the
new Oracle, but they're compatible, so
it's just about ID to be updated. But then
there are some different parameters, such
as, yeah, we are doing some delay in the
Oracle version 1, right? And yeah, it's
also about, yeah, epoch is the same. But
yeah, there is delay.
Do you have a first time decision coming
up in a year or was that already done?
No, not quite. But by the way, for new
applications, yeah, it's better to use new
oracles, new application touches, Sigma
lock. So I haven't heard about Sigma lock
for a while.
Maybe I'll have to, I think they're
waiting. I think they wrote me last week
to set up the infrastructure for it, which
yeah. So it's probably on me at this
point. So yeah, hopefully soon.
Cool. All right. All right. We got one
more update that snuck in after last
week's update that I want to talk about
too. Cyberverse update report. Cyber
Citizen NFTs generate CYPX rewards in the
bank. That's cool. Multiplayer combat's a
big thing they're working on. The first
build has been tested. Two players run,
move, dash, attack in real time. Early
Foundation but already feels alive. Sets
the stage for larger battles. Environment
Siberia city gets animated trees and
plants. Oh, wow. Awesome Really gonna push
the video card there adds life in motion
to the world environment is improving with
each update I wonder if this will play for
you guys.
Let's see Will it play? It will not play
for some reason. I think it's my OBS
choking out. So very cool. Very cool.
Well, short update. So let's go on to the,
we were hearing some things about
marketing approaches and we just got a new
member to join hopefully the Ergo Twitter.
And I'm wondering if Aberg can chat about
his approach to community marketing.
Hey. Hey, everyone. Hi. Welcome. Thank
you. Thank you. So we started with the
Raiders group on Telegram. And we're
growing, I would say, reasonably fast.
We've got 20 members now. So just for
starting, that's pretty decent. I'm going
to create a Google Drive link, which is
going to be public, where we can upload
promotional content for Ergo. And anyone
can use it. We can post it in the Ergo
group chat on Telegram and Discord. Also
on the Raiders group on Twitter.
Can you mind explaining what Raiders is
to people who might not know?
Great, sure. So the Raiders group is a
telegram group where we can post a link
and we can set targets for how many likes
we want to achieve, reposts, and replies.
And the raid is basically where you could
click the link in the telegram group,
you'd like it, and it would go on for 15
minutes. So we can set targets, track the
targets and try to get more exposure on
Twitter. So it's specifically for X.
And then I'm going to work on simplifying
some content for non-technical people as
well, such as myself. And I'm going to be
posting that onto the Google Drive link.
And then we can also get some stuff done
for technical people to onboard some more
developers to the Ergo ecosystem as well.
So you could, you could technically work
hand in hand with the main Ergo platform
account, post things to that raid, that
kind of thing. Is that how, is that how
that would work together?
Yes, so any admin on Telegram, on the
Raiders group, I think I've made you an
admin as well, can post a link to any
tweets. So we don't want to promote trash
tweets. We want to promote good tweets. So
that's why the admins can only post the
links. And then you can set targets.
Everyone will get a notification. It will
update every time someone likes. OK, let's
say we set 15 likes. We've achieved 10. So
it will say 10 likes, 11 likes, 10
retweets, so on and so on and so on until
that raid is either achieved or it's past
the time limit. It's got to the time limit
of 15 minutes and then the raid ends.
Very cool. Anyway, this can work hand in
hand or somehow work together with Erg1?
Yeah, of course.
Of course. We could promote any tweet in
the Raiders group in the algorithm system.
Nice. So in general, it's a group of
community members that, by joining the
group, have volunteered to participate in
raids when they're present and do those
actions of the raids when they're active
kind of thing.
Yeah.
Cool. Okay.
Yeah, and it gives notifications all the
time. So they'll get notifications on
their phone and updates on how many likes
it's achieved. So it's consistently
pinging all the community members.
Oh, very cool.
Oh, that's nice. So yeah, let me put a
promotion of this group into more groups
around, including national ones. So we
have actually quite active National
groups, especially Russian, Indonesian.
Indonesian folks in particular are quite
active in marketing, right? Uleos, Qi, so
they're doing a lot. Uleos is bombing
CoinGecko all the time and so on, doing
translations. So yeah, it would be good to
get people. on promoting. I think from 20
we need to get to 200.
What I find is that sometimes the most
effective thing, at least for Twitter, is
it's the initial hit right after the post.
From the things that we've seen go big, if
we have an initial hit of quite a few
people, that seems to get it in front of
more people's eyes and then it multiplies
beyond that kind of thing. The ones that
are slow burn, they just continue to slow
burn as they go. But like the big ones, we
get a couple hundred likes right out of
the gate within, within like 20, 30
minutes. It usually goes pretty big after
that. So, so this can be, you know, really
big to help out those kinds of things.
This is great.
Awesome. Does this come with leaderboards
or anything like that, Aberg? Or is this
just, this is just community kind of stuff
with no leaderboards?
Yeah, there's no leaderboards.
Good, I hate leaderboards, but somebody
might like it.
Maybe I could find a way to keep track,
to somehow, I don't know, reward the most
active members. That would be nicer. Let
me try looking to that.
Gotcha, cool, cool, cool. I think we can,
you can probably, if you have something
reporting back to Telegram, then a bot
could read that and then keep track of
stuff perhaps. Otherwise, I think you're
pretty limited on the API access to
Twitter from what I remember. I think they
nuked it right when Elon took over. Yeah.
I'm not sure. Yeah. Cool. That's awesome.
Look forward to it. Yeah. I mean, that's,
that's kind of an easy thing, right?
You're sitting there with your phone and
you get a ping on telegram that a raid
started and you just click a button and
hit like and retweet and you're done or
quote tweet. So. I think it's a pretty
effortless thing to do there. Yeah, and
Grayman's saying, don't forget Erg-1. And
I think, Grayman, I think this sounds like
it has an opportunity to work with Erg-1,
right? So if you're doing Erg-1 and you
want to retweet one of your Erg-1 tweets,
you can bring it right in and do a raid on
it kind of thing.
Yeah, neat. Should I let should I let
iPhone into the into the chat from the
waiting room? I'm a little a little gun
shy from the last couple zoom bombs.
Can the guy be muted just and then
present in text chat for status?
I can force let me let me change the
settings here that people enter mute. Yeah
Okay, yeah, he's muted. Yep. Okay. Good.
Yeah, then we need for proof of telegram
accounts. So basically, the telegram or
Twitter.
Yeah, there he goes. That's funny. I'm
glad I muted him. And he's changing his
name. That's funny. Hang on one sec, let
me get him. Okay, he's done. It's really
funny. Good thing I, what's it called? I
brought him in muted. Did he make you his
stuff? Oh, that's funny. Wow, in there.
These people are creative. Somebody really
hates us, I guess.
Actually, yeah, that's funny. So, I mean,
some guys, yeah, actually quite nice. So
there are lots of trolls in chats. Yeah,
they're actually quite helping because
Yeah, well, because of them, now, well, we
are providing some instructions, right?
Like how to find truth, basically, right?
How to do own research without having
trust. And that's actually quite awesome
because, well, it's about absence of
trust, right? It should be. So then, yeah,
well, trials, which are, trying to, feed,
feed lies, is basically a reminder of
that. Yeah. There, there should be no
trust, right? Right. Right. Yeah. Exactly.
So yeah.
No, I think we've got a good setup here
right now for for at least verifying
people coming into the thing so the worst
that he just did is he spammed our chat
inside here that nobody can see and called
us some pretty bad names and then did some
emojis to try to lock up the screen and
then he apparently is running a script too
that changes his name to sweep him up and
down the participants list, but
I guess that doesn't work on mine because
I was able to pin him easily and get rid
of him So for sure an idiot, but what can
you do, you know? Hey Great. All right.
Well, that's always fun to try to
circumvent that every every week challenge
accepted, buddy But yeah, like I, like
Kushti was saying, I think these help,
these kinds of things help develop systems
of trust, right? Of somewhat trust of
initially having to prove yourself. So
right now the chats are muted and people
have to come in and, and actually, you
know, engage and then they'll be elevated
to able to unmute and chat kind of thing.
Yeah. So neat. All right. What else is
new guys? We got the, we've got the, Event
in Colorado coming up. It sounds like
there's going to be a bunch of beer there
after lunch. So when you guys are
listening to the chats, whether you're at
home listening to the stream or you're in
person in sunny Colorado Springs, there'll
be a wide selection of local brews for you
guys to sip from, courtesy of the
Sigmanauts. So that'll be fun.
as well as the speaker list. Let me go
through the speaker list again. Hang on
guys, I'll let you, I'll allow you guys to
unmute. All right, you guys in the chat
can now unmute if you want to chat. So the
list right now is, and let me get to it.
Okay, so we have 9 a.m. come for coffee
and tea donuts provided by the SIGS. Joe's
going to pick him up. He knows a special
donut shop, so that'll be good. 945,
you're going to hear a welcome from the
one, the only Joseph Armeanio. So that
starts at 945. I gave him 15 minutes, but
we all know Joe. This could probably take
five hours. This might take the whole day,
actually, if we can't stop him. So we've
got to stop him after 15 minutes. And then
after that, our first speaker is LGD, also
known as MGPi. He is going to talk about
gluon theorems and maybe a little bit
about his staking that he custom wrote,
but gluon. 11 a.m., I think that's
probably, I know it's before noon, but
that's when people break off to grab their
lunches and bring them back. And we'll
have the beer open by then and alcohol.
And that's when Perfect Timing 1130 Cheese
starts talking about Lithos Protocol Deep
Dive. After that, you can refill your
beers and there'll be a small break. And
that's when Cannon comes and talks about
something really cool that he wants to
show the community. I'm looking forward to
that chat too. I'm looking forward to all
the chats. It's going to be great. After
that, there's going to be a small mining
workshop with Mark that's going to be
streamed as well. All this is going to be
streamed. And then our final speaker of
the day is Ann on BR. That's Allison. And
they're going to talk about Machina
Finance, which is going to be in maybe
something else. Maybe there might be a
secret thing that he's going to talk
about. So you got to stay tuned. Depends
if Joe can convince him. And then 3 p.m.
There's going to be a live roundtable AMA,
depending on how everybody feels, if
they're not too saturated with the beer
and they're not going to make sillies of
themselves. Live table AMA, we'll stream
in as well. Everybody can chat about the
day as well as the future of Ergo holds,
that kind of stuff, whatever you fancy.
And then we break off and go help Chris
shop and Chris is going to make everybody
Korean barbecue. At dinner right at the
facility. So that's gonna be good. I
really hope there's enough beer. I think
there will be There's a big budget for
that. So everybody should have a good time
with that at least Looking forward to that
CannonQ Grayman. You guys are going right?
Oh We're unmuted. Yes.
Okay. Yeah, you guys can unmute now.
Yeah, I I'll be there. Very nice. I'm
looking forward to your talk, CannonQ. It
should be interesting.
Yeah, it will be. For sure will be. I
will be here. You're going to be that
fantastic, Grayman. But this is the first
of many, I think. It always has to start
somewhere, and these kind of meetups are
great. I was talking to CannonQ and Joe
Armeanio yesterday night, and I was
thinking that maybe next year I could host
it up here in New York.
stuff's fairly cheap around here hotels
that kind of thing and it's beautiful
during certain times of the year and we
can try to integrate some sort of cause
Cornell blockchain thing inside it as well
and and host it on campus hopefully if we
can start a group like that so so there's
a lot of potential for that as well to
gather more people as well interested in
that kind of thing so yeah looking really
forward to the beginnings of this kind of
stuff and continuing the tradition
Moving on year after year What one quick
programming note LGD is Luca So I think
he's doing gluon and I think MG pie is
talking about something about Palm Staking
or something like that or Machina maybe
Right, right, sorry, I read them as one,
didn't I? Yeah, Luca and MGPi, they're
dual-talking. I forgot about that, right.
Yep, so I think... Did we get the location
of the venue? Yes, sir.
I was laughing at you because in the
first draft of all that stuff, It had all
these details and there was no location
for the venue. She's like, what is wrong
with you guys?
It's on the blockchain, sir. It's in the
meetup chat. Go to the meetup chat,
Grayman. It's right there posted. There's
a link to a website for the venue. It's
Colorado Springs. You just show up and ask
somebody. I'm sure they'll tell you where
it is. Just yell very loudly. Joe will
hear you.
Ask the homeless people?
The unhomed, sir. I haven't offended.
Awesome. All right, what else, guys?
We've got a couple minutes left.
I applied to get Kushti a H1B.
I know, right? Somebody hire Kushti.
We're going to get that handled here,
guys.
Let's get 100 grand. We'll get Kushti an
H1B visa, and we'll get him here for the
event. Anybody got 100 grand?
Oh, but yeah, well, I need to spend some
time also, so it's not that. Easy. So
yeah, let's see. Maybe next time. But we
discussed actually also maybe something
around Anarkapulko in February. So it, it
will be, late, late probably February,
2026.
What's the weather there then? Is it
nice?
What's the location? So it's the Acapulco
of Mexico. Oh, and, yeah, it should be
nice.
Hell yeah.
I can hear the tequila agreement.
I'm looking up the weather right now
there in February. It says it is, on
average, 86 to 74 degrees Fahrenheit. I
don't know what that is in non-freedom
units. Somebody can do the calculation for
me. That's pretty nice. That's great.
Sounds like a good temperature. We have
venues down there. We got connections.
Kushti?
Let me check. So, Yeah, well, our friends
Lutz and so on, so they proposed a booth a
few years ago. I don't know what they're
doing this year. So yeah, let's think with
them. So it will be an AnarkoPulko
conference. organized by Vigilante group
and others. So, yeah, let's see, let's
see. And yeah, Vigilante also, yeah, so
they know Ergo, so they've written
something back in 2021. So it would be
good to get in touch again.
Talking about marketing, I think it's
quite easy to sell Ergo to Bitcoin OGs. At
least Bitcoin OGs, I know personally.
They're quite fond of, especially
recently, when I started to describe all
the ideas around Chain Cash and so on. How
can we realistically separate money from
the state? That's the very original idea
of Bitcoin. Yeah, well, it's a resume with
Bitcoin OG mentality. So yeah, we need to
do this for more. Definitely.
You've had success with that, you think,
Kushti? Sorry, you've had success with
diehard Bitcoin OGs?
Yeah, I know personally Wow, I mean so
public Bitcoiners OG Maybe not so OG even
probably quite different, right? So
they're playing maximalism all that stuff
But I know so when you talk with some real
OGs in person, yeah, that's that's quite
different experience actually I mean,
well, anyway, if you are not buying
separating money from states, then yeah,
well, you are not quite a Bitcoin OG,
right?
True, true. Nice. All right, well we got
10 minutes left unless you guys have
something to say we can wrap it up and
save some more stuff for the AMA the the
extra AMA on Saturday afternoon Where
everybody's half sloshed would be nice and
loose
I'm going to say I would love to see
Kushti and Joe on that Vlad podcast, the
Bitcoin podcast. Like I would love to see
that because he has long like detailed,
like they go through the technicals. I was
actually impressed by some of the things
by Casper because I never really dove into
their project until I saw the clip of what
he said about Kushti. So I thought, OK, a
little more interesting than I thought.
All right, so Vlad's podcast, right? So
yeah, Vlad is there. So yeah, he's
following me after that Casper episode. So
yeah, let's try to reach the guy. Yeah,
well, we also need to organize finally an
episode with Mark right from Kraken,
Kraken now.
Yeah, the schedules just need to align.
That's all I think I think the balls in
his let me check the Twitter I think the
balls in his court right now or it's in
our court. Hang on No, it's not every day
The balls in our court Kushti, he said I
think we were trying to decide if you're
gonna go to 2049 or not Marks at 2049
token 2040. Wait, that's over. Isn't it?
When's token 2049 Kushti
It's over. Yeah.
Yeah. All right. So let's think of a new
time. Kushti, just DM me your schedule.
Oh, so I'm flexible. Yeah. So this month
I'm flexible till 26. Yeah.
Okay. Just give me your time ranges. I'll
send it to him and we'll facilitate
something.
All right. All right. So yeah, that's
all.
Yeah. That'll probably just be you and
Mark. I don't think Joe can, Meeting with
somebody that works in an exchange is not
a good recipe for Joe's behavior, the
meaner to stay settled. So Joe is opting
out of that conversation. So it'll mostly
just be Kushti and Mark. Maybe I'll
facilitate, perhaps, but we'll see. So
yeah, that'll be great. Yep. All right,
everybody. That's great.
Thanks for joining. Maybe a CannonQ. We
have a lot of webinars. We do? Yeah. We
need to have more voices.
Let's have a roundtable with that. That's
fine. So anybody that's interested, please
pop in your interest in a DM or something,
and we'll keep track of it. And then we'll
invite you all to that talk if you're
interested in having a conversation like
that. Fantastic. Yep. Great. All right. We
will see everybody and the stream at least
at the AMA if you're not in person or the
whole day I mean with streaming the talks
Bring a glass. I don't have a glass and
Sip away while you enjoy the events of the
day folks Great. All right
Thanks everybody set up a yeah, we set up
a telegram group We probably could have
glass link it on somewhere on discord as
well So people will ask questions or you
know, if they have feedback during the
presentations Right, right. That's a good
that'll be a good place to do that.
Yeah, great I'll try to monitor those
during the presentations if people have
questions, you know remotely. Yep.
Awesome. So yeah, the presentations will
go for maybe 30, 35, 40 minutes, and then
there'll be time for questions afterwards
from either the Zoom audience or the
in-person group. So yeah, of course.
Great. Who wants to close it out today?
Kushti, Byron?
Sorry? Who wants to close it out today?
We got to switch around, Rob, in closings.
But maybe anyone has thoughts on
marketing, like proposals and so on?
Because, yeah, I mean, there are a lot of
talks that more marketing is needed, but,
yeah, well, what's... Yeah, usually those
are... What's doable? What can someone
propose?
Yeah, Kushti, it's easier to shout into
the wind than walk into the wind, you
know. So I find until somebody starts
walking into it like Aberg is, then
there's not much you can do, right? Except
for invite them to walk towards you into
it and actually do something. So I'm so
happy that Aberg is taking those reins and
doing it and going to work on Twitter as
well.
Yeah, but on this call, I believe we have
active people, right? So not just talking
for years, the chats without doing
anything.
Marketing is all about assessing the
market. Who are you talking to? And
CannonQ was sort of orchestrating some
pretty good work in that direction, but
really focused on miners. Which I think is
interesting, however, GPU mining is ever
since the merge in Ethereum has kind of
fallen off. But it's an interesting pool
of people that you could potentially draw
in because, I mean, what other coins are
strong in GPU mining? There's Ravencoin
and whatnot, Progpow, whatever. But I
think Ergo is pretty near the top. So
that's a pretty good place to go and look
for people. But if you're going to reach
out in general on X or Twitter, then
you're talking to the whole world. And the
question is, who does it get spread to?
You've got to really narrow your message
or have multiple messages and use
different venues for those or different
approaches, maybe different people.
Yeah, I totally agree, Grayman. In
regards to multiple messages, we could try
target developers, miners, non-technical
people. I think a progressive approach is
to set some KPIs for myself, for example,
and post x amount per day and try to meet
them KPIs regardless and stay consistent.
Because I'm sure you know how the
algorithm works, the more consistent you
are, the more exposure you'll get. And it
only takes one or two accounts to really
recognize the tech and the community
behind Ergo. So I think a progressive
approach will be KPIs and consistently
push content out there. and we can create
some memes, not meme tokens of course, but
some funny old school memes about Ergo,
some kind of controversial tweets, we'll
get it approved before putting it out
there, as well as pushing for the vision
and our values and what we actually stand
for.
Sounds good to me. But yeah, it feels
like X is unfortunately, you know, it's
hard to break out of the bubble of crypto
Twitter and get into the other places in
the in the glory days of Twitter before
Elon bought it. It was, I mean, there were
so many different communities. I don't
really see a whole lot of that on my feed
ever since I switched to be, you know, I
guess I get primarily crypto people now.
So I don't really have a feel for it, but
maybe a different venue. QX was talking
about Facebook, I think. Byron. I am not
on Facebook and I will never be on it, but
that's another way to go. But I really
feel like the other thing that we're kind
of missing long run is trying to reach out
in the academic world, not just towards
students, but that would be a good way to
go.
but also towards researchers and in other
fields like economics and what have you.
We have some contacts already. Well, I
mean, one of them is right here. He
actually works at Cornell. We have people
who, like for example, Shai, I think he's
some professor at Harvard. We already have
some contacts in that realm, but it would
be good to expand it. Just because even
though that doesn't lead to an enormous
amount of people coming in, it leads to a
very high quality of person coming in and
then from there you can leverage that to
go get the more people.
I think that's a great idea, Grayman.
Could we do, because I know Scala has
conferences, could we do booths at Scala
conferences? Because I'm not sure if
there's other projects with Scala, like
syntax or code, unless I'm mistaken. Could
ERG do something like that, like physical
conferences, like do booths and things
like that?
Yeah, we can try. So Scala and Rust
maybe. So Rust community is super active
now in regards with contributions to open
source. So yeah, may make sense to reach
all the circles. So developers in Scala
and Rust and yeah, academics. So initially
Ergo was well, quite well known right in
certain circles but yeah but back then I
think cryptocurrency research was more
foundational and probably more profound as
well so yeah well make sense to
to get more recognition there. Probably,
well, upcoming stable coin workshop
organized by Bruno will be helpful, right?
And then, yeah, let's think for more.
I'm still a really firm believer in that
people are lazy, right? And I see this all
the time at school, right? These kids who
There may be an event or workshop or
something that literally will help what
they do tenfold, right? Or literally is
exactly what they're interested in, what
they're doing, but they don't go and it's
not well attended. And you're like, what
the hell? And I think the same thing
happens with marketing, that kind of
thing, right? It's really hard to get
people involved, especially even more so
hard because they're not even using your
product, right? So I'm always a firm
believer as well as marketing and
grassroots outreach as just making a
gosh-darn product and getting them on
board kind of thing. Getting them using it
because at least they're using it at that
point and maybe they'll come to a
conference because they like it or want to
make it better or whatnot. But yeah, I
find that stuff tough at least outside of
the blockchain circle to get people
interested in stuff that they're already
interested in and actually using even.
Just my two cents.
Yeah, and hopefully with GitCircles and
other tooling for real-world needs of open
source developers, hopefully, yeah, it
would be a viral, right? And hopefully,
yeah, that's how we would get more
developers around. All right, let's see.
So hopefully, yeah, in like a few weeks,
yeah, well, promotion of GitCircles can be
started. Well, initially with just a few
communities to be onboard, but then more.
Great. Aberg, I'm going to give you some
delegate access later today. After I look
at your profile, make sure you're not a
crazy. And we'll see some new posts on the
main Ergo Twitter. That'll be great,
combined with the Twitter raids. And maybe
we can get Ergo One involved as well to
have them promote to send stuff to us as
well, so we can help pump them to their
project. So yeah, awesome. Why don't we
let Byron close it today? Byron, any words
of wise?
Bloody hell. Everyone be safe this
weekend. Tune into the stream. Let's have
some fun.
Thanks everybody. Have a great day. Ciao
ciao.
Thank you, Byron. Thank you, everyone.
Bye.