Hi everyone, happy anniversary Ergo.
Today I'm going to give you a few updates
about Gluon.
Gluon is a new stablecoin protocol and
Gluon Golden Ergo is the first
implementation of this protocol.
It's the first autonomous gold-backed
stablecoin.
To try it, visit gluon.gold.
To learn more about how the protocol
works, check my previous talks in previous
Ergo summits.
In this talk, I will just report our
recent progress in the research and
development of Gluon.
One recent good news is that
implementation of Gluon on Ergo was
independently audited by Krasavice Blazen
and no further vulnerabilities have been
found.
The audit included not only inspection of
the code, but also a simulation of the
protocol itself.
Here in this slide, you can see part of
the audit report and also a part of the
Python simulation code.
On the research side, we have already
proven five out of the six stability
theorems that we intend to prove.
And the last theorem is almost proven as
well.
Here you can see parts of the paper
showing the definition of the protocol,
lemma one, and also part of theorem one.
We are also formally verifying these
proofs in Coq.
This turned out to be much more time
consuming than we originally anticipated.
Here you can see the beginning and the
end of the formal proof of theorem five.
As you can see, it's almost 1000 lines of
Coq code to prove this theorem.
If we finish the proofs on time, we are
planning to submit the Gluon paper with
all the proofs and formal verification to
the first stability workshop.
This is a new academic workshop that I'm
organizing and everyone is welcome to
participate and submit a paper.
And the update that is probably most
relevant for users of Gluon Gold is the
release of the new frontend.
It's still in beta and it still has some
issues, but we decided to already replace
the old frontend because it's already
significantly better.
Notable improvements of this new frontend
include the fact that it has no dependency
on a backend anymore, so it's more
decentralized.
There's more transparency in the
calculation of fees, as you can see in
some of the screenshots here.
The dashboard also displays now the
protocol's state, showing information such
as the reserve ratio, the total value
locked, and the volume - information that
is relevant to decide whether to mint
stable coins or to redeem stable coins.
And also, one other thing that this
frontend has, which is something that
people had been asking, is a more familiar
swap style UI/UX.
That's all for today.
And for more, join us in Gluon Gold
Telegram.
Thanks.