There it is.
Welcome everybody to the Ergo official
AMA, right?
So you're only seeing me today because I
think it's a sign of the evolution of
Ergo, right?
So I am here to announce today that AMAs
in the future are going, for the time
being, moving to full-on community
peer-to-peer AMAs, right?
So that means that all community are
involved, all communities sit at the
table, and all community can have a chance
to chat with legends like kushti, like
Joe, like Dan, all once a week on Thursday
mornings.
So I think that's good news. And I think
that's particularly the path that Ergo
should take and is taking, right?
We're moving everything off EF servers
with the InfraDAO. Why not take AMAs and
move them off the official propped up EF
channel to a community event, right?
That's what we're going to be doing
starting next week. You'll start seeing
promotions about that at least five days
in advance to give you guys a heads up of
what it's going to be, when it's going to
be.
We'll start off similar to how we did
before and see how that goes with
everybody in the frame of this YouTube
channel and broadcasts at Twitter.
I'm looking forward to it. It's going to
be a lot of fun. It's always tough to
gather everybody together, kushti, Joe,
myself, Dan, with our schedules, and
figure out exactly who's going to be there
and when it's going to be there on
Thursday.
So these chats, I think, are great where
a couple of us show up next week, next
group, next week, and the community's
there.
So very community-centric, which is
exactly how Ergo should be.
Also, that being said, this AMA is going
to be very short, mainly to announce that.
Also to give you some updates on what
we're doing.
And I can try to answer any questions
that are in the capacity for me to answer.
Paul Sargeus asks, when live stream with
Mark? And he says, no, the Kraken guy.
That will be, I just pinged kushti,
actually, and Joe's asleep, so I didn't
bother pinging him, but MGPi sent me the
chat.
And so I sent it to kushti and Joe and
ask them if they wanted me to facilitate
it for them.
So I think that's great. If we can get
Mark, it'd be amazing if we can get Kraken
Mark in a community AMA, but I understand
people might want more of a sophisticated
podcast between somebody like kushti Mark
and Joe to chat about that kind of stuff.
So I understand both of them, but either
one would be cool. So yeah, let's try to
facilitate that and get that going.
That's going to be exciting.
All right, let's see what else. Ergo's
hashrate's pretty not terrible, right?
It's been down to five in the past couple
of months and the other day it's up to
seven. Again, seven, almost eight, so not
doing terrible there.
There has not been discussion given Ergo
added to Phantom Wallet, Gandalf, that I
know of. So don't have an answer for you
on that.
All right, so let me go over some things,
new things, at least on my front that I've
done recently. It's been a really busy two
and a half, three weeks with the semester
starting back up at school.
So I've kind of been just working with my
head down and popping into Ergo when I
can, but that doesn't mean that things
have stopped.
We just added a new user to a new member
to the Ergo InfraDAO, that is the Stroof.
He is, I believe he's an Oracle runner as
well. He's spun up some hardware and we
have load balance into as well. So super,
super cool.
Anybody has those URLs? They're in chat.
They're on the InfraDAO page.
You can point your Nautilus wallet or
your ErgoMobile wallet or whatever you
choose to use to the peer-to-peer nodes.
And they are geo load balanced. So that
means right now we only have East Coast of
the US and Australia. So two very
different things, and Singapore as well.
So depending on where your location is
and whatever is closest, the load balancer
will send you to that peer-to-peer node or
GraphQL or API or Explorer. So really
excited about that. Super cool.
No, Bevis, it wasn't false. We're still
on the short list per se, right?
So if you missed it before, we had
discussions and chat with, not Mark, but
Mark's replacement, whoever that guy was.
I think Joe, kushti, myself, Mark,
Blaskauer, and chats with him.
And it was tough to pin them down in
exactly what was the requirement for being
listed on there, right?
And so the thing that I spoke about in
recent AMAs was that the easiest path that
they thought forward for Ergo in the
immediate, right, long term would be the
native coin on the native chain on Kraken.
But in the short term, the idea was that
we could get Rosen-ERG from Cardano
listed.
And so then we saw Joe come up with a
proposal for Rosen Bridge to actually
airdrop Rosen-ERG to people in Cardano to
increase the wallet count.
And that's still in Paideia. So it's
interesting to hear people interested
about in chats here, but not engaging in
Paideia.
So again, what I say is if you're
interested in this kind of thing, you
should hop on Paideia and you should join
in the discussion for that proposal that
would take Rosen raised funds from the
GARD's and distribute some of them to
wallets to make that goal that, this is
named Dave, I can't remember his name,
Kraken Dave, make that goal of X amount of
wallets in Cardano that would say, okay,
there's enough wallets and holders for us
to do that.
I mean, honestly, we're, Ergo is a
different beast, right?
We're dealing with these, even the guy we
dealt with, even Dave, again, I hope his
name's correct, seemed to understand,
there was confusion at first of what chain
we were on, that kind of thing.
So once that was cleared up, there was,
oh, hang on, I gotta stop this call from
coming in.
There was talk about integration, right,
and how that works. So it was kind of
teaching him to be able to do that.
So then when he came up with the
requirements, it really felt like to us
that it wasn't like a sheet. It's not an
Excel sheet that he's looking at or a CMS
that he's looking at saying, okay, in
order to be listed, we need to hit these
marks and these marks.
It really felt like he pulled those
numbers out of his ass, to be frank.
So we're still, the idea is we still try
to hit that. It's not going to be a
challenge to hit that over in Cardano with
Rosen Bridge. And we approach with that
and we see what happens.
So I encourage you again, if you want to
see that happen, if you want to see
something like Rosen Bridge listed on
Kraken, then please go to Paideia, go
check out I think it's proposal three or
four that is up on the GARD's DAO for
Rosen Bridge, but it's obvious in the
title what it is or in the body of what
that proposal is.
It makes some comments on it and then
encourage people to vote on it, guys.
We're a community, right? Nothing happens.
We can't wait for mommy and daddy to push
us along, right?
It's up to us to take that and embrace
that. Because if we can't bootstrap
ourselves as a community, then what's the
point, right?
Augustine says, can you please explain
what this new DAO is you're mentioning?
Yeah, so the DAO is the InfraDAO, and our
goal is essentially to remove reliance on
centralized EF servers, right?
Ergo is a peer-to-peer protocol, so why
should we need to rely on a central entity
to host the shell, the core blockchain of
Ergo, the nodes, the explorers, and those
kind of things.
What the DAO does is it brings in members
who have their own hardware and have a
decent internet connection and uptime. And
we've made a package for Explorer and
Node.
And we have people to run that. And once
they're fully synced, we add them to the
Cloudflare load balancer. And as I said
earlier, geolocation spreads to those
people.
So right now, it's myself and two other
people. A third person has spun things up
on a raspberry pie, but it's just not
quite fast enough.
So they're actually going to get one of
my spare machines here. We're going to
send it to them. And there'll be a fourth
person.
There's two people actually from Cardano
Stake Pools that we're interested as well.
Once we get this fourth person up, we'll
talk to those guys again and bring those
in.
So it's looking really good. It's looking
awesome. The hope is that we have 10, 20,
30, 40, 50, it'd be amazing to have that
many people on it.
So that's essentially the start, right?
And once we get enough people running
Explorer and Node on there with GraphQL
and API, we can look into other hosting
methods as well.
Say that the Ergo Miner now wants more
robust and spread out mining core
instances. We could host those on some of
them. We can host things like ErgoExplorer
run by Aco or SigmaSpace as well, right?
That browser. So all that stuff is
possible there when you deal with open
source and volunteers, right? So that's
the idea with that.
Sigmanauts asks, we need to be louder on
social media. Who runs a Sigmanauts
account on X? It's been a week since the
last post. Please post more high quality
content in community posts.
You guys, we're looking for volunteers,
right? These things don't run themselves.
This is community organization. If you see
an issue that the posts aren't coming fast
enough and you have the time to see that
issue, then maybe you should take the time
to be a delegate of the account and post
as well.
I invite everybody that wants to post in
promotion of Ergo on either the Sigmanauts
account where you can start off. And if
you prove yourself, then we can promote
you to the main Ergo platform account.
Please, by all means, DM me. We'll start
you up on the Sigmanauts account. And if
that works, then great. We'll get you up
there.
But yeah, we need you. We need your help,
right?
Dan is sleeping, if that's what you're
asking. It's probably 11 o'clock in Japan.
Something I want to show you guys that's
kind of cool. Let me minimize my screen
here.
We're going to be doing this, hopefully
I'm going to make a push to CodeUTXO on
this at some point.
Something I've done at work here is I've
noticed that there's a ton of, there's a
good entry point videos, right?
So a lot of people have made a lot of
Ergo videos about how to set up oracles,
how to set up nodes, how to make paper
wallets, how to set up cold wallets, all
that kind of stuff. People have made
videos.
But what happens is those things can't
interface with AI, right?
So what I found is I found that I can
take, and I've done this at school first
as a test, there's a piece of software
called Grasshopper that's built into a 3D
modeling program that's a fairly difficult
piece of software, but there's a ton of
video tutorials out there for it.
So I've created subtitle files for these,
and I've scripted in timestamps and
bookmarks into every single line of the
SRT file.
And so then I've ingested that into a
knowledge base in there, into the AI. And
then when you ask it a question, not only
does it come through all the steps that it
reads from that knowledge base, but it
also gives you exact locations of the
video.
So I want you to think of this as like,
let's say I'm setting up a node, right?
There's a lot of documentation online that
the AI can access. And with the help of
these videos that people setting up nodes
and the AI knowing all the timestamps of
that, you can actually type in, hey, I'm
stuck on this part of the node. How do we
get past this?
Well, then the AI will write to you and
say, hey, here's how you do this and this.
And here's the exact spot in the video
that I'm talking about. And here's another
guy that does it. And here's an exact spot
in the video.
So it works extremely, extremely well.
It's a big project to take on. But I think
that would be very beneficial for the Ergo
community, especially if you notice, I
mean, I'm a little older here, but AI is
essentially what a lot of the younger
generation are using now for, like even
their search engines, even like just
asking stupid questions.
So it's an interface that these kids are
really, really used to.
So we can swing that around and say,
look, if you don't want to scan through 30
hours of videos on how to set up something
on Ergo or how to do something on Ergo,
then type it into ChatGPT and it'll take
it right to that 10 second spot, the sound
clip.
So for not only we can do that with
training videos, but we can also do that
with every single AMA ever made on Ergo,
right?
So now when you type into AI about, hey,
what about this in Ergo? What happened to
this? The AI can say, well, Joe talked
about it in September of 2024. In December
of 2024, he gave an update. Here are the
two links to those videos right at the
bookmark where he spoke about those kind
of things.
So the possibilities are amazing for
engagement and intake of information.
I'm going to actually show you how it
works really quickly. Let's see. I can
share my screen here. Hopefully, I still
have the screen correct.
OK, so this is based on the application
that I did for our classes here. So I can
say, how do I make a spiral staircase?
So it searches through the knowledge
base. It searches through all those SRT
files. Just imagine it's an Ergo. And it
takes you through every part of the way
that it knows how to do it from those
videos.
And you'll see each part of these lines
has an actual link. So if I click on the
demonstration, spiral will be a
symmetrical points, it literally takes me
to that exact spot in the video where it's
doing that.
Adjusting the radius and height takes me
to the exact spot in whatever video that
it's doing that.
So now, as I said, imagine that with
Ergo, with all the AMAs, with every single
video that we've ever done, with all the
tutorials of wallets or anything like
that, now, you can hit that with an AI
model and it can spit out those points for
me.
So, think about it also with somebody
trying to, we said we needed help with the
Sigmanauts account for Twitter.
Now, think about it, that person can just
go to this AI model and type in, give me
some cool things that have happened in
Ergo in the last month that I can make a
tweet about, and quote me something from
kushti too.
Boom. And I'll spit that right out for
you from all the media that we've put out,
give you the links directly to the video
so you can add that to the chat. Done.
So this is something cool that I think
you'll probably see in the next couple of
weeks or so as I'm working on it.
And once we try to host it from CodeUTXO
on a local server, the credit should be
very, very, very cheap as far as that
goes. So look forward to that in the
future.
Any other questions that I could answer
properly?
Would I trust an AI agent with my key
phrase? No. Not my main key phrase. I'd
trust it with like a trading bot,
probably. If I put a couple hundred
dollars of ERG in a trading bot and let it
go, yeah, that's fine.
You always got to think you're going to
lose it, potentially. Not just it's going
to be compromised, but the agent's going
to screw up in Dumpia or that kind of
thing. So just treat it that way, right?
All right. So just a reminder to
everybody, short AMA today. Thanks for
joining. We are moving fully to community
events after this for the time being.
So I hope to see all of you in chats in
the Zoom meeting. Don't feel like you have
to turn on your video, but please come in
and ask questions in person and join us
that way.
Continue the evolution of Ergo to the
peer-to-peer protocol and state that it
actually is and get us to a point that
really sets us apart more than we already
are from other chains right.
All right everybody thanks so much for
joining and kushti and I and hopefully Joe
will see you next week in community AMA
ciao.