before we know if it starts on there.
But welcome, everybody.
Welcome to the Ergo Community AMA.
It's like the eighth community one we've
done, maybe seventh, maybe sixth.
Today joining us, we have Grayman and
CannonQ.
Kushti was here.
I think he maybe is experiencing some
connectivity issues.
Hopefully, we'll see him back after he
gets connected.
It looks like we are live on YouTube too.
So everything's working.
Welcome CannonQ.
Welcome, Grayman.
How was the... Oh, we got Jemai coming
too.
How was the Ergo Meetup?
I guess that's a big question.
How to go from your point, guys?
I'll let you go first, Gray.
I don't know if Gray wants to talk, sir.
too much traveling, I guess.
Or maybe I have to make him, let me, I
gotta make him co-host.
I got a anti-spam protection.
All right, hit it, Grayman.
You should be able to unmute now.
It was fantastic.
I got to put a face to some names that
I've admired for a long time.
Got to talk to them with, you know, the
real-time feedback that you can only get
from a in-person conversation.
And overall, it was just a nonstop,
intense experience of learning and sort of
understanding that I've made the right
decision to join this group of people a
couple years ago.
Started with Joe giving what amounted to
off the cuff remarks.
He threw away his prepared speech.
and gave a banger about sort of the state
of the industry and why we're here.
And then speaker after speaker, whether
it was technical or not, it just got to
more and more backing for the concept that
Ergo is a truly different project, that we
are true to the essence of Cypherpunk and
that we are here to stay.
and that the ideas that are cooking on
the front and back burners are going to
change the way everything works.
I think the funny part there, Grayman, is
that you think Joe actually prepared a
speech.
I think that's Joe for you, right?
Always off the cuff, but that's always
ends up being the best, that's for sure.
Yeah, yeah, it was, it was a lot of fun.
You know, I said, you know, I was unable
to make it due to a last minute emergency.
But so I ran the show from the digital
side of the show from New York.
But, you know, sitting there all day,
waiting for
I think I made the mistake of telling Joe
that the schedule is there, but it's not
super important to not feel rushed or
anything, and that was probably the
biggest mistake of my life.
There were times when I'm like, Joe, you
ready?
You ready to go?
And Joe's like, yeah, they're all outside
for a smoke break.
We're outside.
It's probably going to be 30 minutes.
Then at lunchtime, you guys decided
instead to bring your lunch back to enjoy
yourselves out of the restaurant, which
was fantastic.
That was really funny, but we played it
and it worked really well.
But as I was saying, it was really
amazing to sit there and not be bored out
of my gourd.
These typical things that I go to,
blockchain conferences or anything like
that,
You're sitting there and typically the
speaker gets in the way of what they're
trying to convey, even if they have
something somewhat interesting to say,
right?
They get in the way either with ego or
with just trying to push something that
doesn't make sense or whatnot.
or some corporate bullshit that I just
can't sit through.
But listening to these guys talk, all the
speakers that we had, MGPi, Ann and BR,
Ken and yourself, Joe, Cheese, it was
absolutely fantastic.
Luca, everything that I listened to, I
was engaged in and able to understand.
I didn't even have to try to ask
questions or come up with any because you
guys really nailed it from your end,
keeping those guys engaged.
So that was amazing.
I just want to say you guys did a
fantastic job presenting.
It looked like you had a ton of fun.
I hope you guys stayed out of the wacky
tobacco too much down there, did you?
We didn't have the mic pointed towards
the audience.
I'm not sure that all the questions came
through, but I think the speakers did a
pretty good job of handling that.
And yeah, it was amazing.
It was anything but boring, especially
considering that a couple of these
projects are really just on the threshold
of coming to fruition, like Lithos.
I mean, this fall is going to be very
interesting for ERG, regardless of what
the market does.
Yeah.
Yeah, I agree.
I agree.
It was great to hear what's it called?
what's it called?
Lithos.
That deep dive of Lithos was, I don't
know, that was great to listen to.
Just listening to what the possibilities
are and then the kicker at the end where
this is not even Ergo agnostic.
This can be applied to any mining chain
as well.
So it's amazing that we have people in
the community and people in the
and the dev sphere here that build
because it's a great idea and then it can
help benefit more than just our wallets or
the people right in front of our faces
kind of thing.
So I thought that was really awesome to
hear that from Cheese.
What was the highlight?
What was your highlight, Grayman?
The night before for drinks.
and get our picture taken in front of
that shiny neon sign that said, girls just
want to have fun.
We were supposed to send that off to the
Cardano girls and see what they thought.
But yeah.
Sir, you sure that wasn't a male strip
club?
It's hard to pick a highlight because it
was, like I said, it was a very intense
experience.
I mean, it was nice to wind down
afterwards with that dinner.
Yeah.
Tell us about the dinner.
What happened?
Yeah.
FAKU plus Chris Ray did his, did a tour
of duty.
I think Benzo helped them to collect all
the stuff and get things prepped.
I was on KP because I was a professional
dishwasher earlier in my life.
So.
It was delicious.
It was everybody.
It was cook at the table basically and so
that encourages a certain amount of moving
around and talking to each other and sort
of winding down after all the talks.
The one regret that I have from us being
sort of disorganized about the timing of
things, I'm sure that was frustrating for
you, but we were sitting there thinking,
you know, anybody that didn't make it to
this thing, they can suffer.
You know, they're going to get to watch
this on YouTube anyway.
But my regret was that we didn't go to
the Garden of the Gods on a walk
afterwards, because by the time it was all
finished, it was time to get ready for
dinner.
And I guess a couple of people drove
there.
but I think they missed the sunset.
It was wonderful.
Awesome.
How about you, CannonQ?
Cannon, what was your experience?
I didn't really know what to expect.
The most interesting part to me was I've
watched
in recent and past history, like Luca,
Shashir, Cheese, Karat, even Allison, like
give presentations.
And I think everyone is more comfortable
with that now, which, I mean, the first
three I mentioned are all pretty young
cats for those who haven't watched the
videos.
But all of their projects
or either like in a beta like live or
about to be there.
And so the thing that every one of them
said was, I even understand it better.
Like a year ago when I was talking about
Lithos, I didn't really have it all
figured out yet.
You know, and so there's an amount of
courage that goes into even presenting a
concept that you don't have all the
details fully fleshed out or how you're
going to get there.
But then seeing those guys, that was very
impressive.
There's a lot of different
protocols, I guess, if you want to call
it that, that are coming online in the
next probably, let's say, six months,
maybe nine months, because there's
probably going to be snags at the end that
weren't foreseen.
But there's three or four that aren't,
they're not done anywhere else, you know,
in quote unquote, crypto.
Like, it's going to be interesting to see
how that goes.
It just continues to be, you know, head
down and build.
It's just encouraging to see.
So anyway, it was that was probably what
blew me away the most.
There were too many things that I enjoyed
to say, like one favorite, one of the
One of the things I enjoyed was Joe,
myself, Shashir, Luca, and Karat went to
Garden of the Gods.
And of course we were 20 minutes late.
You know, we were, I think HQ said it
best.
We were one long block away from being
there before sunset.
We missed it.
But.
It was that was fun, you know, the
getting those guys out in nature and to
Grayman's point, I wish everyone had been
able to go, but it was just, I mean, it
was late, trying to get everyone, you
know, moving around and stuff, but it
definitely has a different vibe than
trying to do everything just online.
And it was crazy.
I mean, there was three countries there,
three different countries, even though
we're out in South Colorado.
So.
Yeah, good trip.
And your talk was great, too, CannonQ.
That was fantastic to hear that that kind
of thing kind of exists already in the
fiat world without blockchain and that
there's an option or an entry point where
you could possibly put that over top of it
and offer that.
Yeah, the funny feedback
Joe's sister was there and she had had
poor experiences with barter like back in
the day like 10, 20 years ago to the point
where she wouldn't accept it if a client
asked if they would accept barter credit
she just turned the client down initially
like right there.
And she was like, you know, what you're
describing is not my experience.
And I said, well, this group in my local
region, I mean, they're really hustling.
I mean, like it's shaking hands, kissing
babies, making sure that things happen.
They're involved in almost every
transaction that's over, you know, call it
four or $5,000 just to make sure
everything goes well.
You know, so there's a lot of local
handholding on this kind of thing to make
it work well.
So where a DAO could jump in that manner,
right?
An oversight DAO kind of thing.
I think you're going to have to have even
like more handholding than that.
But I don't know yet.
You know, like I'm open to anything.
Leave room for somebody to do some work
and make some money.
And yeah.
And these guys are already making money.
you know, in a conventional database that
they host system and the value add that
was presented is pretty intuitive to all
of us, but maybe not to people that are
already in that industry.
And yet, by being in a barter or in the
position of trying to convince people to
barter their services and goods, they're
already sort of stretching what is the
normal
way of doing business in America, and so
they might be receptive to that.
I think it's a fantastic idea.
It's more of a sales job than a technical
job, although I know, and so I was pretty
excited to see how much effort you put
into that presentation and presumably
talking to these guys down in Arkansas and
Louisiana.
Yeah, yeah, well, and let me get, so
here's the highlight.
Joe's sister says that she's really
polite about it you know and she just flew
back home and she just sent a message to
Joe this was late last night he sends it
to me so before this is her quote so
before Saturday I hadn't heard the word
barter in more than a decade tonight I was
introduced to a guy
And he is leading the charge of one of
the largest global barter entities.
I mentioned very top-line what you guys
were talking about.
And he is interested in learning more.
What a crazy coincidence.
Wow.
The fates have aligned.
What are you manifesting there, Cannon?
Yeah, I don't know, man.
But it's just...
I mean, it's sort of it's a joke, but
it's like good vibes, right?
Like when I used to be on Twitter, I'd
post surf videos.
I mean, those are like the happiest
athletes.
I know they're bearing down, but, you
know, them and skateboarders got to be the
happiest athletes.
It's just good vibes, right?
Because they're doing something you
shouldn't be able to do.
And I think that's sort of where we need
to be.
And it's
Yeah, I'm excited.
I mean, it's it has to be basketball
players for sure.
For sure.
Think about it.
That's a job, man.
That's a job.
My business partner.
That's true.
I met professional tennis players, all
those things.
It's a job.
It's a business.
Surfing is a good point.
It's still sort of ancillary, right?
Like those guys are making money, but
they're not getting
You know, twenty fifty million dollar
contracts and having to change their whole
life for it.
But anyway, yeah, that was sort of the
full circle on even my little discussion
as a non-dev just for a crazy idea.
So, yeah, I just want to I mean,
publicly, I said it there before the
recording, but thank you to Joe for
You know, just saying now that sounds
cool as he and I were talking about it for
the last couple months.
He's like, yeah, why don't you present?
I'm like, yeah, I don't know.
And then I think he publicly said, oh
yeah, Cannon's going to present on this.
So I couldn't really back out at that
point.
So anyway, I appreciate it and appreciate
the opportunity.
Yeah, that was great.
Yeah, FAKU is there as well, right,
representative?
I was hoping maybe next time we can get
FAKU to talk about local trades and those
kind of things with Honey and how those
kind of things work.
And you can bring those into the
blockchain.
But maybe we can get him to talk about it
next year at the next meetup.
How's that sound, Jermai?
Yeah, any thumbs up?
Oh, did I make Jemai?
Let me see if I blocked Jemai from
talking.
No, he commented.
He commented.
Okay.
He said skater die next time.
Perfect.
Great.
That sounds good.
Yeah, I think, I think this is a great
start.
I think Kushti mentioned that he wanted
to have it in what's a Barbados?
No, some, what was the place Kushti
wanted it next year in Mexico?
Acapulco.
So it's the late February AnarkoPulco
conference.
So.
Let me check how big is that.
We may ask a route, so they visited it a
few years ago.
What conference is it at that time?
AnarkoPulco.
It's a blockchain conference there?
Or you mean just have the meetup there?
So it's...
So a lot of cryptocurrency folks there,
but yeah, it's basically anarchy related.
So not necessarily cryptocurrencies, but
yeah, a lot of cryptocurrency folks,
including organizers, which are super OGs,
Bitcoin OGs, yeah.
Oh, awesome.
Okay.
All right.
We'll get that figured out, Kushti, and
then we'll start trying to plan it and see
how it looks.
Yeah.
Let's see.
So let's have a chat with Lutz or the
telegram.
Great.
So that's where Lutz is from?
Lutz is from New York.
Yeah, so before, so now he's doing some
marketing for Komodo and before he did
some efforts for Pirate Chain and yeah,
they had a booth back in 2020 or 21,
something like that.
So they invited us Ergo community back
then, but yeah, we didn't have folks back
then around.
to join.
So yeah, not possible.
So let's check what's pirates and other
communities.
Yeah.
Not bad weather there too.
Right.
Cannon, you looked it up.
It was like 80 degrees in February or
something like that.
Yeah, I think so.
OK, I think we can handle that, right?
That's swimming weather.
Maybe not in the Pacific, but definitely
for somebody in New York in the winter.
Definitely feels warm.
Yeah, the Pacific's always cold.
Yeah.
For sure.
What else?
Ben, you were there.
You were at the meetup, right?
No, I was in New York.
Different Ben.
You're not Benzo.
Yeah, all right.
Too many Benz.
I get them confused.
Oh, yeah, my bad.
Wrong profile.
But yeah.
Oh, there you go.
Yeah, I was there.
I had a situation where I left my
physical card.
So the perfect use case was there.
What did you do?
I left my physical card and I needed cash
to make a purchase for some commodities.
Okay.
And I couldn't get these commodities in
Colorado that I needed without my physical
card.
You know, tap is everywhere.
You can have your debit card, credit
card, you know, whatever card, gift card
on there.
So I'm thinking you can pay with that.
They're like, oh, we don't accept this.
Don't comment that on my commodities.
Oh, I think I think I know what you mean,
because some some facilities don't allow
credit processing because it's a federal
crime still.
So they like cash.
I'm not going to mention what that
facility is.
So what'd you do?
You found some nice guy who does like
local barter trading with honey and you
gave him some herbs?
Yeah, yeah.
I wonder who that could be.
He's like 6'10".
You know what I mean?
Works for the CIA.
No, I'm joking.
He had his cool chill shades on,
transition lenses.
That's my guy.
So tell me the story.
You sent him some ERG?
Yep.
We made the transfer.
I got cash in person and then we made a
quick transfer.
So we got to do it in front of Anon,
which is nice.
So if he's going in February, I'm going.
That is awesome.
Did your swapper make you wait 10 blocks
for confirmation, just like the central
exchanges do before they said it was OK
and you could have the cash?
Oh, no, no, no.
They fronted me the cash because we're
all at the... That is Kushti.
Yeah, it was just off the strength.
It was just off the strength, you know.
Pre-block time.
You can see those tweets back in 21.
Proof of history, right?
Oh, that's awesome.
I paid for my share of dinner with four
silver quarters.
Oh, nice.
Did you bring some dime bags as in silver
dimes, Grayman, with you?
I brought a bunch of silver dime bags and
I've got some of those left over that I'm
not going to touch until I meet some other
people in person.
And I also brought a handful of silver
quarters and gave one of those to
everybody that spoke along with their dime
bag and paid for my dinner with silver
quarters.
In fact, I overpaid a little.
I gave them five of them.
But then Chris needed a couch to crash
on, so he gave me one back.
It was a I can't I can't pick just one
because Joe started off because I love the
rants.
So whenever we get those type of rants,
I'm all that's my type of time.
But then I like the like by the book
accounting that Kenny was doing.
But I really liked the Lithos.
But the explanation that M.G.
gave was amazing.
When he gave his explanation about how
the differences between the styles of
contracts and how they're executed and all
that type of stuff in the trees, I was
like, oh man, that's dope.
So everybody gave a great presentation.
Oh, and then Anon's at the end with the
bytes.
And then how many, 290 transactions?
I was like, oh good God, that's not even
with sub-blocks.
3,601 for a minimum, and then 16,000, I
think, was the maximum with this.
So mind blowing, right?
It's absolutely crazy.
You're talking about Machina Finance, and
that was absolutely mind blowing for me.
I hadn't really considered it before
because I'm not really interested in any
of these parts of crypto that resemble
stock trading.
I don't give a shit.
I'm here for the local exchange stuff.
But listening to that was fascinating
because I know that one thing that people
are constantly wringing their hands about
is liquidity.
And that's a system that could
potentially bring an enormous amount of
liquidity on chain passively without
investors having to actively make trades.
They just set its Machina Finance.
So basically within your wallet, without
going through central exchanges,
There's a bot that you spent a part of
your of your assets.
You assign them to this bot and you tell
it I want you to trade within a grid
against other traders who are also doing
this and maximize my ERG stack or maximize
my SigmaUSD stack or whatever it is you
want to try and trade towards and assign
it that task or maybe even just assign it
the task of just collecting at a certain
price or something simple.
But you'll be able to do that.
You'll be able to set it and forget it,
and it will trade against other people who
are doing the same thing without any ERG
ever having to leave or these other assets
ever having to leave the ecosystem.
So now when people want to make a trade,
they don't have to worry about is there
enough liquidity at this particular
trading pair or what have you.
The first thing that they're going to do
is their machine is just going to try and
execute that trade for them.
Now you can be patient because instead of
worrying that, oh shit, you know, I put my
assets on trade over and I'm waiting for
this trade to go through and I'm just
going to give it some time.
But all of a sudden the Canadian
government decides that they're going to
raid their offices.
And suddenly the money that you had
waiting for your trade is gone and you
can't pull it back to your wallet.
This is non-custodial trading.
And I don't think that any of these DEXes
are ready for what's coming their way.
Once we get that shit online, it's going
to start slow because nobody knows.
But once people figure out that that's
possible, why would you go to a DEX?
Yeah.
I mean, anybody that knows anything, why
would you go to a DEX, right?
Yeah.
And then over time is always going to be
the tightest spreads.
They can quote.
That's always going to be the argument.
Yeah, that question is getting more
people involved.
And yeah, the main thing that centralized
exchanges have is they have the ramps
right now and they control the ramps.
So Alex has mentioned a couple of times
like something like BISC or something, you
know, finding ways to go back in time sort
of.
I think that'll be key for sure.
But I want to give a big, he gets it all
the time, but Alex Kushti, with you and
the guys that develop Ergo platform, I
think everyone there came away with a
bigger appreciation for how much foresight
you guys had and adding
AVL trees and NIPoPoWs and just all these
different, you know, the ability to add
sub-blocks after the fact.
Yeah, I mean, just the way that the
protocol and the platform was designed is
we're all still scratching the surface,
but
All three of those young gigabrains, all
of them said, yeah, I think it was two or
three years in.
And I was trying to figure something out.
And Kushti was like, why don't you use
AVL trees?
And Karat was like, what the hell is an
AVL tree?
And he goes, now I use them all the time.
Luca uses it all the time for Pidea.
Everyone's using them, but they didn't
even know what they were.
And his comparison was they have the
Merkle trees and trees on Cardano.
But it's almost like it's an L2.
It's a bolt on.
So there's still an air gap between you
and that tree where on Ergo, it's in the
base layer.
It's just anyway.
I mean, all of us were just in awe of
the research and the foresight that went
into this protocol.
So thank you.
It's almost like Kushti could see into
the future, or at least learn from his
mistakes and pulled into that.
I think one thing that people should have
hopefully picked up from MG Pai's talk
At least you have a guy that works for
Palm, which is a multi-chain company,
right?
They're on Ergo, they're on Cardano,
they're on Binance.
All right, so this guy's worked with
Ethereum contracts, this guy's worked with
Cardano contracts, this guy's worked with
Ergo contracts.
And here he is telling the community,
while he mentions, you know, Merkle Trees,
also
mentions that, you know, Ergo's tech in
that matter is better, right?
Or more well thought out.
And as Cannon said, bolted right in and
not bolted on top.
So absolutely amazing to hear that from a
dev that's multi-platformed that can come
back and say, yeah, Ergo is kind of where
it's at with this kind of thing.
Byron, just interrupt us.
No hands, man.
Oh, no.
I'm going to go out to Kushti.
He was going to speak.
Oh, Kushti.
What were you going to say?
Yeah, actually, some notes I would like
to give.
But the most important probably is about
local trade, right?
So this is the thing we need to empower.
So yeah, did a lot of
updates to basis contract and tracker
recently.
And now, Grayman, I'm going to put silver
sense document in the Chain Cash repo, if
you agreed on that.
And then, yeah, I think to add details
and yeah, try to get it technically sound
right and then implementable.
What do you think about that?
You can do whatever you want.
That three paragraph thing that I put up
there was just a summary of a bunch of
other stuff that I've written.
I've been trying to assemble something a
little bit more presentable in general,
both from like the 30,000 foot
perspective, but also one from the vendors
perspective.
I like to think of things in sort of game
theory like who wants this and why and how
are they going to use it?
So I have more writing
Already done, but it's not organized
enough to commit to any sort of public
documentation.
But if you want to grab that and run with
it, go for it.
I mean, there's nothing that I said in
there that I think is wrong.
I just think it's incomplete.
And also, you know.
Silver sense depends on some stuff that
that just doesn't exist yet, including the
work that you're talking about doing, but
also just fundamentally.
I mean, it needs Dexy Silver or some
other
Silver stable coin that is independent of
the mechanism proposed in silver sense and
which is redemption by actual physical
silver by the issuing by the one that
issues the note.
But at the same time, I mean, forward
motion is forward motion.
So go for it.
Don't let me stop you.
All right, so let's try to understand why
it is incomplete, right?
So yeah, I need to get through details,
right?
And yeah, about Dexy Silver also in the
Gold Oracle Group, we had discussions just
yesterday or today.
depending on a time zone, merging silver
oracle code into the oracle pool
implementation and then it's possible to
run the silver oracle pool and then it's
just a question of
liquidity bootstrapping rights to launch
Dexy Silver or Gleon Silver.
Then, yeah, I also recorded recently an
implementation of that scheme I've
proposed at some point on Ergo forum about
making insurance with digital commodity
for a physical
one, right?
So it was about gold, like doing
insurance with digital gold for a risk of
physical gold non-delivery.
So maybe it would be useful as well,
right?
In the context of SilverSense.
Yes, it will.
I was thinking about that paper because
it was speaking specifically about volts
and how they would use it.
And the entire point of SilverSense is to
give a special status, but also some
responsibilities to vendors as opposed to
customers.
So they all use it, but the vendors are
the ones that sort of act as the
distributed banking system.
And so they would need, they would use
this essentially as a way to make it
convenient for trade between each other
and with their customers.
And also as a sort of a form of
insurance.
And so, you know, when they're trading
with other vendors.
So I think, yeah, that that definitely
relates.
And then there's also the reputation
system issues that would have to go into
it.
So when I was handing out these dime
bags, I was I was basically saying it was
essentially just a little bag.
And, you know, for any foreign viewers
that don't know a dime bag is in the old
days, it was how you bought pot if you
were just buying a little
And so, but these were, there was no
marijuana in this.
It was just a silver dime and a paper
wallet that I printed using the MewMart
Paper Wallet tool.
And those paper wallets contained about
as much in tokens as the value of a silver
dime at the time that I minted them.
And so now the race is, which is going to
be worth more per year.
And silver's off to a good start, but
we'll see.
I'm betting on ERG personally.
In any case, I told people, first of all,
don't put anything valuable on that paper
wallet, because I got the keys to all that
shit.
And don't tempt me.
And secondly, SilverSense itself is a
ways away from implementation.
It's an idea right now.
But eventually, it's something that makes
sense just because we have this asset here
in America that I don't think is very
common of just this very large
and already distributed current tokenized
currency that's uncensorable.
So it's kind of a cool asset to take
advantage of, but it'll take some time.
We got to wind it up.
Doesn't happen without forward motion.
So like I said, do whatever you want in
terms to push it forward and I will keep
growing as I can.
That's awesome.
Byron.
You can let T-Maz jump in there.
I think he was, or Kushti.
I'll go after everybody.
Whoever wants to chat, just jump in,
guys.
Go for it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, Grayman, so, yeah, let's put some
more meat there, right?
So, yeah, a lot of code get done
recently.
So, yeah, now we just need to connect the
dots, right, and understand, well, the
missing parts and the...
Yeah, so Thomas authorized Kent.
On the note of the silver sense, I've
actually been trying to develop like a
prospectus to send into local credit
unions and like gold or coin shops.
So my idea behind it is kind of like what
Grayman was thinking, you know, like a
local distribution hub of sorts almost.
So
The only thing is with it is that it's a
little bit confusing, like how you guys
were speaking about the bartering earlier.
You know, a lot of people are kind of
like apprehensive, like, oh, this is on
the blockchain.
And then they get like a little bit like
kind of sketched out.
But I think overall, like given enough
time, there's really no way we'll be able
to get any large, like a tier bank to
support any of those kinds of transactions
just simply because
they just don't want to unless they have
a contract with somebody that's like an
insider thing like the DEXes basically
there's really no possible way that that
could ever be achieved so the next best
bet I figured is like local credit unions
like for example
This is different than like gold or
silver, but this is like even an expansion
upon the idea.
Say you have like a thousand dollars of
like silver or you buy like some beater
piece of shit car that you take into your
credit union and you give them the title
and then they'll give you a loan based on
that amount.
But that can basically be like kind of
like a interactive way to like kind of
ATM.
transact via Ergo so like if you go to
your local credit union or your coin shop
and on on top of that like with the coin
shops they could even be like custodial
holders for the chain so they could get
like incentivized like if you pay for an
ETF like I think it's 0.05 percent for
like holding fees and stuff because
From what I have talked to the shops
about, that's their main concern for the
ones that there's actually a fair amount
of people that are interested.
They would just like a prospectus for it.
So the main problem with them though, was
they were saying the amount of insurance
extra costs for the amount of inventory
added, there would need to be a way to
cover their insurance costs, obviously.
So that way they don't just have a whole
ton of gold sitting there for Ergo.
That's not insured.
But that's kind of like the route that I
was thinking about going down with like
how to implement Chain Cash and things
like that into actual function.
So that's a little more centralized than
I'm thinking.
But I acknowledge that some degree of
centralization is necessary.
So I'm a little less centralized because
I'm thinking this is not going to be
handled by credit unions or coin shops.
It's going to be handled by the vendors
that want to transact in this stuff.
And the most valuable thing that's on the
network is not going to be the silver
dimes and quarters or the silver cents
tokens on Ergo.
It's going to be the goods and services
that they're trading for those things by
definition, because that's why people want
to engage in that trade.
So it distribute also by making it silver
cents instead of gold or like larger, more
numismatic silver or other precious
metals.
By just making it this simple crappy junk
silver, right?
It makes it so that you can't really
accumulate enough of this to become a
target for, you know, organized crime or
the IRS.
But I repeat myself, you know, it's it's
more of a like a local commerce, small
amounts of money.
But if it caught on, those small amounts
of money have access
to about $15 billion worth of these
tokens that are already spread all around
this country.
So no bank, no credit union needed.
The vendors are the banks, the ones who
are selling their services, which is the
valuable part of the whole system.
That's what makes an economy.
It's not money.
It's the goods and services that are on
exchange.
Money is just the token that moves it
around.
Banks and coin shops love to gather that
stuff in and think about how they can
profit and make an economy off of money.
But the real economy is people cutting
hair, moving furniture, building things.
That's the economy.
So if you design it in such a way that
the people that are doing those things can
be the ones who are maintaining their
small portion of the bank, leaning on the
blockchain for the creation of this
credit.
And for also accounting for, you know,
the distribution of these of these tokens
and then they just have to keep enough on
hand that they can redeem for like if
another vendor gets enough of these of
their silver cents in their hand, they
come back and say, look, I love you and I
love your haircuts, but I've got like $10
and silver cents here and that would get
me haircuts for the rest of my life.
How about you just go ahead and give me
the silver so that I can go and
and buy something else with it for
somebody that does not yet believe in
these silver sense.
And so that distributed issuance and
redemption is what makes it such that you
don't need credit unions, coin shops, or
anything quite that centralized.
It's still centralized, but I mean, it's
not totally distributed to the leaves of
the tree.
I mean, the customers get to use this
stuff and maintain anonymity,
But the vendors themselves are the ones
who are kind of centralizing their notes
and promising to redeem their notes and
putting a time frame and a physical
location where they would do that on
chain.
So, exposing themselves to the world in
the sense that that information is going
to be out there.
You know, philosophically, I agree with
you, Grayman, but I don't think they're in
opposition to each other.
So they can coexist different use cases,
different assumptions and fees for what
you do.
So that philosophically, I'm on board
what you're saying, but they can coexist
with each other.
And but I agree with you saying.
But I kind of think of the coin shops
almost like a local chime ATM service.
Like if I want to go sell silver as of
right now, there's literally no way for me
to do it on the blockchain peer to peer
until Chain Cash comes out.
And even then it's just algorithmically
pegged.
Like it's not like the actual asset of
silver or the commodity of silver.
So in a way, I feel like you have to have
like,
a minute physical distribution hub they
could I get exactly what you're saying
instead of them actually being like the
primary vendor they just use the service
in order to distribute it but I do like
with Byron like what he's saying I think
that there should be a way to at least
like partially incentivize somebody to be
a vendor for it all by not giving them too
much power over
The network in any regard basically just
simply like i was saying earlier like a
small like point zero five percent fee of
like whatever transaction costs they
handle.
On the network and like a gross value
basically.
Well, they're collateralized.
So their commodities that they want on
chain would be collateralized.
So if someone wanted to purchase that
collateralized form, they would redeem it
there.
These are just public vendors, just like
a store that you know you're able to do
this action at.
The whole point, what Grayman is talking
about, the everyday person is going to do
what Grayman's talking about, these small
amounts, but in the case that Grayman
accumulated over 40 years and wanted to do
something for a large amount coming out of
training, he would probably go that route.
So they can coexist.
They're not in opposition to each other.
They're just use case defendant.
Like right now, you could get $100
Face value for you know 3300 bucks from
one of these coin shops.
So yes, they're going to be the ones that
are going to distribute a significant
amount of actual physical silver.
They're already the concentration points
for this stuff.
So when I say that it's a pre existing
well distributed tokenized.
Uncensorable currency.
It's pre distributed, but let's face it,
there are whales and there's, you know,
There's a lot of it out in people's sock
drawers, but people don't really think
about this shit right now.
If it changed and became something that
was used on a regular basis by people,
that would be because it became either a
necessity, which it might, if there were
like an extended power outage and internet
outage, then you might be trading dimes
and quarters.
But also it might just be because it
becomes more convenient.
And that's the point of Silver Sense is
that it just becomes an app on their phone
that looks like a frequent customer card
or whatever from their perspective.
And so they're just carrying that around,
but it's keeping track of, and they can
use it at other vendors, but it's keeping
track of value.
And so the guys that are the vendors for
this, they might need to go and talk to SD
Bullion or to their local coin shop
about getting enough so that they have it
on hand to redeem.
But again, the amounts of money can't be
that large.
That $3,000 sack of $100 face value is
not something you're just going to carry
around in your pocket.
And that's only $3,000.
Silver is just not that dense of value.
And so it protects you from getting
involved in the types of trading that
attract criminals and problems.
It becomes a waste.
Silver has long been
the coin of gentlemen, the coin of people
just trying to get about their daily day.
Gold is for kings, silver is for
gentlemen.
On the whole note of like the silver
sense thing too, I was also thinking, this
is kind of like where I get my idea from
for like my outlook on it.
So for instance, I do a lot of scrapping
like with scrap metal and like gold
recovery and such.
Basically, there is, unless I sell my
boards directly to a board sort, board
sort, they'll actually give you sometimes
$100 a pound for raw gold fingers.
But there's really no way to transact
that value into cash unless I give it to
the vendor to be able to sell it.
Like realistically, nobody's really going
to go looking on chain on Ergo right now
just for like a single like, okay, oh, I
could buy scrap metal here.
Oh, I could go buy silver bullion.
or whatever.
And also too, there needs to be a way to
like, if I'm buying, part of the reason
why scrapping is so attractive is because
like if I have the gold or if I have the
copper just sitting there, that's
basically as good as just like $500 in
cash.
If I have $500 of copper, all I have to
do is just take it to the scrap yard and
they'll just give me the cash right there
on hand.
But like what if I want SigmaUSD for it
or something instead like what if I want
Ergo SigmaUSD or I want Ergo tokens, you
know, that's where I feel like the thing
like silver sense and like that whole kind
of like Chain Cash idea would be really
useful there for vendors because then it
gives them an easier way to
like basically move value around without
having to use like a traditional banking
system and it's all tied into RWAs.
Like I was saying earlier, you know, you
could even expand upon it even more.
Like I'm pretty sure basis is doing this
or at least into the future.
It's probably going to be the plan to
like be able to tokenize.
Like if I want to, reverse mortgage my
house to Grayman, for example, I can sign
the deed, put it up onto.
Like a DAO.
Right.
Then the DAO overview is like, okay,
yada, yada, he's got the title.
Here's bill of sale.
Here's everything.
And then it goes into a trust on, like a
legal trust.
This is why I say like certain things
need to kind of be done off chain or else
there's no like legal backing for it.
Cause who's to say I actually have to pay
gray, gray man, my house, if I default on
like the $250,000 of loan that he gave me.