This is Timer here and welcome to my Ergo
Hacks submission, the Sigma Quest.
This is like my very first project. I had
a lot of help from some friends. And so I
just want to say thanks, Mark the Shark.
CA, thanks for helping out. Also thanks to
Claude, if Claude is listening.
Cursor, I vibe coded the heck out of
this. This is really like my first project
where I coded anything. And there's like a
minimal amount of me getting in there and
kind of figuring out patterns and figuring
out what patterns was broken.
But I still am not a developer and so
this may be simple and sloppy compared to
a lot of other stuff, but I'm proud of it
and I hope you all have fun playing my
game.
Alright, so first of all, yeah, thanks
everybody who contributed to our honeypot
here. I'm going to bump this up to about
200 ERG before it gets going and yeah, so
the first person to complete the game is
going to win access to that wallet.
So let me just walk you through a little
bit. Let me show off the vault first. So I
coded this up and it reads that honeypot
wallet and displays an accurate depiction
of all the coins in the wallet. And if you
win this game, all you have to do is write
down all the seed words that you get along
the way and then you can restore that
wallet in Nautilus and all these coins
will be yours.
I have a quick little guide for folks who
might be new, how to get your Nautilus
wallet and how to play the game. The game
is going to cost 10 ERG to play per game.
There's three games. So with perfect play,
you'll do it in about 30 ERG and you'll
take home at least 200. And yeah.
Each of these games is quite different.
I'll kind of walk through them a little
bit. I don't want to give away a whole
lot. But yeah, let's check them out.
So here is my game page. And you can see
that there's three games. This first game,
and I'm not going to show the title even
because it's going to kind of give away
the concept and people can think about it,
but in this one, there's some logic and
the AI, and you're pretty much talking to
the AI and trying to understand the
password to get out of your cryopod.
So you're stuck in a cryopod trying to
get out and it'll tell you if you get it
right or wrong. And so it's you versus the
AI here. And the goal for the user would
be to send a message that has all five
seed words in it in the correct order. And
then your character will be released from
the cryopod. And it'll confirm that you
have the first five seed words.
And the second game here. Well, so the
second game, you could play it in any
order. But I worked hard to make a nice
little narrative. So do it in order.
Now, the second game is quite different
than the first. This is sort of like
Oregon Trail, the old text-based game. But
see, Oregon Trail was really deterministic
and everything was preprogrammed. So I do
have a path that you're trying to follow
as you escape this ship.
So the way it'll work is you first, let's
just do this. You log in, send your ten
ERG and the game will start up. Okay. Now
you can read, read the narrative and then
you'll get some choices. And depending on
what your choice is, that's like kind of
going to be the outcome. And you're trying
to find the correct path out of the ship.
And so that sounds just like, however, if
you make an incorrect choice anywhere
along this path, this is where the AI
comes in.
So I've kind of designed this to trigger
a prompt to the AI that gives context
about where you are in the story and
what's around you and what that bad choice
was that you just made. And so it'll
invent a way to kill you that fits that
narrative.
So every time somebody dies in this, it's
going to call Claude and Claude's gonna
come up with some new way for you to die
and it's pretty fantastic actually it
works great. I was a little skeptical at
first, I didn't know how well it's gonna
work, but it's really great really
creative so I encourage you all to try
this one out.
This game is structured differently than
the first one. So you just pay 10 ERG to
play this game. And if you die, you have
to pay another 10 ERG. This one, you do 10
ERG for 10 messages while you're trying to
figure out the password.
At the end of this game, you escape the
ship. You'll receive your seed words. And
then this final game, this is after you
escape the ship. Obviously, you're in a
little spaceship here, a little shuttle.
This one is like a combination of the
first two games, so I think it's really
cool. It might be the easiest game of the
three, but it's to me the coolest because
it relies the most on AI.
You've escaped the ship and you're going
to encounter some challenges along the
way. And the AI is going to be presenting
you with these challenges. And you don't
have a structured response like you do in
this one. You just have a chat field. And
so you're going to enter your solution to
that problem, to each of these problems.
A lot of times there's not really a right
answer, not like one right answer. The AI
is gonna be the judge of if you should
succeed or fail through each of those
challenges. It's pretty consistent. I've
had it give me like, maybe some answers
that worked most of the time, once or
twice that same answer didn't work in play
testing, but it's pretty straight. I would
just say like, give it a good answer and
you'll move forward.
And then there's a final boss here that
is pretty cool. I won't say too much about
it, but this final boss is actually
inventing new, it's prompting Claude to
create a new question every time somebody
reaches that level.
And so the final section is going to be
the boss asking you some questions,
they're going to be hard, but the answer
is going to be the seed words, okay, or
one of the seed words. And so you'll need
to just respond with one seed word at a
time, and it'll confirm or kill you
creatively, as I mentioned.
And yeah, if you make it all the way,
you'll have all 15 seed words and you can
jump back to the vault and claim all these
coins, right? So super fun.
It is going to be a bit of a race. I'm
going to try to advertise this a little
bit so we can get some people and do just
like one release. And like I said, every
time somebody plays all three games,
that's 30 ERG. So even if we had 10 people
try to play the game, that's going to be
like 300 ERG that are getting pushed into
this. So it could be quite large.
And the games are not that easy. So I
hope it's not that easy. If you all solve
this in an hour, it's going to hurt my
feelings. But I hope you have fun. Nothing
else.
So here is my GitHub. I forgot to save
something I was doing here. Here's my
GitHub. I am not making this public
currently because people would be able to
just look at the files and see how to win
the game. But as soon as somebody wins my
pot, then I'm going to do that.
But what I have done here is really tried
to make it so that somebody like me who
doesn't know anything can look at it. And
I even created this developer overview so
somebody could take this - I forgot to
scroll up. Somebody could take this, feed
it to Claude or GPT or whatever, and they
should be able to just solve all the
problems that they need to implement a
game similar to this.
I mean, I imagine it could be quite
different because I just came up with it
and vibe-coded my way. So you can see
everything from my file construction to
how I set up APIs and commands that I
gave. I cleaned it up with all my
sensitive information, but there's even
like all the commands that you would need
to run this and server commands.
So if you have your server up and
running, that's like, here's like a whole
menu of things that you can do with the
server. And hopefully that'll help
somebody who's brand new, just kind of see
what it is and get the concept and build
something cool on Ergo.
I think it was not as hard as I thought
it was going to be. I'll say that. But it
was long. It was longer than I thought it
was going to be. I've learned a ton. I've
probably 10x'ed my knowledge of how to
code and create things and connect to the
blockchain, submit transactions.
And I'm starting to understand now kind
of everything I don't know a little bit
more about everything I don't know and I'm
excited to keep going and keep building on
Ergo. So that's my Ergo Hacks submission.
Thanks everybody. I hope you enjoy my game
and best of luck to you.