Okay, so here we are on the computer.
Now, I've got my Ergo Mempool website
open, and this is really what it looks
like.
Now, let me talk you through some of the
things.
Here at the top, I just put a temporary
logo here at the top left.
I can probably do a better job at making
it pretty, not really my strong suit.
I've got some buttons. I'm quite keen to
show you guys how these buttons work.
There's a test transaction, so that's
basically if you want to send a test
transaction, see it pop up in the mempool.
You can also connect your wallet. So
again, I'll show you guys how that
functionality works.
Again, pretty cool. I'm super stoked that
I managed to get it working.
So here at the bottom or just below that
is the block section.
So these are the mining blocks. So on
Ergo, more or less every two minutes,
there is a block.
So on the left-hand side here is the
block that is yet to be mined.
The next to it is in purple here, all the
four blocks that have been mined.
So you can see the block numbers
associated to them.
Underneath it, it's showing you the
actual size of the block.
So what you would see here is a typical,
I think the max size of an Ergo block is
two megabytes.
So you can see that you just saw the
animation as a block got mined.
So anyway, so if I come back, the size, I
think an Ergo block can hold two
megabytes.
So you can sort of get a feel for how it
is utilized or how full the blocks are.
Some of the stuff that I would love to
add in the future is sort of a visual
indication around how percentage full a
block is based on some animation.
So that's some stuff that I would like to
do.
Underneath that is the total reward.
Now, what I'm showing there at the moment
is a combination of let's call it the
subsidy or the block rewards which at
least at this specific point in time is
about 15 ERG and then at the bottom is all
of the transaction fees so it's not an
awful lot transaction fees for the miners
at the moment, but that's sort of what it
is underneath that I'm showing the amount
of transactions within the block and then
sort of the time since that block and then
the mining pool and associated or that
found that block.
So I've got sort of addresses around what
the mining pools are and then I've got the
little logo next to it.
Again on these blocks you can actually go
click on them and it should show you the
transactions that make up that specific
block.
The total fees as you probably saw from
my screen. I'm a big fan of the Sigma
Spaces website so I've got most of my
links pointing to this at the moment until
I further build out my own type of view of
this information.
So that's sort of what this top section
shows.
Again, some of the cool stuff here is a
little animation. As soon as a block is
mined, you can see it sort of shifting
across.
Now, underneath that is the mempool
visualizer.
So this is again, at the moment, it's
showing you the mempool on Ergo.
So for those that don't know, these are
transactions that people have submitted
that is yet to be put into the blockchain
or on the ledger.
So they're sort of in limbo here at the
moment until it gets picked up.
Hopefully with sub-blocks in the near
future, I'm not exactly sure how this is
going to impact this application but I'm
sure I'll figure it out now so some of the
stuff that you see in the mempool
visualizer and again I've played around
with a lot of things here I actually want
to make it a lot prettier than what it is
at the moment I was thinking of tetris
game or some building happening here with
the blocks just to give you a little bit
more information, but you can get a view
of how many transactions are waiting at
the moment.
You can see that is sort of correlating
to what is in the block.
I've got two types of formats here based
on the size of the block.
So you can see this one is bigger, so 629
bytes versus 630.
You can also do it on value.
So it gives you an idea of how big these
transactions are or how small they are.
So this is the mempool visualizer.
Again, I'd love to make this a little bit
better in the future or make it more fun.
There's another block that literally just
got mined.
Now, what you see at the bottom here,
again, is just these transaction IDs at
the bottom.
These are the transactions that relate to
this.
Again, I can click on any one of these,
then it should open up, again, the Sigma
Spaces view of that transaction.
That's what that does for me at the
moment.
This is the main aim of the website or at
least the minimal viable product that I
developed in the last couple of days to
get it up, but it literally just shows
this button.
At the bottom here is the link to the
GitHub.
This is obviously open source. Anybody
can go ahead and see how bad this is.
Again, I'm not really a developer.
The real developers probably looking at
this thing and saying, oh, this is the
worst thing ever, but I'm super proud of
it, created it.
But again, it's not the end, it's really
the start.
But this is the GitHub, this is open
source, the last bit of code I committed
earlier today to sort out that block
transition that you see at the top, so
make it a little bit smoother.
I also have this page I'll probably take
away once the Ergo hack is done, which is
just the presentation section, which I got
AI to go and create this for me.
So it just literally just shows some of
the features and all sorts of fluff
associated to the website.
Again, I probably don't need this much
longer.
And then there's a donation button.
So again, that talks to you some of the
functionality of the tool, which I will
show you guys next.
Okay, so let's test some of these
features.
So as I mentioned this is the mempool
visualizer.
So there is a couple of websites
available on Ergo where you can have a
look at the mempool.
And they basically just show the section
here that I've got at the bottom.
So at least now you get them in a block
format.
But some of the other cool stuff is what
I wanted to show you guys.
So what I'm going to try and do is click
on the test transaction here.
It's going to say, oh, I need to go and
select the wallet.
So I've built this at least with the
Nautilus integration.
I'll talk about some of the tools that I
used.
But I first need to connect the wallet,
so I'm just going to hit Connect here.
Unfortunately, I've already connected one
of my Nautilus wallets, so it remembers
that.
So it's probably something that I need to
go and look at or file under bugs that I
need to clear the cache as soon as you
disconnect from it.
But yes, this is one of my testing
Nautilus wallets.
I'm going to click on the test
transaction now.
It's going to come up with a small amount
of ERG and then a wallet.
So you can actually change this wallet
address in case you wanted to send it to
some different wallet.
I'm just defaulting a wallet. I don't
even think this one is mine, but either
way, we're going to send a small amount.
So I'm going to hit Send Transaction.
It's going to build a transaction at the
top. It's going to ask me to sign.
So it shows you the details. So you can
sort of see exactly how much you're
sending.
I'm going to go and put in a password.
And then I am going to sign it.
So what that does, you can see there it's
now created a test transaction.
So if we give it a couple of seconds,
hopefully soon we should see at the back
end I've got a couple of APIs.
So most of the APIs is built in Python.
So it's going to go and hit the main
explorer and go and try and find all these
unconfirmed transactions.
So basically everything that's within the
mempool.
At the moment, I'm just pointing it to
the main explorer, I guess.
If I did point it to my own node, it
probably would be a lot faster.
What I do expect here is in the next
second or two, it should go ahead and
create a transaction, and I should
actually see it in here.
Every couple of seconds, that API is
going to go and have a look and see if it
finds any new transactions.
I can force the fact here. So I can go
ahead and refresh.
Again, I'm going to go ahead and do that.
At the moment, it's not picked up my
transaction just yet.
So we'll give it a second. And I guess
I'll talk to the other function here.
So what I'm going to do is also donate.
They work very similar.
So I'm just going to go click on this
Donate button here just to show you that
while we wait for that transaction to pop
up in here.
See if I hit Donate. Again, same type of
thing.
This is actually definitely one of my
addresses that I know for sure.
So I'm just going to go and put in. I'll
just hit Cancel for a second.
So as you can see, at least that test
transaction is now popping up in the
mempool.
So what you can see here is it is
highlighted here as a gold color within
the blocks here.
If I hover my mouse, you would see there
is my test transaction.
You can see it's also labeled it as a
test transaction.
So it's pretty cool. So it highlights. It
does two things in this visualizer.
Number one, if it finds a transaction
that you have created, it's going to
highlight it.
It will just be this gold color, what
you're seeing here at the moment, or
that's what it is.
And it will highlight the transaction in
the list.
If it is the test transaction that you've
created, it puts that little, I don't even
know what the English word is, that little
probe thing inside of it.
Now, the donation works basically the
same.
I'm just going to go back and donate
myself.
Also, a small amount, I'm going to hit
Donate.
It's going to build the transaction. It's
going to ask me again to sign that
transaction.
I'm going to do exactly that.
Then it's going to submit the transaction
starting with 2E3733 or whatever.
Again, similar thing is we just need to
be a little patient, but that should also
pop up within the mempool.
So it's pretty cool.
At least I am super excited, I know, for
real developers. And I'm not a real
developer.
By nature, I don't develop in my day job.
I did study a little bit of development
in the past.
So you can see our previous transaction
got confirmed. Our transaction is gone.
It is now within this block.
But what you can see is the donation
transaction has popped up in here.
So it's pretty cool. So it's got a heart
here.
So again, this is just sort of
visualizing that type of thing.
So again, I think it's super cool that
you can create the app that connects with
the Ergo blockchain actually create and
submit transactions.
So it is pretty cool.
And that's really what the functionality
is looking like at the moment.
So again, I'm not a real developer on a
daily basis.
I did study a little bit of programming.
I've got a Bachelor of Science degree in
IT, which had a major in programming in
Java, but it's been 20 years.
I haven't touched a code at least for
work related stuff so I don't code for
work but anyway so that's sort of what it
looks like there's a lot of things that
I'm hoping that I can improve but at least
for this week's project this is sort of at
least what the functionality looks like
and again to recap basically just looks at
the mempool gives you some information
around what was the latest blocks who's
mined how much transactions was in there
what was the fees that's sort of the
visual cues again if it detects your
wallet if you've connected your wallet
that is it's going to highlight at least
some of the transactions here associated
to your wallet okay so next up let's talk
about tooling so how did I come up with
this so no surprise I have used I mean I
just use VS Code.
So it's within here, I publish it from
GitHub or to GitHub from here.
In terms of AI, what AI have I used to
help me create this?
I definitely use some AI, as I mentioned
before.
I'm not really a developer in day to day,
so I'm definitely rusty, but I get the
general idea.
Most of the AI, let's call it 90% of the
AI, I've used via continue.
So I've got Ollama installed on my
computer and I host all my own models.
So as you can see here, if I go to the
model section, the main models that I've
used is Qwen 2.5 Coder, the 14b model.
One of the other ones, I guess it's not
in here, and then let me just drop down so
you can actually see it, is the DeepSeek
one.
I think the DeepSeek one, at least from
an open model perspective, is probably the
best one, or at least in my opinion, is
definitely better than Qwen 2.5, but it's
hard for me to run that.
Now, how it works, it's really cool,
super interesting.
So if I go back and go to last session or
just close this model and just go back to
chat and then ask it a question.
So if I just start a new question and say
something like, I don't know, how do you
start a Flask app as an example.
So it's going to use that now.
And if I open up my task manager, you
will see it hit my computer pretty hard.
First up, you can see it hits my GPU
memory.
So I've got a 7900 XTX.
So it's going to load that up.
All 24 gigs of VRAM is going to load up
most of that and you can see also my
system RAM gets used.
So running these models locally, it's
pretty cool like that.
It gives you an answer. It's pretty quick
as well responding.
So I'm a big fan of this.
So 90% of what I've developed, I
basically used Qwen 2.5 for majority of
the stuff.
DeepSeek again, I can run, but it maxes
out my PC.
So I can't ask it more than four
questions on the same topic without having
to restart.
So this computer was obviously not built
for AI related stuff It's more of a gaming
PC and it's getting old a little bit at
least on the CPU side on the RAM side But
this is what I've used for the majority of
my AI stuff I also used at least the guys
in the Sigmanauts mining pool.
They were raving about how good Claude is
and I don't really want to pay for
something if I've got a computer and I can
actually use some of these AI features.
But I did use the free version of Claude
a little bit, but probably 90 percent I
used these self-hosted models via Ollama.
Some other tools that I used on the Ergo
side, I used this dApp connector.
So this is awesome.
This Nautilus share that is also within
the Ergo documentation.
So this is fantastic.
Obviously, I use the Ergo documentation
for the APIs.
So that's why I've got majority APIs.
But in terms of getting the wallet
connected in the app, this is what I've
used.
I spent a lot of time trying to figure
out how to make that work in Python.
That's probably where I wasted a lot of
time, but this works.
I did try and use the FleetSDK a little
bit.
There's a lot of things in here, probably
a lot of things that I don't need to use.
I mainly use the dApp connector.
And the other thing that I did use, which
I think is fantastic, some of the again,
another miner, he's creating also a
different application around ciphers and
securing your passwords and seed phrases
and stuff like that.
So he has a guide.
So he helped me get the transaction to
actually build a transaction.
So I got stuck.
I should probably know the UTXO stuff a
little better, but in this example here,
it's got code of exactly how do you go
about building a transaction so that it
actually gets picked up.
So this saved me a ton of work.
I don't know how long I spent, probably a
couple of hours trying to get this
transaction to build or getting it to
build blindly.
I don't know what I needed to do
necessarily.
So this helped me a ton because it shows
you practically around which boxes you
should be using and which not.
So this was super cool.
So that's again in terms of the some of
the tools on the Ergo site that I use in
order to make this work.
So again, big thanks to all the guys that
create some of these things.
It's easy then for a novice like me just
to go and pick up this dApp connector,
let's say, and just hook it up to the
site.
So it's awesome like that.
In terms of, again, the application, I
mean, it's mainly Python, not for any real
reason.
As I mentioned, I'm not a programmer by
day, so I'm sure there's better for these
type of website apps, there's way better
stuff to use.
Again, I'm not in the know of what is the
best thing out there and what I should be
using and what's the most efficient and
all of those type of stuff.
This is just easy for me to understand.
I can follow it.
I can do it a little bit by myself
without having to ask AI to create some
dumb stuff for me.
I can do a lot of this myself.
That's really what it is.
But again, probably longer term, I need
to go and try and use at least what the
cool kids are using.
In terms of hosting, I'm hosting this on
the Flux network.
It's pretty cool.
If I just jump to the dashboard here, I
host some of the other apps that I've
created also on here.
I've got the ErgoMempool on here as well.
If I just show you guys what that looks
like, I've got it deployed at the moment.
With Flux, I mean, you can get a lot of
instances.
I think you can get like 100, but at
least for now, the lowest option that you
can have is three instances.
Again, it's pretty cool from a
decentralization point of view.
You can also go ahead and manage it here,
so it's sort of what your details are, how
long are you going to be running it, what
your hardware requirements are.
I didn't give it restrictions, you can
give it geolocking and all sorts of funky
stuff like that.
Again, this is not really a flux video,
but that's where I've got it hosted at the
moment.
In terms of running instances, as I
mentioned, there's there's four at the
moment.
There's three in the US and one in Spain
at the moment.
So again, I'm hosting it via Flux.
I've got some Flux. It's pretty cheap.
So that's what I'm using in terms of
hosting.
So that's really what my application
looks like.
So as I mentioned, I'm not really a
developer.
So if any of the developers are watching
this, again, thanks for open-sourcing a
lot of your stuff so that people like me
can pick it up.
Again, if you're a developer and you
think I'm doing a bad job, please give me
some pointers, make comments, or give me a
couple of tips.
If you want to help me with some of this
stuff, please reach out and help.
I'm definitely not going to say no for
any help.
But at least for now, I'm going to try
and build it out a little bit more and
explore at least some other platforms that
is maybe not Flask / Python related.
But that's really what my app looks like.
It was super fun for the last couple of
days to work with some of the Ergo tooling
and create something that, at least for
me, I think is super cool.
It visualizes the Ergo mempool and I can
also send an interact and send
transactions on the Ergo blockchain, which
again, I think is super cool.
But that's really what the Ergo Mempool
project or entry within the Ergo hack
does.