Hey guys, I am Cheese Enthusiast and
today I'm here to talk about Lithos.
Now I've made videos before but today I
want to give a bit of a different
perspective. Since the testnet is getting
close to coming out I wanted to do a video
for potential miners and what type of
information they're gonna need when they
start using the testnet. Just so you guys
have a better idea of what to do and what
kind of options you have.
Quick overview for those of you who don't
know, Lithos is a decentralized mining
pool protocol, which allows miners to
connect to smart contract-based mining
pools. These smart contracts ensure
fairness, they give complete control of
block production to individual miners, and
miners using Lithos can select storage
rent, they can select transactions, and
they can even earn ERG through
collateralization.
This is just another overview of what we
already talked about, but yeah, in terms
of the benefits of Lithos, you get
complete control of block production on
the side of the miners. That means that
miners can select transactions, gain ERG
through MEV, and they can choose what
UTXOs they want to claim for demurrage or
storage rent.
In Lithos, payments are completely
controlled by smart contracts and that
means that you know you're never getting
cheated out of any ERG. It's fully
transparent and it's fully fair.
Lithos also uses collateralized mining
pools. This is used to ensure
decentralization but it also means that
miners and people not involved in mining
can earn ERG through collateralizing
different mining pools and essentially
you're giving the ERG to the mining pool
so that they can help create the block and
doing that allows you to earn a fee.
Now point four, this is what I really
want to focus on for this presentation.
It's that Lithos or rather the Lithos
client is a locally run program. Now,
obviously that means latency and stale
shares are not a factor when mining on
Lithos. But more importantly, it also
means that miners get full control over
the difficulty parameter. And that
parameter is going to be really important
when using Lithos because it can tweak
your profit levels. So let's talk about
that.
When you're mining on Lithos, you have
obviously the stratum server on your PC.
And inside the stratum server, you have
the ability to control the difficulty of
the shares you produce. In Lithos, this
difficulty parameter is called D. And
unlike other mining pools where the share
difficulty is more about how many shares
you create and whether or not it's
overloading your network or whatever,
that's not so important on Lithos. What's
really important about the difficulty is
that it can help you manipulate your
reward consistency and the amount of ERG
you get per block.
So let's talk about using difficulty and
why it works differently on Lithos. So
Lithos is not using traditional miner
payment systems. If you've been on other
mining pools, you may know about systems
like pay per share, pay per last end
shares, et cetera. Lithos uses a new
system based on non-interactive share
proofs. Now, not going to get into weeds
here about what that is exactly, but the
important part for miners is that changing
the difficulty inside this payment system
changes how you are paid and how much
you're paid.
Now, when you first start mining using
the Lithos client, your difficulty
parameter will be automatically set based
on your hash rate. For example, if you
have a hash rate of 500 mega hashes, your
difficulty parameter in the configuration
file for the Lithos client, it'll just say
500M. Once it's been set, you're free to
adjust the difficulty up or down according
to your own preferences.
So let's talk about what exactly
adjusting the difficulty will do. So this
is a pretty simplified table, but it gives
us all the important information. So let's
assume a miner with 500 mega hashes
decides to try mining on Lithos. Let's say
the Lithos pool in total is one gigahash.
So this miner is representing 50% of the
hash rate for the pool. The table below
shows how changing this miner's difficulty
changes the total number of payments he
gets, along with the amount of ERG he gets
per payment.
So when this miner first starts using
Lithos, their difficulty will be
automatically set to 500M. Now this table
shows a sample of how this miner's
payments might look over 100 blocks. So
when the miner sets their difficulty to
500M, they were able to get 98 payments.
They got around 7 ERG per payment and the
total amount of ERG they got was 686 ERG.
This is again over 100 blocks and the
block reward was 14 ERG for these blocks.
So considering this miner represents 50%
of the hash rate, they're getting 7.0 ERG
per payment.
Now, if you look at the 300M difficulty,
which is obviously significantly lower,
the miner got 100 payments, they got 4.3
ERG per payment, and a total ERG of 430.
As for the 700M, the miner got 84
payments, 9.8 ERG per payment, and they
got a total of 823 ERG. So as you can see,
adjusting the difficulty value essentially
proportionally increases the amount of ERG
you get per payment, while it's inversely
proportional to the number of payments you
get. So increasing difficulty means you
get more ERG per payment, but less
payments. Decreasing difficulty means that
you get less ERG per payments, but more
payments.
Now, that's not exactly the full story.
So yes, difficulty affects how much you
get paid and increasing the diff gives you
more ERG per payment. But in reality, the
instability of payments with a high
difficulty balances out the increase you
get in ERG. So this new table below shows
what's called the max potential. And this
is the maximum amount of ERG the miner
could have made within 100 blocks. So as
you can see for 300M, they could have made
a maximum of 430 ERG, which in this case
they did because they got paid for all 100
blocks. For the 500M difficulty miner,
maximum they could have made is 700 ERG
over 100 blocks. And for the 700M miner,
the maximum amount of ERG they could have
made in 100 blocks is 980.
So that looks good, obviously, but
reaching the max potential is extremely
unlikely because it requires that the
miner is paid for all 100 blocks, which is
significantly less likely the higher the
miner's difficulty is. So what this means
is that, generally, increasing the
difficulty makes payments less stable,
even though it increases the amount of ERG
you get per payment. So it's very
unlikely, in the end, that someone hits
their max potential. So increasing your
diff doesn't necessarily guarantee you
more money over a long period of time.
And you can see that below with what's
called the real potential. And that's the
average ERG per 100 blocks. So the maximum
potential is the real amount of ERG that
somebody could get in 100 blocks, assuming
that they're paid for every single block.
In reality, that's unlikely, and the real
potential shows the average amount of ERG
they're going to get per 100 blocks over a
long period of time. So you can see that
for 300M, the miner can still only make a
maximum of 430 ERG. For 500M, they can
make a maximum of 700 ERG per 100 blocks.
And the same thing for the 700M.
So as you can see, increasing the
difficulty doesn't necessarily guarantee
you more ERG. Instead, it changes the
consistency of your payments, and it
changes the local instability in the
amount of ERG you get for a small period
of time. But as you can see, over a long
period of time, it all balances out in the
end.
So what this means is that Lithos doesn't
let you cheat to get more ERG than you're
deserved, right? If you have 500 mega
hashes and you're mining at a 700M
difficulty, you're not going to get more
ERG per time. In the end, it all balances
out that you're still gonna be getting the
amount of ERG that's proportional to your
share of the pool's hash rate.
And the table also shows that decreasing
difficulty reduces your earnings, so it's
not necessarily useful for a level like
300M, but there may be times where your
default difficulty level that you have is
maybe a little bit too high and you feel
that your payments are a bit too unstable.
In that case, you may want to decrease
your difficulty because then you'll be
getting more payments and you'll just have
a better idea and a better stability in
terms of how often you get paid.
Now, this sounds too complicated. I
wouldn't worry. Using the default value is
probably good for most people. But if you
want to try and maximize what you can get
out of Lithos, I would definitely look
into playing around with the difficulty.
And if you're on the testnet especially, I
would really appreciate if you could try
to mess around with the difficulty as much
as possible, see how you could break
things in a way.
This is a new protocol so there's always
going to be unexpected emergent properties
that could come out so I think it's good
if you're on the Lithos testnet it'll be
good for you to play around with different
difficulty values, see whether or not you
can maybe get lucky if you increase the
difficulty, maybe you hit a lot of
earnings. Or if you feel that things are
unstable, you could try decreasing your
difficulty and see if that helps with
that.
Just in general, I think it's good to
mess around with the difficulty. You'll
probably be able to get more out of your
mining that way as well. And specifically
for Autolykos 2, if you can try to factor
in the table generation time into your
mining and your hash rate, you can figure
out probably a better difficulty for your
specific hardware because table generation
time can vary depending on your hardware.
So if you can factor that in, you can get
a better difficulty value that works
better for your machine and that'll
maximize your profits in the end.
So lastly, let's just talk about the
mining features that'll be available in
the Lithos testnet. So as we've stated
here, we'll have difficulty adjustment and
I'm working on this right now, but we'll
have demurrage in the Lithos testnet
client as well. For demurrage, it'll
automatically be collected by the Lithos
client, so there shouldn't be anything
that you need to do specifically. Just
watch out for it and make sure that things
are working smoothly.
For MEV and transaction selection, those
aren't our biggest priorities at the
moment. So they won't be integrated into
the UI and testnet, but theoretically, if
you wanted to, it's possible to manually
implement it. It's obviously completely
possible by the protocol. It's just not
supported by the UI yet.
Thanks for watching guys. Hopefully
you're able to learn more about how to use
Lithos for the upcoming testnet and maybe
you can play around with the difficulty
values there and see how mining on Lithos
feels compared to normal pools. Anyway, so
thanks, thank you again for watching and
keep updated with Lithos. We'll have more
news coming out soon about the testnet.
See you guys.