Hello everyone, and welcome to the
Pattern demo.
And today, I'm thrilled to introduce you
to Pattern, our AI-powered agent that
connects to multiple data sources to
deliver real-time blockchain insights.
Pattern has been architected from the
ground up as a modular, extensible AI
agent.
At its core, Pattern maintains connectors
to a variety of live data streams,
everything from public APIs to on-chain
data providers.
Today, we'll focus on Pattern's
blockchain integration capabilities.
By leveraging common blockchain APIs,
Pattern can fetch smart contract source
code and ABI, invoke contract functions
directly, pull transaction histories, and
even perform on-chain analytics on the
fly.
To get started, let's look at how Pattern
interfaces with blockchains.
We've built connectors for many of the
most widely used chains, Ethereum, Binance
Smart Chain, Polygon, Arbitrum, and more.
For this hackathon, we're excited to
announce that we've extended Pattern's
reach to include the Ergo ecosystem.
That means you can now ask Pattern about
Ergo smart contracts, transactions, token
data, and other on-chain details in real
time.
Let me show you a quick example.
Let's go to the Pattern demo site at
mvp.pattern.global.
There, you can sign in with your Gmail
account or wallet and begin typing your
query.
For example, I'll ask, to which contract
does the box, provide the address, belong?
What is that contract's ErgoTree script?
Then, simply wait for the pattern agent
to scan the available Ergo tools, pick the
most relevant ones, and retrieve the data.
Now you can see the agent's response to
this query, including the extracted
ErgoTree script.
Next, I'll ask, what is that ErgoTree
script about?
And then wait for the answer.
Here, you can see the pattern agent's
response to the explanation of this
ErgoTree script.
Here's another example.
First, start a new chat so the previous
history won't affect your new query.
Then ask, when was the last transaction
of the wallet at address, giving the
address, and how much ERG was transferred
to the owner of the first box?
And hit Enter.
As shown in the model's response, it
first retrieves the wallet's most recent
transaction, then identifies the owner of
the first box linked to that wallet from
the transaction data to calculate how much
ERG was sent to them.
Below, you can see the details of the
last transaction, including the amount
transferred to the wallet owner.
Whether you want to fetch on-chain data,
analyze contracts, or track wallet
activity, the agent is ready to help.
We'd love to hear how it works for you,
so please share any thoughts or
suggestions you have after exploring the
demo.