Let's talk about user experience and
transaction states in a proof-of-work UTXO
chain.
In the classic approach, there are only
two transaction states, unconfirmed and
confirmed.
For a seamless user experience, this is
not enough.
We need at least four.
Let's look at an ERG to Dexy Gold swap as
an example.
We exchange ERG for one Dexy Gold.
On the left, our transaction appears
immediately.
At the same time the wallet opens, we
sign and send the transaction.
The transaction enters the mempool, and
two to four minutes later it is included
in a new block.
A transaction can also be cancelled at
any moment, either by the user or by the
network.
In the positive case, the transaction
passes through three stages: prepared, in
mempool, confirmed.
Everything starts with the status
prepared.
This is what the user should see
immediately after pressing the swap
button.
A short double blink draws attention to
the change, and the status icon remains
visible as a bar loader.
After the user sends the transaction, it
moves to the In Mempool status.
The status icon switches to a circular
loader.
When the transaction is successfully
included in a block, its status changes to
Confirmed.
The transition is accompanied by a double
blink with green highlighting, and the
icon turns into a checkmark.
Now let's examine all the cases where a
transaction changes to the cancelled
status.
First, the user cancels the transaction
in the wallet.
Second, the user signs and sends it, but
it is rejected by the mempool.
Third, the user sends the transaction.
It appears in the mempool, but is later
replaced by another one through a higher
fee.
Fourth, the transaction is in the
mempool, but its input box becomes
invalid.
Fifth, after the transaction enters a new
block and receives the confirmed status, a
block reorganization occurs.
Any transition to the cancelled status is
accompanied by a shake animation with red
highlighting and the icon switches to a
cross.
Thank you for watching.
Always remember to provide real-time
feedback to your users.