Community AMA with the Ergo proof of work
blockchain cryptocurrency freedom
financial self sovereign I don't know come
on keep giving buzzwords guys keep going
what else
Nothing?
You guys just wake up?
Peer to peer.
Yeah, there we go.
Yeah, it's a peer to peer network.
There we go.
Welcome, welcome. We've got a couple
people with us today to start off. We hope
that this is a community Zoom. If you look
in the YouTube description, you will see
that there is a passcode and ID. Please
feel free to join in. There's a waiting
room. We've got somebody joining in.
Perfect. Don't be afraid to join and chat
with us.
Meanwhile, we'll just start off with a
normal AMA, I guess. We've got Nir coming
in, too. Let's bring them in. Hopefully,
we don't have any bad things happen in
these kind of circumstances, but my finger
is on the ban trigger, that's for sure.
We'll see how that goes.
All right, what's new guys? How's
sub-blocks going? How's that Joe? You're
talking a lot about side chains. How's
that going? Sigma chains, all that good
stuff?
Well, it's been kind of a goal for like
two years to look at this idea of taking
kind of the energy we have in proof of
work and start scaling horizontally,
right? That's something that's kind of
been a dream around Bitcoin actually for a
long time, where it's like you have all of
these people that are mining the chain and
essentially they're investing in SHA-256
machines, right? And it creates this
security wall that secures Bitcoin. Long
term, there's kind of a question in terms
of the economic sustainability of that
model, right? You know, after we see a
couple of halvings, the miner reward from
the blocks is on its own cascade downward.
And you kind of see this pattern that I
think Ethereum actually started, which is
where you get a lot of value leakage into
other layers of the network, right? So
when you have all of these layer two
solutions, what happens is people end up
essentially locking assets on the main
chain and the transactions move to another
layer. And the downside is that kind of
acts as this parasitic form of value
leakage from miners to, whatever set is
securing the layer two. So it kind of
represents this net loss and rewards,
right? And to some degree that actually
makes the sustainability more questionable
because not only are the security
subsidies of the blocks dropping, but the
transaction demand on the layer one itself
is dropping simultaneously, right? And
that's problematic. I don't know if people
have fully figured that out yet long term,
but that is the trend. And you can kind of
clearly see that with Ethereum where a lot
of the transaction volume is no longer on
the layer one. That's bad for miners,
right? And I know that many people kind of
dismissed mining, right? But ultimately,
that is the security mechanism for Bitcoin
itself. So there's like an incentive
misalignment that's occurring. And I don't
think it's fully shown up to where it's
popular enough to broadly talk about, but
it's starting. There's starting to be
questions like, okay, well, what happens
as an example, what happens if we need to
update some of the old address structure?
Well, you're going to end up changing a
lot of the assumptions on the base layer.
If you say, okay, well, we're just going
to try to force this upgrade and how many
people lost their keys, how many people
have zoned out to where if there was some
sort of threat they're at risk, right?
We're already starting to see mainstream
talks about that. We're starting to see
discussions about drive chains on Bitcoin.
You know, with Rosen, we kind of both with
the bridge and allowing Bitcoin to access
other L1s as this smart layer and also
playing around with runes and OP_RETURNs
and stuff. You know, we're hacking around
on Bitcoin for things that it wasn't
necessarily intended for, right? So
there's a question long-term in terms of
the path. If it's a miner-driven path,
what we'll see is that security umbrella
moves sideways, right? That way you get
this mechanism of pegging to a side chain
and you get greater programmability, but
you also get miners absorbing more
transaction value. You get, many of them
are already mining Namecoin and other
SHA-256 driven rewards. So it's not as
though that's outside of the scope of
where miners are already focused, which is
extend your profitability. But there's a
programmability issue, right? In a
dev-centric future, they will move to
other layers because ultimately what
happens is usually developers control and
create a lot of value on layer twos. If we
see a mining-centric future, we're going
to see more of a horizontal scale towards
the drive chain idea. And then the
question is just how to securely do that.
How do you update to where there's like
this ability to trustlessly peg and move
sideways into different environments. It's
going to be a really interesting thing to
watch. I don't think it will fully, my
personal estimate is going to be like
2032. That halving is probably going to be
rough and it's going to put miners in a
position where they need to monetize their
value, right? And so with Ergo, we have a
greater programmability. So we have kind
of this ability to be in front of that
problem and create kind of a framework
design in UTXO that I would hope kind of
gets miners aware of this potential issue
because the layer two thing, well, yes, it
does potentially open up a lot of scale.
It's also relatively parasitic and it's
hard to align value there. If that makes
sense. So it's something that kushti and I
have been talking about for like two years
on and off. I know that initially I wanted
to try to create a merged mining framework
for super clusters, right? Which, I think
that's an interesting path. kushti came up
with a much more interesting path and as
usual, I lose the argument and my idea,
however valid it is, is less interesting
to me now than what he's come up with. But
that's the benefit of smart friends right
there.
Yeah, but I think, well, different
directions to explore, right? So, well,
different consensus algorithms are still,
well, interesting topic, right? So, we
have still some demand for proof of work.
And then, yeah, well, we have a lot of AI
GPUs becoming obsolete in coming years.
Then, yeah, well, a lot of I6
underutilized because, yeah, well,
changed. They were created for not doing
quite well. So, yeah, a lot of possible
directions for sigma chains for consensus.
But for programmability also, well, there
are a lot of interesting ideas to explore.
So I've published global transfer policies
recently, right? Which is kind of a solar
punk mode to extreme, right? So well, you
can create basically your own money and
well, precisely define these rules. That's
it. But yeah, I think we also can do more
interesting experiments. So well in recent
few days I probably got an idea how to do
well pretty efficiently also kind of dark
tokens right on well maybe Ergo even in
the future but probably better to start
with sidechains right before doing some
hard fork to do some evolutionary
development on the main chain. So the idea
for dark tokens is to use not just numbers
as amounts but possibly arbitrary bytes
including encrypted amounts and then you
can use global transfer policies which are
checking that encrypted amounts are
correct, like done in Monero, for example,
with bulletproofs, right? Hiding amounts
as well as requiring for anonymized
transfers, for example, to stealth
addresses.
Could you hide amounts in liquidity pools
as well in that manner? Like if you had,
any time you exchange, right, you're going
to expose the amounts that you're
changing. But if you could hide the
amounts in the liquidity pool as well, you
could potentially completely obfuscate the
transfer process right there with a swap.
It's hard to do well. Yeah, so if a pool
is public, right, then you need to show
its amounts properly, right? Well, to make
interaction possible. So you can do
somewhat pooling, but more limited than
public liquidity pools, right? So you can
use kind of a dark pool, but yeah, well,
hidden amounts, but maybe with possible
opening of chain, something like that. But
yeah, well, in general, if you have just
Liquidity Pool, which is public, so
accessible to everyone, then everyone is
needed for some efficient on-chain method
to get amounts there. Otherwise, how can
you trade with it? Yeah, it's problematic.
Imagine like trying to set a limit order,
but you can't read other limit orders,
right? Or you're trying to move into it.
You're trying to move into a pool, but you
have no idea what the liquidity and the
slippage is. So there are some areas where
it's like you need some mechanism to
understand data to make a decision. And so
if everything is totally private and you
have no ability to read it, the DeFi kind
of breaks down and that's been an
interesting problem to watch in this
space. I've seen some people kind of like,
I call it ZK spoofing where it's like,
maybe there's a central server that can
read everything, but users can't, and then
your trust assumptions in terms of who can
read and manipulate order flows, just
moves to a single party.
Right. So yeah, if it's controlled by a
single few party, then yeah, it's can be
done in zero knowledge, right? Proofs
generated by those trusted parties, but
that doesn't make sense. Basically. Yeah.
It's zero knowledge proof. But that's how
people are usually trying to solve it.
Trying to sell solutions, let's say.
We got quite a few in here. Why don't we
open up guys.
Don't be shy. Don't be shy at all.
Grayman's texting.
Hi, hi, Grayman. So yeah, well, I think,
well, it's Grayman and Joe here. So I
think there is need to revive efforts for
completing the Ergo book. So let's add
Martin, maybe some of the guys willing to
contribute. And yeah, well, now some
writings are done. So I made like a few
writings in recent months are not public
yet. So well, now I can jump again on the
Ergo book and well, do some stuff there.
We've got MGPai. MGPai, why don't you
give us... Oh, no, Grayman, go for it.
You're going to talk. Perfect camera on.
Let's hear it.
I was just going to say I'm sorry, I've
kind of fallen off on that. I've been
pulled in a lot of different directions
recently, but where I was sort of stuck
and going to try and I got halfway there
and the other half you had requested that
I review the free banking era in America.
And I've been reading up on that in a
number of sort of weird contexts on a
state by state basis instead of the
federal basis. It's interesting. And I
really have to delve in and understand
ChainCash and practically how it's going
to work before I write that part because I
think that's the analogy that makes the
most sense. So I've been looking at that a
bit, but then I've got two new clients and
crazy stuff going on with my family. So it
is what it is. Life moves on, but I'll get
back to it soon.
Oh, yeah, that would be amazing. So yeah,
for ChainCash, we now have even some new
contributors, right? And well, yeah, well,
still the blocker is the same. So yeah, we
need to define who will use it, right, and
how to do UI then. So then, yeah, like
foundational aspects do matter a lot here
in this definition.
MGPai, you there? You with us, sir? He's
there. Perfect. Hey. Nice. Where are you?
Are you in Japan?
Yeah, I'm just leaving the office right
now.
Safest city in the world, right?
Yeah.
Awesome. Tell us about your release of
your... So for those who don't know, MGPai
is, when he's not being slaved by Dan and
forced to work for zero pay for Palmyra
and Zengate, he runs a consulting and dev
firm called Four Eyes. So the Sigmanauts
have hired Four Eyes a bit back to create
SigmaLock. And why don't you give us an
update on that, MG, if you've got a sec.
Yeah, yeah, for sure. So, we're quite
excited for this release. You know, we've
been working on it for quite some time.
Actually, well, unfortunately, it's been
like a year since start, but I couldn't
work on it until like last month.
Oh, we don't want to hear excuses, MGPai.
Just dive right into it.
Yeah, yeah. Well, I'm very excited. You
know, a lot of work's been put into it. I
rewritten, I mean, I written from scratch
like an entire indexing framework in Go
lang, which is like a language which very
few Ergo apps, if any at all, are written
in. So it's completely done from scratch.
And this will allow like really, really
good performance for the users on the user
end. So people will see any transaction
they do for a specific contract,
instantly, right? Because we're not
querying the blockchain or anything,
right. We're parsing a transaction, you're
querying a backend directly, which stores
the exact data that you need. So it's
really fast. So it's a good user
experience. I've included indexing with
mempool, which is like big, it was like so
much extra work because you know, there's
so many edge cases you've got to handle,
like transactions dropping or being
replaced and so on. But with this indexer,
it considers all that. And as soon as a
user makes a transaction, it's going to
show up in your UI, like you'll see it.
And then you can see it confirmed in real
time. And so on. So, you know, we're
really focusing on the user experience and
making it as good as possible because the
idea is that this project is going to be
completely open source. So anyone in the
community can take a look and fork it, use
it however they want. But for me, the main
goal is to have like a foundation to just
continuously build on, right? You get it
right the first time. Then you just copy
paste, like the boilerplate framework for
all your other projects. And furthermore,
you know, I spent a good amount of time on
it to be ready for sub-blocks and all. So
if I ever want to integrate that, you
know, it's ready to go.
That's awesome. Yeah.
You want to go ahead and explain what
SigmaLock is, what the project is about?
Yeah, so the idea was, you know, we have
locking things on, we have things like
HODLERG, and HQ just came up with a
locking mechanism like an hour ago, just
announced it, congrats HQ. But we wanted
something that was more of a, something I
could sell to my grandpa or somebody like
that. And the idea was, could we create a
product that competes or is similar to
kind of like a life insurance passover or
some sort of inheritance kind of thing to
where we could lock something up and we
have choices of whether it's still in our
control or not in our control and somebody
else's. So the idea was that let's have a
system that somebody can go to. They can
choose how long they want to lock it up
for. They can even actually set, this is
an addition, they can even set a price
strike as well that lets it unlock at a
price strike if it gets crazy. So you can
go there, you can choose some options
right at the beginning that say, look, I
want to create, let's say two unlock keys,
and that's it. And these unlock keys can
only unlock it if the price of ERG goes to
$1,000 or 20 years have passed kind of
thing. So then you can give those unlock
keys to your children or your
grandchildren or your lawyer or some sort
of digital lockbox or something that keeps
things for legal reasons. And that's
option A, essentially, where everything's
you can't do anything once it's set.
Right. But we all know that things change
in the future. Maybe your kid joins
Zengate and he betrays you and pisses you
off and you never see him again kind of
thing. And you want to cut them out of the
will. So instead, you can check a little
box that says the creator of this contract
still has permissions to completely modify
the contract. So at that point, you check
that box. And then in five years, when
MGPai leaves us for somebody else, I can
sever him, I can rewrite the contract and
sever that from, pull my funds out, redo
the contract and make new keys and send
them to my other favorite children or
something like that. So giving some
flexibility in that kind of thing, like
they exist outside in the real world, as
well as the ability to really lock it in
and be immutable with a smart contract.
That's the idea. We're trying to create
things that make sense on chain, not just
bash blockchain over the head of things
out there that might not make sense. This
kind of stuff makes sense. You have a lot
of wealth in the blockchain system right
now, and we're not at that stage where
people are dying too fast and holding on
to their ERGs because it's such a young
system that this is going to be something
I think that people might be interested in
in the future, near future. Yeah, and Four
Eyes has been great.
What's that, Grayman?
What happened to Dan?
I think he fell asleep on the keyboard,
passed out.
Yeah, it's quite late in Japan right now.
It's like 11 o'clock, 11:30? 10:30. Oh my
gosh. What are you, like, a high schooler?
Yes, yes. Getting to my bedtime soon.
They've got good whiskey in Japan. He
should be awake.
Oh, yeah. That's true. No, Dan's been
working hard. I think he had some early
morning meetings at like 6 a.m. or
something and 2 a.m. stuff. Unfortunately,
the Japan time zone isn't favorable for
business meetings.
Well, let's hear from HQ. HQ, you want to
unmute and tell us about your new release
an hour ago about your lock program. Maybe
HQ is asleep too.
Hey, good evening, everyone. Hey,
basically more simple way of doing this,
right? It is not backed by any backend. It
is already done on Explorer uses the
Explorer APIs to fetch the boxes. It is
simple and just go and do I want to lock
this much till this height and the person
who creates the box has the only right to
unlock it. You can lock tokens, you can
lock ERG, you can lock NFTs and you can
lock everything which is on chain. So
that's simple and I think that was the
requirement from some of the community
members. So we just kept it simple that
way.
Nice. So you're protecting yourself
against yourself. It's a good way to force
yourself to hold, I guess, right?
Yep. Maybe you can put that new Mew you
got in that lockbox, HQ.
I think I will add option to add names to
the boxes. So I will maybe add name of my
son. and we can name the boxes with the
name, or we can add description to the
boxes.
Yeah, that would be nice. That would be
cool. That is cool. Very cool. Nice. How
long you been working on that HQ? You do
it in secret and just popping it out? Or
did you bang it out with some coffee in a
late night?
Yeah. I think some people take one year
to build it. I just take one day.
Oh, shots fired, MGPai. You're going to
let that happen?
Oh, he's not going to answer that.
That's only cause Dan hasn't got a hold
of you yet.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Poor MGPai. He's got
point two percent of his time that he can
devote to anything other than Dan. So
that's what happens. Oh boy. Well, what
else is new guys? Chris? What's it any
anything in the pipeline any theories or
philosophies you've been working on that
you want to implement?
Yeah, I guess so. It's going to take a
while. It's heavy on the front end, so you
know how we are with UIs and Ergo. Always
a long stretch of development there. Seems
like we're getting there. I like what HQ's
got going on though. You know and
everything over at MewFinance. That's
pretty cool. I use that a lot probably
going to be looking at some of that
front-end code for the swapping and
exchanges for what I'm working on. But it
is, it's just really an idea stage right
now, so we're thinking about how to
develop an application for coupons
basically fundraisers, and this is a US
project so it's quite complicated where
you know everybody with rewards might be
able to trade their rewards for rewards
that somebody else might have and use
those in different areas of their
communities. It'll be community focused in
a sense. So these coupons that you know
you have for shopping at your supermarket,
you can trade off for rewards that
somebody has earned at the car wash, let's
say. In a free market kind of place. And
you know that the intention there is to
provide our communities with a free
trading platform and kind of goes along
with our ideology of providing peer to
peer access on different levels where you
have Joe and kushti working on these high
level projects. And I think a little bit
down on the ground where how can we build
something that can be replicated for
normal user in peer-to-peer fashion. If
that doesn't make any sense there on the
coupon side of things, I think that it's a
good benefit for communities. In my
vision, I see where high school
fundraisers and church fundraisers might
pull up our application, put their donors
or contributors, business contributors
that are in their community, put their
coupons on this application and allow
their community to trade back and forth.
And I think it's kind of a LETS idea
without having all the equipment and
technology, try to make it user friendly.
So that's why I say it's heavy on the
front end. And tax ramifications.
LETS without tax ramifications. Yes,
nobody is going to tax me when I buy my
coupon book.
Just list coupons on MewFinance and
that's it right? You can just list coupons
on MewFinance and it is P2P so someone
wanted they can buy it and you can use
another source to just provide them with
the codes and that's it. So you have front
end for it and you have back end for it
too. And it is all on chain.
But isn't this, isn't what Chris is
explaining more of a, Hey, I've got, you
know, this many points at BJ's. I want
this many points at Walmart. Can we do a
swap from BJ's to Walmart for these kinds
of things? Is that where you're explaining
Chris, as opposed to I want to buy with
ERG your points?
No, so the ideal application for this
would be you and I attend the same school,
QX, and we're a part of our fundraiser for
our football team. And we go out and in my
part of the country, we were always
creating fundraisers for our kids. And
it's sourced from community businesses,
mostly where a business says, yeah,
they'll contribute and they'll give these
offers and they create a coupon booklet,
usually a physical item. And then these
kids can go out and sell these coupon
booklets for $20, $50, different prices.
And then the community can have a coupon
booklet to go out buy different things
from the community. Well what I find is
that I don't use half that booklet when I
buy one, okay, so these coupons still have
value and I might end up giving them away
giving them to one of my sisters one of my
brothers or grandma. And the idea would be
that QX, you like a particular item in
that coupon book, and I like a particular
item in that coupon book, and we create a
market that allows us to trade back and
forth. This is on a very, like I say, on a
very small scale in a community. And so
your points of value where you have 20%
off on a frozen custard. Hey, I want in on
that. You know, let me give you 20% off on
what, what do you like a hamburger? What
is it? You know? And so creating a very
small trading platform for each individual
community. And HQ putting these kind of
things on MewFinance is it's a great idea.
You know, but with what I'm looking at
doing, it's also going to take a marketing
campaign. So very much going to be like,
not a MewFinance, not really centered on
Ergo exactly on how to market this to
fundraisers people that want to raise
funds for their football team people that
want to raise funds for their church or
for their local golf course, you know.
It's the marketing is another big push on
the front side of things. But it's very
specific to how to distribute this free
marketplace for communities. And it's
going to be very little on the marketing
side about blockchain and how to use
peer-to-peer finance. But the underlying
message of peer-to-peer for communities is
the fundamental foundation that I'm going
to be standing on to do it. So that's kind
of what's in the pipeline. It'll probably
be a year or two before something like
that really rolls out just with all the
work that goes into it, but definitely
going to be running on Ergo.
So if you want to market it to the
fundraising people, then you got to make
it easy for them to reach out to the
sponsor people. That's going to be the
trick is making a nice interface for that.
But don't tell us how you're going to do
it because pretty soon it'll end up on
MewFinance too.
You guys keep using this M word. I'm not
familiar with it. Can you explain what
this marketing? What word is that? I don't
know.
Oh boy. That's awesome, Chris. Anybody
got an update on Keystone Wallet? We got a
question. Didn't PGR456 give a good
update? He just did something last week
recently, kushti?
Just looking for an update on Keystone.
Oh, so the latest is from July 21st and
it was tweeted by the Keystone. So yeah,
the latest is about connecting Keystone to
Nautilus, generating transactions, signing
requests for Keystones, can sign
transactions from Keystone, done. What's
remaining? Bug fixing in transaction
serialization. Finish Nautilus-Keystone
interaction UI design, full integration
tests. So yeah, it's signing with
Nautilus, so quite close. It seems. And
yeah, well, there was some video published
on July 21 as well. I guess it's on the
Twitter also. So you can find it in the
Keystone wallet Twitter. But yeah, I think
it was posted around. Yeah, we retweeted
it too. I talked with the team yesterday.
Yeah, they said that it would be like four
weeks to six weeks to have Ergo ready. So
that's what the estimate time they gave
me.
Yeah. They want me to build a custom page
for them on VoltPay so they can accept
multi-chain payments and sell keystones.
So that's what the estimate time they gave
me.
Are those Rosen weeks or are those
Keystone?
I'm sure they're not Ergo developers, so
they don't understand the four weeks
thing.
HQ, when are you going to put more stuff
up for sale on MewFinance for Mew? I was
hunting through there to spend some Mew.
You have merch already on sale on
MewFinance for Mew? On proof of merch.
No, I mean for Mew. I want to buy stuff
with Mew.
Okay, I will talk to the guy who makes
mugs.
I want to buy a mug. I want to buy one of
those beautiful mugs for Mew instead of
SigUSD. Put a bunch of stuff up with Mew.
I'd love to spend some Mew.
I will see if I can convince Echo to add
maybe Mew to proof of merch so it will
have its own Mew delete there too.
Oh, that'd be awesome. I also mean the
handmade mugs too, the guy in Europe that
makes them. That's beautiful.
That depends on him. If he wants to get
paid in Mew or not.
What's that kushti, by the way, do you
hear me guys? Yeah. Yeah. So parcel sent
by proof of merch, reached Dubai recently.
And yeah, a pal of mine is quite excited.
Yeah, about it. Let me what did you order?
kushti messages. So it was some merch and
a few t-shirts. Maybe a couple of mugs. I
forgot. That's awesome. But but yeah, the
guy is very excited about it. And yeah,
we'll promote around now with some merch.
So, yeah guys, please order proof of merch
and spread around.
Yeah, as soon as you add Mew to that HQ,
I'll order a bunch of stuff. I couldn't
imagine spending my Mew any other way.
All right, Grayman, you threw a question
in chat. You want to use your pretty voice
to ask a question?
Sure. Actually, I got two now. And they
might be related to each other. So the
first one is about Rosen and the guards.
And it makes sense to me that it started
out as a federated system because on some
level you have to start with trust to
build a trustless system, right? You have
to start with people that you know are, I
mean, it should have some slashing and
other tools to make it so that you can
punish people that act poorly. But if you
go right out of the gate, and that's all
there is, is a whole bunch of people
attacking the thing that would not be
good. But eventually, to get to the stage
where it's sort of living in the wild, and
if Joe gets hit by a bus, and so do all
the other devs, it still lives. Carried
off by an eagle, whatever it is.
A bear. A bear's more appropriate for
Joe.
Fells a tree on himself. Then we need it
to keep going. So you got to have a way
for these guards to be permissionless,
right? What is the how do you do that? How
do you transition from one approach to the
next?
Joe, let me fix this real quick. Let me
fix one thing real quick before you jump
in. So my understanding of federation is
federation is the ability to remove access
currently at any time. Right? So while the
guards, I guess you could throw around the
word federation where the guards were hand
selected, right? I would call that more of
a startup ceremony perhaps. Selected. Once
they're selected, essentially slashing can
begin. And there's no federation in that
Rosen can say, oh, Sigmanaut, you're out,
bye. We're just selecting you and removing
you. It would still take the other guards
to perform a new ceremony to include, you
know, some new signing keys and all that
kind of stuff. There's no federation
currently, I believe, with the Rosen guard
set. There's a selection process, yes. I
would be hesitant to say that the guards
set become like the watchers set where
it's permissionless, and Joe can correct
me if the vision of Rosen is different
than this, but as far as I understand it,
the guards are always going to have a
choice whether they perform a ceremony to
include people or not at some point. So
that's always going to be somewhat of a
selection process in that manner,
different from the watchers as far as I
understand. So I don't believe it's
federated at this point because there's no
way for people to be removed without the
full guard set being able to be involved
with that. Joe, go for it.
Sure. So in starting Rosen, the ideal
would be that you have some sort of
collateral in order to set up that set,
some economic treasury that backs the
value being transferred. And I think that
if you're trying to bootstrap a peer to
peer community locally, one thing that I
think is very valuable collateral is
actually a history of proof of work,
right? So it's like, okay, this person has
a skill set and they've demonstrated the
ability to create value, right? More than
just credit as collateral. So that was a
big part of how the initial set was
established. Now, longer term, in my mind,
the thing that makes the most sense is to
always try to build yourself out of
importance, right? And I think that there
is a powerful way to potentially do that
where you actually create an avenue to
where you allow multiple various guard
sets to use the same second layer, right?
So let's say that Grayman and Byron and
Chris get together and say, hey, we're
going to form our own guard set with our
own collateral treasury, and we're going
to actually start settling transactions
for people. I think that having the
ability to scale the guard set sideways
beyond just a singular party is probably
the best way to foster competition right
and then it's like as a user you know you
may actually get to the point longer term
where it's like okay you want to transfer
asset from here to here well you have
multiple intermediaries you can go through
that have various levels of let's say
treasury backing so then you kind of get
this idea where a user may be able to go
through different intermediaries depending
on their level of collateral they hold
their history in terms of how quickly they
settle transactions and actually create a
competitive framework around it. It's kind
of hard to make it fully, I would say
non-federated. So the best way to foster
competition is then to create open
competition between federations, if that
makes sense. But yeah, I think that should
always be the goal is it's not necessarily
to build solely to capture value, but to
build innovation is then to create open
competition between federations, if that
makes sense. on that, then it's like they
have this avenue to come in and
potentially out-compete the original guard
set. Potentially they could adjust how
quickly things settle, but that comes with
trade-offs. You may want, if something
moves faster, you have less confirmations
and especially in proof of work. There's
always this idea that energy added to the
chain enhances the assumption of
settlement, right? So sometimes if you
have cross-chain mechanisms that are
optimistic and they're faster than the
chains assumptions I'm not sure how long
we can go with that until something breaks
but that's more of an you also adjust fees
and
We made Rosen super modular and we
haven't really flexed that to where it is
possible to not just adjust the fee in
terms of the bridge basis, it's actually
token by token by token on the map. So we
could potentially say, hey, perhaps we
create a marketing campaign around this
one token, or perhaps we make that a fee
service where if somebody locks Rosen or
pays some sort of fee for that service, we
could actually individually raise and drop
the fees. Long term that's powerful. Short
term governance can be like herding cats
and unfortunately sometimes I'm like the
hardest cat to herd. So it's like the
blind leading the blind. But I do think
that like as a long term path of creating
a competitive federation of guards
actually makes the most sense from a free
market approach and an open source
approach. Otherwise, we just keep building
to where my relevance increases and that's
not really the position I want to be in
long term is more and more responsible.
Ideally, if you build something that's
open and has decent security assumptions,
you become less and less responsible as it
proliferates and this organic growth takes
over. And that would be the optimal
outcome.
So then the other question was about
Nautilus. and is it possible to just sort
of gank some other wallets, open source
code, I don't know, like Electrum or
whatever, and add BTC as a native and then
build some sort of a structure so that I
never have to leave my wallet. I don't go
to a rosen.tech app, but I just put my
wallet, you know, switch between BTC and
RSBTC or other Rosen, you know.
Yeah, so when we designed Nautilus, we
did actually make, we re-engineered the
backend to where long-term we have the
ability to support multiple environments.
And that's important if you wanted BTC in
Nautilus, you'd actually need information
from the Bitcoin blockchain. And the other
let's say component there that would be
needed is going to be SDK to integrate
Rosen directly into the wallet. And that's
kind of been our. I don't want to say
bastard child, but let's just say it's
something that we've been working on as we
have the bandwidth, which long term. We've
kind of been in this position with Rosen
where the ability to connect environments
is, let's say, a powerful base, but you
actually need something on top to where
liquidity providers can manage assets.
It's one thing to be able to move assets
into different environments, but you need
some sort of middleware on top to be able
to manage them in a uniform environment,
right, instead of a fractioned
environment. And so we've been in this
process of working with Hummingbot for
quite a while We actually were next in the
queue to get support and then they said
hey we're going to refactor a lot of our
code and you know move towards kind of
like a I think a lot of it had to do with
actually following liquidity, which is
kind of natural where they wanted to say
okay Well, we need to optimize this to
support Solana because a lot of liquidity
is moving to Solana so we're going to
refactor our code base to work more with
that environment versus being more
Ethereum centric and then that kind of put
us on a holding pattern for a while as
they updated their code base. And they
should be open to new connectors in
version 2.8, which I think right now they
just released 2.7. So hopefully we
actually can get that kind of unified
experience. And that makes Rosen a lot
more powerful, in my opinion, because then
you not only get quick arbitrages in
different environments, but you also have
a lot of central exchange connectors. A
lot of market making outfits will use
Hummingbot and then they'll just write
their own parameters for trading. They do
kind of come with the default settings and
usually people will throw up some Python
scripts with whatever the let's say
parameters of the project they're trading
with are. So it's a really powerful tool
that is coming online, not just market
access, but market making those two need
to go together. And so far they haven't.
So I haven't worried too much about the
liquidity and activity and Rosen because
it's an incomplete product in my opinion.
until that second layer is there, it's
like, yes, we have this ability to move
from Ergo to Cardano or from Bitcoin to
Ergo, but when you see the price slipping
to where RSBTC is worth $31,000 and then
Bitcoin's worth $67,000 and there's no
ability to quickly balance that liquidity
differential. And the price differential
is something isn't fully complete yet. So
we're getting there. I wish it was faster,
but when you're working with third
parties, I don't know. Sometimes you just
have to wait for your woman to get ready,
right? Pushing it just makes more
problems.
So you have a pretty comprehensive and,
let's say, old school understanding of the
whole crypto space. Can you tell me, are
there any other multi-chain wallets that
are open source? I mean, of course, a lot
of hardware wallets are multi-chain. We
already talked about Keystone.
Oh, I would say Cake is probably one of
the better open source wallets around. It
creates a, I don't know, a weird
assumption where sometimes it's like
they're fully open source. Sometimes
there's partial ability to view. But the
most important thing is how are the keys
stored and managed, right? And what are
the terms of agreement? And you know, the
devil is usually in those details, in my
opinion, because there are a lot of
products that I'm just going to call them
spyware. You know, there's no other way to
really put it. They're spyware. They're
scraping your IP address. If you're
submitting some sort of swap, they have
the ability to kind of see your order
coming in and act, you know, in front of
you, which is somewhat manipulative. But
Robinhood is a good example where, you
know, like as an application to some
degree, it's spyware and it's selling your
information to Citadel, which is then
front running you, right? That's not an
ideal assumption. For markets, right? But
you know having the ability I've said this
many times he who controls order flow is
king and I don't think people fully
understand how When you have the ability
to get in between the market participant
in the market you have an asymmetrical
advantage that you can make profitable
pretty much every time and that's moving
into the crypto space, which is why, you
know, I would say for best assumptions in
a peer network, stay low, build your own
transaction, right? Don't allow that order
flow information to be passed around
before it hits the network.
It just feels like we're here to promote
Ergo, but if Nautilus was available for
BTC users and became in some ways uniquely
good because it enables them to engage in
DeFi. Yeah. then that draws in new
customers that don't necessarily initially
even need to care about Ergo. All they
care about is, hey, look, this Nautilus
wallet has a sort of trading tool built
right into it. That's cool. And it's open
source. And we can sort of figure out that
these guys aren't spyware, right? And then
they can be promoted like that. And then
suddenly you have access to a huge
customer base that doesn't immediately
have to think, oh, this is Ergo, let's
learn about Ergo, but then once they're on
board, then they realize, oh, this is all
powered by Ergo. Let's learn more about
Ergo and buy some ERG.
I think long term, in order to put more
resources into wallet development, we need
to put some form of transaction fee into
that type of wallet. Right. And I think
there should be a pretty clear disclaimer
like, hey, you're choosing to be a user
rather than a peer. If you want to not pay
this, you know, here's how you spin up a
node and here's how you become a lower
level in the network. But I think having
that mechanism to incentivize development
would be big. We haven't done that yet
just because there wasn't many options.
And I think that, again, it kind of
doesn't really make sense if you're the
only game in town and it's open source and
you're trying to just bootstrap community
to fee gate it right out of the gate. But
I do think that long term that probably
has value there. in terms of scaling into
new environments and having kind of the
incentive structure for constant support.
All right. And by the way, about wallets,
so if you have some feature requests, some
ideas in regards with Ergo wallets, yeah,
please create a GitHub issue, so send
ideas to me. Yeah, well, it's possible to
add something in the coming months, but we
need to consider roadmap.
HQ, maybe you should make a telegram bot
that posts directly to different
repositories for issues. So very normal
people aren't afraid to post comments on
GitHub. If you don't do it, I'll do it.
But you have more time than me.
Now we can have a bot which can maybe
register people issues. But the thing is
you will have more nonsense in that than
the real issues. Then you have to sort out
the real issues.
Well, that's where you come in. You can
just sort that out in your free time.
Who says that I have free time?
I mean, you're building all this stuff.
Obviously you have a lot of free time.
It's not that I have free time. I have
free will. That's a different thing.
Oh boy. Oh, we're at 57:05. We got
another question. Oh, Byron says, who
chose a meetup outside of snowboard
season? Mission reduction over gliding?
He's right, Joe. Why are we going to
Colorado? Not when there's a lot of snow.
Probably because people will be cold.
It's funny, whenever East Denver happens,
which is a pretty big conference in
Colorado, every year you have people that
fly in and then bitch moan and complain
that, oh my God, it's so cold. But it was
funny, I was there, I think it was two
years ago, where it's like the second day.
In the mountains, usually you'll feel this
instability in the air, where it's like
you get these bursts of winds, which means
the pressure is changing. Right. And, you
know, being from the mountains, you feel
that and you're like, oh, it's going to
snow. And you look at all of these, you
know, script kiddies from that are wearing
shorts and flops and you're like, oh, they
have no idea what's coming. And then two
hours later, it's snowing and everybody's,
you know, freezing. And then, you know,
afterwards, you're like, oh, it's the
worst experience ever because I went to
the mountains and I forgot to bring a
coat. So hopefully hopefully we hit the
season where the leaves start to change,
which in Colorado is its own magic. And
it's still crisp, but warm enough that you
can go enjoy that.
You have trees with leaves in Colorado,
not just conifers, evergreens.
Oh yeah. The Aspens. If they're hitting
the point where they're turning gold,
that's its own magic.
Very nice. Oh, Byron, you're still in
chat. You want to ask your next question
live? You're still up here if you want to
pop up. That's great.
Oh, put the pressure on me. Okay. Let me
go back to the question. You're talking
about are intents the same as weakly
confirmed transactions. Because I've been
seeing intents a lot lately and I also
reviewed the Ergo hack with CBK. So I want
to know if that's similar to how you're
doing it. Armeanio with the OP_RETURN and
RGB, I don't know what the plus plus is.
Are you talking about RGB plus plus and
intents?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, RGB plus plus. Why
don't you answer that kushti? I wasn't
following.
hackathon CBK yeah so i need ideas
towards intents but so actually i think
Ergo by design so well it's it's not just
intents friendly it's intents oriented
right so well you are specifying well, for
following good design patterns, right, so
you are specifying only conditions which
do matter, right, and leave the rest to
others so that's how swap contracts are
done right and others so that's why
they're composable by the way and so on so
i think intents is kind of products of
accounts based blockchains like NEAR and
so on. So when they tried to relax what
kind of strict contractual descriptions
they have. They come base approach right
so that that's kind of relaxation they're
doing and actually it's quite funny so
recently I've checked some dark tokens
proposals for Ethereum and here it seems
they all are implementing UTXO model
actually and Yeah, I think, well, intents
and also that thing from Ethereum, account
abstraction. So they're simply not needed
here because they're here since day one.
It's kind of, yeah, there's considered
overlap between terminology, right? I
think a good way to look at UTXO is it's
like you have spending conditions, right?
And spending conditions are in a way an
intent, if that makes sense. versus when
you get into the account model, there's
just a larger program path you have to
follow that they're somewhat trying to
simplify and get away from in order for
things to move faster and not execute. So
I think perhaps in UTXO, we should just
call them spending conditions, which is
kind of an intent of the transaction.
Yeah, spending conditions, guarding
propositions. So yeah, intents is
basically a way to write them where you
can write, well, some minimum rites of
spending. But that's what you're usually
doing right here in UTXO programmability.
So that's how you are doing things in Ergo
and before in Bitcoin even with more
limits. So, yeah, but basically intents I
hear since day one, just under different
terminology. Naming, right. Yeah. Well,
we're just following Bitcoin basically.
And yeah, well, account abstractions also.
Yeah, since day one because everything is
a contract. We don't have any special kind
of accounts, contracts, whatever. So,
well, it's just one type, right?
To some contract and you take it. Is that
still going to be the same when we convert
to proof of stake guys in the future?
Someone ban this.
But to some degree you could call you
could call every register on Ergo
declaring an intent. If that makes sense.
And then, you know how the registers
interact is like a contractual basis of
intents. I guess.
Right. So yeah, well, it's also the
question of terminology, right? So what
are we doing as a community? So are we
pushing our own or are we following
Bitcoins, right? So are we adopting and
somehow modifying EVMs? So yeah, well,
it's... I have a feeling that we are quite
doing all the three things right in
discussions, which also does make some
sense. It's hard to get.
Can we start using outputs per
transaction versus TPS?
Yeah, it's hard to find concise consensus
about terminology, even, which is kind of
crazy. But sometimes, like, I don't know.
Sometimes when marketing leads the space,
words don't mean anything.
I mean, that's everywhere. Even in
blockchain.
That's everywhere. It's not just in
blockchain, even. It's five companies out
of the same thing, and it's just named
differently. Yeah. So it's, it's, I don't
know, unique terms can dilute the value of
language to some degree. Cause there's a,
there's, it just lacks concise boundaries
of what it even means. And I don't know,
different language from different projects
sometimes just pretzels my brain. Cause I
don't know, what does this concisely mean
even? And then I have no idea what
anyone's talking about.
We got more questions, guys. Let's bang
them out while we can. We've got a few
more minutes. Thanks so much for turning
on your video, Byron, and asking the
question.
Yeah. Do we have time? And by the way,
hello, Byron. Happy to see you. We're here
as well as other new guys. Guldis, Zed,
Nir, Odi, Karim.
For the viewers of 2021, maybe 2020.
He means new on zoom Byron he means new
on the zoom.
Oh, okay. Yeah. Yeah, wish he remembers
everybody on your system. Don't worry.
You're new on the blog, but yeah, well,
please join some calls for more We will
have more right in coming weeks. Maybe
especially
Yeah, next week we're going to have the
same thing, so that'll be great. Andy's in
the woods camping for two weeks, so we are
doing this instead of the AMAs. Yep, just
for two, just for the AMAs.
Yeah, so actually, yeah, but I think it's
a good initiative, right, to have more
voices for them. Yeah, yeah.
100%. You want to answer a few more
questions, guys, or you want to call it?
Joe's like, I could go back to sleep. Now
we got three more questions. Let's bang
them out. This one's for Joe specifically.
Is Machina Finance an order book DEX or
will it utilize the existing AMM pools
also?
Either. Neither. It's kind of a design
that it's again it's an old idea that it's
like finally we have some bandwidth for I
would say it's called an order based DEX
and so the cool thing about what we're
trying to build is that let's say that
Chris wants to sell an asset right and he
has the ability to create his own local
contract that's offering the limit of the
asset, right? And so then you have this
backend that's able to match all of these
local smart contracts and kind of create
unification of just these UTXOs around the
chain that are offering different, you
know, buy and sell limits, right? So it's
not a book. It's like everybody creates
their own pages and then there's a
matching engine in the background. And
kind of the cool thing about that is
longer term, it allows this idea for
automation of trading, where it's like,
okay, if I want to buy within this range
and sell within this range, I can create
local smart contracts to facilitate that.
So it's not really a order book, because
usually order books are unified, right, in
terms of there's usually one party that's
more or less writing all of the buy and
sell orders in a book. It's order based
and it's peer based. And one of the cool
things about having a peer based setup
like that is again, you're operating from
this low local level where if I create the
sell order and Chris buys from me, you get
a peer-to-peer contract interaction rather
than having the bookmaker in the middle.
So it's not AMM, it's not order book, it's
kind of this specialized UTXO order base
DEX that then you have this ability to
aggregate. And if we open source the
aggregator, then everybody can essentially
run the book. if they want to, right? So
again, you're kind of removing the central
contract or the central bookmaker, whether
it's AMM or the order book, and you're
creating just this ability to create local
orders and then match them.
It's more decentralized than a DEX.
Do you mind if I ask a question? So how
are we validating those? So let's suppose
that I want to sell one ERG and I want to
sell it for 1.2 USD, right? So I want to
swap. For example, I am actually working
on something like this on MewFinance
already because I'm utilizing the same
smart contract, which lets me sell for it
and lets me sell token for anything. So
what I really do is I create order. I tell
that I want to sell this for this much.
And the other party, if they like it, they
can accept it. So what I'm trying to
understand is what is the difference here?
Is this off-chain bot which is running and
matching those orders and publishing them,
executing them, or it has to be manually
done by the other party to accept the
offer?
Right now we're working on the backend,
putting together a Rust-based backend to
aggregate orders and be essentially the
matching engine. If you want best
assumptions, you're going to want to run
that. And how many people are willing to
do that? Well, that's always kind of the
problem with local hosting and
decentralization anyway, but having the
path to be able to create orders and then
run your own matching engine is pretty
unique. I don't know if I've seen an
application that does that. And it's kind
of neat because at least in UTXO, you
know, long-term, it's like, if we could
get that right, it creates this ability to
where the entire chain itself is the book.
Yeah, exactly. That's why, because if we
look at the MewMart main contract, it's
basically that. So yeah, I just wanted to
create a new interface on top of it to
show it like a DEX.
Yeah, I think long term, that's a really
nice design pattern for UTXO. It's just a
question of saying, okay, well, how many
people are actually going to run their
aggregator and be their own matching
engine to where they are the bookmaker in
a way? I don't know. That's always hard.
Sometimes it's hard to get people to even
get off exchanges. But having that path
towards pure, peer-to-peer finance that's
just smarter, more performant is always a
good path to try to conceptualize, play
with, and then make reality.
I guess we will check it out how many
people will actually use that. So I think
I can run an instance and see if people
are even interested in that.
Yeah, I think long term. I don't know. I
keep coming back to this idea that I've
talked about over the years where it's
like, I think probably for users anyway,
you need just light wallet that's more
comprehensive. And maybe long-term, we
need some sort of node package. We kind of
saw that to consider, but that's also hard
to build because then you need standards
and contributions and it can be its own
centralizing I don't know.