Hello, and welcome to the new setup of
the Ergo Community Chat.
We started a little early this morning
than our normal 1700 time just because I
wanted to get through the dev updates and
then maybe have people join slowly and
chat there and go from there.
I managed to snag HQ. HQ, good morning.
How are you doing?
Good evening from me.
What time is it there, sir?
It's six o'clock, six p.m. Oh, that's
nothing.
You were talking like it was like two
a.m., man.
Yeah, you thought I was Joe, or Joe's
alt, right? And you thought I would just
show the people that I am.
One of Joe's 30 alts, right?
Yeah.
Nice, nice. All right, so let's dive
right into, well, let me start off with
something else. Let me start off with
something else that I put in the chat the
other day, right? And you might have some
good words on this, too.
So everybody hopefully at this point
knows that the Ergo Foundation main goal
was to bootstrap the community, right?
Essentially get things propped up, get
things going, prime the pump, and
hopefully the community is up to speed and
available enough to continue the ecosystem
going.
And we're kind of at that point right
now. We're kind of at that crossroads.
Now, that doesn't mean the EF will go
away. The EF could continue to sign
exchange listings as that entity. It could
continue to maybe try to get grants for
their treasury, perhaps support
development, support research, any of that
type of thing. The EF, as far as I know,
is not vanishing.
The point is, we have a couple
outstanding things that are at the prime
and are needed for the community to take
over. And some of those things I listed in
the Sigma Not Chat the other day were,
one, market making. That bill is about
$10,000 or $12,000 every quarter, I
believe. It's not a small bill, right? And
that bill is never going away if we want a
market maker.
And a lot of other chains will utilize
market makers that trade against their
community and saying that they'll run the
market maker so that they make a profit
off the spreads, right? So that when you
guys, the community, trade against it on
other chains, potentially you are putting
money into whoever's running that's
pocket, splitting by the market maker and
by the people that hired the market maker.
So Ergo has never done that, ever. That
was a whole stipulation for the market
makers that we get. We also have market
makers that are friendly in the US, which
can't do that kind of thing. So our market
makers currently do not make profits off
our trades, off our supporting the spreads
and debts. And that's painful, right? So
it's about $12,000 every three months to
the market maker to support that.
Now, there are some community members
that have come forward that are willing to
give it a try with their bots and with the
liquidity that we already have there. So
that is something that we're going to be
testing over the next month or two. We're
going to have some people perhaps give
that a try, see how that goes, utilize our
market maker for advice and tips on what
to do, what we're doing wrong, and that
kind of thing.
And then take market making into the
hands of the community, which is kind of
scary and cool at the same time. Some of
our community members have already been
running some market making on other
exchanges. So it's not like they're just
going to take this from scratch. They have
experience with this. So nothing to be
worried about there. But that's one of the
things.
The other things we've spoken about quite
a bit are the main explorers, right? So
there are some pretty beefy machines
running in Hetzner right now that cost, in
total, the Hetzner bill is about 760, it's
about 680 euro, whatever that is, in
freedom dollars, 720 freedom dollars per
month. And that's not an easy cost to
swallow either.
So in the Infra P2P DAO, it's running.
And it can take probably 99% of all
queries, simply. But it can't do these
massive queries that take machines with
about 120 gigs of RAM. HQ and AQL have
been sending some test queries for me to
check out over the past month or so. The
main explorers can hit, but not the
smaller P2P machines.
So the solution around that, just to keep
you guys informed, is to run the beefy
explorer that I have here with me. And I
have another machine that will ship to
Jamai. And Jamai will run the other one
for now. So essentially, we'll continue
the use of the main Ergo platform, the
Explorer. We'll redirect to those. We'll
encourage everybody to use a P2P nodes,
except for large queries. And we'll go
from there and see how that works.
Hopefully, maybe we'll get older machines
with a lot of RAM that we can also add to
that. Maybe at some point, something like
a Sigma, what is it called? Sigma Explorer
HQ?
SigmaSpace.
Thank you, SigmaSpace, which is built for
fast returns on large queries. But it
takes a decent amount of hardware to run
it. So maybe those will be integrated as
well in there. But the main important
thing is the big bottleneck on what we see
is Cloudflare with these kind of things,
right?
So the idea is that we publish the main
Explorer link. We publish the P2P DNS
URLs, which are load balanced in many
machines. But also, we encourage
developers to go to our list of individual
machines, which we'll parse out for the
P2P, and we'll also have the two machines
from the main Ergo Explorer, so that if
Cloudflare goes down, your app
automatically rolls over and uses a
straight-on DNS or even IP address of one
of the Explorers.
Or, hey, if you're a developer, why not
host your own Explorer? Write HQ.
Yeah, it's actually it's not hard. There
are a couple of Explorer built on nodes.
You can dockerize them and run them for
you. You just need maybe a user index
node. If you don't have, you can use any
exposed index node and run your own
Explorer. So yeah.
Exactly. And there's even the P2P
infrared dial put up. We put up a GitHub
that should get you going really quickly,
too. Just change a couple of parameters
and spin up the Docker, and then wait for
the node in the Explorer database to sync.
So it's there, ready for you. And don't be
shy from it, right?
Meanwhile, you're checking that I would
like to add some comments to that. Why do
we have the market making and why do we
need it? So the sad part of the crypto
industry is that you're required to have
those services if you want to maintain or
sustain your tokens on any exchanges.
So that it's not that we really want to
run those bots or we really want to trade.
is that if you want to be part of the
ecosystem in which the crypto has become,
you need to have those things and you need
to have your trading and volumes and all
that. So it is understandable that people
run those and EF running those and
sustaining those and on no profit. It's a
good thing.
So if we plan to not use them in future,
we will be required to have a basic
minimum volumes on any exchanges. So
that's why there is going to be a
community members who are going to run
these things for the community. So there
are no more delisting or any things like
that in the future.
Right, exactly. It's if you want to be on
the exchange, you got to play the game,
you got to pay the piper, essentially.
Yep, so it's unfortunately the way the
ecosystem is right now, right? The
industry, I guess you could say, but it
sucks. But hey, why list tokens and
exchange coins and blockchains on merit
alone when you can literally extract as
much value as you can from them via
trading?
Yeah, I think that's a sad part of
crypto, right? All the exchanges which are
centralized. So if we go on more
decentralized exchanges, if Rosen gets
more attention, then we won't be needing
that. So if there are more users using
Rosen and they are using the DEX on any of
the connected chains, then you actually
don't need, if you have enough volume and
enough trades with your wrapped assets,
you don't really need the access to
exchanges.
So yeah, it's a path which we are on and
we have to just keep our heads straight
and go towards that. And that's, I think,
the only path we have. Seeing all the
scams and everything and exploits
happening in the exchange and all the
shenanigans they do. So I think the best
part is to go that pathway.
I agree. And then additionally, on top of
that, at some point, hopefully that
Hummingbot community repo will come out
with Ergo integration with DEXes. Is that
the Rosen team that was working on that or
still kind of slow burning that?
I think it was Rosen plus Splash.
So just Rosen.
I need to check. Yeah.
Yeah. So hopefully that comes out at some
point. And then community. I mean, even if
we're talking like you have a few hundred
ERG kicking around with something like
Hummingbot, multiply that by a couple
hundred users running these themselves,
just like Watchers, that'd be amazing.
What would be cool, too, HQ, is if Rosen
found a way to integrate Hummingbot into
their watcher protocol so that running a
watcher also means arbitraging and market
making via Hummingbot. That'd be neat, but
you can't do that because you have to have
separate accounts and everything and it
gets messy. But yeah, that'd be neat, but
cool.
Well, another thing they can use is
VaultPay, right? Which has no KYC and you
can do all the swaps there also. That is
also creating volume. So if you don't want
to check, if you don't want to touch any
exchanges or don't want to KYC, you just
swap your assets through any provider and
you are just creating the volume there on
those exchanges. So you're not touching
the exchange.
No, we don't want to go there. Is it on
your main page?
VaultPay.store.
There we go. All right, so you buy
straight up, right? Gift cards.
Yeah. So for example, if you're going to
make a trade on, let's say, BTC to ERG. So
you just select, I'm changing BTC for ERG.
And it will give you like, there are four
providers who will give you this and that
and that. You choose the provider in the
back end. What is happening is you are
sending your BTC or BTC to the provider,
which is exchanging those on exchanges.
I like that you're actually showing the
swap providers here as opposed to not
knowing which ones it's going through. I
actually use this right here. This worked
well. Swapping from crypto to a prepaid
card, they email you the card, you type it
in, you go to the site, you can use a your
bogus email address or your private email
address. It doesn't matter at that point.
And then you can pay services like
Lighthouse Storage that we use for ACO and
HQs and auction houses.
IPFS, of course, yeah. Yeah, IPFS kind of
stuff. So prepaid cards was really well.
It was really
I was worried that... We are in
Christmas, right? You have also gift
cards. If you want to gift someone gift
cards, you can buy them also with Ergo.
With Ergo. That's awesome. So what are
you using? So VaultPay is your, this is
your code right here, but what are you
hooking up to and integrating with?
I'm working with Trocador, which is
actually known in the community from
around six to seven years in all the
crypto industry. So they have a very good
reputation. And then we use a swapper,
exotics, and multiple providers in a
backend, which basically do the swapping
for you.
So if I want to, there's no, there's KYC
when you buy with currency though,
correct? Was that the deal? I think it
blocks me in the US, I think, or in New
York state. If you're buying with crypto,
no? No, if you're buying with cash, I mean
with credit card.
There is no option to buy with credit
card. If you're getting a prepaid card and
you are not allowed, there are several
countries which are not allowed to get a
prepaid card, because they won't work
there. But the USA one is working. So you
are basically getting a swipe card. And
you can use that anywhere.
Yeah. Awesome. Cool. Let's go back. Let's
put this up while we're chatting some
more. Why don't you talk quickly, before
we go to the Dev Update, since you did it
this week, why don't you talk about what
you did last week for your use
integration?
Well, I was getting sick of seeing people
asking the question about when use. So I
was like, OK, let's fix this. So we
integrated the native pools of use and
Dexy Gold in MewDex. So you can now swap
inside the DEX, and you can also provide
liquidity. And on the other end, there are
two functions in the protocol, which is
freemint and arbmint. So basically, when
there is a price difference, you can free
mint it so it can level the price between
the LP and the bank.
So if you go to bank.MewFinance.com, you
will be able to see that on you. If you
select use, it will give you that. This is
the LP price and this is a bank price and
it will give you recommend you what is
best for you. So you will be able to
directly swap on bank to interact with the
DEX LP and also to buy in the bank. So
it's all in the same widget. You will be
able to do that.
Very cool. And you got this out before.
We're still waiting for the other
interface, right?
No, I think they have. Yeah, but they
don't let you augment or they don't let
you do all those. It shows that it can be
augmented, but you cannot mint those
tokens from those UIs. Yeah.
Awesome. Awesome. Hey, CannonQ, welcome.
Is CannonQ here with us? Can you hear us?
Yeah, can you hear me?
We can. Welcome. Good morning, sir. How
are you doing?
Hey, doing all right.
Nice, nice. We're looking at use
stablecoins right now with a new
MewFinance integration of it. Super cool.
All right, guys, let's jump to the
developer date really quickly. We'll bang
through that, and then we'll start
chatting some more after that.
Great. Let's see. I'll go quickly through
here. We've got Game of Prompts finishing
up the interface in the contract, likely
have it completed before the end of the
year. The Wallet UI library received for
two or three PRs implementing ErgoPay.
Banner received more than 50 PRs. Great.
Some of them focused on searching for
potential bugs in the contract. All right,
so this is Joe Sameh with Game of Prompts.
kushti was part of an Unstoppable
Hackathon and Stability Workshop,
presented chain cache paper for Stability
Workshop to help Unstoppable Hackathon
teams with mentorship, design, and code
reviews. Was that the thing where he was
just in India just recently? Yeah, cool,
very cool. He's traveling right now, which
is why we don't see him.
kushti is continuing to test chain cache
basis. Krux by Louis Vatra. Let me turn
off this so you can actually see names.
There we go. Louis Vatra, Krux added DEX
LP swapping, extract SOC to NFT on token
from Ergotry constants and fee from swap
Ergotry constants. So should support all
instances using the same template.
Who is this guy you know, autogenitor?
Right? Yeah. Working on Ergo Power,
Launcher Script Power Optimizer, Control
Script. You guys know what this is? You
guys paying attention to this HQ?
If you want to read it and read the
complete smart contract, I would be glad.
Because I think they just copied and
pasted the chat GPT, and that's it.
Oh, this is that. OK. I got you. What is
this thing they're working on?
Actually, I didn't read it because I saw
the chat GPT. Would you like to modify
this somehow? And I was like, OK, so
that's like.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, interesting. OK.
All right. We'll come back to that maybe.
Lethos release version 2.2.0. That's
cheese. Cheese enthusiast. Upgraded sync
process to be multi-threaded. Rollups NISP
trees. NISP trees. Say that fast five
times. Now sync individually. Change
logging for sync process. Most APIs
listing data objects are now sorted by
height of the mine block as they're
associated with fixed LDB errors related
to multiple database instances. So Lethos
is still going strong.
Degen's world. If you guys haven't played
around with this, it's a lot of fun. It's
pretty darn neat. Launched two new mini
dApps, token board, letter board style
view for native tokens, and ergo trace. Is
this what I think it is? Let's see. Do we
have an address? I don't get it.
Ergo trace is one of the best things I
have seen are OK built.
So yeah, yeah, yeah. Let me see if I can
get an address, which, yeah, I don't want
to use that one. Do I have an address
here? One second. We can do this. Let's
just get that.
I was just telling him to just maybe use
heights and balances on different Block
height so imagine that if user had Two
thousand ERG at one point you check at
that one how much he had that that from
that till next from to Block height it
will give you that he sent this here. He
sent that to exchange He sold this much.
He has this much yesterday in that night,
right?
That would be such a nice tool to have
all right Let's see what happens for
everybody to see I may have grabbed too
big of an address. Yeah, I think I got a
huge address. We're crashing it.
Yeah. Just grab the Spectrum LP pool one.
And I think that will burn your computer
too.
All these addresses are big. Yeah, but
you guys check this out. It's a very nice
3D representation of the blockchain
showing some really cool animations back
and forth. Maybe we'll, yeah, it's too big
of an address. Let me see.
OK, we'll take tipper bot address and see
that go. And I really want people to see
this. I haven't seen it yet. OK, we'll let
that run. Yeah, there we go. So you can
see the Explorer here. Pretty neat.
Everything connected to it. So this is my
tipper bot wallet that is a very neat
token node transaction. How come you
didn't build this, HQ?
I have this already built for me.
Also, Glasgow has a version of this. He
has set up for tracing these kind of
things, which is neat, too. It's on
GitHub. But this is definitely the
prettiest that I've seen it happen. Yeah,
cool.
All right, what else do we have? We have
token boards and letter board. He's got
Zirgon working on encrypting local
database persistence for PONW scores. PONW
scores plans to test GPU-based models
while mining to determine impact to
latency and mining performance. Man. Rob's
really cranking it out.
Added local files or created several
files for use with local LLM models, doing
some vibe code testing with context, added
contract audit examples. Ultimately, there
should be a list of optimizations within
ErgoScript that can use this as context
for a starting point. Nice, nice, sir.
What else do we have? Chris has updated a
lot of language things in Nautilus,
Aircraft Explorer, WalletApp, SigmaUSD.
Always thank you to Chris for adding those
things to things like CoinGecko. Whenever
you see all those socials added, I think
he just added a bunch to that, which is
great. Thank you, Chris. Is this a thing?
Nope, that's just a discussion.
And we have Louis Vatra working
ErgoScript, LSP, POC, Vibe. Oh, Louis Vibe
coding now? We're in trouble. A lot of
trouble.
How do you think that you got the swap
model on Crux?
Oh, he vibrated. Well, I guess if it
makes him go faster, right? As opposed to
the usual two-part theory.
Yeah, the thing is that he knows which
cells to touch and which cells not to
touch.
True, true. Yeah, very true, very true.
All right. Where were we here? We'll leave
that up for a second. All right. Anything
else you're working on, HQ?
No, I would like to just shout out to
Michael because he's doing some nice PRs
and he's learning how to be a dev.
Oh, what's he PRing on? What's he doing?
He's doing stuff on crux. He added top
trading. He is working on front end now.
He's working on APIs. So yeah, I just want
him to see that how painful it can be
sometimes.
That's awesome. That's fantastic. Yeah,
great.
So what else I have been building? I
think I, I started working on a wallet.
Wait, what kind of like your own wallet?
It's, it's best.
Yeah.
Not like a, not like a, not like a frosty
wallet HQ. Remember the frosty wallet?
Yeah, I remember that one. No, it is, it
is like a dApp. It's a dApp, but which
acts like wallet. So you can create an
wallet. You can send transactions through
it. You can send money to send tokens to
others. And it will have the integration
of all the mew apps in it. So for example,
you have love in your wallet. So you go
and click on your balance and you will see
all the options under it. So you will see
swap, lock, burn. So you will be able to
interact with all of those through that
wallet and you won't be signing them
through anything because you are using
already fleet. So you can import your
wallet directly into the browser and use
it. It will have password protection and
everything. So yeah, I think you saw some
screenshot I shared in the MUFI dev chat.
Yes, perhaps. When's that going to come
out?
I don't plan to release anything for now.
I think I have released a lot. And I want
to see some adoption to those things
first, because I'm just burning myself
here.
That's true. You're making a lot of
stuff, so I got you. We got a comment in
the chat that says, we love the new
on-ramp for Nautilus. We need more of
that. And for people who haven't seen
that, you can see there is the Buy ERG
button right there in Nautilus, which
takes you to Banksa. Which they're going
to yell at me because I'm in New York and
we can't do anything fun in New York ever.
So yeah, but that's nice. So the good
news is too that what's it called stealth
swap saw this and we're like, hey, we'd
like a button there too. So we're talking
to see how deep that integration is and
what they want to do with it, if they want
to do it themselves or if they're asking
for money for that. But I think that'd be
neat at least to have another button here.
So buy or swap. And then why isn't Vault
Pay in here?
I think because it is I think I will make
a PR, yeah.
Yeah, make a PR. So the question is, is
Stealth Exchange same as Stealth, whatever
did you just say?
Stealth X. Stealth X, yeah.
I do. I do. VaultPay uses them as one of
the providers.
Oh, amazing. So just put VaultPay in
there. We don't have to put Stealth in
there. Yeah. All right, make a PR right
now. Don't forget, sir.
I think Anand won't like it because it's
backed by centralized stuff. So the
providers are centralized, so he won't
like it.
And BankX isn't? Banksa isn't? I bet this
is very centralized.
Yes, it is not centralized. It is like
military protocol. They ask you for how
many moles do you have on your left leg
and then your right leg also.
Oh, gosh damn it. I got you. I think I
know someone who even had to send them the
photos of their kids to just tell them
that they are their kids.
Oh boy, what's the world coming to? I
think if we're going to stay in this
industry and if you want something
decentralized, Bankside is not the thing
to get into.
What's that, CannonQ?
The big issue or the reason why we pushed
for Banksa was there was a common refrain
in Ergo that there was no U.S. access. And
other than you in New York, you now have
U.S. access. And people are now
complaining there's a 10% fee. Well, do
you want to access or not? Everyone knew
that was the fee ahead of time. Perhaps
that wasn't explicitly stated, but if
you've ever used any of these or looked at
them, you knew it was going to be a 10%
take rate, which is less than any of you
guys in the US that are using FanDuel or
any of the other crappy betting apps.
They're taking more than 10% from you, so
shut up and buy your ERG or don't.
From the man himself, CannonQ, that's
your advice. Shut up and buy your damn
ERG. Oh boy.
I think we have a quarter of the day.
Shut up and buy your own.
That's perfect. I'll make an NFT of that
one. Perfect.
Oh, what's going on here? I got a fake
Joe writing me. Awesome. Great. So
speaking of that, let me, and I know
people want to hear more about probably
like, ERG price go up and that kind of
thing. But I'd like to just give the
audience right now, and at least a
recording of what we're integrating here
at Cornell to empower and make better
function of tools that we already have.
So there are a couple of ways that we're
integrating our token into the thing,
we're trying to create somewhat of an
economy for the token. So that means you
have to have a distribution method, so
ways that people can get a hold of the
token, and then ways that people can
utilize the token, right? Because if you
just dump a token on people, what are they
going to do with it, right?
So we've got a couple onramps and several
offramps now for this token. The onramps
are essentially, if you bring in plotting
paper to recycle, and we have a lot of
kids coming in probably right now while
I'm in my office and ignoring everybody,
Recycling paper, we give them some of the
token. And then also you faculty members
would be able to give students tokens,
staff members give students tokens for
other things as well.
There's also another method that if you
follow our shop safety protocols and you
properly swipe in your badge, then I run a
script every once in a while and it takes
your check-in and it automatically sends
you some brick, some token. So that's our
on-ramp to the students, how we currently
distribute it to students.
Now, for the off-ramp, we have a couple
of different methods. You can pay for
plots. And let me find that thing right
here. You can submit a plot at the plot
center right here. I filled in the info
already to make it quick. I've told my lab
model not to touch this darn test. And
I've chosen blockchain as a payment. So
when I hit Submit Print Job,
And this is what I was talking about the
other week where I'm very grateful to
Louis Vatra for the tip bot so that we can
really make an ease of kind of what's it
called? Easy introduction to students who
are using this. And I think I've waited
too long on my page and it's died. Anyway,
so that's three. Oh, there we go. Perfect.
So that's been submitted. It says
blockchain payment required. And if we
look, let's go to here. We can see that in
my blockchain payments channel, it's given
me all the information with my NetID and
everything.
All I have to do is copy that. paste it
in, and now I've successfully tipped that
brick to the system. And in the back end,
all we're waiting for is, let's see, we're
waiting for it to pop up here after it's
confirmed in the blockchain. So that's one
way that students can spend their brick at
AAP on the blockchain.
The other ways are for staff. We have
appreciation portals where we can send
brick to people. And those appreciation
points, the brick can either be passed on
to other people. See if we can have a nice
built-in connection wallet here. Or we can
go to swap brick. And we can actually
trade those brick for real Amazon
dollar-to-dollar appreciation points. So
you can see if I connect my wallet and I
put I want to pop in 100 brick to trade
right there, we'll get $12 of appreciation
points. So that's a way for people to, if
they want to exit the system, can off-ramp
into real dollars as far as that goes.
And then, of course, we have a large
system for the students as well. You can
see we have a lot of recycling done in the
top here that we've been giving out brick
for students, massive amount of
information of how to set it up. The
students can then go also and submit their
brick to a 3D printer swap, which means
that at the end of every month, when
they're ready to be built for the filament
that they use in a 3D printing lab,
our owner of the 3D Print Lab will go
into this system and will upload an export
from the 3D Print system. And this system
automatically parses it, combines it with
the brick that was sent from that student,
and removes that price from the student's
bill. So if a student was going to be
billed for $50 worth of filament for 3D
printing, and they submitted $20 worth of
brick that month,
then they're only going to be billed for
$30 worth of filament. So it's a really
cool way for kids to be able to take their
brick also and spend it there. And since,
of course, we're not asking students to
buy any ERG at all for that, at least now,
I have my admin top up, essentially, that
checks all of the balances of the wallets.
And if there are wallets with less than a
few transaction fee amounts in it, I just
hit the build transaction and boom, and it
sends them all enough to do that.
You'll see this in about five seconds
here when we go through that. So the
reason I'm showing you this, guys, is
because I hope some people that are
watching this or watching in the future,
that are very speculatively oriented, that
are like just into crypto for, let's get
some speculative assets. Let's make 200%.
Let's, so see, we found six wallets with
less than three ERG. We go down, we can
see which wallets have less than that.
There we go. So all we have to do is
connect Nautilus and send the proper
amount of ERG.
And we have sent it. I just got the
tipper bot message. So now these guys are
going to be funded with enough for
transaction fees that they can go forward
with. So back to that. So I'm hoping that
I can show you guys that there's no screen
share. Oh, yeah. There's no screen share
on this zone. Sorry, CannonQ and HQ. Just
going to have to trust what I'm saying. Go
to YouTube and check it out, CannonQ and
HQ.
So the idea I'm trying to promote here is
that I hope, at least Ergo's mission has
always been to try to drive innovation and
try to drive use case scenarios with real
electronic money, right? That's in your
hands. And this is essentially what we're
trying to do here. We're trying to make a
system that we can give value to the
students, right? Give value back to the
students, and then not have control of
that value once it's in their hands,
right?
Now saying we can technically stop
students from, yeah, when tuition payments
and brick-nice We can stop the exit
points, right, of brick being spent here
at AAP if we want to, but that doesn't
stop their possession of their token and
what they can do. A student could take my
GitHub and pull the stuff off of it and
make a swap for themselves kind of thing.
Like where is it? Like this site right
here. This is the same thing. We have it
up for students. They can come and they
can swap brick right here. We could hit
that and it would bring up our Nautilus
wallet and ask us for the 1,200 brick, all
built in right here. So it's kind of like
what HQ built for physicals. And we can
see a student's already posted their Steam
Deck for US dollars, actually, not brick,
because nobody quite has this much brick
yet after the first semester and a half of
this. But kids are using it, and it's
pretty darn neat.
Let's see if this is. Transaction hasn't
cleared yet, so we don't have our plot
here quite yet. But yeah, so the idea is,
If I can reach anybody out here that is
just into crypto for speculation, it's a
little deeper than that. That burns fast,
that burns hot, that goes out fast, right?
This kind of stuff is really what we could
use it for. Giving value back and power
back into the hands of the people who,
should have it, right? The decision makers
or the non-decision makers or everybody's
a decision maker. If you wanna be blunt
with that.
Yeah, so that's it. Sorry CannonQ and HQ
that you couldn't see my screen share.
One thing is, which I would like to
clarify, is that there are people who
think that crypto and blockchain are the
same thing. Right. So crypto is one thing
and blockchain is another. So there are
thousands of things you can do on
blockchain which are not crypto related.
You can build anything on a blockchain.
You can use the blockchain as a database,
as a validator, as a verifier, as an
amplifier or whatever you want to.
So you have to just get the thing that
the dollar value is something you have to
get out of your mind. So one ERG is going
to be one ERG. And every time I say this,
people will be like, yeah, but it is 0.47
right now. I was like, that's a dollar
price kid. You can do so many transactions
with one ERG. Just imagine 0.004, that's
the minimum box value you need. So imagine
how many boxes you can build with one ERG
and imagine how many data you can put in
one register or one box. So that's the
power of blockchain and that's what Ergo
offers.
The things built on top of Ergo are what
gives it Another perspective, it's the
DeFi, it's the DeFi on Ergo you can find.
But the main core of Ergo, the one thing
which made me love Ergo was the blockchain
and not the price or not the crypto aspect
of it.
And I think we'll get there eventually. I
mean, it's definitely a long haul, that's
for sure. But I think we'll get there. I
think we'll get more and more people
weeded out that are just here for the
gambling and for the chains that will
offer that to them. And we'll filter
through that and we'll get people that
stick around and actually want to see
utility and want to build it and use the
blockchain for what it's meant to be used
for.
Yeah, I don't I don't blame those people
because that's what is crypto sold as far
as to get is to get rich and people will
do whatever they can do to get rich.
People scam people will do frauds. People
will do anything to get rich. So that's a
sad part of crypto.
Yeah, I agree. I agree. Let's see how my
block is doing. Has it confirmed yet? Can
you speed up the chain? HQ, it's still
unconfirmed. We got a long block when it's
live. That's how it always works, right?
Dude, I hate it when I do a long chain.
Every time I have to test something in a
smart contract, then I will Another good
point thing, which I didn't say, is that
you can now use socket on MewTech. So what
does mean that if you transfer some ERG or
anything to another address and you
connect it right instantly, you will be
able to see that you have that. So you
will be able to create stuff when they are
not even confirmed.
So you're using chain transactions up
there.
Yeah. So the swaps will be much faster
now. The only thing which always happens
on the DEX is a slippage. So if there are
many people trading in the same LP, so
just have that in mind that there will be
some stock order because that's how the
protocol works. Just change the slippage
and try to try again. That's it.
Yeah, and for people that don't know,
too, that are watching this now or later,
the Nautilus also has this feature. If we
go to Settings right here, you can turn on
zero conf which is exactly what it sounds.
So if I'm sending something from one
wallet to another wallet, or somebody sent
me something, I can see it in my wallet as
soon as it hits the mempool, just like HQ
was talking about. And then I can send it
out while it's still in the mempool, it'll
do a chain transaction. So that's a really
neat feature that's part of Nautilus now
as well, down here in experimental, that
works really well.
I've never had trouble with it with Ergo
and normal sending transactions. It's not
like other chains that start with an E
where you send a transaction and, oh, I
got to add 20 more bucks to it to pop it
through. That doesn't really happen on
Ergo. So chain transactions are very
successful in that manner. Do you use this
feature? Do you have this turned on in
your Nautilus HQ?
Yeah, by default.
Nice. Wait, I don't think it's on default
now.
Well, for me, it is for you. For you,
yes, yes, yes. Yeah, but last I checked
with it, and it was something, it was not,
it was just in testing phase. It was not
kind of like polished.
Yeah, I don't think so. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah,
nice.
Let's see, what time is it? 12.26? Well,
we've been going for an hour, but people
may have just joined us 30 minutes ago.
What else we have to talk about? Let me
see if there's any hooligans in chat or
questions. No.
I think we might do we might do Ergo
Santa. So what we are looking for are some
contributors who would like to drop tokens
to the two part. So so we're planning to
do a DEX campaign where we will. We will
say that trade this that or that in those
pairs and that at the end we will be
dropping the. No, first we are getting we
are collecting all the funds to do the
airdrop to all the people who contributed
in the campaign. So we already have one
million FAKU from CannonQ. Okay, I will
add another one million FAKU from me.
You guys are FAKU.
Well, now you're a FAKU whale. You should
be doing more than a million. I'm just a
minnow here.
Okay, I will do two million then. Okay.
You do one million, I do two million, my
friend. Okay.
That's like a thousand dollars coming out
right there.
Wow. What else? I think we have Disco
Solaris is also providing some PHP also.
And what else? We will see if there are
someone who wants to contribute. So please
just go to the MewFinance Telegram and
just look for me and I will provide you
address and you just drop those there. And
at the end of the event, we just
distribute all those tokens depending on
the contribution the people did on the DEX
campaigns.
Oh, nice. I think I have some FAKU LP,
only like a couple hundred bucks. But I
might be able to pull that and put that
in, because there seems to be a ton of
FAKU LP already in there. I don't think
it'll hurt it much. I think there's like
six grand LP in FAKU right now. Let's
look.
Eight grand, I think. Yeah.
Last I checked, it was eight. Yeah.
Well, we got a price dump. So yeah,
around 5.5 or 6.
You got a price dump on FAKU?
Yeah. Not on FAKU, but on ERG. So
basically for ERG price drops, then also
price LP drops. Yeah. Yeah. So that's why
we launched Mew paired meme coins, which
were runes from Bitcoin. So they don't
suffer that much. And to have more
activity on the block, on the DEX also,
because people are, people are more
emotionally attached with their ERGs and
not that much with the Mew.
Yeah. What did you do with the Mew? Did
you vault that Mew that I sent you, HQ?
I think I locked it and I unlocked it.
And now I think those 15K Mew will be
distributed to all the top in the
leaderboard for the runes and DEX
campaigns we created. So yeah, we have to
just I'm just spreading them. I have too
much mu to get.
Good. Good. Spread the mu. Spread the
joy. Yeah. Let's see. Oh, look at that.
The block confirmed. Fantastic. Let's see
if it's... There we go. Perfect. So now
that the block is cleared, the plot shows
up in the back-end lab monitors, and they
can actually send it out to a plot. Pretty
neat.
And another trick for you is you just go
to live.ergoexplorer.com and you can see
when the block confirms. So it will show
you the in-comings of TXs and then when
the block is confirmed, it just goes away
and then your transactions start coming
in. So that's one way you can see.
This is Echo? Yeah. You didn't build this
for Echo?
No, I just gave him the emotional
support.
Nice. All right. Let's see. We've got any
last questions here. Oh, yeah. Graeme
wants to ask about Ergo Santa. Is that
going to go? Is that not going to go?
Yeah. Graeme can send all his shitcoins
to us and we will distribute them all to
all the contributors.
Do you have a live page of the bank? You
should have a live page of the bank.
I think it is. Yeah, it is
ErgoCentra.MewFinance.com. It is live and
it is updated and you can already send
messages to Ergo Santa. You can write your
letters.
What is it? Ergo Santa? Yeah.
.MewFinance? .com.
It doesn't like it. Just say try center.
No, it should be
ErgoCentra.MewFinance.com. Throw it in
chat if you're on desktop.
No, I'm on mobile. I'm not on desktop.
The last time I touched desktop was two
months ago.
Is it on here? Is that on your main site?
Yeah, if you go to the MewFinance.com,
there it is.
It's santa.MewFinance.com, sir. You have
too many URLs you don't even know.
Yeah. No, you said ErgoSanta. Don't
listen to me. OK. So do we have
contributors? So no, what I was talking
about is you should have a list of, I
mean, I guess we can go to this wallet and
see exactly what's in there, right?
Yeah. If that is a contribution wallet,
yeah, you can see whatever is in it.
All right, everybody, let's see if
there's anything in there yet.
Just be aware of the Anaconda, please.
Of the what?
BBC, I think.
Oh, don't worry. I won't do the visual.
Yeah, we got some MewGarang. Is that real
auction house token? I don't know. It's
some clown. 3D collection NFT from Comet,
Cat with Bat. Oh, look at that. You've got
some evotes from Frosty.
Damn it.
Those things are never going away.
Now people will call us scammers now. Got
some quacks, some ERG god. Okay. I will
add, I will add five NFTs of proof of work
girls thingy that.
Oh, perfect. Yeah. Yeah. That was a good
one. Yep. I will add, I will add five of
those also. Okay, I will add 10 of those,
okay.
Maybe I'll throw in a few Greasy Hex NFTs
from season one or two, but I don't know.
I don't know if I can. I love those
things. If I have a double, I'll throw
some of those in.
Okay, what else can I drop? Let me think.
Do I have my NFT wallet hooked up here?
Let me see. Hang on.
Okay, I think I can drop some Blitz cards
too, because I'm not seeing any future to
those.
I don't think I have my NFT holder. Yeah,
I do. Here we go. Let's see. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Something like Rollerblader number
four, Rollerblader three. I can't give
those away. Maybe I'll donate this one. I
paid a lot of money for this one. You guys
remember this one?
I think we can't see it.
Oh, you can't see it. Sorry. It's the
ErgoBass NFT.
Oh, damn it.
You want that HQ?
No, thank you. That dance is very smelly
right now. It's been two years, I think.
That's very smelly. Yes, yes. Yeah, all
right. So it looks like you got a good
start. You got some neta in there, 710
neta. You got 20 padilla. You've got some
kushtis. You've got some suns. You do have
a lot of BBC in there. Woof.
We have blun.MewFinance.com now.
There's a million FAKU coming. It's
inbound now.
Oh, sweet. Let's see if he's telling the
truth.
Of course I am.
Yeah, just go to live.ERG. There you go,
folks. You can see it on screen. CannonQ
just donated a million FAKU to the Ergo
Santa. Hot damn.
340 bucks, by the way. Merry Christmas or
whatever you guys celebrate.
All right, everybody. You know what is
the fun part of all this? CannonQ, how
much was it? Three ERG or five ERG? Two.
Two ERG. I was just talking to someone the
other day. I was like, dude, if we really
want to be on top of the charts on any TVL
or any volume, this takes us maybe 30 to
50 minutes to release something and pump
it because it is so simple.
I know. It just shows you how bullshitty
it is.
Look, if I go and lock all the Mew I
have, let's say in the Mew smart contract
for the tiers, So that will boost and give
me another maybe one million into the TVL.
And that puts us in maybe in a second in
all the proof of work chains on DeFiLlama.
It's just, it's just stupid metrics. I
would say.
Yeah, I know. It's like, it's literally
like, I feel like these kinds of things,
like central exchanges, when they do this
kind of bull crap and other projects that
fake this kind of stuff. I feel like you
ever go to Like an amusement park or a
winery and they have a pond and they have
these carp, there's like a billion carp
that are like tripping over each other. I
feel like it's sad. It's like just so
easy. It's just like, here's some
breadcrumbs and there comes a billion
fricking carp to it. It's like, it's just
so asinine. Now you've ruined my day HQ.
I think you are married. You don't have
any days in here.
That's true. Speaking of that, I got to
go pick up my dog and bring him back home
and then get back to work. So I think we
will chop chop this thing. Sound good?
Sound good, boys?
Yeah. Have a nice day, guys. I'm going to
cut some veggies and make some shawarma.
All right, guys. Definitely. Everybody
contribute to Ergo Santa. It'll be fun.
You'll get something back. Hey, real
quick. Are you guys splitting that up this
time? So if there were, I don't know, 200
keys, you're just taking whatever the
token value is dividing by 200 or somebody
getting.
No, I think, I think we're just, we're
not sending any keys this time. It will be
a DEX campaign. So we will be set up, set
up multiple DEX campaign based on tokens.
So for example, if we have a lot of FAKU,
so we can create a campaign on FAKU. So
you have to trade in this liquidity pair.
And as this is one of the rewards, you
will gain more on top of that.
I'm just asking because it says get
airdrop. That's what I'm just trying to,
you know.
Yeah, because you will get the airdrop.
So if you contribute in a DEX campaign,
you will be part of it. It doesn't matter
if you do a single ERG or multiple ERG or
whatever you do. It will be depending on
your contributions, which you do, but you
will get a drop. Maybe you get some gold
or who knows whatever you will get.
All right, boys. Sounds like a plan.
Thanks, everybody, for joining. And next
week is another break. So it's Christmas
here in the US. I guess in the world, too,
right? It's not a US-exclusive holiday.
Oh, please help me. In which world do you
live? Dude, I live in no sleep and
building and all that kind of stuff. So
yeah, I know. Tell me about it.
And then after that, maybe we'll do,
what's it called? A dev update. I'm going
to try to record a video with Joe at some
point. If I can talk him into it, maybe
we'll just pop on late at night and drink
and do it. Those are always fun. But other
than that, yeah, CannonQ just mentioned in
chat, please listen to the, it's right
here. Let me show you. It is the chat that
he just did, kushti just did with a, now
it's too far down. Goodness gracious.
What's the name of it, you guys remember?
Here we go, right here. Bitcoin Takeover,
full episode right there on YouTube. You
can go through it right here, right there.
Super neat. Really good talk between
kushti and this guy. It doesn't say, does
it, what its name is?
Yeah. It's Vlad Kostya.
I think you're right, Vlad. So guys, go
listen to that. It's really short. It's
three hours and 21 minutes.
Half of it's the hotel kicking kushti off
the Wi-Fi.
Well, I think I listened to an hour and a
half of it, and then I had to hop in the
car, so I didn't finish it up. But from
what I heard of the hour and a half, it's
pretty good. Some good insights from
kushti. Some good dig in there. So
everybody, enjoy yourselves. If I don't
see you before the holidays, have a great
holiday, and we'll see you on the flip
side of the new year. Thanks, everybody.