All right. Everybody that came in person,
thank you for coming. It's pretty cool to
see a little group of people focused on
the same thing. Ultimately, peer-to-peer
networks kind of replicate real life where
your community, people you know, people
you exchange with kind of create the basis
for everything in your life, right?
And that's one of the really interesting
things about decentralized systems, is
that on one hand you have like technical
parameters, but on the other hand you have
a social system. And kind of like any
social system you have various levels of
like trust, sometimes you could call that
belief. And in the extreme, I would even
say it's healthy to have an element of
faith in each other, people in your
networks.
Now that is both something that can offer
a lot of benefits. It can allow you entry
into a peer-to-peer system, but it's also
something that is an attack vector, right?
If you have people that kind of exploit
your trust or your belief or your
emotions, that doesn't always end well.
I had a presentation put together to kind
of cover the basis of Ergo itself. And
then I was thinking last night, everybody
here anyway, and many people that are
probably tuning in already know these
things, right? So what is the point of
just repeating, I don't know, what's
publicly available, and anybody with some
time, energy, or desire can easily read?
Now I know that's somewhat of a skill
that's being lost, is the ability to read,
but it's there, right?
I do think it's fascinating kind of the
events of yesterday, right? So let's just
speak to the moment. Yesterday I was out
having some beer and some food with some
of the people that showed up completely
oblivious to, you know, the workings of
kind of the broader crypto ecosystem and
you come back and they're like, oh, you
know, there's been a spiral effect of
deleveraging and, you know, billions have
been removed from the market and what's
happening and all these people I don't
know, hopefully manage their risk, right?
A good starting point is understanding
like risk management and leverage.
Leverage is a powerful tool when it's
needed, right? But it's also risky. It's
not without its trade-offs. And I think
that sometimes you have the talking heads
in the crypto industry that do not like to
talk about risk. And I think that's a
fundamental failure of the cryptocurrency
ecosystem broadly.
Because ultimately in our world, money is
a control system, right? We live, let's
say, within the United States. You have a
group of people on a hill somewhere, they
say, right? And they go into a room and
they discuss in private. Okay, publicly
they'll say we have two parameters. We
want to have employment at a certain
level. We want to have inflation at a
certain level.
And those two don't necessarily correlate
in terms of how they move anyway, right?
But they go into a room in secret and
everybody around the world gathers and
watches. Say, what are they going to do
with our money? What is going to be the
cost of money? And we sit around and
speculate and sometimes people have fun on
polymarket or whatever.
And eventually smoke comes out of the
chimney and we say, okay, this is our new
updated policy. They forked the network,
so to speak, and this is going to be the
cost of money. And we go through this
ritual, you know, regularly, people around
the world tune in and watch and position
and try to kind of front run whatever that
trusted setup is going to be.
And then on a higher level we have this
idea of, let's call it the type of
cross-chain tariff, right? Where
arbitrarily you have new costs added to
the system. That's, I guess, what was a
part of the madness yesterday, more or
less. Let's see. Where suddenly, you know,
you have these two economies that interact
and we're going to add a hundred percent
tariff, right?
And there's no real consensus mechanism
to understand what is coming, right? It's
a trusted system where the individual has
very little power. They have very little
power in terms of understanding what the
assumption is today and what the
assumptions are going to be tomorrow. And
that's not the type of environment that
produces I don't know, the right mindset
for risk itself, right?
And that's one of the most interesting
things about this idea that started with
Bitcoin is saying, okay, can we have a
system where the parameters are set?
Right? Where monetary policy is more or
less set, and then build economy on top of
set expectations. And based on how the
network is set up, within a certain set of
assumptions, you can assume honesty.
That's powerful.
If you look at kind of the traditional
system that we're all born into, it's
something we just naturally inherit. It
changes depending on where you're from,
right? But it's kind of more or less the
same system where you have high
concentration of power and then of course
one of the most profitable things is to be
close to power, right? Close to where
money is being distributed from and
generally the further away you get from
that initial distribution point of money,
the more inflation and expansion of money
supply tends to hit, right?
I would say a lot of the crypto industry
has really gotten away from first
principles. And in my opinion, that's
based on toxic social systems. Because
that social system is inherent to these
type of networks. Where you constantly
have people that are saying, trust me,
believe in me, have faith in me. And I
think that is not the ideal environment to
create the systems that we want to build,
right?
It's a part of why, at least with Ergo,
I've always tried to push for building
public. We should ideally have these
primitives in place that are the
equivalent of public goods. They're open,
they're auditable, and hopefully through
time and with testing, they also become
extended, right? They become extendable.
You could look at something within the
Ergo network like SigmaUSD, right? You
have first it's based on research, right?
It's not something that is just
willy-nilly thrown together, which we do
see a lot of that in the space, right? So
as an experiment, it has a solid
foundation, right? Then you have kind of
open code, open parameters around that
experiment.
That even if the experiment itself
experiences difficulty, you have the
ability to extend it, adjust it. It's
open, right? It's open to new ideas. It's
open to new iteration. And ultimately,
through time, I think we can build solid
public goods with that framework.
And my hope would be that creates its own
flywheel effect. Everybody in crypto these
days will talk about the flywheel in terms
of financial games. The ideal, in my
opinion, is to create flywheels with
software to where you have these public
goods that can then be reused, right? And
the more diverse these building blocks
come, you can suddenly cater to a larger
class of functions and applications and
build something that has a solid
foundation.
Sometimes we get away from this idea of
open code. And I think that type of
transparency should be a solid base for a
healthy social system because it's based
in trust, right? Not faith.
You know, we are a proof of work network.
And proof of work, one of the interesting
things is a coordination mechanism is it's
leaderless. It's apolitical, right? And
that's something that people often
struggle with, like grasping in terms of
the social system. You know, they'll say,
hey, Armeanio, you need to go dance over
here. Go do over there. You're supposed to
be a leader.
And it's like, well, I have a certain set
of skills, right? But meeting everybody
that attended, and I'm sure everybody
watching, you have a different set of
skills. No different than in the off-chain
peer-to-peer economy, you bring different
skill sets, different abilities, different
specialties that you've developed through
time in your life, and you create value
using those.
I don't think there should be that much
difference. I'm not universally
intelligent enough to be the leader of
everything, right? I have my areas where I
would say I've learned and grown and
developed a certain skill set, but in
other areas, you do not want me in charge,
right? I'm not the guy.
And people struggle with that. Because in
social systems, a lot of the competition
is to be the guy, right? You know,
certainly if I have people's trust and
belief in faith and they follow me, you
know, I guess that's an attack vector that
we see all the time in crypto.
And it's funny how, you know, the sheep
are taught their entire life to fear the
wolf. And then in the end, the shepherd
eats them. Right? You know, so having that
basis of how do we create trustlessness,
not just in software, but also in the
social system itself, that takes
responsibility. It takes a collective
responsibility, right? We're going to
build things the right way.
And at least in Extended UTXO, there is a
trilemma, let's call it. You have the
contract itself. You have the off-chain
logic. You have the front end, right? In
the ideal scenario, all three of those can
be replicated locally. That's what I would
say makes for a decentralized application.
That's pretty clear parameters, right?
So as an ecosystem, I think it's healthy
to really push for that. That's something
that I've always tried to promote. And
it's hard to build open code, right?
Because you are in essence being naked in
public. It is sometimes a process to get
there, right? But I think that is
ultimately, a solid goal in terms of
building public goods.
You know, so we hear about this trilemma
in blockchain all the time. You know, you
usually have, it's a selling point. For
lack of a better term, it's a selling
point. But I do think that within the Ergo
ecosystem anyway, I would like to promote
the idea of our own little trilemma, which
are those three aspects of an application.
And ideally, if you have those three
aspects that are open, and you have
tooling that becomes kind of a common
knowledge base for developers to use and
build off of. You have things in place to
start creating the right flywheel. That's
kind of hard to bootstrap from nothing,
but I think we've done a pretty good job
as a whole of creating that mindset and
mind-share.
There have been a lot of developers, some
of which are here, some of which choose to
remain faceless, which I totally respect,
that have contributed to that type of
mindset. And so, you know, everybody
that's contributed to that ideal public
goods, I kind of have to tip my hat to
you, that's ultimately powerful when it
comes to not just the network itself, but
also the social system of the network.
Now, from first principles, crypto should
be about the distribution of power. Proof
of work kind of represents that in terms
of the distribution mechanism of money
itself. It's something that you can
certainly compete for and build into, but
having clear assumptions in terms of
distribution of power is needed.
And sometimes that is buried behind
really good marketing. Sometimes that's
buried behind social systems. Sometimes
it's buried behind this trust me bro
mentality that permeates the crypto
industry and I think that's toxic and I
don't really care if people don't like
that. Right because if you can't call a
spade a spade your social system is not
going to work right. That's just honest.
I know there's a lot of financial games
and cultural movements and things like
that. I've said from day one, for me
personally, I would rather go to a casino.
I know the drinks are free. That's a solid
assumption that I can bank on every time.
And whatever my parameters of risk are
with the games that I play, at least I
know that assumption is going to hold.
Now, security is another powerful
mechanism of both the network parameters
and kind of this social layer, because we
do need to address both, right? Sometimes
we see them as separate and they're
extensions of each other, you know, in
terms of what people accept.
Security, at least in our industry, is
something that's formed through time. You
usually have research as the bedrock of
computer science. Then on top of research,
you have implementations where people will
try to take research use engineering
skills to convert that into something
that's tangible. And then you have the
test of time, which kind of is the
ultimate teacher in life.
So having things that are built on a
solid foundation and are introduced and
kind of go through this test of hardening
through time ultimately should be a goal.
That doesn't mean you can't innovate,
right? It doesn't mean you can't extend.
It doesn't mean you can't provide
research.
Certainly in Ergo, we have led in various
areas of implementing things that kind of
came from the academic sphere. But I think
there's an element of wisdom in being
conservative, right? And sometimes that is
not the focus of the crypto space, right?
Innovation is wonderful, but I would also
say that sometimes iteration is
innovation, right? Where you take
something, you extend it. It holds you
extended, it holds you extended rather
than, you know, trying to reinvent the
wheel for the 700th time and, you know,
it's good for marketing. It's not
necessarily good for security, right?
Because you have a weird curve
distribution where through time, you know,
usually you have the research side, right?
And like the engineering complexity let's
say, is much higher. And then through
time, as it becomes more of a standard, it
becomes easier to adopt. There's better
tools.
Like that whole process of evolution is
not something that you can cheat very
effectively. It's something that is much
slower than the hype cycles that people
are taught, right?
So I want everyone to remember when it
comes to security that time is ultimately
the test. We can look at the first
principle of privacy, which is probably
fundamentally one of the most important
things we need to explore.
There is some potential future where the
children people in this room have could
grow up into a world where every economic
transaction they touch is audited, stored,
and you know, you could watch every penny
that someone has touched throughout the
course of their life. That type of control
system is getting to the point where it's
technically possible, and that should
frighten the hell out of everybody, right?
That type of system, I do believe there
are some powers in this world. That's
where they would like to take humanity,
right? Because it certainly offers them
greater power and control.
And so I think having the ability to
remain private, anonymous, have your
personal space is going to be one of the
most fundamentally important things that
we need to work to protect as an industry.
And that doesn't just mean we're going to
add zero-knowledge proofs to everything
and have more control systems in place.
I think that's a bit of a perversion from
privacy itself, right? That's a trade-off
that many people see is quite sexy, right?
Where, you know, we're going to have ZK
compliance and, you know, if you just get
more and more and more and more ZK
compliance, you have a stronger control
system.
So I think we need to really look at this
idea of privacy, make that an absolute,
chase that on multiple layers of networks
rather than have it be toy. Because, you
know, I would say in some cases, yes, it
does offer like visibility assistance in
terms of people not seeing your
transactions or what's happening, but in
terms of the broader assumption, it's toy
privacy, it's not real.
And I think we need to be very clear in
terms of what our set of assumptions are
long term with privacy and what the goals
are with privacy. Because there are a lot
of projects, there's a lot of research
beyond Ergo itself that is valuable in
terms of preserving privacy, preserving
anonymity.
I think that ultimately should be one of
the most important tenets of creating
censorship-resistant systems and
censorship-resistant money.
You know, the other area has to do with
inclusion, right? We are seeing a mix in
the space where it comes to regulated
assets, non-regulated assets, bearer
assets, non-bearer assets. And that needs
to be something that there's a lot of
clarity with, because not everything in
crypto is the same.
I know that in the social layer,
everything is a ticker with some letters
in it, right? But the underlying
assumptions that you need to make in terms
of custodial, non-custodial, is this a
bearer asset, is this not a bearer asset,
is probably going to get even more complex
when we start seeing regulated assets
appearing.
We've kind of seen some of this freeze
and seize with stable coins, but the
crypto industry is changing. Even
yesterday or two days ago, there's an
announcement that these 10 major banks are
going to collaborate and create some
stablecoin instruments. Oddly enough, they
tend to be the same banks that are in the
corporation that's on the hill, but that's
the side journey that probably not the
rabbit hole for right now.
But that type of assumption of inclusion
is going to get really important. I do
know that kushti has been working on a
whitelist mechanism, which I think is
probably the better way to deal with
uncertainty in terms of power.
Where, you know, rather than you join and
you might get blacklisted at any time for
any reason, you make a voluntary
agreement. And hopefully there's clear
assumptions in that agreement in terms of
the risks that you're inheriting in doing
that, right?
Last is probably this element of
resilience, right? And ultimately, I think
that's why open source code is so
important because good ideas are hard to
kill, right? I do hope not just within
Ergo, but within various aspects of the
cryptocurrency space and some of the
privacy space that's been around, we're
able to develop tools that ultimately
develop into truly resilient systems.
I've operated under the belief that over
the long arc of time, the only thing of
value in cryptocurrency really is state
resistance. Everything else will probably,
in my opinion, distill down to the common
denominator underneath, which is
centralization.
Because if you're not shooting for state
resistance, ultimately the most efficient
thing is going to prevail through time,
and the most efficient thing will be
centralized. No, maybe it'll be pseudo
centralized. We can have a debate whether
Amazon Web Services is distributed,
decentralized, because you have data
centers all over the place that optimize
speed.
But I would say that in terms of power
distribution, we have to be honest and
say, OK, it is distributed, but the actual
concentration of power there is pretty
apparent.
So over time, if we build on first
principles, I do believe that the crypto
space is capable of developing open source
tools for coordinating capital and
creating systems where within a certain
set of assumptions, we can assume honesty.
And luckily, at least with Ergo, we have
this proof of work mechanism that has a
pretty well time tested mechanism of what
are your assumptions of honesty? What are
your attack vectors?
In terms of the contractual layer that
we've come up with, it is relatively
conservative. So I think those are solid
building blocks towards a larger goal.
Sometimes within the social layer of
crypto, you sign on to TwitterX, whatever
you want to call it, and you listen to
the, I don't know, commentary, the talking
heads. It does kind of leave you
wondering, what the hell are we doing?
Right?
Why are we here? And I think that
ultimately should be the most important
aspect is we need to have clear intent and
clear purpose. Because if you don't have
clear intents and clear purpose, you're
not going to be grounded in what you do,
right? And crypto as a whole, I would say,
needs to be more grounded, right?
I do hope that over time, we create a
tool set that's diverse enough, you know,
and again, an extended UTXO that's going
to be contractual, it's going to be off
chain, it's going to be front end wise. We
create enough tools around those three
problem areas, the trilemma, let's say,
that we can serve a diverse set of needs.
And I think sometimes marketing and kind
of just social spam buries that intent,
right? So my hope in going through all of
the presentations that we've set up all of
the speakers, everybody here is doing
really unique things that are targeted
that improve like the assumptions that
offer new tools and understanding that as
a piece that can be replicated within a
whole, over time I believe will lead to a
broader tool set that's powerful.
And I think we've done a pretty good job
as an ecosystem developing open public
goods, sets of tools that have led to some
interesting things. We just went through a
major upgrade with Sigma 6, new node
version, right? And that will open the
door to a lot of new capacity.
And I hope that as we kind of build to
enhance new system capacities, we stay
focused in on mission. Because that type
of purpose I think is important. It's not
just important for like solid programming,
beyond the network, it's important for the
social system.
And the social system in crypto is very
toxic. It's just honest. You know, I
sometimes have said, you know, my favorite
thing is seeing all of these tools that
enhance individual power, takes
responsibility. My least favorite thing in
crypto is people that look for a savior,
right?
Because that's not really how
peer-to-peer networks work. That's the
client-server relationship, my friends. So
if we get back to this idea of saying,
okay, how can we distribute power across
peers and empower peers to have tooling,
to have access, to have software that
ultimately can serve them and their needs,
that's the ideal for cryptocurrency.
I would say everything else is just
digital money. And I think we need to kind
of lean into that because, you know, the
possibilities if, you know, privacy does
not work as an industry, if resilience
doesn't work as an industry, the
trade-offs are huge in terms of the world
long-term, you know, that could be spun up
around us.
And, you know, sometimes I wonder what
kind of world my children will live in,
right? Like, I can see myself, I was born
into this strange system, you know, you
got the people on the hill, you've got,
you know, this distribution of power that
I can't really touch or interact with
much.
But what about the future? How much
stronger could that get theoretically? And
that should scare the shit out of
everybody, in all honesty. So for me, I
think that kind of sums up the purpose,
the intent of why I'm here, right? It's
the only thing that matters.
So I do hope that as an industry, it's
something that, you know, we can mature
around, look at all of the trade-offs of
control in different areas and build
wisely. So I'm going to kick it off to
MGPai and Luca. I need to set up their
mics, set up their presentation, get them
ready to go. But thank you everybody for
tuning in and enjoy.
Hey, guys. So that was a great speech
from Joe. And thank you to Joe and the
Sigmanauts for sponsoring and hosting this
event. It's wonderful to finally see some
faces. So today, we're going to be talking
about Palm staking on the UTXO model.
So over the last year or so, I worked on
implementing a native token staking
platform on Cardano. And as you know,
Cardano and Ergo are very similar in terms
of how their contracts work. And they all
share the UTXO model. So I'll try to keep
this as easy to understand as possible so
everyone can understand.
So we have some existing implementations
of staking already. So if you guys don't
know, over the last cycle DeFi summer, we
had sushi swap and pancake swap. And for
really anyone new here, pancake swap was
like how Solana is today. They had all the
memes and they were going crazy with all
the meme coins, all the launches, and
staking with those meme coins.
And before PancakeSwap, we had SushiSwap,
which really was a Uniswap clone, but they
actually did some research and they were
the first ones to implement this native,
the modern native token staking or ERC20
staking. So sushi swap had this staking
which really is to incentivize people
right because staking makes people hold
their tokens right so it kind of
stabilizes price movements and yeah sushi
swap pioneered this and then we got
pancake swap which basically copied it and
made some improvements and really brought
it to the mass users, right?
Tons of people were just making meme
coins and having staking with it. So, you
know, you don't sell those meme coins and,
you know, kind of like inflation and Ponzi
scheme and so on.
So let's have a refresher. So what is the
account model and what is the UTXO model,
right? So the account model is... Let's
start with UTXO. So what are UTXOs? UTXOs
were pioneered by Bitcoin, right? That's
how they started their entire system.
So UTXOs stand for unspent transaction
outputs. And it's basically the outputs of
the previous transaction you did. So when
you submit a transaction, you have a bunch
of metadata, right? You have what went
into the transaction and what came out of
the transaction. And the outputs of this
transaction are referred to as UTXOs.
And the transaction model really is an
exact digital analogy to cash. So let's
say I have a $10 bill, and I want to pay
for $6 coffee. It's probably $8 now, no
inflation. And if I want to pay for $6 of
coffee with my $10 bill, I can't just rip
the bill in half, right?
I have to spend the entire $10 bill. So
what do I do? I give the cashier my entire
bill and that's it. They have the bill.
They're not going to rip it in half or
anything. It's just gone. But they're
going to give me back $4. And this $4 is
completely new. It's not the original
bill, it's just completely new. The $10 I
had, it's gone.
So this is how you can think of the UTXO
model. When you have an input, it always
must be spent. It's always unique. You
cannot spend an input more than once.
Unlike cache, I guess the cashier could
spend it in other places. But in the UTXO
model, it can be only spent once.
And another analogy that I like is with
the old-fashioned piggy banks, right? So
you would have savings in a piggy bank,
and if you ever wanted to spend it, you
would have to smash it open, right? It's
like a one-time thing. So you can also
think of that, right? I have $10 in my
piggy bank. The piggy bank is the UTXO,
and that's like the input, right?
And then if I want to actually spend it,
I would smash the piggy bank open, and
it's gone, right? Just one time. So that's
really a brief overview of the UTXO model
and Cardano and Ergo both make use of
this.
So what's the account model? Account
model is really the newer model and it was
pioneered by Ethereum. And account model
really is analogous to your bank account
where you just have a list of transactions
saying that maybe $10 was deposited and
you're spending $1 and you have a list of
transaction history, right?
So addresses are seen as accounts and you
just have a direct tally of balance. And
the thing with this, and I think of it as
a problem, is that you need global state,
right? So you need to know the history of
everything from the start, right? When the
account got funded to how much you have
now, to know how much you have at this
moment, right?
You have to do some calculations, right?
Some balance add, balance deductions and
so on. So but this is overall how the
account model works and it is also quite
popular, right? All the Ethereum forks use
that and Solana uses that and all the
newer model and newer blockchains also use
that.
For those of you following Cardano, they
have a new blockchain called Midnight that
they're probably going to launch next
quarter or so. And Midnight uses a hybrid
of account model and UTXO, so it's quite
popular.
So let's talk about the advantage of
account model in the context of this
staking. Staking is more analogous to a
client-server interaction. What that means
is that a server is really just a computer
that never turns off. It's always running
in the background. Client is really the
people who hit that server. You need to
talk to that server to do something.
For example, if you're logging into your
email account, you're accessing a server
which holds all your emails and all. And
you're the client, you're trying to log in
from your laptop. So that's a
client-server interaction.
So staking is similar to this
interaction, where the stakers are the
clients. And they deposit their tokens to
a contract. And this contract, you can
think of it as like a server in the sense
that the contract has to manage all the
global state, right? It has to track the
balance so it knows how much rewards that
you get, right?
Because rewards are a function of how
much tokens you deposit and how long you
have deposited them for. So Solidity is
the smart contract, a very popular smart
contract language that runs on this
account model. So Solidity is perfect,
right? It has a single authoritative
contract storage, right?
So you have something called a map, and a
map is a very basic data structure that
you have a key. So a key is like the user,
like your user, your wallet address. And
if you access the data within that wallet
address, you have a bunch of data like how
much they have deposited in the contract
and how long they had the tokens on and
all sorts of useful information. Perfect
for this.
And then this doesn't translate well to
something in the UTXO model. So for UTXO
contracts, you have a single UTXO, right?
And each UTXO, you can think of it as its
own entity. So an UTXO has its, each UTXO
can have its own contract. So a contract's
state release with respect to the UTXO
it's inside of.
So a UTXO has this bottleneck, right? You
can't just store infinite data in it,
right? The UTXO, you have a size limit.
And you also have a broader transaction
size limit because you can argue that,
hey, why don't you have a bunch of UTXOs,
this single UTXOs, interact with?
So you can have a bunch of data. So if a
UTXO data size limit is 4 kilobytes, you
can be like, OK, why don't we just do
1,000 UTXOs? Why not? Why not make it like
four gigabytes or something, right? No,
that's not possible because you have your
bottleneck by transaction size limits.
You can only deal with a specific amount
of UTXOs per transaction. And then on top
of that, you also got the block size
limit, right? So you can only have a
certain amount of transactions per block.
So a lot of bottlenecks here. So how can
we move on with this?
It almost seems impossible to bring
something that needs such a large global
seed. Because remember, this might
translate to like 10 users, 100 users. But
how are we going to scale to like 10,000
users? Because each user are going to have
some size of data that's not going to
scale. So how do we do this?
So I had to rethink staking on the UTXO
model. So data stored for the global
variables, so for all sorts of staking
calculations, they need to be bound to a
constant size limit. You can't have it
scale with the amount of users, right? So
you can't be like, OK, one user is like
one gigabyte of data, right? 10,000 users
is 10,000 gigabytes.
We can't scale like that. It has to be
one user is like one gigabyte of data. A
million users is still one gigabyte of
data, right? How can we make that happen?
It has to be constant.
So a clear solution which several
projects on Cardano and Ergo follow, so I
think the people behind Crux Finance, I'm
forgetting their name, I think they're
shut down now but you know they pioneered
a staking model and then a bunch of
Cardano projects have their own staking.
So what do they do? So they have some
sort of position or UTXO or NFT that you
can think of which indicates a share of
how much they have staked, right? So let's
say you stake a certain amount of tokens,
you'll get back like a unique token saying
that, hey, this person staked like 100
tokens on the platform at this time,
right?
So if you ever want to claim that stake
back, make an update, you have to deposit
that unique token you got back into the
contract, right? And this is a pretty
straightforward and well-known solution to
this problem. However, this was not ideal
for ZenGate's purpose because of legal
conflicts.
The problem is that you can have
derivative markets of something like a
position token because I can take my
position token and I can be like okay I
don't want to be in this anymore but I
don't want to lose like that accumulation
of rewards right like maybe like the
longer you stake the faster you earn
rewards or something right it keeps
compounding so maybe I sell it to someone
else or just give it to someone else right
or what if...
So you create these derivative markets,
and it's a conflict from a legal
standpoint. I don't know why, but it is
what it is. It's a very gray area in
general, unfortunately.
So I thought of this data structure
called a Merkle tree. And this was
absolutely perfect. So on Ergo, you have
the AVL tree. And it's quite similar, so
it can just translate to Ergo.
Also, what's actually really interesting
is that the Merkle Tree data structure is
something that was just implemented at a
contract level on Cardano. However, on
Ergo, ErgoScript, you have AVL tree as
like a native data structure within the
language.
So what that means is that basically you
can trust the data structure on Ergo more
because like the core team, so basically
kushti made the implementation like in the
compiler itself, right? So it's not like a
third party code that you're trusting to
be correct, which is like, which is the
case on Cardano.
So let's see what is a Merkle tree,
because I honestly barely knew about it
until I did this.
So a Merkle tree is a tree-based data
structure. And a tree-based data
structure, you can really think of it
having a root at the top. And it has
branches pointing to more roots, right? So
you can kind of see that data structure in
the diagram behind me.
And the boxes, they're called nodes. So
you have one root node. It's the main node
on top. Then you have those lines are
called branches. And then you have another
node that's called branches. They're like
intermediary nodes. And all the way at the
bottom, you can see a bunch of nodes, like
the final nodes. Those are called the
leaves.
That's just a very well-known data
structure in computer science. So a Merkle
tree is a variant of this data structure.
And it's made by hashing hashes of data.
So I know that's confusing. So let's break
that down.
So behind me, you can see that you have a
block of data, like a block of files. So
A.txt, B.txt, C.txt, D.txt. And you hash
this block of data. And hashing really
means is that you take data of any size
and you convert it into a fixed-sized
string of a certain data size.
So in this, or in most cases, it's always
32 bytes of data. So it's like a string of
64 characters. And the cool part about
this, which is really important in a
security context, is that it's
irreversible. So if you have this
fixed-size string, you can't get the data
back. It's impossible.
But that's beyond the scope of this
presentation. So again, you have a data,
and you transform it into a fixed-size,
unique string. So you can see A.text has a
hash H1Z2, B.text has its own hash, and so
on.
So how does this translate to a Merkle
tree? So look at the tree behind me. All
the way at the bottom, the leaf nodes, you
can see that we brought those hashes over,
right? The H1Z2Y77A and so on, right? So
those are the hashes brought to the node,
and they're at the bottom.
So now you look at the left side, the
bottom left side of the tree. So we take
the H1Z2Y7FA. We can't read it from here.
And so those are the hashes for A.text,
B.text, right? So we take those hashes and
we concatenate them. We put them together.
And we take the hash of that.
So the hash of that, you can see, is
right above those two. So it's U67R on the
left side. And again, we do this exact
thing on the right side. So for C.txt and
D.txt, and we get a hash. Now those hashes
in the middle, again, we take them, we
concatenate them, and we get the hash. And
that final hash is called the root hash.
So why this is really cool is because you
can find differences between two states,
so meaning like two different trees. So if
you made any modifications, you can find
the difference between them like really
fast because think of it logically right
if you have two pieces of data what do you
have to do you have to iterate through
them right like one like bit at a time
like the smallest like unit of difference
right you have to iterate through them so
you know if there's like a million pieces
of like units of data you have to make at
least like at most a million iterations
right it doesn't scale so with this it's a
lot faster right it's like the log of a
million maybe that's like like a thousand
or ten thousand.
I don't know, but it's a lot
significantly faster, right? So let me
explain this further. So you can see that
we had the text files, right? And we
changed the contents of C.text. And what
does that do? We got a new hash. So you
can see A4W12, right?
So on the right side of the Merkle tree,
you can see that all the way at the
bottom, that changed, right? It's in
yellow. And now, since that changed, the
hash above it, which is, remember, made by
concatenating the hash of C.text and
D.text, that also changed, right? And
since that changed, the root hash also
changed.
So you can see here that when you
traverse the tree, you first check the
left side. And you're like, oh, the left
side's exactly the same. So you know that
A.text and B.text is clearly unchanged.
But then you go to the right side, and you
can see that, OK, D.txt isn't changed,
right? Although at the bottom right, it's
still the same.
So then you know really quickly that
C.txt is changed. So it's a really clever
data structure. It actually powers so much
of the modern infrastructure. You just
don't know it. But that's a quick
introduction to a Merkle tree.
So yeah, you can see here the comparisons
made, right? So on the left side was the
original tree, and the right side is the
tree with the C.text changed. So you can
see we just make three comparisons. So
this scales really well.
So now what we actually use for the
staking is something called the Merkle
Patricia trie. And what this is is
basically an optimized version of the
Merkle Tree. So a trie really is a, you
can think of it as a key value map indexed
by the key's nibble. So it's just like a
bunch of characters, like ASCII
characters. And that's what a trie is.
And Patricia is just an optimization of
the path, right? So it's a very optimized
structure. So you make even less. So in
the previous slide, we made like three
traversals, right? So this makes it even
smaller, like maybe like one or two. And
then Merkle is from what we discussed
before.
And then the proof is the path of nodes
that you traversed, right? So in the
previous slide, we traversed through like
three nodes. So that's like the proof, you
can think of it as that. And then proving,
right? What is the action of proving?
So you have the inputs of the known root
hash, right? So the hash all the way at
the top, you have that. And then you
provide the proof. So you provide that
path. And then you provide the key and the
claimed value. So you walk through from
the root node to until you get to the key.
You walk through the tree.
And then once you reach to the value, you
stop. And then you compute the root hashes
from that traversal. You can do that same
hashing from the scratch. And then you
compare it. Hey, is the thing I computed,
does it match what I already know? And if
yes, then you know that everything's
correct, like no one's messing with
anything, right?
And yeah, so membership is proven when
the computed root equals the known root.
And the known root is what you passed in.
So let's talk about how this integrates
into staking. So client balances are
stored in this trie-based data structure
and on-chain, so in the contracts itself,
only the root hash is stored. And
remember, the root hash is a fixed size
string of 32 bytes, right? Because it's a
hash.
And that answers the problem in the, you
know, we saw a couple slides back where we
want one user to be, say, one gigabyte of
data, and we want a million users to still
be that one gigabyte of data. So it's
constant. So in this case, it's always a
constant 32 bytes, which is incredibly
tiny.
So it's always this number, even if we
have a million clients, which is really
cool. And thanks to that Merkle tree
diagram I explained, it's hashes of hashes
of hashes and so on. So any time any
insertions or updates done, the contract
does verification.
So as I explained in the previous slide,
you have a proof and you have the known
root hash. So you provide the proof and
the known root hash. And what does the
contract do? The contract only does
computing, right? It only does
verification. It doesn't need to do all
the data storage or anything, right?
You provide the exact data that it needs.
The least amount of data it needs to
actually prove what you're doing is
correct and you're not providing false
information. So, and remember, after all
of this is done, so if there's any like
mutations sent to the state, so meaning
like if you added more stake or you did a
claim or you did a withdrawal, that's a
mutation, right?
The only thing that changes is the root
hash, right? So it's always that constant
size length.
When these updates and claims happen,
you're providing the proof. The downside
of this is that you have to store this
data somewhere. It's not magic. So you
have to store the data in your own server,
right? It's called the off-chain. So you
have to store the data.
You're responsible for storing the data
in Solidity. You can just throw it on the
blockchain and just make sure, like the
EVM nodes, right? The Ethereum nodes, the
heavy 2, 3 terabytes, 6 terabytes nodes,
right? That stores all of that, right? So
you just worry about that. But on the Ergo
sense, you are storing the data.
Great. No, that's an excellent question.
So we got Grayman asking, what if the
staking platform goes down? Or what if I
just disappears, everyone's screwed? What
if I just take down all my servers? Well,
that's actually not going to be an issue.
Because like I said, you're not trusting
me with the data.
I can't just magically change the data.
Because all the mutations, they're done by
putting them through the contract right so
if you have like some initial state you
have to put it through the contract to get
the next state right so the contracts
always the intermediary between state
changes so the contract does all the
checks it needs to do.
Regarding the data, it's really cool
because you can actually walk through the
blockchain, walk through all the blocks
and you can always recalculate it. It's
not magic. The blockchain doesn't store
the data but it has like... You can think
of it as snapshots in time, right?
So you can traverse through all the
original snapshots and get back the
current data, the most recent current
state. So no, you're not trusting me, and
you have as much security as the contract
provides. Is that clear?
Right, and so the question is, how can
you recover if the data is just all
hashes? Then what you can recover, because
hashes are non-reversible. No, that's a
great question. So off-chain obviously
doesn't store the hashes. So whenever you
actually interact with the transaction,
you're providing the actual data, not the
hash, the actual data.
Into the transaction when you build it
and you submit the transaction. And the
contract is actually what hashes the data.
So you provide the complete open data.
You're not hiding the data. And then the
contract does the hashing and the
checking.
So like I said, it does computation,
right? The contract only does computation.
So you provide the raw data, and the
contract just does hashing of the data.
And this is possible because of, yeah, so
I have it in this slide here, that
whenever you do any staking, you provide
the actual raw data.
And it's done through something called
the Redeemer on Cardano. Or on Ergo, it's
called a context-aware. And it's the same
thing. It's just data that anyone can
provide into a transaction when you build
it and submit it. There's some limit of
data that you can provide into this.
We provide the actual data within this
constraint. When you do this, that data is
actually published on the blockchain. But
this is a really special type of data
where it's not actually in the context of
the node, right? So the node doesn't know
about the redeemer.
It doesn't save it for long term, but it
does save it from historical transactions,
right? Just in the same way that you know
the transactions an address did, right?
The address had an initial balance of one
ERG, and then, you know, a year later, it
has like a hundred. You can track that,
right?
So in the same sense, you can track this
data in the Redeemer context variable. So
really, to summarize, you can get back the
data by traversing historical
transactions. So you're not trusting me at
all.
All right, great. So yeah, no, just to
summarize, really, the contract is
something that just verifies the integrity
of the provided data. And that's really
the general theme of contracts on the UTXO
model contracts. Position really just to
verify all the data, right?
It doesn't make new data. It doesn't do
anything special. It just verifies, hey,
is what the transaction builder provided,
is that correct? Are they like lying about
something, right? Because checking
something is always far cheaper than
actually making it from scratch, right?
And I think that's really where UTXO
shines because account model has to store
all this data. I mean, sure, it's easier
for developers, but these node sizes are
ridiculous. I can't run a three terabyte
node in my basement just for Ethereum. And
that's just Ethereum.
You have all these forks, right? If I
want to expand to multi-chain, I have to
spin up like an Ethereum node, a Binance
node, Polygon node, and so on, right? If I
want to do the things the right way and
not, you know, buy like a subscription to
an RPC, right?
And it's not scalable, but in my
basement, I can run an Ergo node, which
has what, like 20 gigs, 30 gigs? It's
nothing, right? Flash Drive has more
storage than that. And Cardano node,
right? Cardano node was like 160
gigabytes. I can run plenty of these
compared to just one Ethereum node.
So you can see the trade-offs here. They
really shine in the long run.
So really the final slide here is
improvements made to the original
protocol, right? So the original contract
was short-lived and static. So like I
said, it was originally meant for like
things like meme coins, right? So where
you just don't want people to sell, right?
You don't really think about long-term.
And the problem with this was it was very
static. So you have one emission rate for
the whole program. So what I also added to
the protocol itself, not the UTXO
implementation, is I made the emissions
very dynamic.
So like every epoch, for example, on Palm
staking every week, people can claim their
rewards. This emission amount can
fluctuate without having to redeploy the
contract or get people to migrate. And
this is really cool because a dynamic
protocol allows us to easily curb any
excess inflation or incentivizes staking
during steep price movements.
So it allows us for more of a
fine-grained control rather than... So,
you know, we actually react to how the
economy is doing. I mean, you saw
yesterday that, you know, things went
crazy. So maybe during a time like that,
you want to incentivize people to hold,
right?
So maybe we'll tell them, okay, we can
increase inflation so that, you know,
people hold on to their palms instead of
selling it on the market just for no
reason right when everything's going crazy
right so then people might not sell
because they'll say hey like I can just
put in the contract I believe in Palm I
believe in this tokens future right I
believe in crypto so like maybe in a next
week you're not going to the tariffs are
going to be reversed and we won't have an
issue.
So maybe I want to hold my Palm and make
some more Palm and money instead of
selling, right? So the dynamic protocol
really allows for this. Yeah, that's it
for staking. So hopefully that was some
presentation that you could understand. I
tried to make it as least technical as
possible so everyone can enjoy. So any
other questions?
Yeah, so it's quite technical, but you
can think of, really, on the actual
usage-wise, rather than the data structure
implementation-wise, kushti mentioned that
the AVLG is actually a lot more efficient
compared to the Merkle-Patricia trie that
you have on Cardano.
Meaning the proof sizes, the really
efficient means that you can do more
operations in a given transaction. The
proof sizes are smaller. The data that you
provide during transaction building, it's
a lot smaller. What does it mean for the
end user? It means that transactions
really will be cheaper.
But there is a significant implementation
difference, how it works internally. But I
don't really know that from the top of my
head, and I can't speak for it that much.
But in the context of this, though, you
can think of it as interchangeable.
Correct, correct. So, Grayman brought up
a great point. So yesterday, again, I
don't think everyone's quite active on
Twitter, but Liquid, so there's a protocol
on Cardano called Liquid Finance and it's
a lending protocol. And what they did
yesterday was because of the extreme
movement.
So I think Cardano literally went from
like 80 cents to like 27 cents in like a
flash because of like mass liquidations.
So Liquid Finance is a decentralized
lending platform, right? So you provide
some collateral in ADA and you get back an
asset. So since the price moved down so
steeply, you're going to have some
liquidations due to that.
So Liquid Finance completely shut off
their front-end interface and you can't
manage your liquidations now right no one
can liquidate you or anything and you
can't make new collateral requests and so
on I don't I don't know why they did this
I mean obviously to protect people from
being hurt but like I don't know I think
everyone's like a grown man here and can
handle their finances so I think that's
kind of silly but it is what it is so yes,
they disabled the front end.
And maybe that I can make a custom
transaction using code to interact with
the contracts. But I actually found
Cardano's very funny. A lot of these
off-chain runners, so basically what
processes your transactions with the main
contract, they're actually permissioned.
So for people to run the off-chain bots,
you need to have like maybe you have to
own you have to be the owner of a certain
address right so only your private key can
actually run the transactions but what's
more common is like it's like a special
NFT right it's all NFT holders are the
ones that can run these off chain right
that and that's a very it's not
decentralized at all it's just made on a
decentralized platform.
So really, this is a very simple check,
right? Like you have a contract, right?
And you're like, okay, all these
calculations happen. It's decentralized.
But you add just one tiny check. Only the
owner, only the holder of this NFT can run
the transaction, right?
So technically, no. For a lot of
protocols on Cardano, no. You can't just
bypass everything and build your own
transactions with code. I can't do that
because I don't own that special NFT that
you need to actually process the
transactions.
And no, this is actually like really bad.
I don't know why. It's like a very common
on Cardano. But yeah, no, it's not really
decentralized. It's the answer.
Again, as Joe kept mentioning, know your
assumptions. It's something permissioned.
For example, we have the HODLerg game.
It's all open source. So if the front end
shut off, first of all, you can just spin
up your own front end because the code is
all there.
Second, you can build your own custom
transaction and you can run your own
off-chain because all that code is open
source. It's not hiding anything and you
don't need any special NFT. Even on
Cardano, if these projects are all open
source, even if the off-chain is all open
source, the website is all open source, it
doesn't matter because you need the NFT to
actually run the off-chain.
It's literally not going to work. So it's
decentralized, it's open source, but you
can't do anything.
Oh, no, that's a great question. Maybe we
can talk to Allison, who's in the back.
He's the Nautilus developer. But what
Grayman said is, hey, can we have a
HODLerg natively within the Nautilus
wallet itself? And I think that's really
cool.
Maybe we can have a dedicated apps
section on Nautilus wallet. I think it's
already there with SigUSD. But I think a
bunch of apps within Nautilus, so you
don't have to go to any website. Right,
you you're actually technically running
your own front end right because it's a
wallet extension so you're not even
reliant on me hosting the website.
So I think that's a great idea and we can
have like a bunch of apps on Nautilus
where just click like two buttons and you
know you interact with the protocol. I
really like this idea because again you're
not worried about any front-end, right? If
a front-end gets hacked, what a front-end
being hacked means is that someone takes
ownership of the domain that it's on,
right?
And injects custom code. So maybe they
made an exact replica of my front-end. And
then they're like, hey, when you click
this Mint button, instead of minting,
you're transferring all your ERG to an
address, right? That's what a hack really
means.
So this isn't really possible if you have
something running on your own instance,
like on Nautilus itself. I mean, it's only
possible if you literally physically
download a virus, and maybe the virus does
some magic where it has control of
Nautilus. But in general hacks, if my
website gets hacked, that's not going to
affect your Nautilus, which is running its
own app instance of HODLerg.
So that's a wonderful idea. We should
definitely get that going. All right, any
other questions, comments?
Yes, yes, it's live on Cardano. And yeah,
it's called Palm-economy.io. And you can
find information about it. And it's
specifically staking for Palm Token, which
is the token for Zengate's Palmyra RWA
platform.
So currently there is no plans to do it
on Ergo and it's not up to me right but in
the future the point is that it's pretty
straightforward right because now that
it's done on Cardano everything maps
directly to Ergo right so since all the
theories studies the theory guys is what
takes a long time right getting it done
right planning it out implementation is
pretty straightforward once you have this
theory, right?
So that's why EVM is so successful
because you already it's been there since
what 2015 and you have so many contracts
So guess what a new fork a new L2 Base has
their own block coinbase has their own
blockchain you take the contracts and you
copy paste it always literally copy paste
and so in a similar sense, since we
already have everything ready on Cardano,
when we're ready for Ergo, we can just
take that code and translate it over to
Ergo.
So it's much more trivial compared to
making it from scratch.
Yes, it's all very similar. It's not
exactly copy-paste, because on Ethereum,
it's literally a fork of the node. It's
the exact same thing. So you can actually
copy-paste the exact code and deploy it on
L2s and so on. So that's not the case for
UTXO. So you can't copy-paste it.
But the overall idea maps directly. So
you're just translating whatever Cardano
smart contract language to ErgoScript
exactly. There's less friction. There's I
mean, there's more friction than going
from like Ethereum to like an Ethereum
fork, but from like a conceptually, it's
like the same because the architecture is
the same. Yeah cheese.
Yeah, I would definitely use AVL because
it's built into the contract, right? They
both serve that same abstract need of
storing data off-chain and then
verification on-chain, right? That's
really the important part. That's the only
thing that really makes this work. So AVL
tree serves the same purpose. So there's
no reason to have to use a Merkle-Patricia
trie on Ergo.
So actually, no, it's already
decentralized in the sense that you can
traverse through Ergo Explorer and you can
get back that original data, the
non-hashed data. And it's actually even
better than IPFS because you don't have to
do any pinning or anything. So it's
actually all there on Ergo already.
But the actual raw data that you probably
were thinking about is the tree data and
the balance data. And that cannot be
stored on IPFS or something, because it's
something that requires a database,
because you're doing database operations.
All right. Thanks for tuning in, guys.