Hello everybody and welcome to a Redux of
the Ergo Classic AMA style.
As some of you may know if you've been
paying attention to socials, we're kind of
changing up what we're doing. We're going
to guarantee the first of the month one of
these kind of style AMAs where we try to
have different people on like as you can
see today below me, we have Richie from
the USE coin project.
We have Joseph Arminio who needs no
introduction. And to my right, we have
Batman. We have kushti right there in the
dark, doing the anon kind of style.
So we'll do that the first Wednesday,
first Thursday of every month. And then
we'll leave the week after that for
flexible things. We've already been
discussing what we might do for next week.
And then for sure, we'll have the third
week Thursday, we're going to have the
classic community chat, community
discussion format, where we hopefully
don't get Zoom bombed too much, figure out
a better media, maybe it's spaces, maybe
it's not, we'll see.
And go from there and then wildcard again
for the fourth and if there's a fifth
Thursday in the month then we'll see what
we can do and then hopefully Joe and I can
connect at 1 a.m. and do some late-night
dev updates or something in between to
fill some gaps so we'll see how that goes
but anyway with that aside welcome
everybody welcome Joe, kushti, Richie how
you guys doing?
Doing pretty good. Hi, everyone. Yeah, so
busy days, but doing well overall. So our
USE launch was successful. Well, at least
what was done, done successfully. So I'm
currently pinging code for USE to run
off-chain bots from today. And from
Saturday or Sunday, we are expecting a UI
launch. Maybe Richie can provide more
details, but yeah, I'm in touch with the
developers. So yeah, it will be available
to end users soon. So off-chain bots will
start to work today.
Well, why don't we have Richie jump right
in? Richie, tell us how the launch went.
You used MewFinance and how did all that
go?
It went well. So the first idea came to
me probably two years ago. So I can talk a
little bit about it. So the idea is that
we have a lot of miners in Ergo that hold
their coins and they are not very
sophisticated in DeFi. So we have lots of
liquidity that is not used for purpose,
that kind of holds our network back.
Compared to other projects, we're not a
VC project. We don't have all these VCs
who pre-mine or allocate themselves all
the capital and then they can use it to
promote. So all our coins are fairly
distributed. So we have to kind of
activate our community, the power of the
community properly.
Now, while many of these guys are just
miners or some people who love the idea of
a fair launch cryptocurrency, they do not
necessarily understand how DeFi works.
They maybe suffered some losses during
this meme coin mania or whatever. So most
of the people are kind of scared to use
their coin. They prefer to huddle for
years and then sell if the price pumps.
So now, because our project is fairly
launched, so there's no one, everyone
needs to understand, there's no one to
pump the price behind, right? So we need
to do it ourselves. We need to work
ourselves to get us where we deserve to
be, right? Maybe someone will jump along
the way, someone will notice and jump
along the way and decide like, you know,
massive capital and invest in Ergo, but
this is not guaranteed. So we need to work
ourselves on this way.
And basically, if someone wants to join
along the road, if he sees the potential,
of course, everyone is welcome in an open
ecosystem. But by default, if we just hold
what we've mined and don't do anything
with it, we might be where we are for
years, right? So that was my idea.
And I was thinking how to create a
framework that allows us to use the
capital, the power of the community, but
then again, be very safe for people. So
with very clear assumptions, they're not
risking too much. It's a very low risk
project for investments, for contribution.
So I put this idea of a CLB framework and
I submitted it during ErgoHack 9, I think
was it, and got in touch with MewFinance
guys who are very collaborative. So we had
some very good discussions and they came
up with their launch path, which was kind
of a little bit modified to meet CLB
requirements.
And we came up with this idea of backing
up the stable coin, a new generation
stable coin that has lots of technologies
behind it to back it up with the community
money, basically, community funds. And as
you could see, it was quite a successful
launch. So we managed to get 395,000 ERG.
I don't think we in the history of Ergo,
we had any of that kind of launches or I
can't remember, right?
So yeah, so what we do now, very clear
assumptions. Everyone knows 129 people
participated. The protocol is already
launched. So what we need is just UI and
some off-chain bots, and hopefully the
coin will be tradable by this weekend. And
after that, the idea is to expand, make it
cross-chain, go to other blockchains and
start offering them stablecoins.
Stablecoins have very clear value. So
everyone knows how much is one dollar,
right? So you don't need to explain what
Ergo is and things like that. The idea is
to expand our dollar. And by expanding our
algorithmic dollar, naturally our TVL will
grow and people will come learn how bank
works, how liquidity pool works, and they
will learn about the chain itself.
But even if they don't, they just simply
buy the stablecoin. For every stablecoin
bought, some ERGs will be going to the
bank, right? So like that, we are creating
revenue stream and some economics. So I
guess there will be many questions about
our plans and future. So this is the idea
to answer your first question. The idea
was to unlock the power of community and
unlock all the coins that have been
sitting pretty much doing nothing and put
them to work for Ergo, right? So, and I
think the first stage showed that it
worked pretty well.
So what, Richie, and kushti, I guess,
what makes USE stablecoin different? I
understand that kushti was involved with
the concept of it or the building of that,
the algorithms?
Yeah, so the contracts, the idea was
mine. Well, mostly I discussed it with
Bruno and so on. Then contracts were built
initially by Amitabh, rest in peace and
then I've extended them and I fixed some
things did tests and so on. Then we had
Dexy Gold launch right and some tests but
Dexy Gold was launched by me so it was
highly experimental so I didn't want to
attract any money from outside, so just
put 1000 ERG into the bank, so it's small
scale.
Now it's bigger, like a few times bigger.
A few K in the liquidity pool and like 3K
in the bank. So yeah, it's doing quite
well, you know, we had quite volatile
price movements, big volatility in recent
months but yeah it's doing well so the
bank is full and so on.
So yeah well after watching our Dexy Gold
behavior in the free markets which we have
like sometimes absolutely free with no
insiders and so on, like in the case of
Dexy Gold. So yeah, well, Richie proposed
to launch USD. And yeah, well, about fair
launch, so I think it is very much needed
to document the launch this time to avoid,
you know, some mythology to be appeared
later like happened with SigmaUSD to some
degree.
I think it's quite unique kind of launch
for this so-called crypto industry. From
what I've seen, well, there were many
algorithmic stablecoins launched back in
2021-22. Often there were some crazy
stories when VCs and teams were involved.
Sometimes they attracted liquidity by
selling $1 for 70 cents before the launch.
After the launch, it was depegged just
because early investors went out.
So, yeah, well, a lot of crazy stories,
which you can find on the internet, some
of them, some maybe not so well documented
even. I think there is need to document
this effort of the community.
Well, before we have this question that
we have up here, let's circle to Joe. Joe,
how do you see Rosen helping out with
spreading across ecosystems?
That's what Rosen is built for, to take
assets into new markets. I do think that
as we grow, we can expand, put them in new
environments, some of which have deep
liquidity already. You could look at a
Binance Smart Chain base as a future
option, and then you can also look at
emerging DeFi ecosystems, right?
Or you may have chains that don't have
access to like the traditional stablecoin
value. And I think there could be huge
demand there as well because it's offering
a new product that they kind of need.
Stable value has a lot of, that's actually
probably been one of the best use cases of
crypto stable coins in terms of allowing
people around the world to access dollars
that potentially offers them more
stability and inflation resistance than
their own local currency.
So I think around the world, it's like
400 million are using Tether, which is
pretty powerful.
Are most stable coins chain dependent or
are they offering some sort of bridge
where there's shared liquidity on one
chain and it's spreading out to other
chains?
Yeah, you know, a lot of like the
traditional stable coins have like a
native implementation. But oftentimes what
happens is they have the same control
system, right? So, you know, they have the
ability to issue assets. They have the
ability to freeze assets. They have the
ability to seize assets in some cases.
There's even talk about, you know,
reversing transactions. So there's no need
for a bridge. They have, you know,
essentially, you know, God mode turned on.
Yeah. So they can, you know, balance
liquidity, move things around as they
want.
But remind me, Joe, with Rosen Bridge, if
the core Rosen team was like, we hate
everything and we want to go away, people
could still utilize those smart contracts
as long as the watchers and the guards
were still doing their thing, right?
There's no central part. The guard set is
distributed enough that if all the Rosen
team disappeared, the guard would still
function. Now, you know, it's like, okay,
it'd be messy in terms of development. The
code is open source. It's there for a
reason. Our contribution standards have
been picked up by a couple of different
layer ones that are in different stages of
integration.
Which is nice to see. Team has been kind
of putting together different test
environments and preparing, you know,
moving from theory to practice as always.
You know, nothing kicks you in the teeth
like life, right? When you have great
ideas in your head. So we're preparing for
a contribution from external chains and
that's going to be a learning process
because it's the first time. But I assume
that once we get that process down, it'll
be, you know, less friction to bootstrap
every time. So I'm looking forward to
that.
And I've seen some great questions from
the Firo team. Maybe there is need to
provide answers in public, right? So that
they were interested in guards, right? So
how hard to censor out certain chains,
right. Because it seems for them it's a
huge issue, right? So most of the
exchanges just throw them away for just
providing very basic human rights,
basically for financial privacy.
Yeah, Rosen was designed with that in
mind. You know, that's the one thing that
we want to do is distribute the guards in
terms of geographically, right? That way
any particular zone of control, you know,
guards could go offline, the bridge still
survives, right? There's no point in
having distributed infrastructure unless
you have that in mind for this type of
project.
So we are globally distributed to where
we don't have enough footprint in any
single jurisdiction that if the guards
went offline, the bridge still operates.
It is something that from Genesis we've
wanted to do, which is expand the guard
set. Now, it probably makes sense to do
that as a batch rather than a single
guard. So, you know, once we have
sufficient development and we're kind of
ready to take on that task, we want to
expand the guard set while keeping like
geographic distribution in mind and
ultimately harden the system, right?
That's really important for censorship
resistance because you can have like, you
know, multi-sig assumptions, that's just
one guy, right? That's not hard to do.
But, you know, to have something that has
decent liveness guarantees and decent
censorship resistance that's actually
distributed across, you know, earth is a
different animal.
Well, we got a question from Iron in
here. I'm going to pop it up here. It's a
question-ish, I think. I didn't have time
to read it real quick. Let's see. Curious,
it's about USE. Curious, other reserves,
non-metals, being shorter duration than
ERG would always net more term premium for
the base chain while not having different
fee structures, only duration, i.e. term
premium. That make sense to any of you
guys? You want to chime in on that?
That was the question.
I'll read it again.
I heard Richie and then my brain just
turned off.
Byron's curious other reserves non-metals
being shorter duration than ERG would
always net more term premium for the base
chain while not having different fee
structures only duration ie term premium.
It's kind of hard, it's hard to predict,
right? I would say the one thing that
we're kind of running into in like the,
well, this year specifically is just
volatility, right? So, you know, we are
kind of entering this phase of, you know,
I would say, mass fear of debt saturation.
And so we've seen gold, silver essentially
explode relative to how they normally
move. I think gold's at an all-time high.
I think silver's at an all-time high.
And then you have the tricky paper market
around both of those assets where they're
rehypothecated to hell, sometimes
overrepresented like 200, 300 to 1 based
on like physical versus paper. So those
are some crazy markets to consider in
terms of like what is possible if you know
people start to actually claim like
delivery, right?
I have no idea. It's one of those things
where market making tricks and, you know,
rehypothecation which creates like
artificially inflated supply creates all
kinds of fuckery. So I've personally, you
know, even had like a silver Oracle built
actually for Rosen, because that was
something that in the long term I find
fascinating. I've kind of made the
decision that based on all the other stuff
that I'm juggling, it makes sense to sit
back and say, okay, well, you know, we
have USE, we have Dexy Gold, you know, we
have some, I believe there's like Jed's
shoe, which is some SigmaUSD variant
that's been proposed.
It makes sense in my opinion to just be
conservative and watch, gather information
and then make a choice. But that is
potential to have, let's say, other assets
in these frameworks. It's just
Oracle-dependent. But I do think that
being conservative is wise here. Sit down,
let them compete, gather real-world
testing information, and then we'll know
how to proceed.
Richie, anything to add to that?
So the idea of adding more derivatives
like silver, gold, well, gold we have is
appealing. But I think the way the markets
are built and it's not like my choice or
kushti's or Joe. So the people, for some
reason, they value the United States
dollar first. And if you even look at all
the stable coins that exist now in
circulation, the dollar dominates. It
dominates over everything.
If you look underneath, the structure
probably is fragile. It doesn't make sense
that the dollar has such a huge domination
and printing the trillions of debts. But
this is the reality, right? And the first
one, the most understood for everyone
currently is the dollar. So that's what I
kind of want to focus on by USE being the
first mover. But after that, yes, we can
definitely expand our lineup to precious
metals, maybe oil, maybe something else.
But it just makes sense to make dollar
first because it's the most understood and
widespread, right? It has the deepest
liquidity. But yes, definitely we're open
for other metals, other assets to be added
under the same scheme.
Well, we got a kind of an off topic
question we can pop in here really
quickly. Let me bring this up. Bobcat is
looking about what your guys' thoughts are
on the Kachina protocol from midnight and
how it could work with Ergo or how we
could use it in Ergo or leverage it
essentially, or maybe even with USE or
that kind of stable crossing.
Yeah, I have no idea. All right. So yeah,
well, I read the paper like, five years
ago something like that so it's a paper
from like late 2010 so yeah well probably
makes sense then to review alternative
approaches like Aleo or dark DeFi and then
yeah provide a comparison right somehow. I
believe that there is some plan for that,
but I'm not sure when time can be found
for that.
I think at some point there is a need to
consider the possibility for private
contracts, but there are a lot of
variables here. Well, the space is now
considering, well, mostly Ethereum
developers, not Bitcoin still,
post-quantum cryptography, right? And that
usually breaks everything we use in
regards with complex protocols and so on.
So, yeah, well, I think maybe it's better
to build some basic tooling right and to
understand how can we build monetary
expansion to the real world and then yeah
consider privacy well also with
considering complications such as post
quantum security and so on, or maybe give
up. So it depends. It's still not very
good shape. It's still mostly uncharted
territory, I think.
All right, well, there's another question
in there, but we'll let that hold for a
sec. Sorry, go on, kushti.
Yeah, but maybe Richie can add, so he had
some thoughts about the need for private
DEXes and so on, yeah, expressed in some
chats. So, Richie, do you have some
thoughts on the need for private
contracts, private DEXes. So what's the
needs do markets have in your opinion?
Because well, we are here to enable free
markets, right? Well, digital markets.
The market definitely values the privacy.
And if it's possible to build a DEX,
leverage trading or stable coins that have
the privacy features, that will definitely
be appreciated by the market. Now, the
Kachina Protocol and Midnight kind of
trying to achieve this. I'm not the tech
person to understand it deeply to say
what's the trade-offs there.
And looking at the roadmap that Midnight
is proposing, we're talking about some
smart contracts going live around Q3, I
think, next year. So we'll see how it
goes. The one thing that is clear to me,
if we connect to Midnight via Rosen, we
will definitely bring a stable coin there.
And if by getting to Midnight, it becomes
private, that will be already a big, quite
a big achievement. So you have algorithmic
stable coin on private chain. That sounds
like a very good combo to me. So while not
getting inside what Midnight plans about
their own technologies, I'm definitely a
big proponent of expanding Rosen to
support Midnight and expanding USE to
getting into that environment as well. Why
not?
All right, yeah, and I believe it is
about bringing tokens just, well, they USE
token right in the first place. So it
should be quite straightforward, right? So
I believe they should provide some
primitives for that, for private tokens on
midnight.
Yeah. I haven't looked into midnight in a
while, to be honest, just in other things.
But I do know at one point, I reviewed
documentation, but that was, that was a
while ago. So I'm no subject matter expert
there.
Yeah. So I need to refresh my knowledge
as well. But yeah, then it's, it would be
good to consider options, because so yeah,
bringing, algorithmic stable coins to
private environments. Yeah. It's a very
good combo indeed.
All right, let's see. We've got another
follow-up from Byron saying, the different
reserves support their own USE, like ADA
USE, ETH USE, making volatility contained
within each ecosystem's proof of support,
a basket of algorithmic stables rated by
open standards.
Yeah, you know, I feel that, right, with
utilizing Rosen to spread stablecoin
across ecosystems, it feels like such a
crowdsourced version of something that
makes the management of it actually so
much easier in the long run, right? If you
have community-run liquidity pools popping
up on chains where it's needed that you
bridge to, then what do you have to do,
you know, as the creator of the project?
Nothing, no, I guess. Richie? Seems a lot
easier to be able to sustain and manage
something like that.
Yeah, I can speak about my plans and how
I see our expansion and just ask me
questions and feel free to interrupt. So I
did some research and if you look at
Uniswap v3 type of pools, now they have
Uniswap v4 but that's done mostly for
leverage trading so it has no benefit for
us. So, but Uniswap v3 is quite
interesting protocol and it's battle
tested already.
So, obviously, we have it on PancakeSwap
and we will have it on Base as well. Now,
the cost efficiency of Uniswap v3, try to
guess. So, for example, Cardano and Ergo,
we are using typical AMM pools, right?
Straight AMM pools, Uniswap v2 type pools.
But at a stable coin, it makes sense to
switch to Uniswap v3 and kind of select
the range, shorter range, and the
efficiency of the protocol goes 20x.
So what does it mean? You need $1 million
worth of liquidity on a standard AMM pool,
and you can replicate the same efficiency,
the same slippage, on Uniswap v3 with just
$50,000 of liquidity, right? So if we
create that liquidity pool USE to USDT
just with 50,000, for example, just as
arbitrary number, but on Uniswap v3 on
PancakeSwap, it's essentially the same as
getting a million dollar worth of
liquidity on AMM v2, or if you translate
it into ADA, like two and a half million
ADA.
So if you look at the top ADA stable
coins now, their liquidity is between two
and I think six is the most. So we can
replicate the same depth and the same
basically quality and cost-efficiency for
the end user with just a fraction of it.
So this is my next step. I already have in
my mind the program that we will launch
for the community, probably in one month's
time, to crowdsource the liquidity to
build AMM v3 type of pool on PancakeSwap.
So with that one, we will have very
efficient rails to move stable coins
between USDT, USE, Ergo and Cardano. I
think everyone will be surprised with the
slippage tolerance and things like that.
That's what is in my mind over the next
one month, like I said. That's the primary
goal.
And after that, we will plan to expand on
other chains, Cardano and maybe some
smaller chains that will join the Rosen.
But basically every chain will have a very
cost-efficient rails to move from USDT or
USDC back into USE and to their own chain,
just to the fraction of the cost. So with
that one, once deployed, obviously lots of
arbitrage traders will jump in because for
them cost efficiency is very important.
And we will have quite a big volumes
moving and trading. So that's what I'm
hoping for, to enable that trading volume
in the next couple months with the help of
the community.
All right, so it's kind of arbitrage
friendly, right, stablecoin. And yeah, I
believe actually, well, in the crypto
industry, so stablecoins are mostly to
tame volatility, right, and do arbitrage,
actually, they're used for. Right. I am
not very proficient in trading. Is that
true?
Yes, stable coins are used for arbitrage
trading mostly and they move to different
chains a lot and cost efficiency is very
important here. So like I said, the Rosen
enables cost-efficient implementation and
Pancake's Uniswap V3 type pools enable
very efficient trading. So we already have
these very efficient rails that we just
need to spread and then people will
naturally jump in as we expand.
Well, nice. And also, it seems it will
enable Binance Smart Chain, right? So
currently, Rosen is still mostly about
Cardano, right? Bringing assets to Cardano
from going back. And yeah, so the plan is
to go for Binance Smart Chain in the first
place, right?
Yes, Binance Smart Chain is the first
priority now because it has USDT. It has
very cost-efficient USDT. It's very
centralized, but that's what people want,
it seems. So they like USDT. And yeah, the
Binance Smart Chain enables that very
cost-efficient use of USDT. So the funds
should be flying back and forth to Ergo,
Binance Chain, Cardano, and later to other
chains.
All right. What about Ethereum?
Ethereum now is improving a little bit.
The cost of transactions on Ethereum was a
bit high. But with the recent updates, and
I just read yesterday that they're going
for another hard fork soon. So with that
update, the cost of using the Ethereum L1
goes down. At the moment, it will never be
as cost efficient as Binance Smart Chain
simply because it's a very centralized
chain.
But yes, I'll be monitoring that. So for
example, one year ago, it made no sense to
deploy on Ethereum because just the cost
of transaction was very high, but it's
getting better. So I'll keep monitoring
that and maybe we will enable it in future
if there will be a demand.
Thanks. We've got another question here,
guys. And maybe it's for both kushti and
Richie. What's the redundancy on the bots
that do the buybacks for the protocol? Any
of them running like on duck pools or only
one or two? I guess like Dexy too, right?
Sorry. Can you repeat this?
What is the redundancy on the bots that
do the buybacks for the protocol, for the
USE protocol? Are any of them running like
on duck pools or only one or two?
Yeah, so currently the code for off-chain
bots done by coder for USE is closed, but
he is promising to open source the bots
quickly after polishing the code. So yeah,
currently he's ashamed a bit of open
source, but yeah, after some polishing.
And I think that there is needs to open
source UI also, right? And to have pools
on Ergodex and so on.
So, and then wallets like Nautilus and
Ergo Wallet. And ErgoMixer actually, maybe
Minotaur as well, not sure. So they all
have a feature to mint SigmaUSD, right? So
that should be an option, I believe, in
the long term also to get USE. Right.
Yeah, I do think that with the matching
of finance, with the grid ordering that
we're doing, it will be pretty powerful in
terms of like community arbitrage around
USE. Just because the amount of orders per
block potentially could really push a lot
of activity through the Ergo network just
in that one use case, arbitrage.
Actually, I have a question to kushti
about data that Joe mentioned. kushti, so
when we have Machina Finance live, do you
think there is a possibility to add a
liquidity pool there that will be also
controlled by a bank? Is it somehow
possible to have two liquidity pools that
banks interact with? I know it sounds like
complicated, but the cost efficiency and
overall the whole structure of Machina
Finance is very appealing to me.
I think that will be a great DEX with the
presentation that Anand BR did during the
Ergo anniversary, that looks like it will
be a very great asset to trade tokens on
Ergo. So I was thinking if we can somehow
make a bank work with the DEX as well, in
addition to Ergodex that we're doing right
now, or maybe transfer liquidity somehow,
but something just theoretical, obviously
you don't need to answer right now fully.
Well, to have two pools could be
complicated, so switching to another pool
may be easier. I think, conceptually even,
it makes sense to have one reference pool,
right? And then others will be equalized
with it. Yeah, arbitrage, right? So, and
with two pools, so the bank does need to
account for both somehow right and then to
intervene into both so yeah well a lot of
complexities here probably maybe even some
variants of Gresham's law I don't know.
Possibly, yes, because, well, pools are
quite different, right? They're different
markets, after all, somehow. But you need
to think about it.
Yeah, we will definitely think about it.
Yeah, actually, very interesting. I would
discuss it with Bruno, I guess, next week.
Yes, it's something to think about
because Machina by its design will enable
next level DeFi on Ergo. So just for
people listening here, Machina Finance
should allow us to match the liquidity
efficiency of Uniswap V3 type pools. So,
think about the efficiency of our current
pools, like Uniswap v2, that's what we
have on Ergo. And then with Machina, with
the grid orders, we will be able to set up
ranges. And it goes like 10x, 5x, 10x, it
depends on the trading pair. So for
stablecoin pairs, it makes a lot of sense
to trade them on Machina Finance. It
should be very novel. It's very
interesting. We'll see how it works. We're
still a few months away from it. But yes,
something I'm already thinking. It will be
a very beneficial development for Ergo
DeFi.
All right. Yeah, it's quite exciting,
right? So we can have concentrated
liquidity pools then, basically, just
without, well, liquidity pools, AMM ones,
I mean, standard, like Uniswap. And that's
quite interesting. And yeah, that would be
useful for stable to stable, right? So
SigmaUSD to USE, for example, Glenn Gold
to Dexy Gold.
Yeah, I kind of conceptualize that
anyway, in terms of extending people's
power from being their own bank to being
their own market maker, where they have
the ability to set these grids within
certain liquidity ranges and essentially
fulfill the purpose that market making
outfits do in terms of liquidity
management in and around spread. So
that'll be cool.
And well, with Dexy design, where a bank
is slow to intervene, indeed, a lot of
possibilities for arbitrage rights with
other stable coins. And that's what helps
the bank as well. So the markets would
stabilize before the interventions,
mostly. It should be the case. And that's
quite interesting.
All right. Let's see. We've got another
hit from Ursa Minor 2010. Wants to know if
there's going to be, if there could be a
marketplace for the Ergo liquidity
provider, the LP tokens. Can you make
liquidity pools with LP tokens as part of
the pair? I'm wondering how abstract this
whole thing can get.
So the question is about creating markets
with liquidity pools.
Yeah, creating a pair with liquidity
pools, markets, trading, arbitrage, all
that kind of stuff with the liquidity.
Yeah, sorry, but you have LP token on one
side and on another side, you have what?
I guess you'd put whatever you'd want the
pair to be, right? Whatever you would
speculate against in that manner.
kushti, I can take that.
So basically, CLB token that was
distributed to everyone is essentially
your LP token. So in two years, you will
be able to redeem CLB to liquidity tokens.
And then with the liquidity tokens, redeem
the liquidity from the main pool.
So Ursa is saying SigmaUSD. I'd like to
make a pair with SigmaUSD, but sorry, go
on, Richie.
So currently, yes, we have CLB tokens
already tradable with ERGs, and they will
be tradable with USE on this weekend or
whenever the UI goes live. And that's
essentially you are trading your liquidity
pool tokens with ERG or with stablecoin.
So what he says is, yes, it is possible,
but it's much better representation when
it's like a derivative of it. So a CLB
token is essentially a liquidity token and
you can trade it even now. It can go now
to any of our DEXes and then buy or sell
CLB tokens. And that's essentially buying
or selling a liquidity token.
You cannot redeem it yet, because that's
the whole idea, to keep that liquidity
working for the ecosystem for two years.
But you can trade it.
Where is it now? It looks like the LP is
in about 10 wallets or so. Richie? Sorry?
That token? I'm looking at its contents
right now. CLB?
No. Whatever that LP token, you've
created the LP token already?
Yes, the LP token is created on the CLB
launch pool, so it will be transferred to
a smart contract and will be locked there.
We'll see how much time it takes to create
the smart contract, the redeem smart
contract. If it will take a little bit
longer, then we will just transfer it to
Rosen for storage for two years. And then
after that, to Rosen Cold Wallet, Multisig
Cold Wallet.
And then from there, we will transfer it
to a smart contract with a time lock until
December 1st, 2027. And then when December
1, 2027 comes, you will be able to use CLB
tokens to redeem your liquidity tokens. I
hope that makes sense with what I'm
saying.
Yeah, it does. Great.
All right, let's see what else we have. I
don't see any other questions unless we've
missed some. What about any other news in
the ecosystem? Well, we have 10 minutes
left, guys. kushti, what you been working
on? Joe, you didn't talk. You're muted,
Joe. But what about your runes?
That's been kind of... Yeah, we have a
lot of news, so 10 minutes not enough
probably. But yeah, we can take another
five. And yeah, Joe, please go ahead.
Sure. So let's start with Runes. Rosen
Runes did go live, which means we can now
wrap assets onto Bitcoin, which is really
unique. Now we're kind of looking across
the Bitcoin DeFi space and I've got to say
it's pretty rough in terms of like the
shallow limits of it.
So we're, we're actually have our own
little thinking group in terms of like
interactive transaction construction,
which is basically where you use partially
signed signatures and then off chain logic
to coordinate more complex swaps. Kind of
like a, I don't know. I don't know what
you call it. It's like an atomic swap on
the same chain with off-chain conditions
that you're agreeing on or coming to
consensus on is the net goal.
So, or actually... How do you enforce
those off-chain?
Well, you have to use partially signed
transactions, essentially. That's a
working group theory that we're playing
with right now, which is kind of fun.
We are going to support a protocol called
Ducat protocol, which is somewhat of a
MakerDAO style protocol, stablecoin on
bitcoin itself that's going to be backed
by bitcoin layer one liquidity i think
they're going to launch next year and so i
do think it's quite interesting if we can
scrap together some sort of amm design you
know we can potentially get stablecoin to
stablecoin pairs on bitcoin you know who
knows maybe one of these days they'll drop
something like BIP 119 and we'll get
covenants and then all of that will be
wasted time.
But Bitcoin is incredibly slow to evolve.
So maybe that's like due 2040. Let's see.
In terms of Lithos, we've launched the
test net. That's been really going quite
well so far. It's been nice to see that in
like a dynamic testing environment. You
know, they've been catching bugs, that
have been coming up. It's been a really
good stress test because right now on
testnet that Lithos is the king.
I've never had so many people mining. I'm
mining test net with a 3090 using mining
core. And I haven't gotten a block in like
days, Joe. It's quite competitive.
No, it's been awesome. And it's one of
those things where, in testnet right now,
we actually are seeing a scenario where
Lithos actually has the majority of hash
rate in the framework. But you still have
a distribution of blocks to people, unique
miners, which is the ideal outcome for
Lithos, is to be able to spread those
block producers.
Today, we did have kind of a big event,
which because we're on testnet, nobody's
really lying about their nisps, the amount
of work that they're trying to submit, and
they're just running the base client, and
the base client is more or less following
its own logic. Quote unquote, honest. So
we've started lying on testnet. And today,
the first fraud proof that caught a
misrepresentation of work worked and it
slashed us.
How much did you put up for the slash? Is
that the same cost as the block reward?
Yeah, so essentially, when you have
miners that are running fraud proofs, when
you reduce somebody's submitted share,
they get paid less and you get paid more.
So there is a nice natural incentive there
to audit other miners, because if you
catch something, you benefit from slashing
them or slashing their share that they
submitted.
So that's kind of the game theory in
terms of like, why would people want
redundantly, you know, auditing the work
of other people because they get paid more
when they catch something, right? So that
does kind of spread horizontally across
all the actors. You know, we still have
more work to do in terms of the test net,
but overall things are going really well.
We're going to get another update, you
know, probably in a couple of days,
getting the collateral system working
properly again, along with the client's
API, but things are chugging along and
testnet is its own beast. It's pretty
cool.
You guys have drained me dry of ERGs for
collateral. If anybody has any ERGs that
is running the Lithos, please just send
them to cheese because I'm all out. I
think I have 2000 testnet ERGs left and
I'm not getting any more because Lithos
has beaten me on the block discovery.
Yeah. If you have any extra sentiment, DM
cheese and send it with cheese.
It's been really cool to see that type of
participation on test net. So hats off to
the community. We are putting together,
like a airdrop thing, for people that have
mined the test net or, you know, maybe
even a little bonus for people that are
able to slash our fraud and that we're
putting on the network.
But yeah, that type of community
engagement is, is really awesome to see.
Looking forward to rolling this thing out
and hopefully, you know, getting the
March, the test night underway or main
net, excuse me.
I'm impressed, Joe. It's been, it's,
Lithos has been a word on people's lips
for a long time and now just plus two plus
years. And now it just pumps right out.
Cheese has been sitting there working in
the background for quite a while.
All right. Will we see a paper behind
Lithos design?
I hope so. All right. I think it would
make sense to put together some sort of
white paper. I do think it's funny how we
have a tendency on Ergo to build it first
and then like, oh, we need to build it. I
don't even think there's a Rosen white
paper yet, to be honest. I have to check.
I think someone was going to make
something.
Yeah, well, I think you need now to
document and sell it, right? So a lot of
coding and well, it's time to sell the
tools, right? And the whole story, I
believe.
About the papers, we've got a bunch of
papers accepted for the first stability
workshop which will take place in Jaipur
city, India on December 15th. I will
present the chain cache paper there. Also
Luca will present Dexy paper and Bruno
with different co-authors including Luca
will present also a few papers.
So maybe we can do our next AMA from
India then me Bruno and Luca but then yeah
I'm not sure about Thursday actually maybe
Friday or Saturday.
Yeah, that's the beauty of the middle
weeks. kushti, we can be really flexible
with it. So, yeah, just keep us posted.
Yeah, and I think it would be nice,
right, to have some, like, bleeding edge
research. After all, for the first time
after, I don't know, maybe years. Then,
yeah, I'm testing basis tracker right now
and then also thinking to jump on doing
presentations, right, marketing materials.
Then there is a bunch of community-made
writings I need to review, such as Silver
Sense by Greiman. So I did some reviews
and yeah, well, with basis tracker
available, there is need to finalize it in
some implementable form, let's say, right,
and then do some real-world experiments.
Then there are some other ideas. So there
is this forum post by Federico, I need to
check about this common currency,
commonwealth currency, how's it called, so
yeah we'll check and probably provide some
review also testing the forum which got
migrated to a new location, right, a lot
of news.
Then yeah we have a new version of
Minotaur wallet and update for Ergo Wallet
is also done and under testing now. So now
it's time to consider publishing details
for Ergo Wallet and I think it's a good
time to start publishing Minotaur as well.
So we need to figure out details.
Then what? Yeah, my father too or at
least sub-blocks white paper. So the
initial plan was about the next week, the
plan which I had right after the release
launch. But with this trip to India, Bruno
also invited me to give a short talk at
the beginning of the hackathon, which will
be from December 13th, so before the main
event.
So on, well, I'm currently not sure about
next week, but yeah, well, it's close and
we will start another DevNet. So I
actually tested it before the USE
deployment with a couple of mining peers
of mine and now, well, it's time for more
broad testing. It will be started in a few
days. Yeah, what else?
Just a shout out to, guys, shout out to
Bez who's been cranking out a massive
amount of community pages here. He's got
ergoblockchain.org. He's got the app built
on ergo theme, right, that he's cranking
out. Fantastic artwork, fantastic amount
of content there as well.
It's the new community hub and it has a
marketing section for you guys so there
you can find a lot of fun pages which you
can distribute around. Then there were a
lot of updates reported during yesterday's
DevChats for Hermes. And yeah, we also
have Digin's World, so QX, maybe it's your
turn to present.
No, no, I haven't. Have you played with
Digin? You know, I haven't. I haven't
played with it much. I tried to build
something really quickly and then
something else. But that's Rob, right?
That's Lithos Rob?
Are they doing it? Yeah, so yeah, it's
Rob and yeah, they have a lot of good meme
NFTs already.
Yeah, but somebody built a really
beautiful 3D block explorer essentially
and kind of like a nice visual where you
click on a floating block and you get the
stars moving by you and then all the block
information shows up to your right and you
can slide through the blocks. It's really
awesome what you can do with this.
I think he's using Gemini for that, for
the coding, which the new version is a
really, really does a really nice job at
that kind of stuff. So if you guys haven't
checked it out, please check it out. I'll
try to repost something on Twitter today
so you can get the link again. But really,
really cool site that he made to be able
to put coding in the hands of non-coders.
Yeah, I'm also playing with AI coding
contracts, so we discussed some things
with Rob and I used an agent to review
Dexy contracts also during the USE
deployment. So along with manual recheck
of like everything here that there was an
agent, coding agents also working on that
along with tests.
First of all, Bez wants to know if we
need to solidify the Mexico trip. Is that
something? Did you talk to, who was it,
Anon or Allison? Or anybody else? MX. MX,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right. So let me check with the guys
how big it will be. So a few years ago,
there were friends from pirate chain
joining the event they offered to share
booth even but yeah now they're not
appearing there it seems so yeah need to
think with them if loot from pirate is
coming that would be great as well because
they have experience with this event but
yeah let's go why not so it will be late
February somewhat second half of February
Acapulco city in Mexico Anarcopulco
conference and so maybe we can show
I know, so some things there like mesh
networks based basis powered peer-to-peer
cache for like community trading,
something like that. All right, and QX,
any updates for BRIC experiment?
Oh yeah, we're going full... It's ready
for... I actually wrote Louis Vacher the
other day, and I was like, Louis, I just
want to thank you for Tipperbot and having
a tool that allowed us to introduce BRIC
in a really easy way for micro payments.
But I'm going to move off Tipperbot fully.
I'm going to sever everybody's Tipperbot
wallet. I'm going to actually pull it from
the Discord. I can't sever their wallets.
And then give them instructions on how to
convert to Nautilus and bring the seed
phrase over.
But the portal is fully built for them.
And there's a new method, too, that we're
going to distribute. So the idea is that
at least administration here, we don't
want to reward things that students should
be doing. So if we want to reward students
with BRIC for showing up to class and
scanning and check-in-ing, that's
something they should be doing. We don't
want to reward them for that.
So there's very kind of unique cases that
we're going to reward them for. And the
latest case that we're going to reward
them for is we have a huge issue in our
physical woodworking shops and machining
shops where students aren't checking in
with the QR codes with the third party
program called Fabman when they go to the
shop.
So a shop technician can't know without
walking through the shop every time
exactly what the capacity of the shop is
and how many people are in there because
people aren't checking in. So what I've
been doing with the portal is I've
integrated the API for that third-party
software in. Every day, it pulls that
third-party software to get people to
check in. And then in the back end, I
already have it made. We can hit a button,
and it builds a transaction and sends BRIC
to every single student that checked in
that day or that week if it builds up kind
of thing.
So that's the second to latest thing that
we've done. And the latest thing that
we've done is we want places to be able to
spend this BRIC too, right? We want an
economy. So what we're doing is I've
already built into the portal as well.
Students can send their BRIC to a wallet
through the portal with Nautilus and then
once a month when the 3D printer shop you
know with the 3D printers are charging
students for the filament that they used
through the 3D printer OS application we
take the export from the 3D printer OS
application they wouldn't give me API
access kind of pissed me off but whatever
we take that excel export I dump it into
my portal and I then subtract the BRIC
that the students have given to the portal
from their portal so if you've donated you
know 50 BRIC that's what that's about
that's about seven dollars six bucks so if
you donate six bucks to the portal then
we're only going to bill you what your 3d
printer cost was minus six bucks
So it's a way to get that BRIC
circulating back into us that we can then
distribute back out for checking in so
that's the latest thing that we're doing
which is super super cool and next
semester will be the full-on launch of hey
everybody we've severed discord for tipper
bot you're all on nautilus now go to the
portal and do it so yeah the portal
I mean, that's what I love about Ergo.
With AI and how easy Ergo is to use, it
took no time at all to integrate Fleet SDK
into just normal JavaScript calls and my
programming that I use to write websites.
And it's just like Tipperbot. If a
student, if I'm going to transfer a BRIC
to a student or another student wants to
transfer a BRIC to a student through the
portal, they type in the net ID, they hit
send. If the student doesn't exist in the
portal, it builds a wallet for them
automatically and then sends that to
Nautilus so the person can complete the
transaction to send the transaction.
But it's wicked cool. I'm really excited
about it. And as this builds and builds,
hopefully we have more use cases to give
out BRIC and more use cases to suck BRIC
back in as well. So yeah, so that's the
BRIC update for the day.
Nice. And do you document experiments,
like maybe not even technical side, but
social and socioeconomic interactions?
No, I don't. Glasgow had a nice write-up
that he surveyed and got everything pretty
right, at least in the initial setup and
set. You're right I mean I'd love to be
able to what I'd love in the future and
maybe a year or two down the road when we
get a real big economy going with BRIC
here and it's swapping through everything
I'd like to see like third party places
like let's say students want to, you know,
students usually buy lumber from 76th
Lumber down the road, right?
How awesome would it be if 76 came to us
and said we want, you know, to, or we went
to them and said, you know, could we have
students drop off BRIC and every BRIC you
hand us back will give you six cents for
right there kind of thing. So that'd be
ideal to have it start spreading outside
of the local economy in that manner for
merchants that want our students'
business.
Yeah, I think possible.
I think so, too. I think so, too, for
sure.
All right, guys, we're 11 minutes over.
This is great. All right. Yeah. So there
are more updates, but yeah, let's wrap up
with that. Already quite solid. I believe
free stuff updates. So, yes. See you.
Yeah. Thanks everybody. Thanks Richie for
coming, talking about USE, Joe for USE and
Rosen, kushti for USE and everything else
on your mind. Thanks so much.
Have a good one. Take care. Bye.