Hey everyone, R.O.B. here, bringing you
Cortex, my Ergo Hack 10 project.
Before I get into the project, I just
want to tell you a little bit about
myself. I was originally part of the
GetBlok team, which was a decentralized
smart contract-based mining pool on the
Ergo blockchain. I was launched several
years back and unfortunately since then,
the pool was closed.
But that project did lead to some of the
concepts and ideas behind Lithos Protocol,
which is another project that is currently
being developed by qx(). Aside from that,
I'm a father of two. I'm a big enthusiast
of proof of work mining, specifically
decentralized mining, and one of the
passions that I've always had was trying
to find ways to decentralize mining even
further.
As many of you know, mining software and
various points of the proof of work mining
process unfortunately still remain
centralized and remain either on a pool
host server or black box mining software
that you really don't know what's
happening behind the scenes. So, yeah,
always had an interest in that.
And that kind of led to some of the ideas
that were built into Cortex here.
Obviously Ergo Hack 10 is an AI-based
themed hackathon. And I had some general
ideas on how can you integrate AI with GPU
mining.
Some of the ideas were using AI to
basically process data, basically train a
model to understand stats specifically
around temperatures, overclocks, memory
clock settings, things of that nature. And
monitor that against mining performance to
really get an understanding of how those
settings may impact mining in general and
get a good data set and truly understand
how that data set could be utilized to
potentially mine more efficiently and
lower your power settings or find ways
just to find little tweaks and gains here
that could make mining a little bit more
efficient these days, right?
So, yeah, that was kind of the original
concept behind Cortex. We'll get into how
the project evolved a little bit further
than that. It became overall an ambitious
project here, but yeah, excited to show
you what I have.
So what is Cortex? Cortex is the next
generation open source CUDA GPU miner for
the Ergo blockchain. And it's focused on a
few different points here, but
transparency and audibility. So we want to
keep this open source. All the code will
be available on GitHub and open for
collaboration or modification.
This was AI generated code. I did use
several different models to build the code
base here, but I found a lot of success
using GPT 4.1. I used some of the project
folder method where I loaded several files
and data points and trained the model on
the instructions I wanted it to use to
build the code base here.
Within the project, we have real-time GPU
control, so we'll give you visibility to
your GPUs in a live monitor format. And
ultimately you can make changes or change
settings to your GPU. However, this is
Linux based code. So there are some
restrictions. Some of the lower model GPUs
have less restrictions and can be set. So
we're looking into that a little bit
further just to see if we can optimize
that.
Aside from that, we do have full stratum
and node mining support. So there is no
deployment built within the code. And the
original concept was to have a node and be
able to launch a node and mine directly to
that node.
Unfortunately, I've been running this on
a single GPU, so finding any blocks with a
single GPU on mainnet would be virtually
impossible. So it did make a shift to
testnet, had some complications,
basically, syncing to testnet node. So had
to pivot, which we'll get into a little
bit here later in the project.
And then AI powered mining optimization.
So as I mentioned earlier, we did find a
way to kind of analyze not only the GPU
stats, but some of the nonce predictions.
And a nonce is basically what you're
trying to solve when you're looking for a
block in simple terms. So once you solve
the nonce or match the nonce, that's
solving the equation. And in turn, that's
the block solution.
So yeah, we have some code that's built
in here that will kind of analyze that
data and it will build a data set. And
over time, we will train that model and it
will just continue to get smarter.
So some goals that I've outlined for the
project. So again, needed to develop a
miner. I'm not a developer by any means,
so I can use some reference and there was
obviously the original Ergo CUDA miner.
And when we say CUDA, CUDA just means
Nvidia. It's just basically the dataset
that gets processed.
So I did use the original Ergo CUDA miner
as a reference, which was developed by
MHS. I trained that into the AM model to
use that code set to build a new miner
from the ground up, basically.
Node deployment. So we do have node
deployment via backend through a simple
UI. The UI would be hosted locally, so it
wouldn't be like you would need to connect
to a server. And that UI can be adjusted
as needed. I just used a very simple
format just to more focus on the backend
structure.
And then, as I mentioned, basic
dashboard, it does have the node control
as well as miner control. And it does give
you some visibility of the GPU, which can
be expanded on later.
The original goal test net block mining
directly through the UI. Unfortunately,
due to some complications, we did have to
pivot to pool mining which had its own
series of complications that will get into
but yeah, well once the test net node is a
little bit more stable and fortunately
having some challenges connecting to peers
and getting up to a full block height so
we can revisit that at a later time.
And then ultimately what we would like to
do is as we train the model and it gets
smarter and we can set it to do an auto
GPU tuning based on the nonce prediction
or any further optimization that we may
layer into the code base. And that can be,
we find more shares if our temperature is
at X or we find more blocks if you're a
solo miner based on these settings.
So it'll be interesting to see if people
can train models a little bit further than
I can, and ultimately those models can be
shared and people can use those models and
it could be a kind of a community-based
tool where people can share different data
sets with each other and that may help
miners find optimizations within their own
mining farm or with their own mining rig,
so to speak.
Current architecture. So try to keep it
fairly simple. We do have a backend, we
have a front end, within the backend it is
there's the node, the stratum GPU manager,
and that's all built with node JS and
express. We do have a front end. It's
react, so that can be expanded on and you
can make it beautiful if you want, or keep
it very simple.
And that all does have live controls that
are monitored or connected through a fast
API. And then again we built within the
CUDA miner some challenges connecting to
the pool and finding shares that we're
working on. We did have a little spike
where we were seen on the pool and the
hash rate was realized. However, working
on just the share control as we ended up
spamming the pool and get rejected
multiple times.
All right. So our node manager, so this
is just a little preview of the node
deployer that we have developed. We'll
give you a little live preview of how this
works, but in a nutshell, it does allow to
launch an Ergo node either on main net or
test net. gives you a series of the
version and you can do live configuration
control as well as have a live preview of
the node status.
Miner manager. So this just gives you a
little snippet here of what that looks
like. Again, very simple UI. You basically
put in your Ergo address, your worker
name, and then there's some backend code
that would load into a configuration and
that would connect to the mining pool.
Currently the code is basically
hard-coded to connect to the Sigmanauts
mining pool. You can change that at any
time by just looking at the code and
changing the IP address of the pool that
you want to connect to.
So just talk a little bit further about
the miner control panel. Again, this is
connecting directly to the backend code.
So it allows you to start and stop the
miner, adjust the configuration. And then
we will have live log right here in the
UI. And that will give you all the status
updates of the accepted shares, any of the
GPU stats or any of the additional log
information that you may want to say.
Again, we did have the pivot to pool
mining. So that was the focus here. We do
have some code built that does allow you
to mine directly to the node. However, we
did kind of pull that out of the backend
code for the time being until we can
connect to a testnet node.
We talked about the pool integration.
Again, we did successfully connect to the
Sigmanauts pool, successfully submitted a
couple of shares. Our hash rate was
realized on the pool, so we did see a true
handshake. But what we're working on is
the job parsing and share submission.
And that's basically what we're working
on moving forward is live share
submission, getting a true hash
validation, and then once that is live and
true, we can connect the AI a little bit
further and get a little bit better data
than what we're seeing today as we had to
put that more into what I'll call a demo
mode.
GPU monitoring. So this is very simple.
Again, we'll show you what this looks like
in the live preview. And then the meat of
the project here is the AI integration
framework.
So again, we did successfully complete a
model that does analyze real mining
information, as well as the GPU data,
share information. And then what we do is
we would store that in a JSON log. So that
information gets stored in the log. We're
using a random forest machine learning
model.
And what that is, just to kind of keep it
very simple, is it is a decision tree. And
it basically takes all the information
that gets loaded into the log, and it kind
of creates a weighted average based on the
decision tree method. And then it provides
a prediction based on what it thinks that
the most predictable number, and at this
point we're using a nonce, but that can be
changed to give us visibility or
prediction into GPU settings or overclock
settings or anything that we may want to
load in there and get predictions on.
In the pipeline, again, we basically
collect all the data in the logs. At this
point in time, it's basically just stats
and share results. What we're doing is
we're actually tying that into the miner
and also bouncing it off the node just to
confirm the block height and the
difficulty that bounces it off of the GPU
stats.
And what it's doing is it's telling the
miner to work on a nonce within this
range. It says 95% confidence. It's again,
mock information at this point because
we're just spamming multiple shares.
However, once we do get true mining, and I
have a feeling this will be more reliable
on a solo pool versus pool mining, but
we'll get it going and learn a little bit
more on the data set once we can get some
true data to analyze.
And then progress summary. So these are
the items that we have accomplished
throughout the project. Again, very
ambitious. I think we were hoping to get a
little bit further than that. Mining
development and mining software is very
complicated and as much as AI has improved
over the years, I think there are still
some room to improve as far as just
overall blockchain development.
All right, so we successfully completed
the node manager and true Ergo node
deployment. We have a node running right
now, so we'll show you that. It's actually
stopped for the time being, so we can
basically build the code from the ground
up.
Live GPU monitoring. We did get the CUDA
mining kernel development active, so we
have a true functioning miner, although
there is some issues with connecting to
the pool and submitting shares
successfully. We did successfully complete
the data-driven AI optimization, again,
built a simple UI dashboard.
We do have the live feedback loop with
live recommendations. And some of the
things that we'll still need to work on
is, again, the share submission, and then
overclocking automation. Unfortunately,
Linux is not very friendly with GPU
settings. So we'll have to maybe take a
different approach and look to offer
Windows integration versus looking at
modifying the BIOS of the GPU, which could
potentially cause issues.
All right, let's get into the fun stuff.
So what we'll go through now is we will
build the code from the back end and then
we'll show you how it's running on the
front end.
So again, try to keep it very simple
here. We have all of our back end code
basically in the back end and this is
really just for the dashboard
specifically. Front end again is just some
of the simple pages that we use for the
UI. And then everything else is basically
our source code, our mining software, some
of the stratum code back end for the
mining. And even the node generation is
built here in the back end. There are just
basically a few commands and a few
dependencies that you'll need to run,
which we have outlined all in the GitHub.
What we'll do is we're going to run the
miner. We'll turn on the AI software or
the AI listener. And then we'll turn on
the back end for the UI where it will
bring everything together. And then we'll
launch that on the front end here.
So what we'll do here is, before we get
into that, I'll just kind of show you how
the miner works in the back end. So we'll
just run that miner command. And then
again, you'll see we'll get our stratum
connection to the pool. We'll get our
subscribe and authorize. We'll understand
the difficulty of the pool, but then when
we go to look to submit shares, what was
happening is we were just spamming shares
like crazy.
So I turned that off just to kind of show
a demo of what that looks like. So it will
basically freeze here. It does receive the
job, but it doesn't work on the job at
this point in time.
All right, so this is the AI listener. So
this is built in Python. And basically
what this will do is there's a couple
things here. So we have two services. We
have the AI service, which is basically
the API service that will connect to the
database and provide information to the
UI. And then we have the training model.
What happens is we will turn on the
miner. The miner will take a bunch of
information and load it into a log. And
then we'll run the train command. The
train command will basically calculate the
weighted method based on the information
that's within the log. And that's where it
will provide its prediction.
So just kind of show how that runs on the
back end, simple command here. Again, it
takes all the information for this model.
Currently, we're just using five data
points, temperature, utilization, power,
the nonce range, and difficulty. And then
it will analyze that and again, do a
weighted average and then calculate that,
calculate a score, and then that score
will kind of predict a range.
Again, we're using nonce, but we can
modify this to one, extend our data out,
our data set out further to collect more
information, or we can predict different
items here, whether it's temperature range
that may be more useful for mining, power
settings, things of that nature.
And then the last one's just the API
service. And we're just going to turn this
on. And again, this just connects the API
to the backend.
And now we're in our backend. So
basically what our backend does, this is
a, we run a file called server JS. It's
just a simple JavaScript file. What that
does is basically ties everything
together. So within this file, we have our
node deployer, which again basically it
does a lot of pretty cool things that it
downloads the jar file from the Ergo
GitHub.
You can pick the version that you want to
use. You can modify the configuration as
needed. You can start and stop the node if
you want to adjust your configuration,
which is part of the setup process. And
again, you have the option between
toggling between test net and main net.
There is a feature where you can add a
snapshot. However, I was struggling with
it. Again, I was using Testnet, so there
was just some challenges in general, even
when trying to sync from scratch. But
there is an option here. You just need to
drop your snapshot into the backend
folder, the dashboard backend folder.
You'll see a folder there for snapshots,
and then that will automatically load it
into the node, and your snapshot will be
live.
Also within here is the mining software.
So we'll just basically turn on and off
the miner as noted. And then we have our
GPU information tied in here that ties
into the front end as well as our AI
analyzer. And so we'll turn on the backend
and again, just a simple command here in
order to warning just cause we're using an
experimental module, but it's working
well. So no worries there.
All right. And then it says that we are
running the server on the backend now. And
then the last thing is just to turn on the
react UI. We just use NPM start for that.
All right. We have built our front end.
All right. So again, very simple UI. We
have our mining dashboard. our node
manager, our GPU monitor and our AI
insights.
So what we'll do is we're going to go
ahead and turn on our node. So I was
previously running a node. You'll see I
have it turned off because we had the
backend turned off. So what we'll do is
we'll go ahead and pick the version I was
using. This is a live download from the
GitHub, so it will always give you the
latest versions, whether it's a
pre-release or a stable version.
There is a just a generic configuration
in here. Obviously, feel free to modify as
needed. All right, we're going to go ahead
and we're going to paste our configuration
in here. sure we're on the right version
or on the right network and you can switch
to test that if you'd like and then we'll
just simply deploy our node.
Now I just had this running so it will
catch up pretty quickly and I'm not fully
synced but again, we do have a log here.
It's scrollable, which is nice. So if you
have errors or issues, it's an issue of
node data is very fast and rapid. So
sometimes it can be hard to parse through.
So this will just give you a little bit of
a debugging tool.
If you're having challenges, setting up
your node and then we give you the status
there. And we do just have kind of simple
checklists here of what you need to do
once you get the node running. Again, you
could stop the node as needed, edit your
configuration, and then you just hit
deploy to rerun it.
And then if you need more help, you can
go to the Ergo Platform Official
Documentation. All right, we'll flip over,
see if our node is running. We are, we're
connecting to some peers, getting up to
height. So yeah, node is syncing.
All right, next we'll go to the mining
dashboard. So again, in a very simple
format. We'll go ahead here and we'll
paste in our address, our worker name. And
then you can save the configuration. If
you look in the back end, this is just a
simple configuration file. I think it's
named config. Again, you can look in that.
And again, if you need to modify it based
on pool format, you can go ahead and do so
as needed.
But this is set up again. We're set up
hard-coded to connect to the Sigmanauts
mining pool. And then what we'll do is
we'll start Miner, and you'll see
basically what you saw on the back end
there. So yeah, that's that. Again, it's
not live mining at this point. Again, we
did turn off the share submission just so
we're not spamming the pool and getting
kicked off for the demo purpose.
More to come as we build this out. We
have a live GPU monitor here. We're not
utilizing it very much, so you'll see it
will kind of just bounce up just based on
what I'm displaying here. So not under
full load. We did test under full load and
it does work accordingly. It does give you
live information. Again, I'm in idle mode,
so my fans aren't even on. It's nice and
cool, so no need to go there.
Power settings can be adjusted. Fan speed
can be adjusted. I did have success with
the 1080. I was having some other
challenges just because it was an older
GPU, so I did pull that out and throw my
3060 in here. But for whatever reason,
Linux just has some challenges running it
without X display. And that was just a
whole other path that I just didn't want
to go down and add further complication to
the project.
So we did get the monitor working. We
were able to make some setting adjustments
to the GPU. And this can be built out
further. And we do have access to
overclock settings as well. But if we
wanted to do anything a little bit deeper
with the GPU. There's a whole series of
settings available in the NVIDIA settings
command as well as NVIDIA SMI.
And then last but not least our AI
insights page. So right now this is just
running off of really what's driving the
data change is the adjustment and
temperature utilization and power. There's
a very limited data set right now. So it's
just gonna throw a bunch of random numbers
out there the more data that gets
collected and analyzed the more accurate
this may be but again with the variability
in nonce just in general with
proof-of-work mining and I don't think
that that may be a direction to go in.
I think where the power of this tool
could be is really just around some of
your GPU settings. And again, going back
to the original goal of the project, how
can you kind of reduce overall utilization
of your GPU and potentially mine a little
bit more efficiently, just obviously with
inflation. Deflation of proof-of-work
mining coins, every little advantage that
you can get in mining all the better.
All right. Well, I wanted to thank you
for watching my presentation of Cortex.
Something that I do again have a lot of
passion behind and something that
personally I think I'll continue to build
out slowly. It's obviously something that
requires resourcing and things of that
nature.
But again, the code is free and open. It
can be found on my GitHub, which I have
the link here. We'd love any potential
collaboration on how we could potentially
expand on this project. Again, the purpose
was for it to be community-driven and the
more people that could get involved and
potentially drive some different ideas and
concepts and know-how in the mining space
could potentially bring this project to
life.
Thanks again. Take care.