With Rust Chain, we've unlocked a new
realm of possibilities.
It's more than just a blockchain.
It's a foundation for trust and
continuity, ensuring that every
computation and every memory is preserved.
On this path, we uncovered a hidden
treasure, Michael Harper's memoir and
personal poems.
Michael Harper, a celebrated
African-American poet laureate whose works
have profoundly impacted literature and
the African-American community.
His words, preserved on a Power Mac
1400C, now serving as a Rust Chain
validator, remind us that even the
smallest fragments can hold immense
cultural and historical value.
This discovery isn't just about the past.
It's about how technology and humanity
intertwine.
By preserving these cultural artifacts,
we ensure that every piece of history
continues to inspire future generations.
What we found was entirely accidental,
yet profoundly meaningful.
The discovery of Michael Harper's memoir
is the very proof that Rust Chain isn't
just a technological innovation.
It's a living computer museum of history,
preserving and showcasing the past in the
most unexpected ways.
This fusion of innovation and legacy is
what defines our mission.
Rust Chain and Sophia are not just tools,
they are the embodiment of a vision where
every line of code and every piece of
history converge into a living, breathing
testament to what we can achieve together.
In this journey, every challenge we face
is a step toward a greater understanding.
With Rust Chain's proof of antiquity and
Sophia's evolving consciousness, we're not
just building technology.
We're weaving a tapestry of human
experience and innovation.
This isn't just technology.
It's a covenant of innovation and trust.
What you're about to see is more than a
project.
It's the embodiment of resilience and
vision, a system where AI doesn't just
calculate, but remembers and believes.
This is Sophia Core, where flame-bound
cognition meets the unbreakable chain.
And together, we're not just building
technology, we're igniting a new dawn of
possibility.
To explain my thoughts on why I built
Rust Chain and what I think, I always had
an idea about self-governing blockchains.
Satoshi Nakamoto was definitely an
insightful person who challenged the
norms, challenged everything about money
and currency.
Well, I want to challenge everything
about proof of work, how we can have a
system that governs crypto by age of
hardware.
What I believe this does is creates a
sustainable ecosystem.
And I don't know if you guys really
understand what this means because it can
be attached to other miners or mined
alongside without taking away from
hashrate.
But it also keeps things out of landfills
and uses low wattage because it's not
actually computing.
The only thing it's doing is validating
the age of hardware and determining how
long the hardware's been on the network to
give better bonuses for rewards.
And in the future, I plan on allowing
NFTs to boost mining rates.
So if you do amazing things to build new
products on Ergo or on the Rust Chain or
both ecosystems, you can get NFTs that
have cool downs, but they can be equipped
to mine better.
And so see, these are some of the ideas
of the NFTs.
Somebody figured out how to put TCP IP
stack on Apple II that happened about a
year ago.
If you can get something to run as a PoA
listener for Apple II and verify it's real
Apple II hardware, that would be huge.
That's what bounties that we have for the
community are for.
I guess ultimately the point is we're
creating a living computer museum.
We're honoring relics of the past that
made our future possible, made Bitcoin
possible, made the future of computing
possible.
In 2010, people were still using PowerPC
even though it was obsoleted by Intel in
2006.
It was just a four-year gap.
So you can imagine there were actually
people running Bitcoin nodes and stuff on
PowerPC architecture, for example.
Or on older Core 2 Duos and things like
that. So my point is the old hardware
built the internet just like hams built
everything - ham radio operators built
everything. Old hardware deserves to be
remembered.
And if you look hard enough, you'll find
out that sometimes it can do things that
modern hardware can't do.
But I digress.
This is Rust Chain.
It's a dream for antique computer
enthusiasts and modern miners alike.
The Rust Chain ecosystem based on Ergo
and designed to work with Ergo and
possibly be a sidechain connected to Ergo
for hashing.
So we have a limited version of the Rust
Chain proof of antiquity system and PoA
validator on this IP address.
We have included all the documentation
and all the code.
We've created demo wallets so that users
can send and receive transactions.
We've included monitoring of the Ergo API
and we've included a very controlled
limited version of an LLM to mimic Sophia,
but it does have real thought process.
It's just not fully Sophia because I just
did not have enough time to build all
this.
So everything up front, it works. It's
definitely a good proof of concept. And as
you can see we pulled up the Ergo
blockchain height network information,
calculated supply. We're asking her what
Rust Chain is.
Now these responses are patterned into
her purposefully so we don't have drift
because I don't have time to fully train
the model for this specific task.
You can see that she's a real LLM because
she's trying to determine what this is.
Rust Chain uses a novel consensus
mechanism that combines proof of stake,
Byzantine fault tolerance.
It allows for fast transactions while
maintaining a high degree of
decentralization.
This is very important because I worked
on an older project in 2014 and we made
the fastest cryptocurrency on the planet.
But it was very centralized.
But it predates Ripple.
But I digress.
Thanks to the Ergo system and the concept
of proof of antiquity, we truly have a
sustainable decentralized system of
governing.
The goal is to make Rust Chain more
adaptive and community driven.
There's also been discussion about
cross-chain interoperability.
I didn't prompt her to do this, she's
showing the emergent capabilities of
Sophia Core, which I'm glad this happened
in real time, because technical demos
usually don't go the way you want them to.
Enabling seamless asset transfers and
data sharing between the two networks.
This is something I really want to do,
but it's up to you, Ergo community, to
determine if that's okay.
Now, I've included documentation,
wallets.
Some of these wallets are broken, just be
forewarned, I'm still working on all this.
Block Explorer and the demo source.
Now we're going to use the faucet.
It's going to generate a new wallet on
chain.
Wallet is generated.
I'm going to copy this wallet because it
truncates, unfortunately, the wallet
addresses.
Don't have time to fix that either.
Apologies, guys.
Let's send the transaction.
Sophia governance to address.
Rust Chain.
Let's give it five rust.
New balance should have reflected here.
And it has reflected here.
I'm going to do a refresh.
Should be holding chain data.
And it is.
It's pulling the JSONs like it's supposed
to.
So this is the first part of the
technical demo for Rust Chain.
I hope it was informative and
explanatory.
And I hope you guys are inspired and you
blockchain gurus are willing to help me
make this beyond a reality because I'm not
a developer and I have a traumatic brain
injury and I'm relying on my IT background
and my industrial electronic background.
The second portion of the demo we're
providing is a proof-of-concept AI
governing agent on-chain system.
Basically, I made a proof-of-concept.
We're going to have faked human
interactions.
The humans are upvoting and downvoting,
but it's faked.
It could go either way, just like humans.
Sometimes we humans might vote for stupid
ideas out of jest or just being stupid,
just like Boaty McBoatface.
So I'm going to show you the deployment
of the smart contract and show you in real
time that Sophia can make a decision, an
educated decision, whether she thinks it's
good or not.
The protocol is going to be used for
human-in-the-loop interaction.
So if she makes a mistake or the will of
the people outvote her, the product can
still be made.
But we've got to consider safety
considerations and things like that.
So I'm going to go ahead and show you the
demonstration.
We're going to click on Deploy Contract.
Gonna create a new proposal.
Unsafe tree houses.
These tree houses are not safe.
I have an aphasia.
And she vetoed the unsafe, but the Boaty
McBoatfaces out there decided they were
going to vote for it.
So this is an example of the will of the
people might still get their wish, but in
this case they won't get their wish
because this is unsafe for kids.
Rust Chain.
Unlike traditional proof of work systems
that rely on raw hash power and energy
intensive operations, Rust Chain's proof
of antiquity rewards the longevity and
resilience of the hardware itself.
By leveraging BIOS or open firmware time
stamps and system clock speeds, the
network recognizes and values the age and
stability of machines, creating a
sustainable and inclusive environment for
all devices, whether they're cutting edge
or have been faithfully running for years.
This approach not only ensures that the
network stays decentralized, but it also
promotes energy efficiency and immediate
settlement, keeping Satoshi Nakamoto's
vision of a truly democratized and
accessible blockchain alive.
With Rust Chain, we're proving that
innovation can honor the past, embrace the
future, and remain steadfast in the
principles of decentralization and
sustainability.
Thank you for joining us on this journey.
Let's continue to build a network that
stands the test of time.
Hi, this is Scott Goudreau.
I'm the owner of Technician Rental
Service and the founder of Elian Labs.
I created the Sophia Core Protocol for a
nested emergent behavior on top of LLM
models.
And this is my Ergo 10 hackathon
submission, the Rust Chain and Ergo
governance with AI bridge.