Music's going, right, kushti?
I mean, Andy?
Perfect.
Welcome, everybody, to the first official
community AMA by the Ergo Proof of Work
blockchain.
We have quite a showing already.
This is fantastic.
We have Grayman, kushti, Blake
Starkenberg, and Nex, Armeanio.
Some people are still waking up, so it
might be a minute before they turn on
their cameras, but that's perfectly fine.
As promised, in the last AMA, we are
going to move this format to what you're
seeing now, which is a community chat.
Community AMA, which means you show up,
you ask questions, or you observe, or you
get asked questions.
So be prepared for anything if you show
up.
And people asking questions, be prepared
for people not to answer if they don't
want to talk.
So, it's a free-for-all, it's an
open-economy system, and this is how we do
it, right?
Just in the Ergo spirit.
So, as promised, hey, kushti, got your
video on.
So, as promised, how you doing, kushti?
How's your week been?
It's busy, busy.
But everything is well.
So preparing a lot of things in parallel.
Well, from sub-blocks to some slides.
I'm going to visit Korean Blockchain Week
and already presenting something to Piers
there.
And it seems it will be a big event like
one of the biggest blockchain events
globally.
I don't like those big conferences like
80% commerce rights, 90% like just
ordinary crypto web 3 scam somewhat but
yeah well anyway.
kushti was, I was asking kushti for a
meeting time with Mark trying to organize
something.
He's like, I'll be in Korea.
I was like, oh, you're going to North
Korea?
And he's like, no idiot.
There's a blockchain in South Korea.
Just the biggest one in the world.
One of the biggest, yeah, and immediately
after it will be Token 2049 in Singapore,
but yeah, I'm missing it because yeah,
probably already would be too much.
And basically the same people, I guess.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right.
So as promised, guys, as a conversation
starter and to pay respect to the
developers and the fact that I don't do
developer update anymore, we're going to
bang through a couple of the developer
updates right here.
And kushti, I'd love if you read your own
updates.
That would encourage maybe Anand Vihar to
come on next time and read his updates or
other people to come on and read their
updates.
So I'm going to share my screen.
And we will do this, let's see if it
looks okay.
It does look okay, perfect.
All right, so kushti says, yesterday at 9
a.m., let's chat, please share your
updates.
kushti, you want to take your update
there?
Yeah, so yeah, it's a kind of small font.
Yeah, can you read it?
Oh yeah, yeah.
Sub-blocks.
Peer-to-peer layer heavily reworked.
Announcements are now done via INV
messages.
Transactions stored in mempool are not
redownloaded.
Only diff testing and polishing things
now.
What's INV messages, kushti?
Yeah, so we are currently testing it with
Potato.
So there is a network with three peers
and yeah, I'm checking logs all the time
and improving things.
Often it is stuck, one node or another,
because of banning another node, because
messaging to be improved.
Yeah, there is a penalization for too
aggressive messaging, but yeah, well, at
the same time.
Well, so some parts are not aggressive
enough.
So yeah, I'm tuning and fixing.
reworking between the maximum efficiency
but also while working on the enemy spam
attacks.
Well, usually it's the parts of the
protocol which developers are not touching
at all, they don't love to touch.
So it's
It's especially true for other
blockchains, especially true for Ethereum.
In Bitcoin there are some updates, but I
think there are a couple of developers
that are just working on peer-to-peer
stuff, so it's quite complicated.
But yeah, so after that, after
peer-to-peer, so there will be a review.
And yeah, I'm going to propose already
one toy pull request proposed in the node
repository.
And this week, I'm going to propose a
second pull request for review, sub-blocks
related, I mean, now in the Sigma SDK
repository.
So, yeah, we are moving forward, yeah.
All right, very cool.
And then you've got an update on
ChainCash basis.
You rework the basis design, off-chain
payments with no need to create anything
on chain first.
Yeah, but wait, also Git Circles.
All right, go, go, go, Git Circles.
Yeah, so Git Circles is a project to
create community currencies for digital
communities, developing communities,
right?
So the idea is that you write codes and
getting tokens for lines of code or pull
requests.
And yeah, well, we already have, so there
are a couple of contributors there.
And, yeah, well, there is already
functionality to grab pull request data
from GitHub.
And, yeah, after the dev chat, one of
contributors reported also on persistence.
They're more or less done.
So we can start testing it in a few days,
hopefully.
I mean, do some testing tokens.
rewarding with it manually for starters.
And then, yeah, we can start to invite
different open source communities to have
the economies on Ergo.
So, well, we will start with some
repositories contributors are working on.
Those are some fully homomorphic
encryption related repositories, some
state of art.
cutting-edge cryptography stuff.
But then, yeah, we will probably invite
some infra framework developers in Rust
and then more.
So kind of cool and we had some heated
discussions yesterday when tokens are
needed, when not.
So I think in this case for open source
communities it makes a lot of sense to
have like contribution tokens.
Even before there is some sponsorship for
open source project, right?
There is some economy and actually it
would help with sponsorship as well.
And so on with providing services to open
source projects by volunteers, well,
promotional efforts.
All right, but then also,
Yeah, well, let's talk further when
tokens are not needed.
So yeah, I think that the current crypto
industry, let's say, so yeah, it's
creating tokens, means money, where it's
not needed usually, right, but not
creating where it's needed.
So it's kind of reversed.
to the needs of digital and real-world
economies.
Are you sure?
You got a long one for ChainCash, kushti,
what did you do there?
Right, so I need to provide some
high-level writing on what's
what's going on with recent reworks so
currently it's probably technical but
what's happening so well you know there is
on-chain like free banking with multiple
backers called ChainCash so it's a kind of
on-chain havala maybe right in certain
regards
But also a kind of generic solution to
build different kinds of monetary systems,
backed and trust-based.
But then, yeah, some time ago I proposed
a lightweight off-chain cache version
based on a little bit similar reserve
contract called Basis, where the idea is
to have the ability to create IOU nodes
off-chain.
maybe even not backed initially but then
yeah it's possible to create on-chain
reserve and have redemption right of those
nodes against the reserve and yeah there
could be multiple reserves and so on but
yeah well
After considering use cases such as
micropayments and so on, I've discovered
that the original design is probably not
quite suitable, so I reworked it and now
it's not about some
Now, but IOU records which are tracked by
minimally trusted tracking agents.
Trackers, right, so it's kind of, I don't
know, like off-channel BitTorrent-like
design, but for money.
So you choose tracker.
a reserve holder choosing a tracker,
right, then it's possible to create an
off-chain cache there and maybe not fully
backed in.
So, yeah, credit is over.
And so on, and yeah, well, after all this
design, I think things like micro
payments, rewarding peer-to-peer networks,
agent payments are possible.
And yeah, well, I hear some technical
details, but I'm going to write some...
high-level description, maybe later
today, because I came to this design only
yesterday.
But yeah, well, it looks okay, and the
contract is done.
And now...
Yeah, a high-level description.
Well, there are some initial contributors
already, so we can do off-chain
functionalities and then some wallets.
And also integrate these off-chain cache
with some credits and credit LETS.
We can inject those functionalities in
some peer-to-peer networks.
So we can start with Celaut, which is
closely related to Ergo already, but then
we can go for other peer-to-peer networks
and replace, well, DP tokens used there
for unclear reasons.
with just uniform kind of money, right,
created and not via some strict rules,
well, pretty fine schedule, which is even
worse.
So, yeah.
I have a question about that, about the
track.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Right, right, right.
You're proposing to create a system of,
like you said, free banking.
So cash systems that are based on banks,
but in this case, unlike the old system,
where you just had to trust the banker
that they had a certain amount of gold,
you're talking about a system where you
could even have fractional reserve lending
or cash issuance.
but that those fractional reserves would
be transparent, not just to the person
who's taking the loan or the cash, but
also the vendor that's accepting it in
trade.
And then going back to the bank, is this
basically like free banking except you
have to wear a pin on your lapel that says
how much your reserve is and whether
you're fully collateralized?
Is that what you're aiming for?
So the idea of tracker is to be like a
ledger keeper, right?
But no more so off-chain ledger records
keeper.
So all the records are signed, right?
So for example, if you are sending me
money,
you are signing an IOU statement, then
you need to hold it.
If a tracker is disappearing, for
example, then still all the records are
redeemable on-chain, and the tracker
cannot still move, well, he cannot forge
your signature.
Right, so then, yeah, well, if it's, if
tracker is disappearing, right, then yeah,
well, the latest snapshot of its state
committed on the blockchain can be used
for redemptions, right, so you can use,
you can lose money
So since the last update, right, maybe a
few minutes, I don't know, one hour.
But yeah, well, you can use records from
the latest snapshot still, right.
And then it can be improved in many ways,
like you can have federated tracker.
you can replace it with some sidechain
even and so on.
It's more or less like BitTorrent in this
regard because for BitTorrent also a lot
of more secure options were proposed but
usually just centralized gatekeepers have
been used.
Is there going to be a standard note?
I heard you a while back or maybe it was
in one of the chats talking about having
pegged to silver, potentially, a small
amount of silver.
Yeah, well, the idea is, but so pegging
is the question of a unit of account,
right?
So I think I can change cash to use gold
here.
I don't know, maybe silver, but why
silver?
So I think gold is kind of more
universal, right, in this regard as a unit
of account.
I mean, maybe it's a bit exotic in
comparison with, well, USD or Euro, but
yeah, well, it's most stable.
I can tell you why I think the answer
should be silver.
Because gold is the unit of account for
central banks.
And that's appropriate for really large
scale transactions.
But the beauty of ChainCash is that it's
more about localized economies and
currencies.
And historically, that's been tied to
silver.
And it's true, silver is also part of a
global market.
And that's part of the reason why it
fluctuates in value so much.
But if you're talking about going back to
sort of a free banking approach, which it
sounds like you are, then silver is
usually the currency of the people,
especially if you're trading services.
Goods is another matter because the
inputs are fairly fixed in cost and
there's the question of how many middlemen
between
you the buyer and how it got to you, but
services are directly provided by the
person.
So when you're trading services, having
the fundamental unit be something like
silver is useful because it's, you could
easily redeem it in person without relying
on the chain.
So let's say you have an under
collateralized bank and people are still
trading it because it's useful.
but then there's some sort of a run on
that bank, you could still redeem the
uncovered ones in physical silver if you
have that around.
And Americans have a lot of physical
silver around.
That's interesting.
So yeah, in the community setting, yeah,
you may have even tokenized silver, right,
of some trusted local provider.
And yeah, well, pay with digital
IOU records which are backed by that
silver.
So yeah in this regard it's the same yeah
for free banking kind of system like
ChainCash but yeah with no multiple
reserves for now but yeah well like in
ChainCash you can do mutual credit
clearing well even fully off-chain
right but yeah also between different
reserves yeah I think this would be
possible but yeah I need to write down
details but yeah it's interesting I mean
but how popular can it be to have like I
know so small communities trading
digitally
against, tokenized, silver, reserves,
some local reserves.
And that's, that's, that's a question.
Do you think it could be popular?
It already happens with farmers markets
and all sorts of other local economies.
Oh, that's interesting.
Yeah.
So America had silver coinage up until
1964 was the last year.
So, there's just an enormous amount of it
sitting around around, 2 billion ounces
worth, one to two.
So, and already denominated, I mean,
they're a little bit worn, but they're
still tradable and recognizable.
So it's just sitting around.
There's an enormous amount of,
a latent capital that is in motion.
It is liquid, not very liquid.
Not everybody knows about this, but
certainly people that give a shit do.
Usually it's used for tax evasion if
we're being real about it.
So people are, instead of horse trading
goods and services, they're pricing them
in silver coinage.
There was even a guy out in Arizona that
tried to pay his employees in gold and
silver, but that was a bridge too far for
the IRS and they nailed him because he
started screwing around with employment
taxes.
All right.
Is he even concerned though, gray man,
with silver or even gold with too many
paper claims?
on the underlying asset isn't that the
main issue in the validity of it now is
what ChainCash provides is like, Oh, we
can verify the underlying claims on asset.
Yeah.
Transparent to everyone.
So if you golf with your banker, right in
the old days, you could be sure that if
they were under collateralized, that you
would be one of the ones doing the bank
run happened that could get your silver or
gold out.
and somebody else would be left holding
the sorry, we're bankrupt note.
But in this case, everybody knows and
there's no, right?
It's sort of broadcast what the level of
collateralization and that's done, I
guess, through these trackers and people
can either bump that up or people can
discount the value of the notes that are
sold based on under collateralized banks.
That's what happened a lot in the free
banking era.
That was based mostly on the difficulty
of redemption.
The further away you got from the bank
that was issuing the notes that were
theoretically backed by the gold, the less
valuable they were for the vendor that was
accepting them in the market, because
they'd ultimately either have to cart them
back to that bank themselves and get the
gold for it, or they'd have to pass them
off to somebody else, and that person's
also going to discount it.
So in this case, you don't have that
problem, but you do have the issue that
suddenly everybody gets to know which
bank, no matter where it is, is
collateralized to what extent.
And if you really want to be safe, I
guess you're going to stick with SigmaUSD
or Blue On or what have you, because
they're over-collateralized.
But the advantage of this type of system
is that it allows you to have a lot more
money on the end, a lot more liquidity.
because it's based on the trust of the
local people that are involved in it.
And so we notice, I really think it's the
only way out of the over collateralized
stable coin and still have it be
algorithmic.
Otherwise you have to rely on these, on
people, right?
On Tether.
Tether tells you that they have a certain
amount of bonds and Bitcoin and everything
else to back up the Tether node, but
effectively they're just a bank
And this new act that came out recently
effectively tells them that they have to
be fully collateralized banks.
But you still just have to trust that
that's the case.
And theoretically, the regulators are now
going to go and investigate and make sure
that's the case.
But that's not very capital efficient.
And all of the banks are creating their
own stablecoins because of this new
approach.
But that's not going to stop them from
trying to issue dollars the normal way
because that's how they'd rather do it.
And that's much more lucrative for them
because they get to print money out of
thin air and collect interest on it.
So they're going to want to do that and
not use the stable coins.
But if we want to do something that's on
chain and has that same level of power,
the power to print money out of thin air
confidence, that comes from credit.
And that's essentially what
ChainCash is, it gives you the
possibility to have under collateralized
credit arrangements on chain and have
people be able to ascertain what level of
trust they should provide that.
So I think it's the most exciting thing
going on, not just in Ergo, but in crypto
in general.
I don't know if anybody else is even
contemplating this type of thing.
They're all worried about trying to get
USDC or USDT on their chain.
And I'm just sort of like, why pollute
your chain with a censored centralized
crap?
Are we trying to get away from that?
If that's the goal, why not just do it
all on a centralized exchange anyway?
You can get USDT on Coinbase, no problem.
So if you've already given up on the idea
of crypto, just go with Coinbase.
Kind of pointless, but that's what a lot
of people do.
Yeah, so ChainCash is fully on-chain,
right?
So you see the collateralization level
on-chain.
So here with off-chain scheme basis,
right?
So the concern is that with using
ChainCash, so in the first place, it's not
quite convenient for micro payments, but
yeah, you need to pay on-chain fees,
right?
that people need to get to blockchain
Ergo Zone.
So here with off-chain, so people can be
onboarded immediately, right?
As well, especially for credit, for
example.
if you are joining some services, like
Celaut, for example, so it's kind of like
Docker on a peer-to-peer, right?
So it's a peer-to-peer computing network
where you can get some computing
resources, right?
And you can get credit like in
BitTorrent, you are getting
some data to download like I don't know
one gigabyte right before the need to
share in return then yeah here you can get
like 10 minutes worth of CPU hour
writes for for your tasks without so they
need to know about their go blockchain and
so on.
Right.
So for for digital economies, that would
be better.
And that would be how can we get a lot of
People actually are onboarded, right?
So just via seamless experience with
using something, creating credit and then,
yeah, they need to pay after.
Then, yeah, in the same way you can use
off-chain cash for agent-to-agent
economies, right?
Now quite popular topic because of, yeah,
and so on.
But yeah, you can use it also for like
retail payments, community consists and so
on.
And, yeah, well, this silver case is
interesting, so I can maybe write a
document how such system can be
implemented.
And then, yeah, so with off-chain cache,
you need to trust
tracker right to get collateralization
level.
So you have reserves on chain, right?
So here the bank functionality split,
right?
So you have reserves, one party and
ledger keeping, IOU records keeping by
another party, right?
Doing it off chain.
But yeah, well, there are a lot of things
you can do here, like doing a federated
trick, right?
So having multiple people tracking a
collateralization level, like Oracle pools
are done, for example.
You can, or wasn't even right, then you
can do merged mine sidechain even, maybe
some roll-up constructions, right?
So you can get some on-chain guarantees
even, but such constructions would be a
little complicated.
for tests to start with just simple
designs so it's just a component in the
system the tracking channel and then for
silver we can write some doc for community
how to tokenize silver and you do
community trading against it.
What do you think about that, Grayman?
I mean, we can talk about different
things like security, well, attack vectors
and so on for a long time.
But I think if there is some more or less
good solution, it's better to try to do
some small scale experiments with that and
then see how to improve things that makes
a lot of sense.
Instead of building enormously complex
from day one, it gets feedback maybe not
so positive after a few years.
Maybe, yeah, well, also some complexities
are not really needed in many cases.
Right, so yeah, it all depends on use
case, so yeah, but it's better to get on
them as soon as possible, I guess.
So, what do you think, guys?
I think it's a very interesting work in
progress, but there's probably other stuff
on the on the dev
update list.
Right, right, right.
So yeah, QX, can we get back to the dev
updates?
Yeah, they've got one or two more, I
think.
This one's really cool.
Right here, Neetram is working back on
their open source hardware wallet, right?
Is that what I'm seeing, the poor man's
wallet?
Yes, so it's DIY hardware wallets which
you can assemble at home and yeah, well,
it's super cheap and also if you order
components and assemble at home you
are not a possible subject to data leak,
right?
Ledger is coming periodically.
And also, if you have such device
somewhere at your home, then a thief, for
example, cannot easily recognize that this
is hardware wallet, right, unlike Ledger.
So the problem with Ledger
From some big holders, the problem that
I've heard is that it is easily
recognizable, right, that you have a
Bitcoin wallet and then thieves can target
it specifically.
But you can 3D print any case for this,
because you make it look like a calculator
or something.
Yeah, or maybe, I don't know, Sega Mega
Drive cartridge, something like that.
That might be valuable, kushti.
Yeah, these days probably, yeah.
Well, that's awesome.
This is great.
Let's see.
Yeah, because he entered the hackathon
with his original idea, I believe, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, some Ergo hack three or four,
something like that.
Then, yeah, we discussed MCP.
You were talking about MCP servers,
right, and AI.
Yeah, so currently I'm trying all those
things for different tasks.
So for core development, yeah, well,
results are not satisfiable at all.
So, yeah, even tests are hard to
generate.
For non-testing codes I'm not allowing
for anything but comments to be generated
by LLMs because it's always tricky to
check the hallucinations when it's a kind
of complex thing.
in regards with this base implementation
and so what we can get tests for contracts
right maybe off-chain bots quite quickly
and so on so yeah the idea is to get some
specialized MCP for building applications
on Ergo right with LMs quicker
Yeah, speaking of that, the thing we set
up for CodeUTXO for ErgoHack with MCP
servers, I'm starting to at least develop
half of that for our work here.
We got some pretty cool things, a couple
of models out already that are seemingly
helping students.
So no use for an MCP server yet in that
AI that we're using, but we'll see.
how it would apply with non-blockchain
things would be interesting for sure.
What else?
I didn't write in the update but we've
got three more infrastructure peers that
have signed up and we've got the three
machines.
That's one for Jemai.
There's one for Satoshi.
And Lucas is going to run in for it as
well.
So these machines will ship out for those
three guys today or tomorrow.
They've got a base installed with Ubuntu
and then they go through the schooling of
setting up the Ergo Explorer node and all
that good stuff.
And then we'll hook them on to the load
balancer and we'll spread our reach even
further.
We're going to have really good USA
coverage, guys, where we need some more
Europe or Middle Eastern or Asian
coverage.
It would be nice to have those load
balancers in there.
So if you're in those parts and you want
to join the Ergo InfraDAO, please hop on.
Depending on what hardware you have, work
with us.
And if we have some more extras of these
things, we can send them out to you as
well.
But ping us and chat.
Talk to us.
More than Merrier for this kind of
project.
What else we got?
Joe, I see you're nodding with your
camera on, your coffee's full.
Hopefully your bladder's empty and you're
ready to chat.
Let's see, with Rosen, we've been going
through the process of integrating the
runes build into the watcher and guard
modules, setting up a test environment to
where then we'll spend a while running
unit tests and end tests, try to break
what we build before we release it.
That's always the most important
like round of building something, but
it's also like the least appreciated in
the crypto space where, you know, everyone
says when, when, when, when, when.
And it's like, no, you just need full
coverage and testing.
So we'll go through that, playing around
in terms of how to potentially take kind
of how we're embedding metadata on Bitcoin
to support the Rosen bridge standard.
and seeing what the capacity is to kind
of extend that, right?
And it's kind of unique to think about,
you know, potentially we could create kind
of our own standard for color coins on
Bitcoin, which I don't know, maybe that's
kind of old fashioned in terms of like,
I guess we're cryptos today, generally,
but an example would be you could
potentially wrap ERG as a rune or wrap
Dexy Gold as a rune and potentially get
some access to some of the infrastructure
on Bitcoin, such as Lightning, depending
on what other builds come up with.
Not one-to-one, you could wrap any amount
of ERG into a single rune essentially,
right?
Yeah, I think it'd probably be smart to
handle it the same as how we currently
handle wrapping assets, right?
Because that's something we already do.
To where it would be more like Rosen
supported for external assets.
And then there's the potential to try to
create some sort of generalized tool.
Maybe two of them, one for general
purpose use and one of them more for
specialized.
use that says, okay, if we can create a
unit of account and then we can attach
metadata to that unit of account, how can
we potentially see unique assets coming
onto the Bitcoin network?
I do think long-term, there's probably a
certain use case for the infrastructure
that's being built on top of Bitcoin.
I'd say right now, Lightning is probably
ahead in terms of adoption.
I do believe, at least at first pass,
Lightning would be able to support that.
Then it's like you have these payment
channels on top of Bitcoin and you kind of
create...
let's say a wrapped asset or some sort of
synthetic, or let's say I wrote an article
a while ago where it's like, could you
have gold in a vault and say, OK, we're
going to tokenize this and have metadata
attached to where's the vault, how much is
in it, et cetera, et cetera, perhaps even
how do I audit this, and then throw it
into a payment channel and make it more
fungible was like a form of payment.
So thinking about that, you know, the
question is like, okay, standardized input
fields, you know, there's certain metadata
standards, depending on where you are in
the world, or like regulated assets,
anyways, and then it's question how big
would that be?
How do you
and I'll create the right input fields
and then basically translate it, hexify
it, chunk it across UTXOs.
It meant something that is kind of unique
for Bitcoin, where you have some sort of
token standard.
It's been like a thought journey still.
Feasibility costs, et cetera, is not
really locked in yet, but interesting
nonetheless.
We also have gone through the application
process for this round of catalyst
funding.
I think right now they're in community
reviews.
To be honest, the Rosen submissions are
actually a little bit boring because we've
already built an open standard.
which is to some degree like I think a
big advantage because it's like okay well
here's the cookbook or standards that
we're gonna you know build with right so
there's there's a certain like I don't
know transparency and expectation of
delivery but it's also a little bit less
sexy because it's like you know it's a
known known right versus sometimes there's
the ability to like upsell and market
things versus just have like
This is our technical documentation and
we're going to go through that and add
this and then add that and then add that.
Let's see with.
Rosen, we're also working on updating
kind of to the Pandora testnet.
It's been some work there, working on
creating an updated version of Ergo
Multi-Sig.
That's hopefully a little bit more
performant.
Yeah, Lithos is just in the same test,
test, test, test, test, test, test, test,
test, test, which is like the least
I don't know, least sexy marketing time
for building a product probably, right?
But also practically the most important
in terms of security coverage.
You know, understanding what can break
and where and how and trying to mitigate
that.
Also, I know that there's some work being
done for Machina Finance, which is kind of
a P2P grid trading framework.
A lot of these were kind of
I don't know, lined up to deliver
hopefully October, maybe November.
I say that and then I regret saying that
because when you're in testing, what
matters is what's in front of you, right?
But we, at least have some sort of a goal
that we're going to do a meetup in
Colorado.
I need to like sync with, Andre coming up
here, to make sure that everything's
smooth, right?
Looking forward to that, but hopefully
when we get to the point, you know, we can
show some MVPs, try to throw up some test
nets,
kind of have some practical example of,
you know, what we've been building and
talking about for a while.
So that'd be fun.
That would be fun.
I have this for the next every, every
week for the next four or five weeks, I'm
announcing the speakers, even though I
already announced them, but doing a
feature read on them.
So Joe was already announced last week as
the welcoming opener.
Yeah.
Yeah, so I think next one's going to be
AdonBR that we'll post today or tomorrow
to promote that as well.
But if you guys haven't bought tickets
to, I mean, there's no tickets to buy.
If you guys haven't bought your plane
ticket or your Airbnb or your hotel, you
know, they only get more expensive, that's
for sure.
So, and also pop chat if there are other
people going.
There's ways to save as well by joining
hotels or
Sharing your Airbnb's.
I mean you might wake up in a ice bath
with a scar over your kidney, but But hey,
you know, it might be worth the same a few
bucks to room with somebody Yeah What's
that You can't camp outside.
I don't know Colorado Springs other tent
fortresses there Joe Yeah, I'm sure
Well, I'm sure it depends on what you
mean by camp.
The space is in downtown, so there are
people camping around there, but I don't
know if they're good bedfellows, so to
speak.
You know, but I'm sure I'm sure there are
there are places to camp in and around the
general area The question is just like how
close and I don't know infrastructure,
right?
Yeah, I've also been I've also been
talking to Chris Ray at one point he
proposed You know just trying to put
together like dinner like that's more
We're holding them to that, Joe.
We are holding them to that.
Yeah, yeah.
We do have at least some facilities there
to where if you wanted to push out some
food, it's possible.
When will they kick us out of the hall,
Joe?
Oh, I have the keys, buddy.
Perfect.
I don't know.
At one point he wanted to try to do like
Korean barbecue, but then the question
there is like basically electricity
logistics.
And I don't know what kind of efforts,
you know, he's talking about.
Using with all that we do.
I mean we do have there is like a
dedicated kitchen there that that's fairly
large so you know, it might be better to
go more old-fashioned than like Korean
barbecue skillet, but I Need to talk to
him to be honest But anyway, but I think
that it's nice to break bread with people,
you know, I have things a little bit more
p2p like and sharing that'd be cool
No, it's gonna be a lot of fun.
Yeah.
Tyler, you just spoke about something in
a comment in Zoom right here that I talked
a little bit about last week that I want
to try to.
So Tyler, if you want to say it in
person, go for it, Tyler.
You want me to read your question?
Yeah, hey guys.
So I've been with Ergo and Crypto since
like 2021, January or so.
and i've always been interested in
building something but I get like I hit a
wall and I can't understand how to like
connect the front end with the back end to
the to the blockchain and all that stuff
so I recently started going back to
college at community college to do some
software development and hopefully like
bridge some gaps with apis and the
databases and how it all works and stuff
and i was just thinking of if somebody
else is already working on something or
eventually as i like bridge my gaps i can
start building dApps and like give more
examples of how it all connects and like
make videos maybe just to get more people
building on the on train oh that's awesome
that's a great idea and you mentioned DECO
in there as well i i miss DECO DECO was
fantastic
I was there for DECO for a little bit.
My instructor was Key and I haven't heard
from him since that was over.
So I'm not sure.
But I hope you still are.
He's around.
Yeah, so last time I've seen him like a
few days ago, probably, so he's appearing
in the chats regularly.
The main chat, usually for some reason.
Not the dev chat.
But yeah, he's around.
And so what are you looking for?
So do you want to develop some front end?
Or do you want to understand how to
connect?
I'm really interested in full stack.
Trying to understand.
Yeah, yeah, so I think maybe there is
need to remind about different tools and
approach.
But yeah, we have a lot of open source
applications also, right, where it can be
seen.
So, well, my idea, well, was maybe Mark
have done that to feed LLM with different
open source applications.
We already have examples, right?
And then, yeah, well, such things can be
shown by LM, even.
QX, do you know the state of the MCP
there?
So the MCPs that we set up on CodeUTXO
are just essentially targeting the APIs
for...
Some trading stuff, right?
Blockchain, yeah, you got it.
So you can say, give me the historical
price for the last 30 days, graph it in a
little graph for me, that kind of thing.
Who's a wallet holder here this so it's
really good tooling for like let's say a
project owner Who doesn't know code and
they want to airdrop to their people?
They can get a list of all their holders
of the token and that kind of thing So
that's the way the MCP works right there,
but that being said Tyler about DECO
Something that I'm doing here on campus
already that students really like and I
think would be amazing with the amount of
content we have on Ergo that is we take
the videos and
And we ingest them into AI so that they
create really nice subtitle files, right?
And then I run it through a script to
timestamp YouTube bookmarks in those
subtitle files.
We add all that data to a knowledge base
on WebUI.
You don't even have to use MCP for this,
kushti.
And then you ingest in the knowledge base
as well.
You can hard code it, but you can link to
specific projects already in Ergo.
So then, Tyler, you ask the question, you
say, hey, I'm having trouble connecting
this to this.
How do I fix this?
So the AI will automatically look through
the knowledge base.
It'll look through every single DECO
video that we put on there.
And it can read the subtitle file.
So it'll look through it and it'll say,
OK, here's how you do this.
And oh, here is minute 75 in DECO lesson
number five.
Click it, and it takes you right
bookmark that YouTube.
So that's my project after we get up and
going is to ingest all those video SRT
files, timestamps into a knowledge base
and then make it available to all of Ergo
because I'll run it on a local 3090 with
like llama or deep seek or something like
that which can run on our own GPU, not
chat GPT.
That's it.
So if you want to help out with that,
Tyler, where we're adjusting and you're
finding videos that are relevant and
you're adding video as well.
And also, you know, being the gatekeeper
for that all.
Yeah, that'd be that'd be great if you
want to join in that kind of thing.
But not until after the infra.
I got it.
We got to push that.
If you want to start it now, that's fine,
too.
Yeah, because I I do pretty good at I do
like reading documentation, but I
definitely learn faster And I like the
videos like watching your Rosen watcher
helped me a lot like get that set up and
then using AI to like kind of ask
questions like hey, I tried this but it's
like not working How do I get it to what
did I do wrong?
And then it'll like see my errors or
something
Now imagine watching, pinging an AI bot
that specific task in mind was knowing
that you're developing on Ergo and knowing
all the documentation of Ergo.
So its questions are not searching the
whole web essentially and knows that it's
focused just on Ergo to help you solve
those problems on Ergo.
So it makes a world of difference to
context does.
Yeah, that's why we need for specific
MCP, right, for Ergo development.
And yeah, well, maybe some tutorials as
well, like what are typical parts of the
app, right, like off-chain backend.
A little while ago, maybe a few months
ago, kushti said,
like most of the code is off-chain
anyways and you just need a little bit to
connect the chain when there's a
transaction.
That part having difficulty connecting.
Yeah, so from my experience, yeah, by
number of codes, so yeah, off-chain is
like 20 times.
well more code so even more right so yeah
that's that's an interesting topic i'm
also thinking a lot these days like how to
organize development because we have
done over the last six years like tens of
different frameworks right on different
levels so yeah now it's it's time to
manage all that stuff right so to organize
some map of all those tooling and how to
use it and yeah well
to employ artificial intelligence, LLM
tools, right?
So, yeah, let's continue.
The developers group, are you there?
Tyler, are you in the development chat?
Telegram or Discord?
Development channel in Discord?
Ergo-developers group in Telegram, are
you there?
Yeah.
So, so please ping me and let's continue.
Okay.
So yeah, let's do something in this space
because yeah, well, it's, it's, it's much
needed.
So yeah, if, if you can provide feedback
to other CIT, it would be awesome.
Right.
So we can use this guidance to improve
things.
All the way.
All right, guys.
Well, it's 10 o'clock.
We got, let's end it so we have more to
talk about next week.
We can't blow it all in one shot, boys.
All right.
Then maybe Mark will be back next week,
too.
But one quick announcement before we go.
In two days, Cyberverse is shutting down
for a huge rebuild.
And it's going to take 30 days, it sounds
like, to do the rebuild.
Yeah, 30 days.
So Hero and Pixel are going to be doing a
lot of late nights to revamp a lot of the
game, it looks like, and bring some big
things further.
I don't know if it'll be a re-release or
not, but it'll definitely be a new opening
and new things in 30 days.
So excited to see that.
So play your little hearts out for two
more days.
If you want to get your cyber tokens out
of the game, they say pull it out because
you won't have access to the game to pull
them out of your in-game wallet.
But other than that, it'll be looking
forward to what they're coming up with.
But that being said,
Thanks everybody for joining this first
official community AMA.
It was great, fantastic.
Yeah, it was awesome actually.
It's good to have free participation and
hear different voices and different needs
and different opinions.
Beats making videos in the basement, let
me tell you.
Wait, you're in your basement already,
Joe.
You're still in your basement.
Yeah, so what color is your lightsaber
over there?
This is purple.
Purple.
I don't know what that means, but I was
impressed.
I did the Disney tour thing where they
take you into the dark room and you build
your own lightsaber kind of thing.
It was fun.
It's good to pretend sometimes, you know?
All right, with that, everybody, thanks
so much for joining.
Ciao, everybody.
Alright everyone, bye.
Have a good one.