Hello everyone.
Today I'm excited to present PandaVee, a
project that combines blockchain
technology with modern access control.
Introducing the PandaVee project.
We've built a blockchain-based access
control system powered by the Ergo
blockchain.
Each user's entry rights are verified
using a unique token ID, replacing
traditional cards or passwords with a
secure on-chain identity.
Every access event is immutably recorded
on the blockchain, ensuring full
transparency, traceability, and
tamper-proof security.
Whether it's for office buildings, event
venues, or smart doors, PandaVee offers a
secure, modern, and reliable solution for
access management.
In this video, we'll show you how we use
the Ergonode and ErgoPay to activate our
Arduino-based hardware and unlock the
door, live and on-chain.
Start the Ergonode and PandaVee server.
Release build PandaVee app to Android
mobile phone.
Plug in module and compiling upload
PandaVee sketch.
Arduino version and Wiegand version will
be integrated.
Here is what we're using and we'll take a
minute to build up our Arduino access
control system.
First, power up our system.
Open PandaVee mobile app.
Log in using ErgoPay signing.
Session ID will be recorded in PandaVee
server.
Here is list of NFT tokens from this Ergo
wallet.
Click token to generate QR, binding
session ID with wallet address for this
weekend.
Scan the token QR code.
Server will determine if this QR is
valid, then access granted, gate or door
will open.
Transaction will be pushed and submitted
to Ergo blockchain.
All transaction IDs can be checked at
Ergo Explorer.
More mobile app functions will be made in
the next coming video, next enhancement.
We'll integrate database records and
improve mobile app functions.
Integrate with some more access products
and hardware.
We're still working hard to learn both
hardware and software.
Hope everyone still supports Ergo and us.
Thanks Ergo and all friends that we got a
chance to step into blockchain technology
and wish everyone happy Ergo anniversary.