Happy Ergoversary everybody.
I'm QX and with me we have Dan, the man
from ZenGate, Dan Friedman.
You might recognize him from Dan. I love
the hat. Where'd you get that hat from?
This one weirdo gave it to me at some
event or something like that. I don't
know. You know, it's just, well, what does
it say anyway? What is that?
Make mining great again.
Oh, okay. It's MGA.
All right, Dan, let's, you know, as
somebody who's in the ecosystem as myself,
sometimes I find that I miss out on things
or I'm not completely clear on things. So
I think this is a great opportunity to
talk to you about what the hell ZenGate
is, what the heck Palmyra is, how Ergo
helps those kinds of things be possible.
Let's start at the top. What's ZenGate,
Dan?
Well, ZenGate is actually right behind
me. We're in the ZenGate office right now.
In Japan. Yeah, in Japan. So this is
ZenGate Japan behind me. We have a couple
other ZenGate offices, but this is the
main one.
I mean, just, you know, long story short,
we're a technology company utilizing
various different technologies like Web2
and Web3 to fulfill one of our core
missions, one of them being opportunity
inclusion for MSMEs, micro, small and
mid-sized enterprises, which are
businesses that mostly produce
commodities, although we're not limited to
commodities, but they're kind of like the
bedrock, they're the lifeblood of the
world.
And so I thought that I was going to
build a company, was going to work with
that sector because that's where the most
impact is. And again, another big first
principle of ours is real world impact,
RWI, which is again, what our technology
is here to provide.
Yeah, and so that's translated in a
series of products, which we call the
Palmyra ecosystem and the Web3 part of
that, which is the Palm Economy. And
essentially, it's a platform that again
creates opportunity inclusion for MSMEs.
We largely deal with commodity and
commodity producers in developing
economies.
And we do everything from giving them
more market access through the Palmyra
platform, Palmyra that app, which is
basically a commodities trading and
purchasing platform that utilizes Web2 and
Web3 for traceability, for authentication,
for logistics, to essentially bring, to
cut all the waste, cut all the gray area,
cut all the black box-ness out of the
process and essentially just connect the
producer with the buyer, with the consumer
and to make both happy, to make sure that
the producer gets the most optimal value
for their commodity and so that the buyer
gets the most optimal value for the money
they spend and get what they pay for what
they're buying.
What's blockchain have to do this? Why?
Why blockchain? And you could do this on
some sort of proprietary system.
So basically, I mean, one of the core
components of this is traceability. And we
all know the traceability is something
that blockchain is really, really well
positioned for - immutable traceability.
One of the main issues with commodity
trade is the lack of transparency and the
lack of traceability and essentially
adulteration and counterfeiting.
This happens across the commodity sector
everywhere you go. And I'm not just
talking about commodities that are traded
on commodities exchanges like the golds
and the silvers of the world. But say, for
example, a commodity like honey. This is
one of our pilots right now is with a
Zambian honey firm called Nature's Nectar.
And so what we did was we put several
thousand producers on chain for
traceability and authentication purposes
for the honey because statistically honey
is one of the most adulterated foodstuffs
in the world. It's literally one of the
most adulterated foodstuffs because of the
lack of transparency between what happens
from the producer, the bee hive keeper and
the producer that is say in Zambia, to
when it hits the shelf at your local
wherever you go shopping over there in
upstate New York.
So when you say that you mean that the
honey farmer is going to get a tiny bit of
the pie when it's on the shelf, it's going
to be 10, 20, 30 times more than that guy
sold it to them for.
Well, it's not just that. It's not just
that it's going to be 10, 20, 30 times
more expensive than what they actually
sold it for. It's also not going to be the
same product in many cases. It is going to
be mixed in with syrups, with other
substances. In fact, there was a study
that I bring up quite often that was done
a few years back that says that
potentially almost 80% of all honey in the
West is not real honey. It is honey
flavored syrup or it might have a
percentage of honey in it, but it's
actually not real honey. It's not 100%
pure honey.
And so this is why it is so important to
have traceability, because in the end, the
producer wants to give you honey. They
want you to buy their honey. But what
happens between when the producer sells
and when you get is what needs to be,
that's where the transparency comes in,
and that's where transparency is lacking.
Basically blockchain, one of the things
that blockchain does is it helps create
that transparency. And so what we have is
called a Winter Protocol, which was built
on Ergo and it's a full traceability and
tokenization protocol. And so this
protocol is being used to track and trace
in this case, and it has many different
uses, but in this case it's used to track
and trace the honey literally from the
beehive because the actual beehive is on
chain to when it actually ends up with you
and in fact this honey is going to be
available through another one of our
portals called Palmyra Express really soon
and we're going to have it at Rare Evo
which is coming up in less than two
months, I think.
Is that a site that any normal consumer
could go to and just buy like a
marketplace?
Yeah. So up until now, all of our
products have been and all of our
commodities have been B2B. A lot of our
business has been B2B oriented. There were
minimum quantities that you could purchase
for various reasons, because a lot of
these guys are not retail stores. They're
bulk producers. So, you know, you can't
ask them to send you, like a half a kilo
of tea. You can ask them to send you 100
kilos of tea, 50 kilos, but not a half a
kilo.
However, we got so much, so many requests
from our community members saying that,
hey, guys, I just want to try this stuff.
Can I just buy this stuff? And so what we
actually did was we created an internal
infrastructure where we ourselves purchase
from these producers and then create
limited quantity offerings to the
community through Palmyra Express and
that's expressed with an X.
And so you can get there several places.
I don't even know which domain name we're
going to put out there, but I registered
all the different variations of it. So you
can go to palmyra.express. To get to it,
you can go to palmyra.express with an X
because the actual branding is with X, but
then, you know, some people might get that
wrong and want to just have an express.
You can also go to palmyraexpress.com,
just palmyraexpress, then
palmyraexpress.com. All roads lead to
Palmyra. That's basically what it is.
How does this work from a logistic
standpoint? Do you have like locations in
the United States or that kind of
continents there? Yeah, somewhere in
Europe and you store them there and then
ship from there. You're not like shipping
right from the producer immediately one
off to somebody in the US or one off to
somebody in Europe.
It depends on the actual commodity.
Sometimes it's going to be directly from
the producer, sometimes it's going to be
from us because we're going to set up a
fulfillment operation as well. Now for
these particular offerings that we have,
what we're going to be doing is we're
actually going to be purchasing from our
producers through our U.S. company and
then we'll be able to resell this directly
to the community that is in the U.S. and
Canada.
And so these orders are going to be
fulfilled through the ZenGate U.S. entity.
And so like I said, sometimes it's
directly from the producer, sometimes it's
through us because it takes a really long
time to get it from the producer because
of various different reasons. Like say the
producer might be in a developing economy
that just does not have expedient
logistics. And so, of course, you know,
while, you know, if you want to get this
stuff directly from the producer, you take
it into account. You don't want to have
somebody who's buying, you know, a jar of
honey wait to have to wait a month to get
it.
So, I mean, honey is good forever,
though, you know, in fairness.
Yeah, actually, yes. That's actually
something that many people don't know.
Honey does not have an expiration date. It
is it does not expire unless there is, you
know, other outside things that are
introduced into it that can go bad. But
pure honey itself does not expire.
So I remember as a kid, we had we had a
beehive in my house when I was a kid and
we used to grab the old honey off the
shelf that was all crystallized. And my
mom would just put it in a little double
boiler for like 20, 30 minutes and it'd be
normal honey again.
It's all the same. it's sort of the same
with maple syrup as well you know maple
syrup or literally do put expiration dates
on it it literally just turns to you know
turns to the crystal turns to sugar right
yeah and sugar doesn't have an expiration
date and so yeah to bring it back to life
like i had this you know, big, giant thing
of Canadian maple syrup, I probably had
for the past, like, eight years, you know,
and it's still like half full, because I
don't really use that much corn syrup or
maple syrup. But once in a while, I'll
have some pancakes.
And I'm like, shit, man, I gotta get once
in a while, you'll have some pancakes,
Dan, let's be honest here.
Well, when I'm in the U.S., okay, but I'm
saying I'm not in the U.S., yeah, of
course. When I'm in the U.S., the pancakes
are a regular thing, but that's because I
compensate. I try to increase the pancake
intake, and then some people. Some people,
although I invite them to IHOP, I invite
them to my pancake breakfast, give me shit
about, oh, it's so far away, oh, wait a
second.
I only missed it once, Dan. I've been
every other time, just once.
Yeah, you missed it once, and that's one
time too many QX.
All right, so tell me, give me, give me,
I've never heard a specific rundown
exactly just from what I've read and in my
head of actual traceability of how it
works. Can you take us through a journey
of a baby tea leaf in Sri Lanka and when
it gets, when it gets registered on chain,
what steps along the way it also gets
registered on chain when the initial
registration happens, all that kind of
goodness. Give us, give us that. Let's
name the little tiny tea leaf Earl, we'll
call them Earl as an Earl Grey.
It's a he what if he doesn't identify as
they them, they they they. Thank you.
Thank you. Come on. Come on. 21st century
got to be inclusive.
Okay, so again, it's not. Well, again, I
don't know if I said it this time, but
traceability is not like a one size fits
all solution. So in different cases, you
can have different levels and granularity
of traceability. And in the end, you get
down to like, is it really necessary? I
mean, how deep do you wanna go? Because
you can go really deep with traceability,
but in the end it's like, okay, yeah, but
if you go this deep, I mean, really, what
is the value here? What are the chances if
you go this deep that this particular part
is actually adulterated or screws up? And
sometimes you're like, okay, yeah, there's
a, you know, it's like a 2% chance
something's going to go bad if you don't
have traceability at this point. But you
think about it, well, 98 out of 100 is
still pretty, pretty damn good. So you
have that, you know, you have that
threshold that you come up with.
Now, if you are at they, a tea leaf that
is being traced, again, it could start all
the way from the orchard. And so the way
they do it is they utilize a protocol
through what we call Palmyra Pro. And so
the Palmyra Pro is part of the Palmyra
suite that utilizes traceability and
really is tailored for, it's producer
focused.
So a lot of data gathering and a lot of
data processing happens when it's still in
production, right? So for example, with
tea, it's not just like a robotic process,
right? Sometimes it is, but really with
the finer teas, what you have is a special
formula for when it is picked, which tea
leaves are used for which types of teas,
which grades of teas, how the tea is
dehydrated, how the tea is cured, how the
tea is stored, how the tea is packaged and
processed.
All of these things can create a unique
taste and a unique variant of the tea. And
so one of the main things that, for
example, happens with tea is producers
often have to record the process of how
the tea was cured. And then when the tea
comes out, they taste it and they see,
okay, so this batch came out really well.
What was the process? What was the
humidity? What was the hydration time?
What kind of process we used for
dehydration? Which kind of crop was it?
Where was the crop from? Like all these
different things, they take into account
because all these different things have an
effect on what it tastes like.
And so what you want to have, especially
in premium blends and brands, you want to
have that premium consistency. And so that
is like, for example, for tea, that is
important. That's why traceability is
important for that. And so what they do is
a lot of times they'll just start right
from the orchard. There is, there are
places like say Sri Lanka that have year
round tea harvesting, you know, just it
happens in batches. And that's how they
set up these tea orchards.
And so you can start with actually
registering all the different tea
orchards, site A1, site A2, site A3, in
whatever batches you have, however your
tea bush is organized. And then you can
put in things like, say, for example, pH
and weather patterns that were present
when the tea was growing. Then you put in
information, again, using Palmyra Pro,
when the tea was picked and how it was
picked. Was it machine picked? Was it hand
picked? Which part of the tea leaf was
picked? at what time in the day, at what
elevation.
And again, elevation, they have low, mid,
and high elevation teas, again, that
create different types of crops. And all
of this is gathered through Palmyra Pro.
All this data is gathered through Palmyra
Pro. So what does that do? Number one, and
again, it goes all the way to when the tea
is packaged and shipped off. And it can go
beyond that. You can put in logistics
information. You can put in a warehouse
storage information, say if you want to.
For example, you can use IoT devices. And
again, a lot of this uses IoT devices for
obvious reasons. You can check the
humidity level of the warehouse that it
was being stored in. You can put that on
chain. You can then also do shelf life.
Tea has, I believe, something like a
two-year shelf life. So you have to also
go and put that on chain if you want to.
And so all this information goes on
chain. And again, you decide how granular
you want. You might not want to put all of
it on chain. You might want to put some of
it on chain. Again, it's up to the
producer utilizing Palmyra Pro to gather
the information, to process the
information, to catalog the information
and then to present the information to the
producer themselves for various reasons,
for internal stock keeping, for recording
and processing of different crops and what
comes out.
Regulations and compliance, for example,
they have to go to say the Sri Lankan tea
board and they have to bring records of
how the tea was grown to get a
certification of some sort to exports, you
know, getting export certificates and
where they have to fulfill different
various different in some situations,
like, for example, exporting to the EU and
the US, they have to fill various
different regulation requirements, right,
reporting requirements.
One of them is called EUDR. It's the
European Union Deforestation Regulation.
And it goes into effect, I believe, next
year. And so while tea is not a commodity,
it's on that list, there is a list of
essential commodities that are on that
list. Anyway, there's about, I think,
yeah, but almost a dozen commodities.
And so these commodities starting next
year, they're going to be required to have
mandatory traceability information to be
able to sell in the EU. And if they don't
have this information, they cannot sell in
the EU. And in fact, if they don't have
this information and they bring products
into the EU and try to sell them, they
could actually be permanently banished
from being able to sell in the EU.
And so this is really scary for people
who like, they're gonna like, okay, so how
do we do this? Because there is no, you
know, the EU didn't say, okay, yeah, so
just use this system right here and you're
gonna be able to comply through it. It's
like, no, you have to have traceability
information. It's like, okay, how do we do
that? You figure that out. That's
basically what they did. And so that's
also Palmyra, Palmyra Pro, that's what it
does. And again, under the hood, all this
is run on the Winter Protocol, which is on
Ergo.
So Dan, so I have a friend in the paper
business. And one of the big things that
this big, he works for connecting paper
suppliers, paper mills to the actual
people who, you know, cut and package the
paper after that, they'll sell the huge,
huge like, you know, six foot tall,
massive rolls in the truck to the company
who will then slice them up into paper
sheets or whatever, depending on what they
want kind of thing.
And the thing that his company does is
they have their own traceability protocol
that's proprietary, right? And the
advantage of that is all these companies
that they're with and these mills are
with, all their data is stored in that
proprietary system. If they want to find
somebody else to do their stuff, it's
probably going to be a headache, right?
It's probably going to be a probably going
to rethink that kind of thing.
So do you feel that the trade-offs of
using a blockchain where everything's
open, where another company could come in
and maybe offer more of a service, maybe
offer some different things and just say,
oh yeah, your database about all your
traceability is public right now. We can
just copy exactly what's going on there.
And that's what we do. And you'll just
continue to add to your traceability
history right on that same chain that you
were doing it before. And you're not going
to notice a difference kind of thing.
So do you feel the trade-offs of using
the blockchain where something like Ergo
where what we've had like zero downtime
since launch kind of thing and the
cheapness of creating the traceability on
chain outweighs those benefits of trying
to keep something close to us and trap
that customer in essentially?
Well, the thing about that is I mean,
aside from just information being on
chain, it's all about how it gets there,
right? And so there's a term that is used,
it's called minimum viable ecosystem, MVE.
And so for you to be able to actually
create an optimal or an efficient way of
reporting, you have to have that minimal
viable ecosystem for this to happen. And
that happens when people are trained. That
happens when people are onboarded onto
something like Palmyra Pro. That happens
when there are processes in place that
utilize Palmyra Pro. And so you can't just
switch it out for something else just
because the information is on chain. It's
how it gets on chain is also important.
And so, yeah, of course, I mean, there
could always, I mean, there's always going
to be competition out there. But it's not
just about the pure information that's on
chain. It's about how that information is
gathered. It's about how the minimal
viable ecosystem is deployed. It's about
the onboarding. It's about the integration
into it. A lot of companies will not just
go, oh, that's just cheaper and let's just
do that. They will look at all of this.
Okay, yeah, it might be cheaper, say, per
month to utilize this, but what is it
going to cost us to actually switch over
to this? Or what is that company, for
example, what are they going to do to grow
with us? Because you also have to be able
to grow with these businesses and
understand what they need.
For example, when we integrate and when
we deploy Palmyra Pro with our producers.
We work with the producers. It's not just
like one of those things like, you know,
you sign up and tomorrow you're using it.
Right. Right.
I mean, you could create that type of
version and eventually we will have
something more just a bare bones type of
thing where you just kind of DIY the whole
thing. But to really have that really big
value add that comes from on chain
traceability, you have to work with the
producer, you have to understand the
particular use case. And you have to
understand all the nuances. And so that's
actually where a lot of the work is.
Yeah, it sounds like we have this
discussion, I think a couple of weeks ago
on the AMA about, you know, with open
source software, it's not necessarily the
tech part of the project that you're
selling to the customer, you're selling
your service and something better than
somebody else can provide at the time kind
of thing.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, essentially it's,
it's that, you know, it's not just about
the pure functionality. It's about the
experience that is around the UX, that's,
that's surrounded. And a lot of times, the
UX just cannot be copy pasted. You know,
it's, it's, you can't, you can copy and
paste an ecosystem. Yeah. That has to be
built. That has to be organic or else it's
not going to work.
Yeah. So besides the cheapest, I
remember, I remember affordability. I
remember MGPi speaking about when he was
working on something where he was doing
something for Ethereum and then for
Cardano and then for Ergo. And he said
something that I always remember. He said
something like, yep, in Ergo, I did it in
a week in Cardano. It took like four
weeks. And on Ethereum, it took, you know,
like a month or two months kind of thing.
And just speaks to the like, turn around
the amount of quick time you can really
get these kind of things set up and going
on Ergo.
Yeah. And again, this is one of the main
reasons why I started building this thing
on Ergo is because it was just all really
straightforward. You know, you just go
there, you figure out. I mean, it's
it's...
You even started it. I remember you
starting to yourself that I remember you
sitting down. Yeah, I did. I did. You were
punching it out there for a couple of
weeks getting at the base started there.
Yeah, I did. I did. I started it because
because it's been some years when I, you
know, since I actually set down to code
and I found out that some of the
development environments I was using are
no longer used. And so I had to kind of
like, you know, I do a refresher and I'm
like, why the hell isn't this working?
Like Alex is, oh yeah, they don't really
use that development environment. Okay,
well, I guess, you know, 2015 called.
But, you know, eventually, I mean, and
again, with the help of the community and
who I ended up actually hiring later on,
like for example, Luca was really helpful,
you know, from the start, explaining just
how to utilize all the different tools on
Ergo. And so eventually I just said, Hey,
why don't we just have Luca work with us?
And so that's how that happened. You know,
and, you know, the same thing happened. We
should share same thing happened with,
with several people that are, that are
working at ZenGate. These people came from
the community, you know, and that's
because these people were, were so helpful
in the beginning that I thought that,
yeah, I just want to keep working with
them.
Yeah. Well, that's awesome, Dan. So I
think ZenGate and other things in Ergo are
really doing what is going to make or
break blockchains, right? You know, I feel
like blockchain at this point in time,
cryptocurrency is on the teeter of have
VCs pumped and pulled and sucked enough
value out of these chains to where we're
finally hitting a point where people, as
kushti's preaching, people are sick of
these VC dumps, and they're looking for
something that actually provides value and
that can bring something to, like you say,
you say RWIs, right? You say real, what
was your term?
Real world impact, that's right.
Yeah, you got it. They have real world,
but I really feel like ZenGate
accomplishes that.
You know, I mean, a lot of this stuff is
noise. A lot of this stuff is noise. You
really get into it and you just realize
that there's so much noise out there in
the crypto space that you really have to
understand what really matters. And what
really matters in the end is when you
build things like this, that's why we're
in this. That's why we're building this is
because that's what makes sense. That's
what makes sense in the long term.
And really those of us that got into this
movement because we saw the big picture.
Sometimes we'll get distracted, you know,
and we'll think, oh, you know, it's over,
it's over because of all this, you know,
useless bullshit that's out there. And
then again, you get back to it's like,
well, no, but the core mission, the core
technology is still there. It's waiting to
be used just because it's being used in an
idiotic way doesn't mean that it
invalidates its core mission, purpose, and
possibilities.
I agree, Dan. Well, anything you want to
say to Ergo or to ZenGate or to the
community before we close up here?
Well, look, I'd like to wish everybody a
happy Ergoversary. Six years old, I think,
right?
2019? Something like that. Six years old,
yeah.
Six years old. I'm going to be ready for
first grade soon. It's been an honor and a
privilege to be part of the community, to
be able to build a business on Ergo, to be
able to build on Ergo. I mean, I just hope
more people out there in the community
take that extra step and really start
building a business because I think that's
really what this needs.
I always say that Ergo is the US Steel of
blockchains. You might not know it by
name, but a bunch of stuff that you use is
built with it. So I think that that's a
damn fine place to be in. I think that's
essentially that puts it as one of the
core building blocks of the entire
blockchain movement. And like I said, I
still strongly believe that and I hope
that others will join me and they believe
it so much that they will spend their
time, their money and their energy in
building a business on Ergo.
Amazing well said Dan can't top that.
Thanks so much for joining us and happy
birthday Ergo Thank you very much.
Yep. Happy birthday Ergo.