Good morning, kushti.
Hello. How's it going?
Good, good. Good morning. Yeah, you have
a good morning.
Yeah. I cashed out everything. I'm
totally out of the game and I bought a
private yacht. I'm out here on the ocean.
Just kidding.
Yeah, good morning. I'm with my family on
a vacation for the week at a beautiful
lake. I'm up before everybody else up on
the roof of one of the houses and just
joining the AMA to talk about Ergo today,
kushti, how about you?
Yeah, so hot here and yeah well doing a
bit slowly due to weather and the location
so I'm back from Dubai. So in Dubai it was
especially hard to work.
It's gotta seem cold where you are now
compared to Dubai.
Yeah, indeed. Probably like most places
of the planet, right? It's quite cold in
comparison. But anyway, so they're doing a
lot of things. So working for 6.0, working
with Machina in turn, then continuing some
blogs.
While polishing things, improving
consent. And yeah, well, I think we can do
public testnet mining sub-blocks
supporting nodes in July. Then writing a
white paper for first merge mined
sidechain. So something like that.
When is voting done, kushti?
So it seems there is 90 plus percent
support. So then we will see 6.0
activation around October. And yeah, we
can think about sub-blocks after. So yeah
well let's try public testnet first and
then consider mainnet activation time
frame.
That'll be good. Is there any what's it
called? I remember there was talk about
not a hackathon, but maybe a mini
hackathon where projects that are more
open source could be funded to integrate
sub-blocks into them. Things that maybe
don't have a hosted interface, those kind
of things could be modified to support
sub-blocks.
So that would be something interesting
that could happen in the future for the
community members looking to bolster some
of those projects. I'm sure things like
Mew and Nautilus and those kind of things,
those devs will update it themselves if
they feel free to take part in that kind
of thing.
Yeah, so I think it's mostly about DEXes,
right? And applications like that, which
will be boosted mostly. So I believe that
for auctions, two blocks are okay, right?
Then for bonds and so on. So for loans
even, right?
So when you can provide a loan to some
farmers in Kenya in like two minutes, then
it's already quite... That's not fast
enough, kushti. It's already quite
mind-blowing, right? So you can do that in
like two seconds instead of two minutes.
It's not really changing anything because
anyway, they will cash it out in like two
days after. They need to reach some
peer-to-peer exchange booth. So some
middlemen in the town nearby. So yeah,
something like that.
But for DEXes, right, so for things we
are completely virtual. Yeah, maybe. That
doesn't matter.
And I think if people have... Yeah, so if
people have, I think it should be enabled
by default, actually. In Nautilus, if
people have enable zero config turned on,
it shows transactions before they're
settled in your wallet.
So from a UX standpoint, it brings a
point of more instantaneous transfers when
you're working on the DEXes or when you're
trying to transfer things to somebody. And
with chain TXs, I mean, we're not talking
about finality here, but we're talking
about user experience.
It really feels the same when I'm bombing
through a DEX swap and then I'm sending
that, like when I had to exit through
SimpleSwap or Rosen Bridge to pull some
funds out for funding something for
Sigmanauts.
Just using that, you could just chain
some transactions together. And for the UX
experience with zero config, it felt
instantaneous, right? But overall I had to
wait the blocks to do it in the
background. So yeah, that's interesting.
I wonder if, applied by default, kushti,
if that would have a speed mentality
increase for the users that are new here
in Ergo. Essentially, they might not be
able to understand chain transactions, but
if to them it looks like they do a swap,
oh, their funds are already there, oh, I
could spend those funds somewhere else.
Do they need to dig in to know that chain
transactions, that's how it's working in
the background, or finality, the
difference between the two? I don't know.
Yeah, but I think in 2025, what users are
mostly paying attention to is distribution
of token, right? Because it seems more and
more are centralized trash coins, right?
So it's a little bit different environment
than in 2024.
First, they tried to find some existing
meme coins, but meme coins are also
well-scheming, like all of them.
The thing that gets me is people at
central exchanges that have grown the
culture in the environment right now in
mainstream crypto and then you see them
bitching on chain online but on Twitter or
other places about how you need serious
projects and utility and things like that.
I'm like guys, you spend years just
soaking money out of these rug pulls and
community and now you're like, oh we need
crypto that actually does something. But
also they just talking right. So when you
see what they're doing here, it's somewhat
different also.
Yeah, so for sidechains development,
yeah, well, I will share first updates.
Well, in the coming weeks, probably, we
can start to do such things. So currently,
there is a repository stop, right, and
white paper and progress spots.
Yeah, well, with like a few developers,
we can accelerate things greatly. Then
yeah what else so a lot of things going on
no not just about sub-blocks right and
well I don't know so this is quite
important thing right but yeah, well, in
2025, it seems that there are a lot of
important things.
Well, people do pay attention to things
like distribution and so on.
So I think that stuff is somewhat picking
up. Yeah, it's slow. Not as fast as you'd
like right, but I don't know. I think
people are ignorant to on purpose, right?
They'll claim for that. They'll claim to
start looking into fair distribution,
miner rights, those kind of things and
then at the same time.
It's like the distracted girlfriend meme
where you're walking along with fair
distribution and open source and peer to
peer and then four coin walks by and jerk
your head to take a peek kind of thing.
So I feel that stuff's always tempting
with the majority of the ecosystem,
unfortunately. But I mean, the trick is to
be steady, be strong and continue to build
like we're doing and exhibiting the proper
principles that matter all along.
Oh, another news, kushti. Drama. We need
to have our feature drama today. So our
drama of the week is, if you guys
remember, I told Joe to go break something
last week. Well, he broke his own Twitter
account. He got banned somehow. So Joe is
officially banned off Twitter again. He's
going to have to make a new account and
get it back. We'll see how long that takes
him.
But wait, so it's Joe's personal account,
which is bad.
Joe's personal account. We don't dare
give him the main account anymore, kushti.
It's too dangerous. So he's trying to get
that back. We'll see how long that takes.
But yeah, maybe they'll let him broadcast
out of Rosen Bridge for now. We'll see.
Alright, what else is new, kushti? Any
news on Ergo Raffle 2.0? Is that still
kicking around at some point for a
release?
Oh, Raffle? I don't know. I need to check
with the guys. Not recently. Let me check.
So yeah, we now have a DAO, right? DAO
breach. So we do. Bring DAO if you have.
So we need now for LPs, right? And we'll
start to do things.
Yep. So Joe's team is working on
Hummingbot, which hopefully should help
with a lot of community run LP. So I feel
that's going to be a really nice change as
opposed to large finances popping an LP
that can pop and remove them just as easy
as they put them there.
It's going to be nice to see bridge
liquidity spread across ecosystems with
community-run liquidity. I think that's
the best option, spread it out. Not only
spread out the liquidity to different
bridges, but you're also spreading it out.
So if I put in $500 into liquidity across
with Hummingbot, and kushti puts in
$1,000, and it just repeats that way for
5,000 users, I feel that's a better
liquidity spread than a few large heavy
hitters pumping in liquidity or even the
project itself pumping in liquidity.
It's got more lasting power. It's less
big waves, more stability. So I'm really,
really looking forward to that, kushti,
getting that hummingbot up for Rosen.
All right. And then there are some
initiatives, right, from Rosen to Watson.
Can you provide details?
We've got to mention that again. Yeah,
guys. Guys, so there are five initiatives
up now in the discussion form of Paideia.
And Rosen team has invited you. The Rosen
guards have invited you to take part in
that discussion, whether it be on the
Paideia platform.
We've made it a discussion, so anybody
can comment on the Paideia discussions
without being a member. You just need a
wallet, that's it. And then Glasgow's made
an article on the Ergo platform website
explaining brief summaries over the
positions that those five are taking and
encourage discussion as well on there on
the socials, telegram, discord, and
Paideia as well from the website.
So please guys, please, this is Ergo
where we try to be as active as we can
instead of being a passive. If you're an
investor, instead of being passive
investors, be active investors.
Take your Sunday morning coffee and read
one of those proposals per day and put a
comment. Even if you like, that looks
great, Joe's a genius, I love what Joe's
saying here, I don't disagree with
anything. Just put a little thumbs up in
the discussion there, just so we see that
engagement and we get those reality checks
and those sanity checks.
So engage, even if it's positive. And of
course, engage if it's negative too. If
there's something that you're like, this
is not going to work because of this, or I
think there's a better way than engage.
Let's be a chain full of engagers, guys.
Let's do that, please.
So those are from Paideia. If you can't
find them, go to the Ergo Platform website
or check out a couple posts before on the
Twitter page, on our Twitter account, the
Ergo Platform Twitter account. We've got
them all listed there with links to all
the proposals.
So that's, for those not aware of what
those are, there's several different
options across the five of them. One of
them is specifically what a lot of you are
interested in, and that is getting
Rosen-ERG in the hands of many, many
people on the Cardano chains via airdrops,
via pickups, those kind of things.
And the idea there would be to create a
wallet threshold of holders on Cardano so
that Kraken, with their latest arbitrarily
statement of how many wallets it takes to
get listed, will hopefully meet that goal
and initiate a listing on Kraken with at
least Rosen ERG for starters.
So please read those proposals, comment,
even if that's the only proposal you
comment on, just show some initiative and
engagement and hop in there and do that,
please.
All right. So how things are going with
Sigmanauts and just so, well, InfraDAO
proposal. So we will check after the.
Yeah, I just pushed out a little update
of some more details about the InfraDAO.
We've got enough people for the initial
machine handout. We've got four or five
people interested. So for those people,
I'm hard baking a machine, cloning it from
the three machines that are running right
now in the InfraDAO, and we'll ship them
out.
They'll hook them up. We'll point the
load balancers to them based on their
internet connection bandwidth, what
percentage we'll point to them. Once those
are running and everything's working well,
then we will start opening up to other
people.
We'll say, hey, if you have this much
bandwidth, if you have this kind of
machine and this much RAM and this much
storage, and you have an external facing
IP, you can open up ports, you can run a
little command line and configs and those
kind of things, then please join the DAO.
And then we'll eventually, hopefully,
have the full circumference of the globe
mapped out with ergo nodes so that if
you're in Africa and you're trying to
submit a transaction or go through the
Explorer. You're actually hitting an
Explorer that's on your continent or that
kind of thing.
So that's the end goal there as well as
of course taking the responsibility away
from the EF so they don't have to keep
bleeding money into unofficially hosted
ergo-infra-DAO. But excited about that.
That's gonna be great. We'll make nodes
great again, kushti.
So they also published some new ideas on
the forum such as global transfer policies
for a sidechain which is kind of a solar
punk on steroids kind of idea probably but
yeah I still need to explain this.
Then yeah so for sub-blocks I think,
well, there is need to explain how it is
designed and done for more, right? So we
will do it in coming weeks, maybe with
some videos. Let's see. We'll try to find
time for that.
How's, kushti, how's any progress on
ChainCash? How's that going? Is that the
back burner for now?
So there is some contributor which is
operating the chat just today so that I'm
going to review some pull requests but
yeah in general so well currently the
biggest obstacle is to consider some real
world use case right so what could be that
and well do UI's accordingly right.
So well it's kind of low-level financial
like primitive from meta-primitive so well
it's kind of assembly language right for
different financial monetary system so we
need to find some concrete instantiations,
right, not just to do some abstract work,
right, to get done, because it's a little
bit weird approach, but they're popular in
crypto probably, right, just to throw
something.
So I think we need to go from the needs
of the real world. Yeah, well, it could be
done differently to change the best
monitoring system from community
currencies rights to some international
trade currencies for corporations even
states rights. Well, we need some
counterparties interested in deploying all
those things.
Then we can do UIs. I think it's more or
less straightforward once a niche is
considered. We can proceed. I think it
would boost the usage of ergo-escalatorial
holes.
Initially, we had DeFi, stablecoin, DEX,
then bridge, cross-chain. Grip, right, of
ERGs to collaterals of different kinds.
Then, now we can do more. So, well, ergo
can go into kind of treasuries, right,
backing collateral, backing instruments
for community trades and international
trade even.
So this would be quite huge, right? In
comparison with DeFi sandbox. I mean,
those four funny games on the blockchain.
I think I'm getting rained on in a sec.
We'll see what happens. Darn it. I have to
go under an umbrella. What happened to,
what's it called? Wasn't there somebody
working on a Hawala system on Ergo? Was it
Jami'i with cups of sugar somewhat?
So, with Jami'i, we just did some
experience. But yeah, I think Jami'i just
sold some honey, right? And that's it. And
he's still selling something and trying to
sell something.
So, what about the reverse of that,
kushti? What about physical to digital
conversions the other way? Not even a real
pawn shop, but what if there was a way to
on ramp with physical goods? Converting
physical goods to digital money.
So like let's say there was a shop
somewhere that just like a pawn shop, but
yeah I guess like a physical pawn shop
that converts your goods to digital.
What's the, so why do you need four
Hawala like tools there?
No, this is a little bit separate from
Hawala tools there. It's kind of the same
idea. So a trusted storefront essentially.
So if there was a storefront set up to
where you knew that if you sent them your
old X-Box, they might give you 70% of the
market value of it or 60% of the market
value of it, but you would definitely get
ERG sent to you as soon as it arrived and
they checked it out kind of thing.
So that would be, I guess a trust of
Hawala would need to be there. But yeah.
There is a GitCircles project from my
friend, which is about creating community
currencies for Git projects. For one
project, you have a dedicated community
currency created for contributions to open
source software. Actually, he has a
specification done and it will be
published in the coming days. He sent me a
specification a few days ago.
It looks good. It will be published in
the coming days. I think there are a lot
of ways to use different techniques for
creating different kinds of monetary
financial tools, fundraising tools. So
that's what we are doing.
I don't know, two years to the moment,
three years, but yeah, well, it's time to
scale up, I guess, right, all those
efforts and to do them in different
environments, so digital, like those Git
project currencies, right, and yeah, also
physical, digital, so yeah, well,
reviving.
Have ideas on digital level and so on.
Getting back to free banking now on
digital rails.
Yeah, I had an interesting conversation
with somebody the other day that was
visiting our place, a friend of a friend
kind of thing. And with the price of
certain coins going pretty high lately,
everybody in your grandmother is like,
should I buy? Should I buy? What should I
buy? That kind of thing.
So I am classically never, ever giving
out advice on whatever to buy. I just
speak about what we do and what others do
and that kind of stuff. And that's about
as much as info as I'll give people.
But it was really interesting trying to
talk to them about the difference between
what Bitcoin is right now and what it was
and what things are like the projects we
work on, kushti, here in Ergo. It's
really, I suggest you guys try it, people
listening, try to have that conversation
with people that don't know much about
crypto.
And it'll be an interesting one for
yourself, that's for sure. They'll ask
why, why are you doing this? What's the
purpose of this? Why can't you just do
this with other tools out there on the web
and that kind of stuff.
It really makes, it really hones your
ability to understand why it's important
to do it transparently on chain
permissionless and those kinds of things.
And if you do it right, you can somewhat
convince the other people that it makes
sense. So it's a very interesting
conversation.
Yeah. So I think with global transfer
policies, it could be made quite clear,
right? So well, the idea is that then
everyone can run on CBDC basically, right?
So well, fully controlled monitoring
circuit, right?
And then the question, the only question
here remains if this kind of tooling per
se is permissionless, right? Because if
not, if consensus is permissioned, right?
To some degree, maybe to any degree even.
So then you are ending up with some kind
of dystopia, right? It's like CBDC is not
for everyone, right? Only for central
banks and their friends. So for some
foundation, right? Shady foundation,
controlling some digital private currency
basically with tooling on top of it.
But yeah so if it's about permissionless
environment right and then it's not so big
deal right it's not so disturbing I guess
if like everyone can do on monetary
circuits right if you even if they are
closed or well like have some kind of
control even full control of all the
operations right so still well if it's a
tooling available to like everyone then
what's the issue so then it's done.
Okay. And that's basically what do you
have in all the cryptocurrency, right? But
now it's made to extreme just, right? So
we already have stable coins with black
lists, right? So we have certain
cryptocurrencies even applying blacklists,
right, on the consensus level.
So then there is need to define, right,
when it's not going to be harmful to
everyone, right. And I think it's about
that. It could be about that after all. So
you need for permissionless consensus,
right?
Right. And I think in this conversation,
I had the kind of sticking point, not
sticking point, but the thing that was
really attractive to this person was the
fact that you go to a bank and you say,
look, I'm renting for $2,000 a month this
apartment.
I'd like to buy a house and my payment is
$1,700 a month with this loan in your
interest. And the bank's like, nah, I'm
sorry. No thanks. Kind of thing. And
you're like, look, I have the collateral
lives and I have the income level here to
pay $2,000 a month just fine. Why aren't
you letting me buy a house for $1,700 a
month lending me?
So I think what attracted about this in
this conversation to this guy about Ergo,
at least, is that crypto in general, is
that those kind of things are contract
based permissionless, right? I said you
can go to SigmaFi. Let's say ERG is
dipping and you want to take out a loan of
SigmaUSD so you can reinvest or whatnot?
And I said you just go to a website I
said you put up your collateral choose
your own interest and make it juicy enough
for somebody to jump into and you click a
button I said the contract collects your
funds and post it up there for somebody to
see and then even on top of that the
attractive thing was like you know what
happens if like my freaking bank just went
through a name change right like what a
pain in the ass the apps change everything
changes it's just a bunch of bullcrap.
I said, with this kind of stuff on chain
and permissionless, it doesn't matter. I
said, you could either pay a couple
hundred bucks to a dev to spin one up from
the GitHub or have ChatGPT help you out,
spin it up on your own machine to spin up
the front end interface.
Go ahead and liquidate the loan kind of
thing or repay your loan based on that.
The idea that finance is unstoppable,
private, but also transparent and in your
own control, I think is something that
hopefully more and more people wake up to
every day.
Yeah, yeah. And so you can do also your
own currency, like QXUSD, right, with your
own rules. Well, your community may have
very different rules, which could be OK
for your community, for example, maybe
restrictive for others. But why should you
care, right, if it's just, well.
Right, I could see bad things happening
too, kushti, though. I could see
corporations inventing their own, or
minting their own stable coin, paying
their employees in their own stable coin,
and not letting, and nobody else really
accepting it on a further basis, so that
you have to kind of buy things at your own
place.
That happened in the US. They call them,
what was it, wooden nickels back in the
day, right? Or something town, what was it
called? That miner town where they paid
them in their own currency and then you
could only spend that currency on rent and
at the general store in the miners town so
you basically had nothing at the end of it
you were enslaved.
Right so yeah I mean that's quite a
common story happened around the world.
Yeah, so around late 19th century. Yeah,
it was quite common I believe around the
globe right to have this kind of factory
currency. So you're selling it and then
buy only in factory store. But Rosen
Bridge to the rescue right let's bring him
on to another chain pull that liquidity
off and.
But yeah, I mean, evil is going to exist
either way. What have we got for
questions?
I mean, at least you have here freedom to
switch right to another currency just in a
matter of seconds. I mean to work for
another currency at least, right? You
spare time and then to switch completely.
Right, and it's not difficult for other
entities to accept that kind of digital
currency as compared to in the past where
it was a wooden nickel or something like
that.
Yes, so I think in comparison with late
19th century here, environment here is
quite different.
I could see Amazon blacklisting the hell
out of there.
Right, right. But then you can blacklist
Amazon dollars, right, also in your
financial circuit. So it could be, then
very fragmented. But also, also, you are
not so controlled. I mean, not so
everything can be controlled at least,
right?
Unlike ubiquitous financial systems,
especially digital ones. Yeah, let's see.
But hopefully, it would be better when you
can have freedom to make your own
contractual, for financial contracts,
contractual monetary circuit, stuff like
that.
I think it's brilliant for companies to
come out with their own stable issued
coins, right?
That's what they're already doing, right?
No, no, I think it's great. I think if
they want to give the community, not the
community, if they want to give investors
an opportunity to hold something stable
that is a belief in that company's ability
to maintain a stable, then by all means,
go for it. That's great. You know might
get some competition to well, I mean
everything's pegged to the damn dollar,
but be nice.
kushti, we got a question for you ready.
All right. It's from Alex T. Co-mining
with Bitcoin. Can you speak to this a bit?
They feel huge potential to integrate with
existing BTC farms and act as a co-mine
smart layer. I know you and Joe are
talking about this quite a bit. Can you go
into detail at all on how that would work?
What's kind of mining with Bitcoin?
Sorry.
So essentially co-mining an ergo
sidechain with Bitcoin on ASIC miners, I
guess, would be the question.
But yeah, so currently the idea is to
have double merge mined sidechain rights
with design like Ergo, right? So inputted
and ordering blocks, like after
sub-blocks. But ordering blocks are
committed on Bitcoin blockchain, right?
And they're also committing to additional
data structures for Bitcoin blockchain,
such as digest of Bitcoin UTXO set,
including OP_RETURN outputs and also we
can add NIPoPoWs of their right for
Bitcoin blockchain.
So then with that data committed by a
subset of Bitcoin miners, you can have
access in different contracts so to
bitcoin you take source right so you can
do rgb like protocols you can have NIPoPoW
clients for bitcoin right and so on then
yeah you also have input blocks which are
committed on ergo blockchain so on ergo
input blocks.
Then yeah like every block in
double-merged mine sidechain is
proof-of-work backed. Also, the state from
both blockchains are brought to that
sidechain to be used in DeFi, so it's
about trustless back with Ergo. As shown
in ErgoHack 7 submission.
Then it could be trustless pack with
Bitcoin using Bitcoin bridge. How do they
call it? Bridgeless, something like that.
So B2M2 based. It seems B2M3 is broken at
the moment. But for B2M2 there are already
a few competing implementations.
And then so then you may have trustless
transfers with two blockchains, right?
Well, a possibility to use all the ergo,
almost all the ergo DeFi tooling right on
this side chain and so on. So would be a
good solution for Bitcoin DeFi, I believe.
Very cool. Yeah, I won't say it. No, I'll
move on. I won't say it. We'll keep going.
Let's see what else we have. Is it raining
on your site? No, it's not raining yet.
It's a big everybody. It's a very pretty
lake that I'm at, but it's going to rain
in like 10 minutes.
No, it's going to rain at 11. I think I
have another hour before it rains because
she should be safe. All right. All right,
let's see Oh, Richie's getting more
specific is there a double merge mining
are there double merge mining coins in
existence? How can you solve a block for
Autolykos and SHA-256 with a single hash
calculation.
Oh. But so well Bitcoin miners are
working on Bitcoin mining along with
Bitcoin merged, let's say, blocks, while
ergo miners are working on ergo mining
along with ergo merged blocks on that
sidechain. So they just need to read data
from other blocks to refer to them.
About other implementations, I'm not
actually quite sure. Need to check. Yeah,
maybe not even, so it would be the first
one.
We've got a question from Hermes, and
that is, can you explain Lithos like I'm a
dummy? ELI-5, Lithos, kushti.
So, Lithos is decentralized mining
protocol. So it's kind of a decentralized
pool, which is backed by contracts on ergo
or blockchain. But also that's done
efficiently, right? So well, in a rollup
like way.
So well, look at these things. Look at
those old boats. Aren't those beautiful?
Where's my finger? Yeah. There we go.
There we go. There's a whole house of
them. Yeah, these old like boats from the
turn of the century, kind of these woodies
they call them.
Yeah, so essentially it's finding a way
to instead of current mining is done by
reporting to a local server on a pool and
solve that way. But right, Lithos
integrates putting your effort proof on
chain itself by the individual miner.
And also it's efficient, so there were
some attempts to do contract-based
decentralized mining pools for Ethereum,
but it was just some theoretical paper.
Done like eight years ago and so for
bitcoin they had a p2p pool but it was
kind of sidechain for bitcoin and it
wasn't big but also wasn't efficient right
for miners to work with dedicated
sidechain for pooled mining just.
So here are also efficient.
We've got, we've got saying how easy will
it be to build with the sigma chain? Will
there be a modular templates? It's a kind
of like pump fun where you can push and
pump out your own side chain.
Right, so yeah, there will be some
library available to easily build merge
mined sidechains. So then it would be the
question also how to make miners, mining
pools to pick them easily, right? Because
you can launch sidechain, but if it's
merged mine, then it should be supported
by mining pools.
Then there is need for some easy tool for
mining puzzles, right? And we will do
that. So it should be like UI, right?
Where they just, pick chains they like and
mine them along with them.
That'd be cool, the era of pump fun
mining, where instead of pumping fun and
hitting a liquidity pool with the tokens
and having people buy them, you're trying
to entice GPU miners to mine your chain.
As you put it, that'd be really damn cool
to see, kushti.
Yeah, the biggest meme coin is mineable,
right? It's actually a merge mined side
chain of Litecoin. Right, so the Dogecoin,
which I'm talking about, is a merge mined
side chain of Litecoin. And it's bigger by
market capitalization than the home chain,
right, the main chain, than the Litecoin
itself.
But it's also helping Litecoin a lot, I
believe, because at least for security
budget, it is helping a lot, right, to
Litecoin. And actually before Dogecoin
there were a few other merge mined
sidechains of meme kind so it was bells
then cats and then Dogecoin after cats but
somehow Dogecoin became popular and bells
and cats not.
But yeah, I believe Bells was the first
meme sidechain. But with programmable
money capabilities, you can do a lot,
actually, also, right? So you can launch
your meme sidechain, but also you have,
some rules of your own, right, for this
sidechain.
But what could that be about, I need to
think. Yeah, could be something funny,
right, if it's meme. Yeah, of course.
All right, let's see. We've got Luke
saying, would it be worthwhile to extend
Nautilus and become multi-chain if it also
has Bitcoin and Cardano natives, then it
may attract new users and make an
interesting interface for Rosen. I had
thought Nautilus's mission was to follow
Rosen, or maybe that was Minotaur, but I
thought it was Nautilus as well.
I'm pretty sure that's what it was.
kushti, is that what you remember as well?
They were going to follow the chains that
Rosen eventually went to?
I'm not sure.
That's what I thought, because that was
his work on MetaMask and integrating into
that and that kind of stuff, from what I
remember.
Minotaur, recently they improved things
like MultiSig and privacy-related things,
so not done.
Multisig on Minotaur is fantastic. I've
said it a long time ago, but I'll keep
saying it. Like the Sigmanaut
transactions, we can bang them out in
like, if everybody's paying attention in
our channel, we can bang them out in 10,
20 minutes. It's super fast, super nice.
Things are saved now so you can go back.
There's still room to mess up, of course,
but once you get the hang of it, it's very
efficient and very nice. So once again,
that's a 2.0 version of Minotaur.
Right but also the improving things
greatly our time so in comparison with
early versions. So much easier now, so try
it. It's actually, well, a great way to do
just simplest DAO, right?
So you can just have multisig wallet and
some forum or chat and that's all ready.
Kind of DAO, right? And I think in many
cases, actually, simplicity, well, it's
bringing some advantages, right? Like
flexibility, for example.
So if you just have some telegram chat
and RTC quality, then it's super simple
and flexible. Then if you need for
something more professional, professional
looking you may try Paideia right but for
starters if you just need to run some DAO
with your friends kind of cooperative then
just multisig and some chat maybe some
forum it's quite good.
Well, speaking of that kind of stuff,
MGPai was telling me something that he did
with his roommates. That was pretty neat.
They all mint their own token, right? So
they all mint, let's say, 500 tokens. The
MGPai token is a Bill token is a John
token.
And then for utilities and things like
that, they send a token to that person
that they need to pay and then at the end
of the semester when everything's purse
are built and every funds come in come out
for scholarships and those kind of things
they look at their wallets and they're
like okay I've got 255 MGPai's in my
wallet. You owe me 255 bucks MGPai and
that kind of thing.
So they settle up after in the cycles
essentially. Instead of like piece by
piece, they settle up at the end in
cycles. So I thought that was a pretty
interesting way to use a blockchain and
use tokens and wallets. So bravo to MGPai
for coming up with that. Pretty cool.
Oh yeah, that's interesting actually.
Yeah, so this kind of LETS right but
exactly. Yeah, but blockchain based and so
your local exchange trading system For
you're not trusting it's not like your
buddies coming to you and saying hey, I
built this app that's gonna track our
finances. You can use it, but you can't
see any of the back end. Just trust me. So
the blockchain really puts an end to that.
That's a great use of it.
Right, but also if you have roommates,
then you can put some SigmaUSD, for
example, right? And come and treasury and
then I have multisig like two out of three
multisig for you.
I grill on the deck.
Yeah, for you or room number 57. That's
quite funny.
All right, let's see. We got one more
question. Here we go. This is from Hermes
again. One additional question from him.
I'm an embedded software engineer, but I
want to get into blockchain development.
What's the best place to start learning
how to develop on Ergo platform?
Oh, yeah. So jump on the main chat, maybe
even later today. So I think actually to
discuss some possibilities. So if you are
embedded platform dev, maybe you know Rust
already, right? And then recently,
I found some Rust developers in the main
chat, which are not contributing yet, so
we can discuss doing something like Git
circles, ChainCash, and then this merge
mine sidechains framework would be done in
Rust, right?
Yeah, well, a lot of things
application-wise and then, but Merge Mined
Side Chains even more like core
development, maybe a little bit. But then
you can go to core developments with Rust,
like touching Ergo Rust and so on. We have
some tasks there.
That there is need to improve some
bindings, like Python bindings, for
example, and so on. So you can say hi in
the main Telegram group, which is bridged
with Discord. General channel also. The
main Telegram group is called
ergo-space-platform.
You can find links on the website
ergoplatform.org. Then probably on Twitter
right and so on so say hi then let's
continue the incoming hours then there is
also ergo development group but my thought
was to use general for a chart what's
what's to get feedback on what could be
useful for community as well in the first
place and what could be a focus for
contributors.
Then how all those things could be
accounted for and rewarded, also another
good question. But at some point, we can
start to use Git circles to reward, to
make accounting at least for contributors.
And then for rewarding, well, there are
different options like raffles and so on.
But if it's about Merchant Mined
sidechains, then it's potentially about
creating a lot of tokens also. Some of
them may be successful. Like Dogecoin.
What else? Some Bitcoin sidechains got
quite successful also. In past times and
nowadays also.
So far, so good. It's two minutes past
the hour. The sun's coming out. I've got
my swimsuit on. I jump in.
Yes. So yeah, I see you're looking
outside, right? So you are willing to wrap
up the may probably, right. And enjoy the
summer. So any news in regards with the
meetup?
No, I think we just retweeted it the
other day. We're doing another retweet.
But no new news yet, nope.
All right, all right. So yeah, so far so
good. So let's catch up, guys. Our
Telegram and Discord chat.
We'll see you guys around chats. See you
same time next week.
See you guys.