So, hi guys, I'm Alisson.
I'm here for some years and involved in
some major things on Ergo, like Nautilus
Wallet and Fleet SDK and so on.
And before I start, I would like to say
hi, glad that I am to be between you guys.
So it's really nice to finally meet
everyone of you personally.
So thank you for making it happen.
So let's talk about Machina, right?
So that's right.
So, Machina is a P2P decentralized
exchange on top of Ergo blockchain.
We like to think of it as something like
a UTXO native application because so far
most of applications on the UTXO model try
to somehow emulate how EVM contracts
works, so we are trying to do something
different there, so where each order on
the exchange is individual contract, so
it's I think it's the best approach for
UTXO structure.
So it's P2P because you open orders
directly and somebody buys from you with
no intermediaries or no batching,
third-party batching mechanism, so it's
based on grid orders instead of liquidity
pools.
So it's pretty novel.
We are taking advantage of kushti's idea
on his grid contracts here.
So this contract is basically you set
orders so when somebody buys or sells from
you it creates an inverse orders making a
profit difference between transactions so
it's also self-custodial so you have
control and ownership of your assets from
end to end no intermediaries here so
And as I told, no intermediaries and also
no proxy contracts.
I'm not saying that proxy contracts are
bad.
They are good in some points because, for
example, it's a good strategy to create
some kind of incentive for running
infrastructure.
But it's not so transparent from a user
experience perspective.
Because you are sending assets to a
string, basically.
And you need to hope that assets get back
to you.
So it's kind of not really transparent.
So yeah, we are trying to do this in the
more transparent way.
So for this to work in a more and having
concurrency in mind, we need to do some
changes on Nautilus side, because we need
batching anyway.
So what I'm trying to do is to implement
a batching mechanism directly on Nautilus.
So you agree for certain slippage
tolerance, so it will resign this
transaction as many times as possible so
you are your own batcher so and as and in
the last point as everything on Ergo it's
open source and very favorable and yes as
everything should be right
So we have the structural overview here.
So as you can see, it's a pretty simple
one. But this has a reason to be like this
because we believe in true
decentralization and decentralization
means not only using a blockchain as a
settlement layer, you need to run your own
transactions.
You run batching.
So the entire application logic runs
exclusively on the user browser.
So UI will do most of the job.
So interpreting UTXOs, parsing, batching,
composing transactions, and so on.
And on the other side, we need some kind
of real-time UTXO transaction, UTXO
streaming.
So here's where Hermes comes to play,
which is a tool we are building.
That's a simple one.
It just takes data from an indexed node
and streams it directly for the UI.
So it's not something really complex.
Generic enough for any other application
to make use of it.
So it's not our actual backend because
anybody can run it even locally and have
fun, be your own bank.
So contracts, we have currently two
different trading strategies done, which
is auto-compounding, so when you create
multiple grid orders, everything, let's
say you create an order selling Ergo for
SigmaUSD, so everything you sold, you'll
be used to buy lower.
So you are maximizing profits and
potentially losses.
Alternatively, we have a cumulative
strategy.
Which is we use fixed rates for buy and
sell.
So we buy fixed rates and sell and fixed
rates.
So the profits are accumulated
separately.
So it can be a more conservative
strategy.
It's composable.
All contracts are composable, which means
you can, for example, borrow something on
SigmaFi or do pools and right away do some
trading on Machina in a single
transaction.
And all the protocols can use its
liquidity to make wherever they want
because it's easily composable.
Yet on composition, we have some
characteristics we wanted to have from the
ground up.
It is highly optimized.
We spend a lot of time optimizing code on
a built-in Ergo tree to fit as much orders
in a single transaction as possible.
So our biggest grid contract has around
300 bytes, which allows us to fit around
219 orders in a single transaction.
So it's pretty usable right now.
This is the biggest one.
We have, for example, single buy-and-sell
orders that are like 16 bytes.
It's ridiculous, yeah.
And also no built-in protocol fees.
So it's okay.
Yes, we are assuming here we are using
regular 97 kilobytes transactions, which
is the regular transaction that the nodes
accepts directly by mempool.
But mining pools can do transactions as
big as they want.
So it can be even bigger.
Yeah, this is a concept we are maturing
for years.
So we reached to the decision that
protocol level fees are not good for very
good growth as a whole.
So we just gave up on this and let's make
a public good, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, absolutely, yes.
It's like SigmaUSD, right, yeah.
Okay, thank you.
So, yeah.
Thank you.
So, with no protocol level, any other
application on top of Ergo can use
Machina's liquidity and do wherever they
want.
So, yeah.
So now we talk a little bit about Hermes,
which is a tool that we use to make
real-time price tracking and UTXO
streaming possible.
So it just takes UTXOs from the index and
Ergo node and streams to wherever they
want.
So it's also mempool aware.
So you can chain transactions by default,
because currently it's pretty complex to
keep track of mempool state.
So I wanted to take care of it.
So, yeah.
So I was saying that we can do 290 orders
per transaction at the worst case.
So all these orders are using the biggest
contracts.
And then, as Alisson mentioned, that we
can do chain transactions, right?
So you can submit transactions one after
another without having to wait for
confirmation.
So if we know the block size limit, I'll
check after this, but we can theoretically
do like 290 orders times the amount of
transactions per block.
So if it's like 100 transactions per
block, we can have nearly 30,000 orders
per block.
This is huge compared to what exists
right now on Ethereum or Cardano.
So I think this is pretty impressive,
something to think about, of leveraging
UTXO's capabilities.
Yeah, I don't know too much about sub
blocks, but with sub blocks too, we can
have so much, just really high throughput
potential here, so.
Yeah, I think sub blocks, we have similar
capacity that you'll be just fitted on a
main block.
Yeah, I think liquidity must be
constructed, but I think we have a natural
incentive here because the market can
explore arbitrage between, for example,
Spectrum DEX and Machina.
So I'm not too worried about liquidity
right now because we are just building
things.
But yeah, I think it's eventually...
Sorry, can you repeat?
Yeah, exactly this.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah exactly because you set up grids you
are your own market maker. Yeah, yeah,
absolutely and also controlled risks
because you are controlling your exposure,
so on a certain range, so yeah.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So back to Hermes, it's mempool aware,
which means back in Nautilus team, we have
a philosophy that every product we build
we tried to extract some outcomes of it.
So, for example, when we built Nautilus,
Fleet SDK is an outcome of it.
It's a positive side effect because we
needed a powerful transaction builder
tool.
So I needed to do this from the ground
up.
So I did it as a library so anyone can
use it.
So this is the same for Hermes.
Because it's app agnostic, anybody can
make use of it.
And you have real-time UTXO streaming and
mempool aware transactions so yeah and
there's a last point I have to confess
something for you guys
GraphQL was a big, big mistake.
We built that in a try to make Ergo work
properly back in 2021.
But it's not successful, so I took
advantage of that, and as we have at least
a caching layer integrated inside
Nautilus.
But yeah, I have to confess it's not
perfect.
So, Hermes, we will replace GraphQL on
Nautilus, so hopefully we have a way
better user experience there.
So roadmap, two weeks, right?
So we already have contracts done and
under closed review by some community
guys.
And by the end of this year, I want to
have Hermes fully functional.
And Fleet SDK for Q1 of the next year.
Oh, sorry, not Fleet SDK, but Machina
SDK.
Because it's important to have an SDK
because we empower a community to build
stuff even before we have a functional UI.
So they can use it and integrate it in
any way they want.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So they can, for example, build arbitrage
bots and something like that.
They gain some time before release.
And on Q2, our plan is to have our full
end-to-end beta on Mainnet.
Let's hope for it.
So thank you and...
Yeah.
OK.
Yeah, so I did the calculations.
Yeah, perfect.
So I did the calculations, right?
So the maximum block size is 1.27 million
bytes.
So like 1,270 kilobytes is the maximum
block size.
And the maximum transaction size is 96
kilobytes.
So that means you can have about 13 max
size transactions per block.
So if you're doing what, 290 orders,
right?
And that's the max that fills the 96
kilobytes, right?
Yeah, yeah, so we can do about 3750
orders per block.
So that's not as much as I probably
claimed, but that's still a lot compared
to definitely more than anything Cardano
does for sure.
So and again, guys, as Joe mentioned,
this is all open parameters.
So miners can vote for a larger block
size, right?
So when the demand comes, we can all like
vote for much bigger blocks, right?
And we can squeeze in so much more orders
per block.
And yeah, just the throughput will be
really fast.
So this is really impressive.
About 3750 orders per block.
Holy shit.
Sorry.
Yes, that's in the worst case.
That's the worst case.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Worst case, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Do we know best case?
How many orders?
Like the smallest orders?
Not many, but I can check right now.
Okay.
Use your ErgoScript CLI tool?
I haven't done it yet, but it's... Yeah,
but I think the baseline, we usually do
like 0.011.
Yeah, so it's pretty much enough for most
of transactions.
Yeah, because for simple P2P
transactions, this baseline is already way
overpaid.
Oh, it will be not backwards compatible
because it needs to use web sockets
because it's real time.
I'm sorry.
Streaming exactly.
Yeah.
Yes, because currently a lot of times do
a real spamming on exploring fractures.
So if real time streaming, we can lower
our maintaining costs while getting real
time.
Anybody else?
That's it.
Thank you.
3,750 transactions per block.
Yeah.
Best case.
Yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, best case is like 16,000
transactions per block.
So pretty much everything.
OK, so I think we are done.