Okay, so I am Cheese Enthusiast and I've
been working on Lithos, the future of
proof of work mining.
So let's talk about the goal of Lithos.
The Lithos team has a vision of bringing
transparency and decentralization to proof
of work mining.
Specifically, this is related to mining
pools.
Now, mining pools have existed for a
while.
They are just a way for miners to
essentially come together, take all of
their hashrate, and produce blocks in a
way that allows them to get consistent
payments.
Mining pools are currently quite
centralized, but there have been attempts
to decentralize pools in the past.
One attempt that I worked on previously
was smart pools on Ergo, if you remember
getblock.io.
We worked on a way to essentially make
the payments of mining pools completely
transparent.
Now, smart pools was a novel technology
at the time, but we found that there were
still many centralized aspects to mining
that could not really be solved using the
sort of setup that smart pools had.
For example, the pool operator inside the
SmartPool system had full control of the
backend.
They could change whatever they wanted in
terms of what a miner worked on, like
their shares, or how much they got paid.
They also had complete control over the
block production.
For example, the transactions that go
into the block, any storage rent that was
claimed from the block, etc.
So the goal of Lithos is really to try
and decentralize all aspects of the mining
pool and make sure that miners can mine to
pools in a way that still allows them to
get their consistent payments.
But at the same time, do it in a
decentralized manner.
So let's talk about centralization in
proof of work mining.
So mining pools in general, obviously
they have some benefits in terms of
allowing more miners to enter the mining
space with less hashrate and then
therefore get more consistent payouts.
But proof of work mining pools haven't
really been perfectly decentralized and
they have a lot of issues associated with
them.
So it started as a decentralized process
where individual miners competed to solve
these complex mathematical problems.
It's turned into a centralized system
where the largest mining pools have
significant control over the network and
can potentially manipulate it for their
own benefit.
For example, while it may not necessarily
be likely, mining pools could perform 51%
attacks on the blockchain.
They could also act in bad ways to get
rewards for miners that they deserved.
Or they could even change what
transactions go into the blocks that are
being mined.
That way they can censor certain
transactions.
You may have heard about this happening
on Ethereum, for example, where certain
mining pools ended up censoring
transactions to tornado cash, which was
seen as sort of a bad thing because it's
about mixing the cryptocurrency and
preventing people from figuring out where
the cryptocurrency came from.
So in general, mining pools have a lot of
power and they're able to do all these
things like censorship, potentially steal
rewards, etc.
So the concentration of power in the
hands of a few large mining pools is a
serious problem.
And it kind of goes against the vision
that Satoshi Nakamoto had when he
originally came up with the idea of proof
of work and its application in
blockchains.
So proof of work today is still very
important.
It's still widely used as a consensus
algorithm in the cryptocurrency industry.
But with the introduction of mining
pools, it has fundamentally changed.
It is much more about the mining pools
and the power that they have rather than
the individual miner and what they're able
to provide.
And this has introduced significant risks
to the security decentralization of
various networks.
I'd say the main issue is really that
mining pools have complete control of
payments and block production.
So payments obviously is about how miners
get paid for the work that they produced
while they were mining a block.
Mining pools have complete control over
this in that they can essentially go into
their database, see whatever shares that a
miner produced, and they can change it on
the fly to whatever they want.
So if let's say a mining pool has some
sort of personal vendetta against a miner,
they could theoretically give that person
less rewards.
Additionally, mining pools have complete
control over block production.
Block production is really important in
my opinion because it is essentially the
way for miners to insert their own
transactions or allow whatever
transactions they want while they're
mining to the chain.
Mining pools have complete control over
what goes into the block and what kind of
transactions are allowed.
As I referenced earlier, there was a
whole tornado cash scandal on Ethereum
where certain blocks were censored when
they contained transactions from this
tornado cash app.
And this kind of really goes against the
whole idea of decentralization in the
first place.
We want people to be able to essentially
submit whatever transactions they want,
have them picked up and then put on the
blockchain.
Censorship from mining pools goes against
this completely.
So the goal of Lithos is really to handle
these two problems.
Make sure payments are completely
decentralized and make sure block
production is in the hands of the miners
themselves.
So what are we solving?
So the first problem are mining pools are
black boxes that are lacking transparency.
They hurt decentralization in this way,
and they have some history of being bad
actors within proof of work
cryptocurrencies.
So to fully solve this problem, we have
to fully decentralize mining pools and
place them onto the blockchain using smart
contracts.
So by doing this, we ensure transparency,
we ensure fair payouts, and we really
empower the miners to do more versus the
pool operators who may not necessarily
have the best interests of the blockchain
in mind.
You also ensure like a more efficient
flow of capital from the coin emission
directly to miners without presence of
middlemen who can manipulate the fees
without any rules.
Now, our second problem is that mining
pools require trustless and fair
distribution.
And normal mining pools rewards are
distributed to miners by keeping track of
partial block solutions, also known as
shares.
Mining pools keep track of millions of
They have databases usually that
essentially keep track of each miner's
shares and how many shares they submitted
during the mining process.
When a block is found, mining pools look
through the database and decide how much
work the miner produced for the mining
pool in order to determine how much they
got paid.
Now, we want to decentralize mining
pools, but on the blockchain, we do not
have the storage capacity to store
millions of shares.
It's just not viable.
It would cost too much.
So in order to solve that, Lithos came up
with this idea of the non-interactive
share proof.
So non-interactive share proofs are
essentially a way to compress the amount
of work that a miner produced into a small
handful of shares, and then that handful
of shares can be verified on the
blockchain using various smart contracts
to determine how much work a miner
produced over a certain period of time.
Non-interactive shared proofs, or NISPs,
are used throughout Lithos.
And they're used to ensure that miners
are paid fairly according to the amount of
work that they produced while a block
solution was being found.
NISPs are computationally very simple to
evaluate and determine whether or not a
miner is lying about how much work they
produced.
Additionally, storage wise, they do not
require a lot of space on the blockchain.
And in a place where space is very
limited, NISPs are able to compress the
amount of data and make sure that costs
associated with the mining pool itself are
not too high.
NISPs themselves are essentially a
collection of around 10 shares with high
difficulty that are used to determine how
much work a miner produced.
They do this through concepts borrowed
from NIPoPoWs, actually.
Specifically the concept of goodness and
the idea that when a person is mining over
a large period of time, it is almost
certain that they will produce a number of
large high difficulty shares throughout
that mining process.
NISPs use this idea to essentially prove
that a miner performed work by checking
whether or not they produce those high
difficulty shares.
Now, in order to store NISPs on the
blockchain, they are very small, but
still, we want to be, when we're dealing
with smart contracts, we want to be as
efficient as possible, space and
computation-wise.
So the current idea of Lithos is to use
an optimistic rollup to evaluate each NISP
and ensure that while computation isn't
too high, we can still ensure that people
are being provably fair and are being paid
according to the actual amount of work
that they're producing.
Sorry.
So decentralizing mining pools requires
ensuring that there is some amount of
censorship resistance.
Now, on Ergo specifically, the Coinbase
transaction has been made so that it must
go to the public key address of whichever
miner mined the block.
So in order for censorship resistance to
really be possible on the Ergo blockchain,
we need to do what's called
collateralizing the Ergo.
And what I really mean by that is to
provide an amount of Ergo equal to the
block reward before the block is mined.
Now, when the block is mined, that Ergo
amount given by the lender is distributed
to the miners as the block reward, while
the actual block reward, which goes to a
certain public key address, is given to
the lender's address instead.
So in this way, you essentially allow for
miners to create their own block, set the
public key reward address of the block to
the lender, and then allow the actual
payment to instantly go out to all the
miners whenever the block is verified.
So this is important for a few reasons.
For one, it does allow censorship
resistance in the sense that any miner can
mine their own block while still ensuring
that the reward of the block goes to all
other miners in the pool.
It's also very useful in the sense that
when you're normally mining on Ergo, there
is a certain 720 block wait that you must
do before the block is confirmed.
And during that wait, nobody is able to
be paid.
Collateralization essentially cuts
through this process and allows miners to
be paid almost instantaneously whenever
the block is found.
So we want to ensure that we have these
collateralized mining pools because we
want to ensure censorship resistance.
We want to avoid these problems like I
called back to before, like with the
tornado cash issue.
We don't want mining pools to censor
certain transactions.
That is really one of the core goals of
Lithos to ensure that miners have complete
control over the blocks.
And giving control to miners over block
production, that also allows miners to
gain more ERG.
They're able to add storage rent
transactions specifically for ERGO.
And are able to produce ERG through MEV.
And MEV was a big part of the reason why
Ethereum, while it was proof of work, was
able to gain so many miners.
MEV allows miners to gain additional
rewards through smart contract
interactions, DEXes, stablecoin contracts,
etc.
And we want to be able to bring that to
ERGO, but give that power of choosing what
actually goes into the MEV to the actual
miners themselves versus the mining pools.
One important aspect of collateralization
is that we don't want to prevent miners
from immediately joining our decentralized
pool without having ERG.
Now, if we force miners to collateralize
themselves, that means, let's say a new
miner comes into the ERGO ecosystem, they
have zero ERG in their wallet, and they
want to join a Lithos pool.
If they have no ERG in their pocket and
collateralization requires at least an ERG
amount equal to the block reward, then
this kind of clashes with the idea of any
anonymous new miner being able to come
into the system and provide work to the
ERG blockchain and then secure it.
So Lithos specifically has focused on
third-party collateralization.
And that means that people outside of
miners themselves are able to provide ERG
to the mining pool to collateralize the
block.
And that would allow new miners to join
without having any ERG at all and
therefore mine on this decentralized pool
without having to put up some amount of
ERG that they may not already have.
Collateralization also allows people
outside of mining to gain ERG by using
pool fees in a way that is contractually
obligated to not be sort of suspicious.
For example, like a normal centralized
mining pool may be able to adjust their
fees any way they want.
With Lithos mining pools, the fees will
be determined by the smart contracts,
determined by the market of
collateralization itself, by all of these
lenders who want to provide ERG to the
blockchain to help secure it.
This also goes into the Lithos token.
Now, Lithos token tokenomics are not
particularly set yet, but the general idea
is to incentivize miners to mine using
Lithos and allow them to gain additional
rewards despite the pool fee that they pay
to the collateralizers.
So let's go into some of the more
technical aspects of Lithos now.
Lithos protocol is an advanced
decentralized mining pool protocol.
There have been some mining pool
protocols in the past that have been
somewhat decentralized.
A few examples that I can name is P2Pool
on Monero has been running for a while.
And that is essentially a sidechain on
the Monero blockchain that allows miners
to mine to the sidechain and then gain
rewards of Monero.
Now, it is decentralized.
However, it faces a lot of problems in
that block production is still not
entirely on the miner's hands, as well as
rewards are a little bit obfuscated.
It doesn't help that Monero is a
completely private blockchain, but
essentially it's not the most ideal
solution.
Now, we've had smart pools on Ergo as
well.
These were a good idea, I think, but they
didn't fully decentralize the entire
process of mining.
There was also another smart pool
initiative on Ethereum while it was proof
of work.
It was also quite decentralized, however,
it lacked efficiency.
And that's something that is really
important to us at Lithos.
We want Lithos to be scalable.
We want it to be able to potentially
handle hundreds of thousands of miners at
once.
And past solutions to decentralized
mining haven't been able to do that.
So the first technical aspect, and I've
talked about it recently, is
collateralized mining pools.
And we want collateralization to
essentially ensure that block production
is in the hands of miners.
We want miners to gain MEV rewards.
We want miners to be able to have control
over their storage rent.
We want to avoid censorship of any
transactions at all.
And another technical aspect here is the
non-interactive share proof, which is
really, I think the most important part of
Lithos and it completely changes how
mining is done.
Mining, traditionally, on a mining pool,
you get your mining software, you connect
to the stratum, and you produce hundreds
of thousands of shares over a period of
time.
The mining pool takes these shares, they
store in the database, and they determine
how much work you did by looking at the
amount of shares multiplied by the
difficulty that you mined at.
And obviously, this is not good enough
for a smart contract.
It just takes too much space and
computation.
So NISPs are the alternative.
And they ask sort of a different question
of the miner.
Instead of asking how many shares did you
produce over a period of time, we're
asking, can you produce, say, 10 shares at
a high enough difficulty to prove that you
did a certain amount of work while the
block solution was being generated.
And this kind of change of the question
has a big implication in terms of how
mining works on Lithos.
You're not going to be mining in the
traditional way.
Obviously, you'll still have a mining
software, you'll still have a stratum that
you connect to, but the way your rewards
are calculated are completely different.
You are not simply adding up the number
of shares and then dividing it based on
the total number of shares produced by the
pool.
You are essentially proving that you did
a certain amount of work by producing
these high value shares.
And then that allows you to store all
this data in a small space.
NISPs also are very important because
they are computationally efficient and
they're efficient storage-wise.
We can use optimistic roll-ups to allow
for greater scalability with the smart
contracts that we're using.
Now, an optimistic roll-up, you can think
of it as a layer two solution that is
essentially it's taking all these NISPs
and it's assuming that each NISP is going
to be completely successful and valid.
Unless it is checked upon.
Now, in Lithos, we plan to have lots of
off-chain bots that will be checking each
NISP submitted to the blockchain.
And if a NISP is found to be fraudulent,
a fraud-proof transaction is submitted,
and that NISP is removed from the
equation.
This is really important because we're
not evaluating each share proof on its
own.
We're only evaluating share proofs when
we know they're fraudulent.
And what I mean by that is we're not
evaluating share proofs on the blockchain.
Obviously, evaluation is happening
off-chain, but we're really focused on
on-chain evaluation because that is what
is costly.
And fraud proofs allow for us to minimize
the amount of computation on-chain while
allowing the majority of computation to
happen off-chain, where computation is
easy to do and there are way less limits
regarding data and space.
There will be incentive to submit fraud
proofs.
Now, usually with roll-ups, we have what
are called sequencers.
And sequencers can be kind of thought of
as people who are submitting their
roll-ups to smart contracts and then
getting some kind of reward for that.
In Lithos, we want everybody to
potentially be a sequencer.
And a sequencer is kind of equivalent to
a pool operator in that they're the ones
getting the shares and submitting them.
Now, obviously, we want individual miners
to have the power in Lithos.
So anybody can be a sequencer,
potentially.
But in general, there will be some limits
because obviously if we allow anybody to
be a sequencer, then there's a classic
problem with blockchains in that people
can spam the blockchain.
So there will be some limits in regards
to who can be a sequencer, but the general
idea is that the limits will be low and
that people will be able to become a
sequencer with a certain amount of tokens
and then submit these transactions to the
smart contracts themselves.
All right.
So another important aspect of Lithos is
that, oh yeah, yeah, no problem.
Oh, no, absolutely not.
Because the difference is that when I say
a high difficulty share, the difficulty or
the high difficulty is relative to a
difficulty the miner themselves chooses.
So if I have, say, like my laptop right
here and I decide to mine on it, obviously
I can't produce many high difficulty
shares.
I just don't have the computational power
to do that.
But on Lithos, you choose your own
difficulty.
You choose what difficulty you mine at.
And that means that a high value share
for you is different than a high value
share for somebody with 20 GPUs in the
back, for example.
So when I say a high difficulty share,
it's relative to your own computational
power.
And this is important.
And I'll get more into it later about how
your difficulty is chosen and the kind of
effects that has on your payouts, how much
you get paid, and how often you get paid.
Now, for Lithos, the usage of
non-interactive share proofs means that it
is essentially completely blockchain
agnostic.
So non-interactive share proofs are
really only evaluating the difficulty,
which is the value of the share or how
high the actual number is compared to the
target value that the blockchain wants you
to find when you're looking for a block.
Because we're only using math,
essentially, to determine whether or not
you did work, it's completely blockchain
agnostic.
And what that means is that you can use
NISPs on something like Bitcoin, something
like Litecoin, other proof-of-work
currencies, Caspa, Alethium, all of these
currencies which are using traditional
proof-of-work algorithms, you can use
NISPs to evaluate how much work somebody
did.
What that means is that we can have smart
contracts on the Ergo blockchain, which
allow you to mine in a decentralized
manner while still mining to Bitcoin.
So you can mine Bitcoin while mining on a
decentralized pool.
Same with Litecoin, same with Casper.
So ideally, the collateralization in that
case would work using RAP tokens, for
example, from Rosen.
So in that case, you would have RAP
tokens that are paid to the miner on the
Ergo blockchain, while the actual block
reward would have to go to somebody on the
initial blockchain, for example, Bitcoin.
And that lender would have to be somebody
from that blockchain, essentially.
So it would be a little bit more
complicated and it would require some
support from, for example, a bridge like
Rosen to completely successfully do, but
it is completely possible.
Now, I mentioned the Lithos token
earlier.
Now, lenders who provide collateral will
be using the Lithos token to essentially
provide that collateral.
And that would allow miners to...it would
allow a sort of proof of work economy to
occur because miners on Lithos will be
mining, just for example, ERG, and they'll
be also gaining these Lithos tokens at the
same time.
And those Lithos tokens would be used by
lenders to essentially lock in their
collateral for miners to use.
And the idea behind this is to
essentially stimulate a healthy economy
between people who mine and people who
don't.
And it would allow people to essentially
gain money without having any
computational power, which is usually not
possible on a proof-of-work blockchain.
On a proof-of-work blockchain, you can't
secure the blockchain without some
computational power, usually.
But the idea of Lithos is to have people
who are not associated with the mining
world necessarily to still help
decentralize the blockchain itself.
Yeah, exactly.
It is similar to staking, but it's a
little bit different in the sense that
it's not really percentage-based in the
sense that having more tokens will
necessarily get you more.
But it's still a way for people who are
not involved in mining to gain some money
while still securing the blockchain.
I mean, I don't think it should be any
issue between Rosen and Lithos.
What do you mean by dual miners?
Oh, no, no, no.
No, I don't think so.
I mean, the way Lithos is working is just
a normal stratum.
So you can do anything that you do with
your normal mining pools as long as it
works with a stratum.
So I know some people do dual mining, for
example, where they partition part of
their hashrate to, say, Bitcoin and some
of it to Ergo.
You could do the same thing on Lithos
without any real issue.
We're using stratum to allow things to be
compatible in a way that doesn't require
miners to update too much.
You don't have to upgrade anything.
You don't have to change your general
setup.
But you're still able to benefit from the
general idea of Lithos itself and the
decentralization.
So let me explain it.
When somebody mines or somebody is
producing a number of hashes over a period
of time, we can mathematically prove that
somebody producing a certain amount of
hashes over a period of time will almost
certainly produce a certain number of high
difficulty shares while hashing.
So what that means is that while they're
producing all of these random hashes,
there's all random numbers.
So for, let's say that person produces
these hashes over the course of an hour.
They will mathematically produce a
certain number of high number of hashes
that will be present inside their set of
hashes that they produced.
So Lithos is taking advantage of that
fact that they mathematically will produce
those number of hashes to prove that
somebody actually produced or actually did
a certain amount of work.
So if I'm a miner and I want to get paid
on Lithos, but I didn't actually do any
work, right?
I just want to say that I mined for 12
hours straight and I produced all these
hashes, but I actually haven't done the
work myself.
To prove that I did the work, I would
have to have a certain number of
high-value hashes that I could show to a
smart contract to show that I actually did
the work.
But if I'm lying, I wouldn't have those
high-value hashes in the first place.
They wouldn't have existed.
So that's the general idea of a NISP, is
to use the fact that high-value hashes
will be produced over a certain amount of
time, and that they will be produced at a
certain ratio relative to the number of
hashes that I did throughout the period of
time.
If I'm lying, I won't have those
high-value hashes to present to the mining
pool.
And therefore, it'll be quite easy for
somebody to see that I'm being fraudulent.
Yeah, exactly.
And there are obviously other aspects
that must be verified.
For example, I don't want to accept
high-value hashes that were produced like
a year ago.
I need to make sure that the timestamp on
these block headers is valid for the block
that we're mining.
I don't want to have a hash from two
years ago if I'm mining a block from an
hour ago.
So there are other sort of qualifications
that need to be met for a NISP to be
valid.
And these are all checked through these
fraud proofs on the roll-up for the Lithos
protocol.
Does that answer your question?
Exactly, exactly.
That is all decentralized in smart
contracts, yes.
The logic itself is being run off-chain.
We don't want to have that computation of
checking each and every share inside the
NISP.
That would take a lot of time.
We're doing the logic off-chain.
We're checking each NISP off-chain.
And if we find an issue, we're producing
a fraud proof on the blockchain to ensure
that fraudulent NISP is taken off of it.
And there's a certain value of incentive
to do this.
If I'm a miner, I don't want some other
miner to take some portion of my money
because they produced a fraudulent share.
If I'm a miner, I am therefore
incentivized to make sure that each share
on the Lithos protocol is valid and not
fraudulent because I want my block reward
to be maximized.
Remember, block rewards are being
separated between each miner inside the
pool.
So if I remove a miner who was fraudulent
from the share of the reward, then I get
more of a reward proportionally for
myself.
So there's a certain incentive to make
sure that miners are always checking each
and every NISP that is submitted to the
Lithos protocol to make sure that they get
paid maximally according to their work
that they produced.
Makes sense?
All right, cool.
So let's talk about the testnet now.
So after around one and a half years of
work and the release of Ergo 6.0, the
Lithos testnet is nearing launch.
The testnet serves as a way for miners to
try out all the new aspects of Lithos.
And it's also to help me find any bugs
that were produced during this process.
Already found a lot of bugs while
developing it, so I can't imagine how many
bugs will be there.
But really, the goal is to try and iron
out all of these issues before anything
gets released to the mainnet.
So now, tying back to what you and others
were talking about, mining on Lithos is
going to be a little bit different to
traditional mining.
Now, for one, the Lithos client is
providing a local stratum for you to mine
towards.
So what that means is that your stratum
or the pool that you're connecting to is
going to be locally produced.
That means there's never a chance of
stale shares.
I don't know if you've mined before, but
stale shares happens when the latency is
too high and the difficulty that you're
mining at is not equivalent to the
difficulty that the pool wanted you to
mine at.
So when that happens, it's just lost
money, lost work for you, right?
So having a local stratum means that
stale shares are not going to happen.
Additionally, miners on Lithos are
solving a different problem.
And this is going back to NISPs and how
they work.
So let's talk about difficulty now.
So normal mining pools are asking the
miners to send a certain amount of shares
at a set difficulty.
So if I go on, for example, Herominers
today, I'll go on their 4G port, and I'll
be producing shares at the value 4G.
So 4 times 10 to the 9, I think, is the
value that I'm trying to produce shares
at, submitting any share above the value 4
times 10 to the 9.
Right?
Now, this is not viable, as I've said, on
a blockchain.
So Lithos is instead using NISPs.
And NISPs are really asking a different
question.
Can I produce, now for Lithos right now,
we're using a value of 10 shares.
So the question that Lithos is asking is,
can I produce 10 high value shares
relative to the difficulty that I chose.
And if I can produce those 10 shares,
then I did produce a certain amount of
work at that difficulty.
So using this allows us to make things
more efficient, make it more
computationally efficient, more storage
efficient.
And it also changes how you mine.
So as I said before, on Herominers, I'm
mining at a set difficulty of 4G.
Miners with different hash rate than me,
they're probably mining at that same
difficulty.
I could have 100 megahashes, or I could
have, let's say, 10 gigahashes of hash
rate.
And I would still be mining on the 4G
port.
On Lithos, it's completely different.
The difficulty that I'm mining at is
relative to my own hash rate.
So if I'm mining at, say, 100 MHz, I will
be mining at a different difficulty
compared to the person with a mining farm
who's mining at 20 GHz.
And what that means is that between the
two of us, we need to produce different
value shares to prove that we performed
work at our difficulty.
So let's say I'm mining at 1G, for
example.
Maybe I need to produce 10 shares at 5G
to show that I performed work at 1G.
Now, if I have 20 gigahashes of hashrate
power, I might be mining at, say, 20T, I
think is the next one.
I'm not sure.
Let's say I'm mining at 20T, then I need
to produce 10 shares at like 50T.
So the meaning of this really is that the
difficulty that you choose is directly
tied to how much you get paid, because the
difficulty is your way of showing that
you're mining at a certain hash rate.
So this has some effects on how you're
getting paid.
So for example, over...
So yeah, that is important.
So the time scale for Lithos is relative
to the usually some set period of time
before the block was found, because when
the block is found, all shares are
submitted and then they're evaluated.
So we don't want miners to kind of lie
and say, oh, I produced 10 shares like two
weeks ago and a block wasn't found until
now, but my 10 shares are still valuable.
They're not really as valuable generally.
So we want to take shares that were
produced within a certain period of time
before the block was found.
For example, let's say 12 hours before
the block was found.
You need to find 10 high value shares
produced within that 12-hour period and
then submit them when the block was found
to show that you performed work while the
block solution was being generated.
And this essentially prevents people from
lying about what work they performed and
when.
We don't want people to have fake shares
that are coming from the future or shares
that are no longer valuable from the past.
We want the shares to be produced while
the current block is being mined.
Now, because you're able to choose your
own difficulty on Lithos, and you're able
to determine what difficulty you want to
mine at, there can be some, let's say,
funky things that happen if you decide to
stray away from whatever the Lithos client
gives you.
So the Lithos client will look at your
hash rate, and it'll give you sort of a
set difficulty relative to your hash rate
that you can mine at.
Now, you're free to change that
difficulty value to whatever you want.
So let's say I want to be a little bit
risky, right?
I want to maybe gain a little bit more
money.
So what I can do is I can set my
difficulty value higher.
And what that means is that my payments
will not be as consistent.
The reason for that is, at my hash rate,
I will not be able to reliably produce 10
high value shares for that difficulty.
However, because my difficulty is related
to how much I get paid, if I do produce 10
high value shares, I get paid more versus
me mining at my normal difficulty.
Exactly.
You're trading your consistency of your
payments for the potential reward of how
much you get paid.
So that can happen if you increase your
difficulty.
Now, lowering your difficulty, in
general, it doesn't actually have much
value because lowering your difficulty,
you're just lowering your reward.
And if you're already getting paid
consistently enough, then it's not that
useful.
Now, if you're having trouble with
payment consistency for some reason, then
you can lower your difficulty and get paid
consistently more often while sacrificing
some amount of reward for that consistency
in the first place.
This is, I think, is a little bit foreign
to, I guess, most miners, probably.
It's not really the traditional way of
mining.
Usually when you mine, you mine at a set
difficulty.
The number of shares is sort of
proportional to how you get paid.
Here, it's all about the difficulty that
you mine at.
And changing that difficulty will change
how you get paid.
How much you get paid, how often you get
paid.
So you're able to play around with this.
Maybe you're feeling risky one day, want
to increase your difficulty, and you get
your big payout.
Or you increase your difficulty, you
don't get paid for three days, and you go
back down because you feel like you didn't
get anything out of it.
So the Lithos client will be the main way
for miners to interact with the testnet.
I want to put instructions out for the
Lithos client, ideally at the end of the
month.
Still working on currently the HTML UI
for it.
Currently, it's just a terminal UI that
you could type in certain commands into.
But I understand that most miners may not
necessarily want that.
So I'm working on an HTML UI, sort of
akin to how the node works.
If you've ever run your own node, there's
an HTML panel that you can connect to
where you can put in certain commands.
The Lithos client will be pretty similar
to that.
So the current testnet, my goal is to
release the testnet week of November 2nd.
Really, the last thing I'm working on is
these interfaces, the HTML interface, and
some of the off-chain code to tie
everything together.
We have a lot of the contracts done, a
lot of the code related with the contracts
done, as well as a lot of the stratum code
done.
Now, the current stratum that is being
used in Lithos.
It is a completely new Java-based
stratum.
Worst thing I've ever worked on in my
life, by the way.
So hard to do for no reason.
But so right now it's only supporting two
miners, Riggle Miner and NB Miner.
My goal is to start supporting more
miners like Team Red Miner, SRB Miner, et
cetera.
But those will happen probably as the
test net goes along.
With the initial release of the test net,
we're going to be supporting just those
two mining softwares.
But yeah, that's really it.
That's the presentation about Lithos.
You guys have any questions?
Right.
So with this client, the current way I
have it is that there are a few options.
Right now, it just automatically can
build the block for you.
And what that does is it really takes
whatever transactions with the highest
fees are inside the mempool.
It takes those transactions and it puts
those inside of the block.
MEV is obviously possible.
It's not currently supported in the
testnet, but it's definitely very easy, I
think, to implement.
It would probably require using the HTML
UI that I'm creating.
Or there could be certain presets to try
and get more value out of, for example,
Spectrum DEX transactions.
Additionally, storage rent is
automatically claimed by the client.
So any storage rent UTXOs that are
available to claim at the time of the
block will automatically be claimed and
given to the miner of the block.
So in general, that's really how the
transaction selection block production
works.
Right, right.
Currently, it's prioritizing max fees.
So if you're not putting in transactions
with high fees, then get the hell out.
Right.
Exactly, exactly.
And miners can also plug in their own
transactions, not necessarily MEV itself,
but let's say you want to, I don't know,
maybe you want to fund some Ergo raffle
contract or something, right?
But you don't want to wait for the
mempool to go through.
You can put in your own transaction while
you mine your block, and it will be put
inside the block without having to pay any
transaction fee because you're the one who
mined it, right?
So that's also possible as well.
With merge mining, you said?
So merge mining, it should be actually
the same because the way merge mining
usually works is you have your mining
software and it is connecting to various
stratum pools and Lithos protocol itself
has its own stratum connection that you
can connect to.
So if I want to merge mine like Zcash and
Ergo, for example, I can mine to both of
them have the different stratum addresses
inside my mining software config and it'll
work normally.
Essentially, there shouldn't be any big
difference.
That is probably true, but you can adjust
your difficulty to a lower amount so that
you can find high value shares according
to whatever hash rate you're mining at.
So obviously, yeah, when you're merge
mining, you won't have as much
computational power, but you can adjust
that so you still get paid at a consistent
amount and for a fair value according to
the amount of power you're putting in
towards ERG.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
It can accept Babel fees.
OK, I kind of get what you're saying.
I guess for chain agnostic things, there
will have to be at least one transaction
on the opposite chain.
Yeah, yeah.
So I guess that transaction will probably
be required to pay some sort of fee.
And that would be by the lender who's
collateralizing on the other blockchain.
But for example, the actual payments
which are being done on the Ergo
blockchain, that can use Babel fees for
the payouts going to each miner on the
pool.
So the incentive is a pool fee, right?
However, I think the difference is that
at least the current idea for
collateralization is to have it be an open
market.
So because miners in the end are the ones
producing the block at their local
machine, they're able to choose what
public key address the mining reward goes
to.
So what that means is they're able to
choose what lender they want to receive
the reward and therefore the pool fee
itself, right?
So essentially you can think of it as an
open market and whoever's providing the
best fees is, that's who miners are
incentivized to choose for their
collateral.
And that means like, let's say I'm a
lender who is providing 35 ERG as the
block reward, right?
And I'm taking a 2% fee.
The miner could look at all the other
collateral UTXOs out there on the
blockchain, and they can find one that's
maybe for 1%.
They'll use that instead.
So in that way, it ends up being most
likely standardized at a certain level.
And lenders obviously have some incentive
to try and increase the fee.
But at the same time, they're also
requiring the Lithos token, which is
coming from miners.
And in that sense, the idea is to have a
sort of balance and a sort of proof of
work economy that allows lenders to
provide their ERG and gain additional ERG
back, while allowing miners to sell their
Lithos token to these collateral
providers.
So I think that is theoretically
possible.
However, one thing to keep in mind is
that as miners gain more ERG, they can
collateralize the ERG themselves.
So then they don't have to pay a fee for
themselves.
And then at that point, you're almost
always incentivized to use your own
collateral if you have the ERG for it.
So third party collateralization is
mostly for miners who don't have the
actual ERG amount to collateralize
themselves.
And this is for new miners who have never
mined inside the ERGO ecosystem before, et
cetera.
So in that sense, that's what third party
collateralization is used for.
Right, right.
So, for example, if you've ever
solo-mined a block on Ergo, you get the
block and then you have to wait 720 blocks
to have that block confirmed, and then it
goes to this certain address, your mining
reward address is what it's called, and
then you can spend it from your wallet.
When we're collateralizing what the
actual miner of the block is doing,
they're changing the reward address to the
address of the lender.
They're getting that block reward in 720
blocks now.
But the collateral that they provided is
being instantly paid to all the miners.
And the difference is that the collateral
they provided is going to be a slightly
less amount.
And that slightly less amount that's
being missing is the fee that the
collateral provider gets at the end after
720 blocks.
Sorry, can you repeat that?
Right, yeah, that's the current idea
right now.
Right now, that's actually not
implemented in the testnet.
Right now, anybody can provide
collateral.
But the idea is that miners who mine on
the pool will get Lithos tokens.
And then in order to create a collateral
contract that will be used as collateral
for any blocks being found, you will have
to stake some sort of...
You'll have to lock a certain amount of
Lithos tokens inside of that UTXO.
And that sort of ensures that there's
sort of a market for collateralizers to
get Lithos tokens and for miners to sell
those Lithos tokens to those
collateralizers.
So collateralizers, they get the Lithos
tokens, they get gain on their ERG, and
then miners, they're selling those Lithos
tokens to those collateralizers.
I'm not gonna lie, I haven't determined
the exact amounts yet.
I'm still thinking about the tokenomics
of the Lithos token.
It hasn't really been my main focus.
My main focus has been having a usable
protocol and then I feel that tokenomics
after will be more important.
It doesn't have to be confirmed, does it?
Yeah.
Theoretically, yes, it does not have to
be ERG.
However, the lender will be paid in ERG
no matter what.
Yeah.
But yes, theoretically, the collateral
could be anything that they want.
And if the miners choose, for example, to
get paid in SigmaUSD, they could if they
wanted to.
Yeah.
Yeah, no, I definitely, I think that's
fair, honestly.
I initially did not even think about a
token, but I felt like I want to
incentivize collateralization and
incentivize people to join decentralized
mining pools, because honestly, most
miners...
They want whatever works, right?
And they see a stratum on Heropool.
They're going to go join that.
They're not going to join Lithos.
So I feel like there should be some sort
of incentivization for them as well to be
part of a decentralized mining pool.
And in that way, we're enforcing, we're
ensuring that more people will join this
decentralized mining pool.
Because they're getting paid a little bit
extra, right?
And that's not to mention as well MEV and
storage rent, which will be additional
rewards for them to join a decentralized
mining pool as well.
No, I think it's tough because especially
these days, a lot of tokens are useless.
In my opinion, there's a lot of things
that don't need tokens that have them.
So definitely it's something I thought
about with Lithos as well.
Do I need a token?
Do I want a token?
Is it really necessary?
Currently, right now, I feel like a token
will be useful in that sense.
But right now, the main focus has been
the protocol, making sure that works.
And then tokenomics will be most likely
the last thing I work on.
I don't want to prioritize it because it
is important.
It's not the main focus of the protocol
itself.
The main focus of the protocol is
decentralizing mining.
It is kind of similar to that, I believe.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think it's an interesting idea.
And it allows people who aren't mining to
gain ERG.
And I feel like that's been a big pain
point for some people in the Ergo
ecosystem.
I've heard that mentioned before in the
past.