Hello and welcome to the fourth Ergo
Community AMA.
What a morning, what a morning. I rushed
to get here so we could be four minutes
late. How's that sound?
We've got with us today, for starters,
from E3, we've got Grayman, kushti, Byron,
and anybody else that wants to join in the
chat for the Ergo Affinity.
So lots of stuff happened this week,
right? We threw stones at Goliath with our
slingshot, I guess, again, with the HTX
saga going on. We printed some receipts
for the conversation we had with them,
which was, if people are not recalling, it
was asking for, it was plainly and clearly
taking their marketing fee and revealing
that it wasn't really a marketing fee
because 30,000 would buy us 14 days with
no delisting and 100k would delay the
delisting.
So it's very obvious in their own work.
These are extortion fees, and it's got
nothing to do with marketing. So it's nice
to have those receipts and publish them
out there. That tweet didn't get quite as
much coverage as the first tweet. I think
we're probably only like 15,000, 16,000
for that compared to the original tweet,
which has got to be over 200,000 views
now. So not quite as much, but it is what
it is.
So to build off that and back off that,
we created a GitHub repo where we posted
the receipts as well as some chat logs of
that and asked the community to, not just
the Ergo community, but the crypto
community to post their receipts. Kind of
like a WikiLeaks or something like that.
And let me let somebody in the room here.
So we're hoping that people stand up for
themselves and the space and expose these
people that are just trying to extract
value from any project that comes along,
right?
That's the awful part of it. We saw one
tweet reply, I forget which project it
was, but same thing happened. They
actually announced that they paid $500,000
for a listing with HTX Global. And same
thing, they were not sent a notice about
being marked for special treatment, ST.
And then they got the delisting notice
and, of course, were stonewalled and
blocked and not really communicated well
by their person.
So it seems like there's a systemic
method. It's quid pro quo at those places
where this is what happens. We put you in
a corner without letting you know really
not giving you a chance to meet whatever
demands that they can come up with at any
time they want to by the way and force
them that's on the contract and then put
you in a corner to where you have no
communication back to remedy anything
because you didn't even know you're on
special treatment list and then meet you
in the back room with hey here's $100,000
and you can stay delisted kind of thing,
you know, so it's disgusting. None of that
happened. Don't worry boss.
Yeah, it's absolutely crazy. So hopefully
if we get more people to join up and do
that, that'd be great just to have those
receipts there so we can at least have a
repository if not in the current history
to have a repository in the future history
looking back of how dirty these things
were in the infancy of the industry,
right? So I'm really glad we have that.
What else is new? kushti, year-round?
What's new on the developer front? What's
new in your corner?
Yeah, a lot of things. Well, sub-blocks,
DevNet progression. Feel free to join
maybe in a few days. Some issues to be
fixed, but not so many.
Actually already left and yeah testing
bombing the devnet with transactions and
yeah well initial supports of input blocks
in mempool and the nodes wallet mostly
done, so yeah, proper progression there.
So yeah, also doing some more demos of
ErgoScript possibilities with coding
engines in form of example tests. We are
now working on global transfer policies
kind of scripts. And then also iterating
slowly our full-fledged bulletproofs
verification, which would be another nice
example of capabilities of the core
protocol in regards to providing a
platform for cryptographic applications.
Doing also with coding agents, mostly a
demo of basis trackers of ChainCash. So
tomorrow we'll meet the developer of
Telegram wallet. So then, yeah, I think in
a few weeks we will have demo to be used.
Well, around different communities, like
human communities, as well as AI agents
and peer-to-peer networks.
So possibly, I think in the long term to
replace many so-called DeFi
cryptocurrencies tokens because yeah well
in most cases they are not needed simply I
believe.
Then yeah also we checked recently with
Git circles guys maybe they will provide
updates in developers' chats on their own.
So yeah, it's progressing well there as
well. So in like a few weeks also they
will start promoting for more once the
initial prototype is done around reddit
and other developer communities.
Developing circles, different framework,
focused communities and so on. So, yeah,
it looks good. I think, well, we need to
get people from outside crypto, right,
because, well, this crypto space is now
mostly about some weirdest kinds of
speculation. So it's better to get
developers right and people willing to
build digital economies for you as well as
real worlds like local economies and so
on.
Then also there were two fundraising
campaigns done. I don't quite know by whom
even but yeah well now it seems well there
are like 7000 ERG in my wallet. So 2k
already there and 5k will be released in a
few days. So like that, need to check. So
that's quite great. So I've assigned the
first bounty and Sigma Rust repository to
have full-fledged implementation of Ergo-3
interpreter in Rust after all, with the
help of that bounty in particular.
And yeah, so we'll publish a plan on
spanning this key. Then what else we have
is Dexy-based USD stablecoin. Still
discussions mostly, but here we have a
clear plan how to deliver and all the
technical parts there, so it's mostly
about discussions, politics, holding
update keys, deciding rules about when to
burn those keys, what are the rules, and
so on.
So yeah, it's mostly about humans, not
technicalities. So, yeah, I think, well,
that also would be a good problem. I
think, right, to bring people from
outside, but now from crypto, so Rich's
idea is to use it outside of their
ecosystem, mostly, right, and he uses it
mostly because of efficient arbitrage
possibilities with Dexy design.
And then what else? So yeah, well, if I
go around, there are a lot of exciting
things on his side in regards with rules.
So, yeah, it seems a lot of things have
been there, right?
Yeah, yeah, really exciting. I know, it's
amazing. They've got a technique to bridge
it the other way too. When Rosen first
started out, some of you may not know that
typical Rosen swap from chain to chain is
you can bring coins or tokens from either
chain to either chain. But with Bitcoin,
it was a one-way bus, right? You could
bring Bitcoin to Ergo or Cardano or
Ethereum or Binance, and it would be Rosen
BTC, but nothing could go back.
So they developed a technique to be able
to bring back tokens and coins onto
Bitcoin itself by using the RUNE protocol.
So yeah, super, super cool, super exciting
to have that there.
Does that facilitate atomic swaps?
Can you atomic swap? I think you can
atomic swap runes, can't you? kushti?
You mean are atomic swaps available for
our runes? I think so. There are actually
multiple atomic swaps before Bitcoin and
other e-tanks of cryptocurrency. So,
tomorrow I will join Komodo folks and they
have some atomic swap based DEXes.
The only thing is, well, still those
things are not quite popular,
unfortunately, right? Well, regardless of
sovereignty and so on. Yeah, it is what it
is. So, well, I personally would be happy
to provide even some liquidity, right, and
so on. But yeah, well, it seems it's quite
complex, right, still, to do all these
things. It's not quite what we want,
unfortunately.
For Atomic Swaps, we had a demo of a
private Atomic Swap made with Bitcoin Cash
even before Bitcoin supported Schnorr
signatures. Jason Davis made a demo back
in 2020. I saw lightning swaps and so on,
but only demos. Nothing popular.
Our guy Death Ergripsson made something
for atomic swaps. Yeah, I'm not sure if
it's finished even, but yeah, well, in
general, well, a lot of such to link
around, but yeah, mostly in prototype
form. And yeah, even if it's quite
finished, polished, it's still not that
good.
Yeah. Well, guys, let's hit a couple of
Dev updates real quick before we continue
on with the discussion.
Let's see what we have here. Let me just
arrange my screen a little better.
Perfect. So first up, we have Nautilus,
that's add-on BR, adding configurable
ledger transport method supports, and
Hermes, added Ergo node client, now
working on mempool tracking. kushti,
what's Hermes?
I think if you go a little bit down, if
you go a little bit lower, there is
explanation about it.
That's an explanation. Let's see.
Yeah, sorry. My was off. So, what's,
what's heard me by a Nautilus. What's,
what, what's sorry.
Hermes right here. H E R M E S added
error client. Now working on mempool
tracking.
Oh, yeah, maybe there is some discussion.
Yeah, I don't see anything. I'll have to
reach out to him. Yeah, I don't see
anything, it's you either.
It's a real time and mempool aware box
streamer on top of the index node. It was
initially designed for Machina Finance,
but it will be generic enough to be used
for any dApp and even to replace GraphQL
on Nautilus.
So it's a Mempool streamer, is that what
you said? Nice. You know, I think MGPi and
Luca built something somewhat similar.
They had to do that for SigmaLock because
they wanted instant responses from the
chain for the locking and unlocking
mechanisms. So they built some sort of
cache streamer as well for their backend.
So it seems to be a need for that. That's
really awesome. Very cool.
All right, ErgoProtica R&D, the rest he
says, he's reviewing PR contract, made
code coverage for the PRD to test it, made
PR with rules for a crush coding agent,
and he's asking for reviewing 6.0 tests
for Sigma. Trying to finish bullet proofs,
verification tests, still a lot of things
ahead.
The cool thing about this update, kushti,
I think I saw you notify some nodes, some
mining nodes is no update needed, of
course, but it is helpful to update to
support the new protocol on the network,
which is neat. Classic Ergo, where we have
serious amazing backwards compatibility
with older nodes.
Basis ChainCash made raw demo, basis
tracker server demo, improving it. He's
discussing contract and possible
extensions for it. And USC Stablecoin,
still planning deployment, will start
issuing first needed tokens this week.
We've got Rosen Bridge. They've created a
root ESLint configuration for the app to
ensure consistent coding standards. The
app, they've put that configuration for
the app to ensure consistent coding, same
thing. They've improved the UI kit and for
the watch app, they had to put the ESLint
in as well.
So, Rosen Bridge, we've, as you saw,
besides just the Cardano, they have other
runes, of course. We're not just focusing
on that aspect of it, but full rune
integration to Rosen, which is going to be
very interesting to bring runes back and
forth, not just mimicking tokens when they
go over to Bitcoin, but bringing them on
to other chains and actually having a
marketplace and liquidity and those kind
of things. It's going to be very
interesting to see those break out.
Chris, our trusty friend Chris, has added
Javanese support and Malaysian support to
the Nautilus wallet. It's always great to
have those in many languages for the
global thing that Ergo is.
Joe Samai is making Game of Prompts,
Judge system done, he's been seeing some
issues if the judges have a lot of
opinions, so he's updating the rep system
again. The current implementation asks for
20 to 50 participants, which is great, but
should be able to be unlimited, so they're
going to try to improve this.
We've got IOSPOR with Netcoats Engine.
They're working on async stream parsing.
This is for storing bundled sensitive
information like transaction history.
Let's see. Here's an explanation. The way
it works is that you request a file from
the factory with a wallet ID as the
initial string. The factory then makes
sure it looks in the bucket that is
associated with a calling application, for
example, the wallet application, and then
all the wallet addresses above the wallet
application, and that wallet ID would
share the same root.
Oh, very, very neat. So if you want to
delete the root wallet and the child
wallets, it could also be deleted. You
know, this is neat. So we talked about,
you know, a year or so ago, I talked with
our identity advisor here at Cornell about
this kind of, I call them vampire strings,
all right?
So the idea is if we're providing
identity for people, right? And somebody
up the chain is a bad actor. How can you
guarantee that the identities provided by
that actor, bad actor, are good, right? So
you cannot trust the identity bestowed
down lower in the chain of that bad actor.
So you have to seize those identities,
right? In current AD structure, that's
difficult to do, right? Because there's
one identity for private provider, it's
federated, right?
But in this vampire logic, right? If you
kill the head vampire, everything after
the vampire should vanish. So I think
that's a way that crypto can really help
out with identity, right? So if multiple
actors are deploying identity and granting
access, you find a bad actor, boom, you
blow it up everything underneath is on
hold until it's rebuilt, right? So really
neat concept for that. Let's see. And
that's it for dev updates. Very cool. Very
cool.
So we got a quick question in chat. Let's
jump right on to that. T-Rog says, is
there any concern for similar delistings
for other exchanges, or has HTX been an
outlier for demanding this marketing fee,
marketing fee, $1 million.
In my mind, that never crossed my mind. I
think HTX is probably, from what I've
heard from the backroom chats, from people
dealing with HTX, is over the past month,
they've started really twisting the knife.
They've set these unfair changes in
liquidity and volume, and pushed them on
people without notifying them, and then
threatened delisting.
And I honestly think it's too, yeah. Chat
in the comments is because Justin Sun is
cash poor. It does almost seem like
there's a directive from the top that
says, we need to make money fast. Let's
make it quick. So I think that's what HTX
is doing, and they're only going to burn
themselves and hurt themselves.
So no, I don't think there's a concern
for smaller delistings for that kind of
thing. HTX seems to not care at all. Even
our contact in the chat just has stopped
replying at HTX. They're brazen. They know
what they're doing, and they're just
hoping that you guys forget about it. And
that's it. And they'll continue to do
that. That's typically what they do. So
the idea is don't forget about it. We'll
keep the repository up. And we'll make
them remember every single time, just like
Pepperidge Farm, right? So no trolling.
Yeah, I will start to reach journalists
today. We need to get maximum exposure,
right? They're doing our own business. I
still think it's not extortion, like push
for bribery, right? It's not about
liquidity or volume, so based on who's got
the list, it's Ergo, Komodo and Firo. Firo
was totally fine and yeah so it's not
about liquidity or volume so it's
something different but yeah I don't know
principle but yeah well let journalists
maybe do their business now right and we
need to get exposure we need to get
interest rates, traffic and so on. This is
the best thing we can do at the moment.
Yeah, about liquidity exchanges. So I had
a talk and also discovered recently that,
well, for some exchanges, we already can
get some big centralized exchanges, for
example, Bit.Get. We can get exposure
basically for free just by providing
liquidity whether on Ethereum LP or
Binance Smart Chain, right?
So then I think Binance will catch up,
right? So just there is need to afford to
provide liquidity on BSC pool, right and
at some point they will catch up and the
coinbase already showing Base LP some
centralized exchange interface, right? So
then base will be supported by Rosen soon,
but yeah, well, there is no need to wait
for anything right now.
So let's consider whether to feel pool on
Ethereum and Binance Smart Chain, so I can
put a little bit as well, right? And with
that, so with some funds in the pool, so
AI, the AI filter, you know, so they using
some AI filter to filter out some I don't
know, fake LPs and all that stuff, right?
So yeah, it will be shown in the
centralized exchange interface and yeah,
maybe it gets much bigger than HTX like 10
times now because HTX is in decline, right
since 2022 and yeah BitGet is on the rise
and yeah especially for last one year and
a half so it's probably number three now
globally so after Binance and Bybit BitGet
is number three yeah I'm not sure about
the US but yeah well globally it's well
recognized now and we can get there
without any well listing fees right just
via Binance for example Binance Smart
Chain or Ethereum so yeah well we need to
decide something and put it into just
then, yeah, the same probably will work
for Binance at some point.
So all the centralized exchanges are now
going to syndicate centralized exchange
and decentralized exchanges to community
rights under the same interface. So BitGet
and Coinbase already done with that, and
yeah, I think others Bybit and Binance,
who else, OKX will catch up, right?
So yeah, that's the way we can get
everywhere for free basically, right? In
form of rep tests, but then in case of
some active trading we can get on a
centralized exchange, right? So we can get
native integration as well.
All right, so yeah, let's discuss that
after the call maybe in Ergo trading, but
yeah, I had a talk with BitGet lady and
yesterday basically and yeah it seems it's
the best way to move forward right so we
need to choose some pool filled with
liquidity so I can put some. We can ask
some known whales and so on, right?
And once we got through AI filters and
once we get some traction interests,
right? So we can get native integration as
well, right? But yeah, well, wrapped
version would be good. And yeah, the same
talk with Kraken, right? So it was about
listing wrapped token, but Kraken is still
using some own centralized solution,
right? So they're not automatically
pulling all the tokens from decentralized
exchanges like BitGets and Coinbase are
already doing.
You know, correct. Correct. And Kraken
also has, you know, we know a brief
outline of what Kraken wants from us. So
we just have to hit that. That's all, I
think, and then re-approach them. I think
we've announced that several times. So
Kraken is in a black box at least that
they would like to see holders in
liquidity on the token they want to list.
I think ERG itself is probably a bit away
from that. But as you guys may know that
ERG on another chain with Rosen is, yeah,
Grayman bought us Rosen-ERG, he says in
chat, is a better possibility in the
immediate. So yeah, Kraken would be
amazing for ERG, I think.
You know, there wasn't too much traction
on the votes up at for Rosen Bridge. I
think that's an issue with, I think every
chain has that issue, right? You have a
lot of participants that are passive
bystanders, right? Passive investors, we
call them. So that's something that
really, really needs to change for these
kinds of things to succeed.
So if you guys are just tuning in, you're
unaware of that vote, go to Paideia and
look up the Rosen GARDs and you'll see a
vote to spread Rosen-ERG liquidity over
Ergo, over Cardano, so that we can reach
their requirement for Kraken listing on
Rosen-ERG.
Yeah, because holding Rosen ERG, right?
If you're just holding, you know,
theoretically there's not much difference
of holding Rosen ERG or holding ERG. If
you actually want to utilize the ecosystem
and participate, you know, that's when you
hold ERG and use it actually. But for
silent partners, as Grayman says, that
should be an entry point at Kraken that's
perfectly suitable.
One thing I forgot to mention is I saw
heroes joined us from Twitter, but hero is
the dev on Cyberverse an update last week
that we missed because we were all
chatting too long about drama. So let me
just hit this for those of you who don't
know Cyberverse.
Down for the month. They're doing a
massive upgrade with P2P combat, that kind
of stuff. So it's really, really exciting
when this comes back. They've worked on
the stat system back in in combat testing.
They've synced stats with the server.
Example 50, EGI boost speed instantly. Oh,
that's awesome. Combat testing, fighting
high level enemies now clearly shows stat
differences. Stronger enemies equals
harder fights. Core system, they've
leveled up resets, HP and gives plus one
plus one skill point, stats window, spend
points, build your citizen, nice.
Inventory, equip, quick use, manage items
and skills window, learn from books, level
skills and points.
I think the treat that we have in Ergo
here is that... Well, maybe, I don't know
if it happens in other ecosystems, but you
can get close to these projects, right? We
can get in the dev update, we can see
these projects go, we can talk to Pixel,
Mr. Pixel, we can talk to Hero, and you
get to, it's almost like a child, right?
You can see this infant from what
Cyberverse started on back in the day when
it was just Ergo integration, and you see
it grow into something like this, and
it's, it's interesting to look back and
remember what it was like playing this
game back in the day and where it's come
and where it's going. And so it's amazing
to be part of that and see those kind of
things grow.
Okay, where are we next? Let's see, do we
have any questions in chat? There was chat
in the chat about a ERG who's right below
us in the zoom was interested in what's it
called? Working on some sort of academy
buildup again. We used to have something
called DECO, which was... Do we remember
what that stood for? Decentralized college
or something like that? Right? Was that
it, kushti? Grayman? Anybody remember?
Deco-decentralized coordination.
Coordination, okay. All right, thank you.
So that was fantastic. There's a lot of
videos there on that, kind of like basic
beginner ERG devs and that kind of thing.
So yeah. It would be very awesome to get
that started again. There's a lot of
videos, and happy to help with the AI
method that I said before about
integrating those videos as well. So
whenever you're bringing up ERG, we can
hit it with all the past searchable and
linkable bookmarks in the AI model. So
students can hit the ground running with
that. So yeah, that's going to be amazing.
That is.
What else? Anybody got anything else?
I've been talking a lot. So kushti,
Grayman?
Yeah, a lot of things going on. So, yeah,
well, there are some guys looking for
developers. So we need for more developers
guys. So if you know some, please bring.
So, well, I brought a few in recent months
but there is need for more all the time so
if anyone is willing to promote Ergo
around development circles so yeah let's
consider some campaign I would be happy to
participate also and yeah so I think,
well, that there is need to promote Ergo
differently, right?
So not as crypto, or whatever it's called
these days, crypto. These days it's quite
confusing to me, right, but yes, platform,
foundation, global, neutral, settlement
layer for building digital economies,
rights for humans, human communities,
developing communities, as well as AI
agents, right, and incentivizing
peer-to-peer networks.
So yeah, well, a lot of use cases which
are handled by others in quite cozy ways.
I think amongst the economist community,
most people that are not already involved
in crypto are somewhat disinterested or
maybe standoffish towards crypto in
general just because it's the way it's
been presented, you know, with the idea
that Bitcoin is going to replace the
dollar and hyper Bitcoin ization and all
this other shit. It just sounds cartoonish
to them.
I mean, economists don't have a very firm
a soapbox to stand on when it comes to
being credible academics. They wouldn't
want to have anybody challenge that in the
press, but the truth is most economists at
the top of the food chain don't really
think of their field as being entirely
pure and hasn't been for a long time since
computers came around and made it possible
for the application of statistical methods
instead of actual thinking.
But now we have cryptocurrency, which
makes it so that instead of just having
statistical methods, you actually would
have a way to track the money as it's
being spent. And if they really want to
turn economics into a science and they
should embrace it, but there's a long road
between here and there. And most of the
people that are in that field are going to
visualize using some computer. So they
think world computer like Ethereum. So
they're all trapped in bullshit land over
there.
But really what it's about is redefining
money and then building that from the
ground up. And I don't see any project
that's doing a better job of that in
general than Ergo. I mean, in some
specific ways, like for example, Casper is
just sort of hyper focused on speed. But
until they win the race and get global
adoption, that's a whole lot of speed
going nowhere. There's barely any
transactions.
Whereas in Ergo, we have a much more
broadly focused concept of of what money
is and how it can be exploited using a
deterministic approach rather than this
kind of open-ended world computer approach
of the Ethereum world. Economists
eventually will understand that and
embrace it, but it's going to take a long
time for that to become apparent and a
whole lot of soldiering on our part before
they'll take any real interest.
So you just have to keep chipping away.
There are a few people like Rubini or, you
know, Steve Keene is the one that I keep
trying to plant seeds in his mind because
in my opinion, he's the guy who has sort
of the best understanding of how the
current system works and how we should go
forward.
But he's also somebody who earlier in his
career, was academically interested in
cryptocurrency and posited several
interesting ideas that, at this point, he
would probably look back and say we're
young and naive on his part. Instead of
having a carbon tax, having a separate
currency for purchasing gasoline or other
rationed products, which would then trade
on its own market, and it would give you a
way to create an economy that would reduce
the consumption of certain commodities
that were used like that.
This is something that he wrote about 15
years ago, maybe 12 years ago, and you
could actually contemplate making currency
systems for nations based on Ergo. That's
why it fascinates me, but there's very few
people that are in that academic community
that are just going to immediately leap to
that because it's so far outside of their
realm of thinking, and because most of the
people that are coming from the crypto
world are yelling at them that inflation
is stupid and why wouldn't you have a
fixed number of atoms of gold as the basis
for your currency and all this other
stuff, and they just laugh and walk away.
But with something like ChainCash and
derivatives that can be built on top of
it, that's a whole new ballgame. And
eventually, they're going to have to get
on the field because we're going to make
them. Oh, and I had a question about
ChainCash for kushti in the chat.
The question was, can ChainCash protocol
be instantiated in a limited form where
only a certain type and collateralization
of notes can be issued on an accepted
standard. Instead of having a more
generalized free banking type system, can
you implement it in a way that it would
only work with certain types of
collateralization ratios and
denominations?
Oh, so that's left to the party which is
accepting, right, so you can accept only
ChainCash notes which are backed by
particular assets, right, and also sets on
collateralization level. So that's, I
think, the whole point, right, so every
party is having individual risk profile
and then yeah well it's not enforced
around the system and then yeah that the
system is not hopefully failing fully,
right, like in 2008, the whole financial
system with pretty much the same
parameters everywhere failed, right?
So some circles could fail, right, in
times of crisis, but yeah, well, more
conservative actors would stay at the same
time.
I'm specifically thinking about this idea
of this silver sense, this currency based
on and tied to the existing United States
constitutional silver currency that's all
around this country and having it so that
the ChainCash implementation of the
on-chain version of that would only be
acceptable from vendor to vendor and
customer to vendor and customer to
customer even. If it followed a certain
protocol, so you couldn't just start
issuing things that that people, I guess
that you already answered the question.
You have to create an interface that makes
it so that the customer understands that
they're getting silver sets. You have to
have a specific token ID for the silver
sets.
In this particular case, if you want to
build some monetary circuit rights within
the whole so you can just make some
default config right for ChainCash servers
and spread right around that silver circle
and that's a default config would set
right particular token ID and
collateralization level maybe, then yeah,
it's possible to change collateralization
level individually also, but probably most
of users would just use default value as
usually happen.
Yeah, I mean, ultimately there would be a
for-profit part of it. There were rollout
apps on iOS and on Android, because
there's no peer-to-peer on-chain activity
without mobile phones. Let's be real.
Especially if you're trying to go for some
sort of a LETS, a local exchange trading
system, you need to have people be able to
just pull out their phones and get a
transaction done.
So, and that's not going to happen
without some company structure and
whatnot. So there'd have to be sort of, I
don't know, sorry, I'm thinking out loud
about this whole thing. I'm trying to
write it up.
Yeah, that's much needed. Well, for now,
the idea is to get some working demo as
quickly as possible and then maybe try to
use it over some, I don't know, like
fairs. How is it so cold? Like for free
trading events.
Yeah, like a festival, I understand. You
have a flea market, swap meet, that type
of thing.
Yeah, so try to do some flea markets kind
of events, right?
The other thing, while I have you on the
subject, just if you could quickly
comment, it seems to me when you were
initially proposing this idea that there
would be a reputation system involved for
people that are writing these notes? And I
don't know, is that true and has progress
been made in other projects like Joe
Sammy's work on reputation system that
could be applied there?
Because it strikes me that in the way I
envision it, you'll have these vendors who
are accepting silver in payment, and then
they can also accept this on chain
version. And so these vendors effectively
act as a distributed bank because they are
the ones with the pools of silver change
and they're safe and then taking it home
and eventually turning it into dollars or
ERG or whatever they want.
But they are the ones who are essentially
holding the larger pools of capital. And
so it's a distributed form of banking,
sort of old school way, except with
standardized notes. And they're
standardized based on these physical
tokens that already exist and already
widespread. So the question is, if you
have only partially collateralized notes,
and it comes to a situation where somebody
decides to skip town and head to Mexico
with their US coins and melt them down,
and the people who are holding their notes
are left holding the bag, and so they want
to redeem them.
And they get part of their
collateralization back, presumably, but
they're still out some and they're pissed.
So how do we make it so that guy can never
come back? I guess that's impossible
because they're going to be anonymous. I
don't know. Reputation system seems
important for this because if you're going
to have a bunch of distributed competing
vendors and banks that are not just
selling banking services, but are also
restaurants or farmers or, you know,
barbers or whatever. They're all going to
have multiple incentives and whatnot. You
need to have a way to keep track of how
well they handle the banking part. Do they
redeem their notes when asked for coinage?
Right, so then, yeah, I think it's the
next step, right, so you can build
reputation only based on some trading
history. So then, yeah, so the idea is to
launch something, right, and then see how
to build some, yeah, kind of reputation
system, which is basically some summary,
right, of transactions history. Right.
That's all what we have here without, I
don't know, like control from state, you
know, like standards.
I think there needs to be a way to
challenge their reputation and a way for
them to defend it and for those actions to
be taken on chain with deadlines and
whatnot in order to prevent it from being
spammed.
Yeah, so there could be some agents,
maybe, which are incentivized to do such
probing, right? That's quite interesting.
So, yeah, well, let's think on this
shortly, hopefully.
I'm going to go and research what Joe
Sammy's been up to because I haven't
really paid him.
Joe Sammy did some reputation system for
payments for his peer-to-peer network
Celaut. But actually, I think it's quite,
I don't know, like parallel effort, right?
So instead of using some reputation system
to provide credit, you can just use this
ChainCash, right? To provide credit. So
it's also kind of reputation system
process. But yeah, need to take a look,
maybe some combinations possible. You need
to take with just me also about that.
He is quite active and around and yeah
well actually we discussed to bring yeah
those basis payments into basis this kind
of off-chain cash in to Celaut particular
network. Because yeah, I think it's quite
interesting. So currently, there are a lot
of so-called DeFi projects, right, with
total market cap of 20 to 25 billion USD
and most of them do have some broken
economies, well, releasing tokens in a way
that they are just going down because of
our supply.
So the idea is that now we can tie supply
with demand by using just some off-chain
cash found by Ergo Reserve. So there is no
need for additional tokens, just Ergo and
Ergo tokens would be enough.
So, let's, let's, continue discussion.
Yeah.
Just a couple of questions, kushti. So,
in regards to ChainCash, would it have a
separate, it would be a separate project
with its own marketing budget and
marketing team? Would you be focusing on
this or?
Yeah, so there will be no token, right,
for sure, because I don't like to issue
tokens at all when they are not needed.
But yeah, there is need to do some
marketing, right?
Is it reasonable to say that if Ergo is a
platform, that ChainCash is a protocol?
And that it is a protocol that will be
used by people to create applications and
that those are what need the marketing.
Ergo is a kind of reserve asset and smart
reserve asset, so it's allowing for
different protocols to be built on top of.
And then we have ChainCash as a monetary
expansion tool, because for being useful
for real economies, you need some kind of
monetary expansion.
And yeah that's quite different as you
say it's right from all the crypto and I
think that's quite a fork of Bitcoin
community idea space let's say of 2010
basically right 2011. So initially, they
had a lot of discussions, right? How can
you build electronic cash, right? When
emission is strictly set into the
protocol. And yeah that they had some
discussions but later somehow the focus
shifted to some secondary issues such as
TPS right whatever now that they are
having hot debates our there are some
parameters in the protocol clients, but
the original talk is forgotten and revived
here.
And those talks, I believe, are the most
important, right? So how to use
high-quality base assets, Ergo-right
proof-of-work assets to build better
money, right, for digital and real-world
economies.
So there was one other question that was
mentioned on the YouTube stream from EAOK
asking any thoughts on the infinite pitch
deck that he shared or they shared in the
Dev Telegram?
I need to check.
Sounds like we need to follow up on the
Dev Telegram.
Yeah, so actually, yesterday I was
occupied with quite a lot of talks with
BitGet lady and we had a nice talk with
Bruno and so on, but yeah, from Yehokai.
Yeah, it's from yesterday. It was a good
time of mine. So yeah, I was occupied with
a lot of talks yesterday. So, we'll
provide some feedback today after coding
session. Right. We will do the, do you
guys, anyone, read it?
I did not.
Do we have any other questions? We're
coming up on the hour here. There was one
other question I had actually earlier in
chat, which was about the upcoming meeting
in Colorado Springs, which I guess there
might be somebody who's listening to this
that could still get tickets or figure out
a way to drive there in time.
You're welcome to come. If you can get
there, then there's going to be a lot of
fun. One question that I had earlier, but
I see that HQ has gone, was what
facilities were doing to make it so that
that is going to be broadcast to the
greater internet. But we'll figure that
out. Tickets are not necessary. You're
just welcome to come. We're going to open
it up to the general public. We're going
to try and put some flyers up in the local
universities. Anybody who's interested and
wants to come and listen and talk is
welcome to come. It's permissionless, no
tickets. It's Ergo.
So okay, just making sure you set
tickets. You made me a little nervous. I
was like, I thought I signed.
I mean, plane tickets. There's definitely
one form of permission, which is just
geographical permission. Yeah, I was
thinking about what you say. I've got, I
got room for somebody to sleep on a couch
and an Airbnb if somebody needs to crash.
But there's hotels and everything around.
We're not recording them. Are we?
I think we are. I think we're live. We
should talk about it on the six chat.
Are there any other questions for this
week's AMA or should we wrap it up? Sounds
like we should probably wrap it up. It was
great talking to y'all in another week.
We'll do it again.
All right. Yeah. Good chat. And, so, we
have, Colorado events, in two weeks.
Right. So quite soon.
Yeah. Coming up quick. It's going to be
fun. I'm going to get to meet Ed. Bye.
Nice. Nice. Before you drop off, Grayman.
I had a question for you before you drop
off.
Okay. Sure. Hit me.
Oh no, you guys can end the chat. I want
to ask.
Oh, gotcha. I think Andy is currently
the, the owner, so I can't control it,
but, it's probably going to. Thanks guys.
We got to roll it out with the music.
Goodbye everyone. We'll see you next time.