Hey guys, so that was a great speech from
Joe and thank you to Joe and the Sigma
Knots for sponsoring and hosting this
event.
It's wonderful to finally see some faces.
So today we're going to be talking about
Palm staking on the UTXO model.
So over the last year or so, I worked on
implementing a native token staking
platform on Cardano.
And as you know, Cardano and Ergo are
very similar in terms of how their
contracts work.
And they all share the UTXO model.
So I'll try to keep this as easy to
understand as possible so everyone can
understand.
So we have some existing implementations
of staking already.
So if you guys don't know, over the last
cycle DeFi summer, we had sushi swap and
pancake swap.
And for really anyone new here, pancake
swap was like how Solana is today.
They had all the memes and they were
going crazy with all the meme coins, all
the launches, and staking with those meme
coins.
And before PancakeSwap, we had SushiSwap,
which really was a Uniswap clone, but they
actually did some research and they were
the first ones to implement this modern
native token staking or ERC20 staking. So
SushiSwap had this staking which really is
to incentivize people, right? Because
staking makes people hold their tokens, so
it kind of stabilizes price movements. And
SushiSwap pioneered this and then we got
PancakeSwap which basically copied it and
made some improvements and really brought
it to the mass users, right?
Tons of people were just making meme
coins and having staking with it.
So you don't sell those meme coins and
it's kind of like inflation and Ponzi
scheme and so on.
All right, let's try to get to the next
slide.
So let's have a refresher.
So what is the account model? And what is
the UTXO model?
So the account model is, all right, let's
start with UTXO.
So what are UTXOs?
UTXOs were pioneered by Bitcoin.
That's how they started their entire
system.
So UTXOs stand for unspent transaction
outputs.
And it's basically the outputs of the
previous transaction you did.
So when you submit a transaction, you
have a bunch of metadata. You have what
went into the transaction and what came
out of the transaction.
And the outputs of this transaction are
referred to as UTXOs.
And the transaction model really is an
exact digital analogy to cash.
So let's say I have a $10 bill, and I
want to pay for $6 coffee.
It's probably $8 now, inflation.
And if I want to pay for $6 of coffee
with my $10 bill, I can't just rip the
bill in half.
I have to spend the entire $10 bill.
So what do I do?
I give the cashier my entire bill, and
that's it.
They have the bill.
They're not going to rip it in half or
anything.
It's just gone.
But they're going to give me back $4.
And this $4 is completely new.
It's not the original bill, it's just
completely new.
The $10 I had, it's gone.
So this is how you can think of the UTXO
model.
When you have an input, it always must be
spent.
It's always unique.
You cannot spend an input more than once.
Unlike cash, I guess the cashier could
spend it in other places.
But in the UTXO model, it can be only
spent once.
And another analogy that I like is with
the old fashioned piggy banks.
So you would have savings in a piggy
bank.
And if you ever wanted to spend it, you
would have to smash it open.
It's like a one time thing.
So you can also think of that. I have $10
in my piggy bank, the piggy bank is the
UTXO.
And that's like the input.
And then if I want to actually spend it,
I would smash the piggy bank open.
And it's gone. Just one time.
So that's really a brief overview of the
UTXO model and Cardano and Ergo both make
use of this.
So what's the account model?
Account model is really the newer model
and it was pioneered by Ethereum.
And account model really is analogous to
your bank account where you just have a
list of transactions saying that maybe $10
was deposited and you're spending $1 and
you have a list of transaction history.
So addresses are seen as accounts, and
you just have a direct tally of balance.
And the thing with this, and I think of
it as a problem, is that you need global
state.
So you need to know the history of
everything from the start, when the
account got funded, to how much you have
now, to know how much you have at this
moment.
You have to do some calculations, some
balance add, balance deductions, and so
on.
So but this is overall how the account
model works and it is also quite popular.
All the Ethereum forks use that and Solana
uses that and all the newer blockchains
also use that. For those of you following
Cardano there have a new blockchain called
Midnight that they're probably going to
launch next quarter or so and Midnight
uses a hybrid of account model and UTXO,
so it's quite popular.
Let's talk about the advantage of account
model in the context of this staking.
Staking is more analogous to a
client-server interaction.
What that means is that a server is
really just a computer that never turns
off.
It's always running in the background.
Client is really the people who hit that
server.
You need to talk to that server to do
something.
For example, if you're logging into your
email account, you're accessing a server
which holds all your emails.
You're the client.
You're trying to log in from your laptop.
That's a client-server interaction.
So staking is similar to this
interaction, where the stakers are the
clients.
And they deposit their tokens to a
contract.
And this contract, you can think of it as
a server, in the sense that the contract
has to manage all the global state.
It has to track the balance so it knows
how much rewards that you get, because
rewards are a function of how much tokens
you deposit and how long you have
deposited them for.
Solidity is a very popular smart contract
language that runs on this account model.
Solidity is perfect.
It has a single authoritative contract
storage.
You have something called a map.
And a map is a very basic data structure
that you have a key.
So a key is like the user, like your
user, your wallet address.
So if you access the data within that
wallet address, you have a bunch of data,
like how much they have deposited in the
contract and how long they had the tokens
on and all sorts of useful information,
perfect for this.
And then this doesn't translate well to
something in the UTXO model.
So for UTXO contracts, you have a single
UTXO.
And each UTXO, you can think of it as its
own entity.
So each UTXO can have its own contract.
So a contract's state really is with
respect to the UTXO it's inside of.
So a UTXO has this bottleneck.
You can't just store infinite data in it.
The UTXO, you have a size limit.
And you also have a broader transaction
size limit, because you can argue that,
hey, why don't you have a bunch of UTXOs,
this single UTXOs interact with?
So you can have a bunch of data.
So if a UTXO data size limit is like 4
kilobytes, you can be like, OK, why don't
we just do 1,000 UTXOs?
Why not make it like 4 gigabytes or
something?
No, that's not possible because you're
bottlenecked by transaction size limits.
You can only deal with a specific amount
of UTXOs per transaction.
And then on top of that, you also got the
block size limit.
So you can only have a certain amount of
transactions per block.
So a lot of bottlenecks here.
So how can we move on with this?
It almost seems impossible to bring
something that needs such a large global
state.
Because remember, this might work for 10
users, 100 users.
But how are we going to scale to 10,000
users?
Because each user are going to have some
size of data that's not going to scale.
So how do we do this?
So I had to rethink staking on the UTXO
model.
So data stored for the global variables,
so for all sorts of staking calculations,
they need to be bound to a constant size
limit.
You can't have it scale with the amount
of users.
So you can't be like, OK, one user is
like one gigabyte of data.
10,000 users is 10,000 gigabytes.
We can't scale like that.
It has to be one user is like one
gigabyte of data.
A million users is still one gigabyte of
data.
How can we make that happen?
It has to be constant.
So a clear solution, which several
projects on Cardano and Ergo follow.
So I think, what was it? The people
behind Crux Finance, I'm forgetting their
name.
I think they're shut down now, but they
pioneered a staking model.
And then a bunch of Cardano projects have
their own staking.
So what do they do?
So they have some sort of position or
UTXO or NFT that you can think of which
indicates a share of how much they have
staked.
So let's say you stake a certain amount
of tokens, you'll get back like a unique
token saying that, hey, this person staked
like 100 tokens on the platform at this
time.
So if you ever want to claim that stake
back, make an update, you have to deposit
that unique token you got back into the
contract.
And this is a pretty straightforward and
well-known solution to this problem.
However, this was not ideal for ZenGate's
purpose because of legal conflicts.
The problem is that you can have
derivative markets of something like a
position token because I can take my
position token and I can be like okay I
don't want to be in this anymore but I
don't want to lose that accumulation of
rewards. Like maybe the longer you stake
the faster you earn rewards or something,
it keeps compounding so maybe I sell it to
someone else or just give it to someone
else.
So you create these derivative markets,
and it's a conflict from a legal
standpoint.
I don't know why, but it is what it is.
It's a very gray area in general,
unfortunately.
So I thought of this data structure
called a Merkle tree.
And this was absolutely perfect.
So on Ergo, you have the AVL tree.
And it's quite similar, so it can just
translate to Ergo.
Also, what's actually really interesting
is that the Merkle Tree data structure is
something that was just implemented at a
contract level on Cardano.
However, on Ergo, ErgoScript, you have
AVL tree as a native data structure within
the language.
So what that means is that basically you
can trust the data structure on Ergo more
because the core team, so basically
kushti, made the implementation in the
compiler itself.
So it's not like a third-party code that
you're trusting to be correct, which is
the case on Cardano.
So let's see what is a Merkle tree,
because I honestly barely knew about it
until I did this.
All right, so a Merkle tree is a
tree-based data structure.
And a tree-based data structure, you can
really think of it having a root at the
top.
And it has branches pointing to more
roots.
So you can kind of see that data
structure in the diagram behind me.
And the boxes, they're called nodes.
So you have one root node.
It's the main node on top.
Then you have those lines are called
branches.
And then you have another node that's
connected by branches.
They're like intermediary nodes.
And all the way at the bottom, you can
see a bunch of nodes, like the final
nodes.
Those are called the leaves.
That's just a very well-known data
structure in computer science.
So a Merkle tree is a variant of this
data structure.
And it's made by hashing hashes of data.
So I know that's confusing.
So let's break that down.
So behind me, you can see that you have a
block of data, like a block of files.
So A.txt, B.txt, C.txt, D.txt.
And you hash this block of data.
And hashing really means is that you take
data of any size and you convert it into a
fixed-sized string of a certain data size.
So in this, or in most cases, it's always
32 bytes of data.
So it's like a string of 64 characters.
And the cool part about this, which is
really important in security context, is
that it's irreversible.
So if you have this fixed size string,
you can't get the data back.
It's impossible.
But that's beyond the scope of this
presentation.
So again, you have a data, and you
transform it into a fixed size, unique
string.
So you can see A.txt has a hash H1, B.txt
has its own hash, and so on.
So how does this translate to a Merkle
tree?
So look at the tree behind me.
All the way at the bottom, the leaf
nodes, you can see that we brought those
hashes over.
The H1Z2Y77A and so on.
So those are the hashes brought to the
node, and they're at the bottom.
So now you look at the left side, the
bottom left side of the tree.
So we take the hashes. Those are the
hashes for A.txt, B.txt.
So we take those hashes and we
concatenate them.
We put them together.
And we take the hash of that.
So the hash of that, you can see, is
right above those two.
So it's U67R on the left side.
And again, we do this exact thing on the
right side.
So for C.txt and D.txt, and we get a
hash.
Now those hashes in the middle, again, we
take them, we concatenate them, and we get
the hash.
And that final hash is called the root
hash.
So why this is really cool is because you
can find differences between two states,
so meaning like two different trees.
So if you made any modifications, you can
find the difference between them really
fast because think of it logically. If you
have two pieces of data, what do you have
to do? You have to iterate through them,
like one bit at a time, like the smallest
unit of difference. You have to iterate
through them so if there's like a million
pieces of data you have to make at least
at most a million iterations. It doesn't
scale so with this it's a lot faster. It's
like the log of a million maybe that's
like a thousand or ten thousand. I don't
know, but it's significantly faster.
So let me explain this further. So you
can see that we had the text files, and we
changed the contents of C.txt.
And what does that do?
We got a new hash.
So you can see A4W12.
So on the right side of the Merkle tree,
you can see that all the way at the
bottom, that changed.
It's in yellow.
And now, since that changed, the hash
above it, which is, remember, made by
concatenating the hash of C.txt and D.txt,
that also changed.
And since that changed, the root hash
also changed.
So you can see here that when you
traverse the tree, you first check the
left side.
And you're like, oh, the left side's
exactly the same.
So you know that A.txt and B.txt is
clearly unchanged.
But then you go to the right side and you
can see that, okay, D.txt isn't changed.
At the bottom, it's still the same.
So then you know really quickly that
C.txt is changed.
So it's a really clever data structure.
It actually powers so much of the modern
infrastructure.
You just don't know it.
But that's a quick introduction to a
Merkle tree.
So you can see here the comparisons made.
So on the left side was the original
tree, and the right side is the tree with
the C.txt changed.
So you can see we just make three
comparisons.
So this scales really well.
All right, so now what we actually use
for the staking is something called the
Merkle Patricia Trie.
And what this is is basically an
optimized version of the Merkle Tree.
So a trie really is a, you can think of
it as like a key value map, indexed by the
key's nibble.
So it's just like a bunch of characters,
like ASCII characters.
And that's what a trie is.
And Patricia is just an optimization of
the path.
So it's a very optimized structure.
So you make even less. So in the previous
slide, we made like three traversals.
So this makes it even smaller, like maybe
like one or two.
And then Merkle is from what we discussed
before.
And then the proof is the path of nodes
that you traversed.
So in the previous slide, we traversed
through like three nodes.
So that's like the proof, you can think
of it as that.
And then proving.
What is the action of proving?
So you have the inputs of the known root
hash.
So the hash all the way at the top, you
have that.
And then you provide the proof, so you
provide that path.
And then you provide the key and the
claimed value.
So you walk through from the root node to
until you get to the key.
You walk through the tree.
And then once you reach to the value, you
stop.
And then you compute the root hashes from
that traversal.
You can do that same hashing from the
scratch.
And then you compare it.
Hey, is the thing I computed, does it
match what I already know?
And if yes, then you know that
everything's correct, like no one's
messing with anything.
And yeah, so membership is proven when
the computed root equals the known root.
And the known root is what you passed in.
So let's talk about how this integrates
into staking.
So client balances are stored in this
trie-based data structure.
And on-chain, so in the contracts itself,
only the root hash is stored.
And remember, the root hash is a fixed
size string of 32 bytes, because it's a
hash.
And that answers the problem we saw a
couple slides back where we want one user
to be, say, one gigabyte of data, and we
want a million users to still be that one
gigabyte of data.
So it's constant.
So in this case, it's always a constant
32 bytes, which is incredibly tiny.
So it's always this number, even if we
have a million clients, which is really
cool.
And thanks to that Merkle tree diagram I
explained, it's hashes of hashes of hashes
and so on.
So any time any insertions or updates
done, the contract does verification.
So as I explained in the previous slide,
you have a proof and you have the known
root hash.
So you provide the proof and the known
And what does the contract do?
The contract only does computing.
It only does verification.
It doesn't need to do all the data
storage or anything.
You provide the exact data that it needs,
the least amount of data it needs to
actually prove what you're doing is
correct, and you're not providing false
information.
And remember, after all of this is done,
so if there's any mutations sent to the
state, meaning if you added more stake, or
you did a claim, or you did a withdrawal,
that's a mutation.
The only thing that changes is the root
hash.
So it's always that constant size length.
And when these updates and claims happen,
you're providing the proof.
So I guess the downside of this is that
you have to store this data somewhere.
It's not magic.
So you have to store the data in your own
server.
It's called the off-chain.
So you have to store the data.
You're responsible for storing the data
in Solidity.
You can just throw it on the blockchain
and just make sure, like the EVM nodes.
The Ethereum nodes, the heavy 2, 3
terabytes, 6 terabytes nodes.
That stores all of that.
So you just worry about that.
But on the Ergo sense, you are storing
the data.
Did you have a question?
Great.
No, that's an excellent question.
So we got Grayman asking, what if the
staking platform goes down?
Or what if I just disappear, everyone's
screwed?
What if I just take down all my servers?
Well, that's actually not going to be an
issue, because like I said, you're not
trusting me with the data.
Like, I can't just magically change the
data, because all the mutations, they're
done by putting them through the contract.
So if you have like some initial state you
have to put it through the contract to get
the next state. So the contract's always
the intermediary between state changes so
it's as secure as the contract is secure
because this contract does all the checks
it needs to do.
Regarding the data, it's really cool
because you can actually walk through the
blockchain.
Walk through all the blocks and you can
always recalculate it.
It's not magic.
The blockchain doesn't store the data,
but it has you can think of it as
snapshots in time.
So you can traverse through all the
original snapshots and get back the
current data, the most recent current
state.
So no, you're not trusting me, and you
have as much security as the contract
provides.
Is that clear?
Right.
And so the question is, how can you
recover if the data is just all hashes?
Then what you can recover, because hashes
are non-reversible.
No, that's a great question.
So off-chain obviously doesn't store the
hashes.
So whenever you actually interact with
the transaction, you're providing the
actual data, not the hash, the actual data
into the transaction when you build it and
you submit the transaction.
And the contract is actually what hashes
the data.
So you provide the complete open data.
You're not hiding the data.
And then the contract does the hashing
and the checking.
So like I said, it does computation.
The contract only does computation.
So you provide the raw data, and the
contract just does hashing of the data.
And this is possible because of, yeah, so
I have it in this slide here, that
whenever you do any staking, you provide
the actual raw data.
And it's done through something called
the Redeemer on Cardano.
Or on Ergo, it's called context
variables.
And it's the same thing.
It's just data that anyone can provide
into a transaction when you build it and
submit it.
There's some limit of data that you can
provide into this.
We provide the actual data within this
constraint.
When you do this, that data is actually
published on the blockchain.
But this is a really special type of data
where it's not actually in the context of
the node.
So the node doesn't know about the
redeemer.
It doesn't save it for long term, but it
does save it from historical transactions.
Just in the same way that you know the
transactions an address did.
The address had an initial balance of one
ERG, and then a year later, it has like a
hundred.
You can track that.
So in the same sense, you can track this
data in the Redeemer context variable.
So really, to summarize, you can get back
the data by traversing historical
transactions.
So you're not trusting me at all.
Did you have a question?
All right.
Yeah, great.
So yeah, no, just to summarize, really,
the contract is something that just
verifies the integrity of the provided
data.
And that's really the general theme of
contracts on the UTXO model contracts.
It's positioned really just to verify all
the data.
It doesn't make new data.
It doesn't do anything special.
It just verifies.
Hey is what the transaction builder
provided? Is that correct?
Are they lying about something?
Because checking something is always far
cheaper than actually making it from
scratch.
And I think that's really where UTXO
shines because account model has to store
all this data.
I mean, sure, it's easier for developers,
but these node sizes are ridiculous.
I can't like run a three terabyte node in
my basement just for Ethereum.
And that's just Ethereum.
You have all these forks.
If I want to expand to multi-chain, I
have to spin up like an Ethereum node, a
Binance node, Polygon node, and so on.
If I want to do the things the right way
and not buy like a subscription to an RPC.
And it's not scalable, but in my
basement, I can run an Ergo node, which
has what, like 20 gigs, 30 gigs?
It's nothing.
Flash Drive has more storage than that.
And a Cardano node was like 160
gigabytes.
I can run plenty of these compared to
just one Ethereum node.
So you can see the trade-offs here.
They really shine in the long run.
So really the final slide here is
improvements made to the original
protocol.
So the original contract was short-lived
and static.
So like I said, it was originally meant
for things like meme coins.
So where you just don't want people to
sell.
You don't really think about long-term.
And the problem with this was it was very
static.
So you have one emission rate for the
whole program.
So what I also added to the protocol
itself, not the UTXO implementation, is I
made the emissions very dynamic.
So like every epoch, for example, on Palm
staking every week, people can claim their
rewards.
This emission amount can fluctuate
without having to redeploy the contract or
get people to migrate.
And this is really cool because a dynamic
protocol allows us to easily curb any
excess inflation or incentivizes staking
during steep price movements.
So it allows us for more of a
fine-grained control rather than, so we
actually react to how the economy is
doing.
I mean, you saw yesterday that things
went crazy.
So maybe during a time like that, you
want to incentivize people to hold.
So maybe we'll tell them, okay, we can
increase inflation so that people hold
onto their Palm instead of selling it on
the market.
Just for no reason when everything's
going crazy.
So then people might not sell because
they'll say hey like I can just put in the
contract I believe in Palm I believe in
this token's future.
I believe in crypto.
So like maybe in the next week the
tariffs are going to be reversed and we
won't have an issue.
So maybe I want to hold my Palm and make
some more Palm and money instead of
selling.
So the dynamic protocol really allows for
this.
Yeah, that's it for staking.
So hopefully that was some presentation
that you could understand.
I tried to make it as least technical as
possible so everyone can enjoy.
So any other questions?
Yeah, so it's quite technical, but you
can think of, well, really on the actual
usage-wise, rather than the data structure
implementation-wise, kushti mentioned that
the AVL tree is actually a lot more
efficient compared to the Merkle Patricia
Trie that you have on Cardano.
Meaning like the proof sizes, the really
efficient means that you can do more
operations in a given transaction.
So the proof sizes are smaller.
The data that you provide during
transaction building, it's a lot smaller.
So what does it mean for the end user?
It means that transactions really will be
cheaper.
But there is a significant implementation
difference, how it works internally, but I
don't really know that from the top of my
head and I can't speak for it that much.
But in the context of this though, you
can think of it as interchangeable.
Yeah, Grayman.
Correct, correct.
So, Grayman brought up a great point.
So yesterday, again, I don't think
everyone's quite active on Twitter, but
Liqwid, so there's a protocol on Cardano
called Liqwid Finance and it's a lending
protocol.
And what they did yesterday was because
of the extreme movement.
So I think Cardano literally went from
like 80 cents to like 27 cents in like a
flash because of like mass liquidations.
So Liqwid Finance is a decentralized
lending platform.
So you provide some collateral in ADA and
you get back an asset.
So since the price moved down so steeply,
you're going to have some liquidations due
to that.
So Liqwid Finance completely shut off
their front-end interface and you can't
manage your liquidations now. No one can
liquidate you or anything and you can't
make new collateral requests and so on I
don't know why they did this I mean
obviously to protect people from being
hurt but like I don't know I think
everyone's like a grown man here and can
handle their finances so I think that's
kind of silly but it is what it is.
So yes, they disabled the front end.
And maybe that I can make a custom
transaction using code to interact with
the contracts.
But I actually found Cardano's very
funny.
A lot of these off-chain runners, so
basically what processes your transactions
with the main contract, they're actually
permissioned.
So for people to run the off-chain bots,
you need to have like, maybe you have to
own, you have to be the owner of a certain
address.
So only your private key can actually run
the transactions.
But what's more common is like, it's like
a special NFT.
So all NFT holders are the ones that can
run these off-chain.
And that's a very, it's not decentralized
at all.
It's just made on a decentralized
platform.
So really, this is a very simple check.
Like you have a contract, and you're
like, okay, all these calculations happen.
It's decentralized.
But you add just one tiny check.
Only the owner, only the holder of this
NFT can run the transaction.
So technically, no.
For a lot of protocols on Cardano, no.
You can't just bypass everything and
build your own transactions with code.
I can't do that.
Because I don't own that special NFT that
you need to actually process the
transactions.
And no, no, this is actually really bad.
I don't know why.
It's like a very common on Cardano.
But yeah, no, it's not really
decentralized is the answer.
Again, as Joe kept mentioning, know your
assumptions.
Is something permissioned?
For example, we have the HODLerg game.
It's all open source.
So if the front end shut off, first of
all, you can just spin up your own front
end because the code's all there.
Second, you can build your own custom
transaction and you can run your own
off-chain because all that code is open
source.
It's not hiding anything and you don't
need any special NFT.
Even on Cardano, if these projects are
all open source, even if the off-chain is
all open source, the website is all open
source, it doesn't matter because you need
the NFT to actually run the off-chain.
It's literally not going to work.
So it's decentralized, it's open source,
but you can't do anything.
Yeah, Grayman.
Oh, no, that's a great question.
Maybe we can talk to Allison, who's in
the back.
He's the Nautilus developer.
But what Grayman said is, hey, can we
have a HODLerg natively within the
Nautilus wallet itself?
And I think that's really cool.
Maybe we can have a dedicated apps
section on Nautilus wallet.
I think it's already there with SigmaUSD.
But I think a bunch of apps within
Nautilus, so you don't have to go to any
website.
You're actually technically running your
own front-end because it's a wallet
extension so you're not even relying on me
hosting the website.
So I think that's a great idea and we can
have a bunch of apps on Nautilus where you
just click two buttons and you interact
with the protocol.
I really like this idea because again,
you're not worried about any front-end.
Or a front-end, if a front-end gets
hacked, what a front-end being hacked
means is that someone takes ownership of
the domain that it's on and injects custom
code.
So maybe they made an exact replica of my
front-end.
And then they're like, hey, when you
click this mint button, instead of
minting, you're transferring all your ERG
to an address.
That's what a hack really means.
So this isn't really possible if you have
something running on your own instance,
like on Nautilus itself.
I mean, it's only possible if you
literally physically download a virus, and
maybe the virus does some magic where it
has control of Nautilus.
But in general hacks, if my website gets
hacked, that's not going to affect your
Nautilus, which is running its own app
instance of HODLerg.
So that's a wonderful idea.
We should definitely get that going.
All right, any other questions, comments?
Yes, yes, it's live on Cardano.
And yeah, it's called palm-economy.io.
And you can find information about it.
And it's specifically staking for Palm
Token, which is the token for ZenGate's
Palmyra RWA platform.
So currently, there is no plans to do it
on Ergo, and it's not up to me.
But in the future, the point is that it's
pretty straightforward.
Because now that it's done on Cardano,
everything maps directly to Ergo.
So since all the theory, that's what
takes a long time.
Getting it done right.
Planning it out implementation is pretty
straightforward once you have this theory.
So that's why EVM is so successful
because you already it's been there since
what 2015 and you have so many contracts
so guess what a new fork a new L2 Base has
their own blockchain you take the
contracts and you copy paste it always
literally copy paste.
So in a similar sense, since we already
have everything ready on Cardano, when
we're ready for Ergo, we can just take
that code and translate it over to Ergo.
So it's much more trivial compared to
making it from scratch.
Yes, it's all very similar.
It's not exactly copy-paste, because on
Ethereum, it's literally a fork of the
node.
It's the exact same thing.
So you can actually copy-paste the exact
code and deploy it on L2s and so on.
So that's not the case for UTXO.
So you can't copy-paste it.
But the overall idea maps directly.
So you're just translating whatever
Cardano smart contract language to
ErgoScript exactly.
There's less friction.
There's more friction than going from
like Ethereum to like an Ethereum fork,
but conceptually, it's like the same
because the architecture is the same.
Yeah, I would definitely use AVL because
it's built into the contract.
They both serve that same abstract need
of storing data off-chain and then
verification on-chain.
That's really the important part.
That's the only thing that really makes
this work.
So AVL tree serves the same purpose.
So there's no reason to have to use a
Merkle Patricia trie on Ergo.
So actually, no, it's already
decentralized in the sense that you can
traverse through Ergo Explorer and you can
get back that original data, the
non-hashed data, and it's actually even
better than IPFS because you don't have to
do any pinning or anything.
So it's actually all there on Ergo
already.
But the actual raw data that you probably
were thinking about is the tree data and
the balance data.
And that cannot be stored on IPFS or
something, because it's something that
requires a database.
Because you're doing database operations.
All right, any other questions?
All right, thanks for tuning in, guys.