Hey everybody, Timur here coming to you
solo today.
I am making a quick video for you to
contribute to this Ergo Summit so that
you're going to see a collection of videos
that are focusing on some of the prominent
applications on Ergo and I get the honor
of presenting to you what I think is one
of our cornerstone applications.
This is something that not only is
functional, but it really exemplifies what
I think Ergo is all about.
It's totally peer to peer, there's no
intermediary, it's open source.
Yeah, and it's one of these things that
just, you can very easily picture yourself
using it and needing it in the real world.
So picture this, imagine you wanted to
borrow some money from somebody right and
okay maybe you have some collateral and
you want to show this person that you are
trustworthy, right?
So you're willing to put up some
collateral. But how do you do that? Do you
need a middleman? Do you need to talk to a
bank, like a broker, something like that?
No, we're going to do it on the
blockchain. And I'm going to show you
SigmaFi right now.
SigmaFi offers peer-to-peer bonds. So
it's built on the Ergo blockchain.
And it lets users create loan requests
and somebody else can come along on the
other side of that and fund that loan.
And all the terms are transparent. So you
can really see what's going on. And you
can see what the collateral is.
You can see what the APR is going to be.
You can set the APR if you're making a
loan request.
So let's dig in. I'll share my screen
with you. And you can see what SigmaFi is
all about.
All right, so whenever you open up
SigmaFi, this is important. This is not
terms and conditions to click accept,
right? Because then you're gonna become a
human centipede.
Read your assumptions, know your
assumptions, and you can check. You can
look in GitHub and see what all this stuff
is. And if you don't understand, you can
talk to the people in the community about
how it works and how to evaluate this,
okay?
So every time you see this, don't just
click past it, but think about it. OK,
yes, I'm taking responsibility for this
bearer asset that I have.
And so I know that I'm using the product
at my own risk, and I'm responsible for
what happens.
OK, so this is our dashboard here. And
these are all the active loan requests.
To clean things up, they have hidden the
undercollateralized requests. I'll explain
what all this means in just a moment.
But you can see here there's not a ton.
And I think it's because the demand for
SigmaUSD is just really high.
You have pretty high APR coming from duck
pools and things like that.
And given the current market, it's a
little tough to come across SigmaUSD given
the reserve ratio is a little bit low.
But, so pretty much, if you want to make
a loan request, you can click this button
here, and you're going to be able to say,
or ask for, you're going to ask for, let's
say you want 500 SigmaUSD, and then you're
going to put up collateral, what you
choose.
And so again, that's why some of these
are under collateralized, because people
are choosing to put up nothing or maybe an
NFT that doesn't have a strict market
value.
So that would be up to you as the
potential lender in this case. But this is
a borrower created loan request.
So they're going to put up 1,000 ERG. And
they're asking to borrow this for nine
months.
They are stating that they're going to
pay 20% interest. So this APR is like an
annualized rate.
So if this were 12 months, it would
actually be 27%. So that's way better than
your bank, I'll tell you that.
You can look at the borrower's address,
and you could probably look up their
history and see if they have a bunch of
successfully repaid loans.
All it really is is you looking at these
terms and agreeing to fulfill that. So you
would send 500 SigmaUSD to this contract.
Then you would, in nine months, receive
your 500 USD plus 20%. So that's 100. So
you would receive 600 SigmaUSD equivalent.
I believe that's just coming straight out
of his collateral.
And so why would somebody want to do
this? I think there's a couple of ways of
asking that question.
Why does somebody want to use SigmaFi?
First, that's really because this is like
a vending machine.
It is autonomous code that's been
published, and there's no intermediary. It
is like an automatic machine on the
internet.
And when somebody puts their money in it,
it makes this request and somebody else
comes and puts their side of the loan.
It is handled really clean and it
executes automatically.
So if this person does not repay their
loan by the end of this nine month
timeline, it actually gives them a block.
Yeah, it actually gives them a block that
they have to submit by.
If it does not do that, then
automatically it liquidates this
collateral to make the user whole again.
So like, super clean, fair, I think. I
think just personally, I've had these
interactions and loaned people money you
didn't get back, and there was no way to
enforce it without ruining your friendship
or something like that.
And I know I keep using the word clean,
but that's how it feels.
Okay. I also think the why of this, the
borrower creates the request, all right?
So it's really, and so that keeps away
this attitude of loan sharking. You see
these rates, these are high because no
one's going to fulfill it.
So it's kind of like a natural market for
this rate rather than it's like the
lenders are the only people who are
setting the rate and it would be way
higher than this because there's no
competition.
This way it kind of empowers the person
who needs the money to kind of say what
they need and put up the collateral that
they can put up.
So if somebody really needed it, maybe
they would put a bunch of collateral, like
more, to kind of show like, hey, this is a
super secure 200% backed loan, something
like that.
Otherwise, you have these where it's
106%. I'm not going to do that, because
ERG is volatile.
If ERG drops another 6%, maybe I'm not
getting my SigmaUSD back.
So that's why I want to use this program,
because everything is so transparent and
it's just very, very clear.
And then there's also the why about why
would a borrower do this? Why is somebody
paying 20%? That seems really high. That's
like credit card rates, right?
Let me tell you what they're doing. So
this is a way to get leverage on your ERG.
So he is borrowing 500 SigmaUSD. Right
now, he's going to be able to buy about
600 ERG with that.
And this is a bet that in nine months,
that 600 ERG is going to appreciate more
than 20%.
So he's pretty much saying if ERG is
worth a dollar or more in nine months,
then he's going to come out ahead.
So that is a bet. This guy's making a
bet.
On the other side, they're kind of also
making a bet, but it's much less risky. So
the lender in this case is accepting an
exceptional rate at 20%.
So pretty much no matter what, they're
going to earn 20% or 1,000 ERG, which
sounds really great.
The real risk here for them is that the
1,000 ERG in this collateral is worth less
than the 500 SigmaUSD.
So that is just a very different risk
profile, in my opinion, a much smaller
one.
Unless ERG puts in a new low, I mean, the
last time it was this low was like 2020 or
2021.
Unless that happens, they're going to get
totally burned. This guy could get more
burned.
If ERG is kind of in the middle there, he
has to make that decision. Am I going to
pay back this loan, or am I just going to
let it get liquidated?
He could not be able to pay back the
loan. Depends on how responsible they are.
Yeah, so it's really just a risk
management tool.
And I really think that this is something
that will be used at some point, like by
miners.
Like, okay, you're mining this. If you
can get to that point where you can put
this away, you can put your ERG away
instead of selling for your electricity.
You can really capture a 20% increase in
your mining profits just by adding that
delay.
Same goes for duck pools. I would love to
see duck pools being used more.
Sometimes duck pools is nicer because
it's a little more liquid. You can always
get in and out.
This is a little bit nicer because you
have some fixed APR and often high APR.
Look at this guy.
Okay, yeah, so I just big shout out
because I know that this is simple and
effective and really kind of elegant.
Something that I struggle to understand
is why it isn't super popular.
Like, okay, there's only six of these
loan requests that are over
collateralized. There's a ton that are
under-collateralized.
And that just happens because, again,
people use things that don't have price
feeds or a price, or they just did some
token and they don't accept their dosage
or collateral, please.
You get it. But we can come over here and
look at active bonds.
There's actually several, more than
several.
Yeah, I just appreciate it. I think a lot
of these folks were smart.
I mean, especially those of you who did
it. Six months ago, 18 months ago, when
ERG was pretty high, you cashed out, you
secured some profit in SigmaUSD, and then
you lent it out, and then you're earning
an extra 20% or whatever that might have
been.
The details of your loan are just kind of
individualized.
So I really encourage people to check
this out. It's just a sound financial
tool.
I remember being really young, my parents
were teaching me about CDs, certificate of
deposit.
And they wanted me to put my money in to
an account that would earn, I think it was
like 6%.
And I just had a job mowing lawns and
stuff. And so it was like a couple hundred
bucks.
And I just thought, I was like, you want
me to do this for $6? Like, I'm not gonna
do that.
Well, this is a different game. And now
we have the tools to kind of be
independent.
And you don't have to give anybody a cut.
I already closed it. But I don't know if
you saw there. The fee for a bunch of
these loans was like $4.
OK, like that's really nothing. USD, 4.5
SigmaUSD.
I think it's like 1%. Might be 1% of the
loan amount. So think about that. It's way
less than your realtor, I'll tell you
that.
So head to sigmafy.app, play around,
check it out.
Put your loan request in there if you're
trying to go long and fulfill some of
these open ones if you're trying to secure
those profits and just lock in that APR.
All right, I'll see you guys around.