Welcome, welcome to the second weekly
Community Ergo AMA.
The new format that we're hosting
involves everybody here, which means if
you show up, be prepared to either ask
questions or listen or be asked questions.
Because it's an AMA for everybody and
it's a community and that's how it works.
We've got a nice crowd today with
Dmitriy, kushti, Byron and Anax, Anthony,
Grayman, Lex, Darkenberg, FAKU and Odi
Bocha.
So this is going to be great that
everybody's here. Thanks so much for
coming.
What's new guys? Anybody?
kushti, you're muted.
Nice company here. Yeah, a lot of new
face also.
It is great to see. We've got, Odie
actually just took over, if you can see,
where is he in this chart? He's over
there. Way over there. There, my finger's
pointing. He just took over the Sigmanauts
Twitter.
So hopefully we see some activity back
out of that Twitter. It's been dormant for
a little bit. So very excited to see what
he's going to bring to the table there.
Hopefully some eye vote for spiciness.
Some people don't like spiciness, but I
think that's the purpose. I think that
account can handle some things like that
that the main account potentially can't.
So looking forward to seeing what's coming
out of there.
How's your week been, guys?
Yeah, also nothing bad in spiciness,
right? So it's actually attractive. Yeah,
that's at some point creating dramas, but
the dramas unavoidable anyway, probably,
right?
It is, it is.
So why to have boring dramas if you can
have spicy dramas.
Oh boy, we'll see what Odi does later
today. He's just going to delete the
account like Joe does, just done. Oh, boy.
Yeah, no, that account could use some
dusting off, that's for sure. It's always
been through the hands of several people.
And everybody that's touched it has done
a great job and brought something
different and new. And I think everybody,
last I checked, everybody that's used it
still has access to it. So there's about
five people that can post it once and have
different voices. And it's a community
account. It perfectly fits that bill, so
looking forward to that, Odie. See what
you bring to the table.
What's new on my part? It's been a busy
week here around. We've had my airport
bots actually went offline for a week or
two, and I had to bring those back up.
There was some NGINX issue.
But infra machines are in the back of my
car, all boxed up that I showed you last
week and ready to be shipped out. I just
have to swing by USPS on the way home by
today, tomorrow, Friday. So those guys
should see that and we'll get an increase
to the P2P.
Infrastructure, I spoke with Mark Glasgow
over the week, and I think the next target
is to infra the ergoplatform.org website
completely, ergoplatform.com, simply
because Google charges us right up the ass
for hosting. It's pretty bad. So if we can
infer that and get that off that, that'll
save a cost to the EF and move it to the
community, which is fantastic.
Slowly moving in that direction. And on a
side note as well for the educational
stuff that we were talking about last
week, I've further integrated more LLMs
into at least my school side here. So
getting more practice to what it's going
to be like in automation when we finally
move on to doing that with Ergo platform
content and videos and all that kind of
stuff.
So really looking forward to that, but
I'm pacing myself. I don't want to start
another task before we finish up and get
the infrastructure DAO fully stabilized.
So yeah, trying to pace that up.
What about you guys? kushti, what's new?
So busy, as usual, composing some text
also will post in the main Telegram chat
just after the call. So other than that,
yeah, so busy developing and managing
developers in different ways, different
projects. So yeah, that's more or less it.
Let's bang through the dev updates that
were yesterday real quick. I'll read them
off and maybe there's something to chat
about there.
All right. Incoming screen share, folks.
There we go. All right. So kushti
yesterday, 9.06 AM, Ergo protocol and
reference client RND.
We reviewed 6.0 changes in Node, made PR
with some minor improvements, polished and
proposed for review second PR. Towards sub
blocks now in Sigma SDK, will be merged
after design doc discussion and approval.
Next for Sigma, plan refactoring and
extensible context to reuse our
programmable money engine and side chain,
off-chain environments, et cetera. And
testing along with Potato and improving
P2P layer for sub-blocks.
Is Potato running a DevNet, kushti, is
that what it is?
So I'm running seed nodes and he is
joining and then reporting. Yes, some
issues. Yeah, well, the last one. So I'm
also joining with my nodes. So sometimes
it's about three nodes, sometimes two. And
yeah, well, so issues he has sometimes not
reproducible on my site.
kushti, how far away geologically is he
from you? I'm wondering how that affects
node synchronization with faster
sub-blocks.
Yeah, but I don't know. Oh, wait. So
Sydney is in Hetzner, Germany data center,
probably. And then Potato, I don't know,
probably late in America.
Somewhat but yeah that's a good span
that's a good test i think that's my guess
yeah so but also our devnet is kind of
extreme so it has blocks every 30 seconds
so and yes 60 sub blocks per block so yeah
it means two sub blocks a second even so
it's it's quite intense
Oh wow so you kept you kept the 30 second
pinet when you moved to devnet and applied
sub blocks there that's pretty extreme
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, but that's good for
testing also.
Yeah. All right. Then you got GitCircles.
You reviewed and merged a pull. You've
agreed to use Ergo addresses instead of
C256K1 and Wish You Balance is improving
implementation. Who's Wish You Balance?
Yeah, so a couple of new developers, so
yeah, BroEtiquette and Wish You Balance.
Yeah, so Wish You Balance is actually a
good cycles idea author, and yeah,
BroEtiquette is, well, some contributor.
So, yeah, I'm actually just reporting
what they are doing mostly. So, yeah, it's
the project after all. And, yeah, so
GitCircles is a project to create kind of
community currencies, but for digital
development communities where you get
tokens for committing to some
repositories.
And yeah, so we will start testing,
creating well, talking manually and doing
some testing transactions manually also,
just like few days and then yeah, the
development is going on. So there is a Git
bot already done as well as persistence
layer. So the next step is some GitHub
application and the Ergo half chain site.
And you think this would ever be able to
implement something like a DAO integration
into Git circles to where if something is
approved on a DAO, if a merge request from
a GitHub repository is approved on the DAO
vote, then an off-chain bot executes a
push or a pull for that GitHub PR request
automatically kind of thing. Yeah, so PRs
are then voted on in the DAO, and then the
off-chain bot executes that push, that
change.
So actually, open source communities
already acting as DAOs, right, just
off-chain. Usually some rules, some
maintainers, which are accepting what's
going to be merged into the main code
base, right? And then everyone can come
and propose a pull request, but not every
pull request would be merged and so on.
Then, yeah, well, it's kind of like hard
topic rights, governance and open source
communities. For example, Linux rights,
it's hard to imagine still 30 years after
its development without the single leader.
So it's a big question how Linux would be
developed without Linux right tools. And
so on.
So yeah, the same dependency is typical
for many open source communities. Yeah,
sometimes even programming languages and
so on. But yeah, well, in some cases, it's
more or less polycentric like bitcoin
rights where there are like five
developers yeah maybe the different number
now which can merge
And yeah, there is no single leader
officially, right? But yeah, in practice,
it's about one or two guys, after all, who
are making the most major decisions.
That's typical for DAOs, on-chain DAOs
also, right?
So when you have DAOs usually, yeah,
there are some, how to say, opinion
leaders, right? So it's actually a quite
interesting topic. So would it make sense
to bring already existing kind of DAO
structures like open source communities on
chain, right? And to try to build on-chain
DAOs or not, maybe off-chain options are
more flexible actually.
What was that, Grayman?
I was just saying they barely get
anything done. I mean, look at all this
debate over the OP_RETURNs issue. It's not
like they're, you know, significantly
changing the structure of the thing. When
is Bitcoin going to get to 1.0?
Yeah, but sometimes I think people are
dramatic there just to get a feeling of
importance right and also get recognized
for more and then church for her
consultancy and her appearance at
conferences and so on.
So yeah, well, I witnessed the first
OP_RETURNs drama a little bit back in
2014-15. And yeah, it also was more or
less the same, so a lot of unnecessary
dramatic talks and yeah, so some guys
hitting the discussions on purpose, I
guess, in order to get more recognition.
There's also just the drama of the big
blocks and the schism, right? And it's all
just over one little parameter. It's not
like it's substantially changing the
nature of the technology.
Before NIPoPoWs, Ergo was different than
it is now. That changed things in a very
substantial way because it enables light
clients that have full security. So now my
phone can be used without the same
assumptions that come from spooling up a
lightning channel.
And so how would anything like that be
implemented in Bitcoin given their current
governance and way of developing things?
Yeah, probably. No chance in Ergo. Yeah,
so we have NIPoPoWs support from day one,
right? So just, well, support and clients
was lagging for some time, but yeah, the
core structure was there.
But yeah, well, for Bitcoin, there are
talks since 2012 about doing QTX or
commitments, which are allowing for
actually a lot of protocols and blockchain
pruning and support for light clients,
even if they still have to download all
the headers. In the absence of, new
proposals, but, yeah, still, because all
the energy spent on, some constants, like
block size.
It feels like we're still in our age of
heroes, part of development and that it's
very hard to put that into a box of
governance and you know, eventually you've
got to get there. I hear what you're
saying. Ultimately, the goal is to write
yourself out of a job so that you're no
longer necessary.
But there are a number of people in this
community that are really carrying a lot
of water up the hill. And that kind of is
the way it has to be. It sort of self
forms a government and people ask each
other for help.
Because we don't have VC funding, so we
don't have daddy that we go to and ask to
keep handing out dollar bills for us to go
and buy some new machine or do some new
approach. We just have each other. And so
the governance kind of self forms.
But in the long run, if you end up like
Bitcoin, it's just ossified. It's
controlled by a group of people that
everybody agrees are sufficiently
undemanding and unchallenging that you can
just argue about things like OP_RETURNs
and not have the thing grow or change. And
they'll say that that's because they just
want to be conservative. But Bitcoin's
unfinished and getting pretty old.
Yeah, and, yeah, so in, in early, years,
2009, 10, so yeah, they, they actually,
were quite. Yeah, quite radical even,
right? About changes. But then, yeah,
well, endless wars started and they ended
up with the current state where it's not
possible to change anything in the
protocol, basically. Especially if not
proposed by certain developers.
Like one or two of them. So, yeah, so
it's quite interesting. But yeah, in case
of VCs, I think it's simple, right? So, I
mean, there is some organization which is
paying developers and making all the
decisions. But then, yeah, it's not, it's
It's not about community, right? So if
such term is used, so it's a little bit
fake community always, I think. Right. And
yeah, it's always controlled by who is
signing checks.
Hey, guys. I wanted to add something a
bit about community. First of all, it's
super great to talk to you all because I
have been following for a very long time.
And now it's super great to speak and at
least to be a little bit more in person
with you than usually on Twitter or
somewhere else.
The project that I've been building is
MindHealer. And what I wanted to point out
is that building was one thing, and now
the most important part is marketing and
community. And it's a whole different
story, and it has its own challenges.
And the challenges are pretty unexpected,
not what I was thinking it would be.
Provided that I'm also a therapist and I
have lots of connections and friends, and
I thought it would have been much easier.
But people are very reluctant because of
this impression, because of this, you
know, what people usually think about
cryptocurrencies, like scam or something
else.
And those who don't have any experience,
they are very reluctant to join and to
try. And so what I'm currently thinking of
is that we have one-to-one calls at
MindHealer. So people can have one-to-one
consultations. And what I'm doing right
now is there would be group calls as well.
So they could have like seminars or
something like that. And my goal is to to
make maybe some three educational classes
about ergo for specialists who would come
so they will have understanding how it
works etc etc and over time they will
start using it more and more.
But something that the community could be
really interested in is that I was
thinking, since there is such huge demand
on money that is decentralized, that is
not attached to this or that country,
maybe we should try and accelerate some
adoption because, for instance, I'm
currently in Brazil, but I've lived in
several countries.
And it's super hard when you move to a
different country because you have to buy
a different SIM card. Work with banks. In
Brazil, banks can close your account
anytime without any without anything. They
just closed the account saying, you know,
we had maybe you didn't pay your taxes,
maybe something else. So we closed your
account. Why? Well, I don't know. Just go
to the bank and ask them.
And it's, well, that's the way things
are. And when you move from country to
country over time, it's a really huge,
huge difficulty. So what I thought maybe
we could try and again, with the
community, try to increase the community.
So there are some bloggers who could
potentially be very helpful, who could
work for us the way, who could do the same
job for us that Roger Ver did in 2012 for
Bitcoin. So they could be ambassadors
filming how they onboard people into Ergo,
something like that.
Again, it's for community to think about
it. But I really like the idea, and I
suggest that in the Russian Telegram
group. And people are kind of interesting,
interesting, not sure. So currently I'm
asking, and let's see how it goes with the
bloggers, I mean.
You're suggesting hiring bloggers and
that kind of thing?
Maybe hiring, maybe inviting them to join
the community so they would promote Ergo,
kind of like reality shows.
So things that I found that those people
have zero interest unless you feed them
funds and money. That's what I've run
across with actually every outreach. There
are a few, like when we started the, when
dev updates a couple of years ago, I
started trying to just get influencers as
interviewers.
It was kind of a tactic to be like, hey,
come talk about crypto in your sphere and
what it's like, and also try to educate
them on Ergo in the meantime. And it was
interesting talking to some of these
people. And most of the people, or
actually all of the people I talked to,
were more on the up and coming kind of
thing.
You know, from the Cardano side at least,
trying to get that kind of exposure. Even,
what can I say? There's very little time
or interest that they have unless there's
something in it for them. I guess there's
a kind way to say it, right?
So it's hard to convince somebody like
that to be altruistic and come to a
project that is altruistic and open
source, right? And peer to peer, where
there's no site for them in the future to
potentially make a ton of money off it.
That's what I found. So it's a tough
balance.
Like look at how much Cardano paid SNEC
or whoever on Cardano paid, SNEC paid,
what's that guy's name, that influencer
with the long hair that he cut short
recently. Like they paid him, I think the
number is 40 grand, I think I heard
secretly that the number was $40,000.
Yeah, exactly. They paid him 40-50 grand
to start promoting SNK and probably gave
him a bunch of SNK as well. So is it worth
it?
I don't know. But that's about so-called
crypto bloggers, crypto KOLs, right? And
usually those are totally retarded and
greedy bastards and yeah they're not
creating valuable content even right but
see if I understand the Dimitri's idea
right so the idea is to have some
borderless enthusiasts also bloggers right
and do some videos like how i make my
money with just gpu right then how i can
bring it to africa right latin america
without well any control and then use
there
I can mine my digital gold but yeah I can
also add... I can also convert it to
stable value, right? Using stable coins,
well, gold packs, USD packs. And yeah,
well, also it's possible to do a crown
funding, right? For a blogger. Because
yeah, well, many of them are actually
doing something like the day trips. I
mean, they're like travel bloggers.
The issue isn't necessarily all with
KOLs, it's that the popularity for KOLs
exists, right? So the issue is 90% of the
communities in crypto, and I don't know,
maybe even more, they're of the mindset of
we're playing with casinos, right?
I mean, look at this. It's so disgusting
that look at the incident that happened
yesterday in the US with the
assassination. There were gosh darn meme
coins that were tripping off at $1.5
million in volume with this guy's name on
it that just got assassinated. That's what
these KOLs are targeting. They're
targeting get rich casinos.
But the point is that there is no need to
spend energy, time and money on those
so-called crypto people. The idea is to
get ordinary people to trust some
decentralized money.
Because the issue is that those calls,
well, aside of some, well, Bitcoin boxes,
right, with like big experience, right,
some of this, so usually they are getting
checks from VCs rights to promote some,
well, not so decentralized, let's say
politely, kinds of assets, right?
So, yeah, the idea is to avoid this at
all and, yeah, attach to like ordinary
people. Because, well, we cannot fight,
right, with so-called crypto. We can just
build some alternative or original,
actually, vision, right?
Right, right. So that's a thought,
kushti. When you get a baseline with what
Dmitriy is talking about, you have to try
to understand right from the get-go who
we're trying to attract. Are we trying to
attract more like buying people like us
who are in crypto for the decentralized
peer-to-peer nature of what ergo is and
what crypto should be. Or are we trying to
attract people to pump the price of ergo,
right? So if that's established at the
beginning, then you can target who you
want speaking for it.
I wanted to tell you about the audience
that I was keeping in mind. So I dropped a
link to one of the guys that I got in
touch with, and why I got in touch with
that guy, because there is a huge... I
mean, I just was thinking about one
community. I'm Russian, so I was thinking
about Russian community, Russian-speaking
community.
What's very particular about it is that
there is a huge, several hundred thousand
people who want money that is not attached
to any particular government. They just
want money. They sometimes want to sell an
apartment here and buy it there. So their
needs are very basic.
And all they know is they know about
Binance and how to use it. That's the best
case scenario. Sometimes they know even
less. They don't know anything about
decentralization. They don't know anything
about this. So they basically want money.
And I was thinking about the audience,
and those trial bloggers, they really
don't know the difference between
centralized and decentralized. We can
basically showcase Ergo to a new audience
and to show that it is cheap. People can
make money transfers, they can use it. And
then little by little, we can educate them
through those bloggers.
Again, we can do it differently. We
should target bloggers that are not
exposed to crypto at all. So they might
have a wallet for donations, but nothing
more than that. And we can make
competition for bloggers because people
who travel, they are not usually very...
So their prices are not very high, let's
put it like that.
And we can make a competition, for
instance, best explanatory video of how to
install an Ergo Wallet app and how to pay
for something on the road or something
like that.
Yeah, that stuff works well, I think. And
kushti also spoke a little bit about the
other method, too. And you were touching
on this, too, Dmitriy, where you're not
necessarily getting an influencer, but
you're finding a leader of a project
somewhere in another country that could
utilize decentralized finance and then
maybe make them a mouthpiece for it
online, not just for Ergo, but for
utilizing decentralized peer-to-peer
finance to accomplish what they're doing
and using Ergo in the meantime to do it.
So I think, yeah. Those are great. Those
are great ideas.
Yeah but also, so, yeah. Had a talk with,
Wish You Balance, again, GitCircles, guy
recently. So yeah, what's, the plan, right
is to, yeah, first to test it and then, to
do kind of an airdrop to existing
developer communities, right?
So in the first place to some Rust
framework building communities for
frameworks used in it's circles and so on.
All right, so the idea is to issue token,
right, and to invite people to get them
and well, yeah, then it's at least
contribution. Accounting kind of tool,
right?
But then, yeah, it's not that hard to
start to attach economies, right? Well,
invite sponsors, draw some sponsors and so
on. I'm willing to put some money maybe
into liquidity pools just, right? Well,
you can just reuse existing tooling. And
so on. But yeah, the idea is to target
developers, right? Not crypto people
because, well, what's the point in dealing
with so-called crypto?
I mean, it's just you know, when you are
dealing with people in crypto, it's mostly
like a competition who is louder, who is
shouting a marketing buzz at the most
noisy level. And yeah, it's better to grab
people from outside, right? And bring to
build, especially developers, right? Bring
to build new economies.
Ben, you don't have to raise your hand.
Just jump in, man. It's community.
Well, so I don't necessarily want to
change the subject, but I want to shift
the focus a little bit. When I'm on X and
I see an ergo raffle for trying to do a
Maxi listing, which I think was one of the
ones that was up there the last couple of
months, there's something in maybe this is
because I'm not crypto enough.
But I think being here is something. But
if I was able to Apple pay $10 from my
bank account to an ergo raffle, I would
participate in 10 times the ergo raffles
that I already participate in, right?
And it's also like if I could just Apple
pay to an ergo raffle, it kind of turns
into more of a go fund me thing rather
than, hey, I need to see this raffle. I
need to remember this raffle. Then I need
to go to Coinbase, I need to buy some sort
of coin and then I need to go to another
exchange to swap that from whatever coin I
chose to ERG and then finally I need to
shift that from the exchange platform to
my ergo wallet and then get that money to
the ergo raffle.
In one, this is a it's more of a, hey, I
want to support the ergo community, but I
don't want to go through 30 minutes of
problems to be able to donate $10 to this
raffle. So is there a way that you can and
once again, I'm not a super dev or
anything. I can't do this, right?
But is there a way that we can make it so
that you could kind of turn ergo raffle
into a GoFundMe type platform, but also
have it have ergo branding to increase
brand awareness?
Because the problem in crypto and
particularly with ergo, is nobody knows
what it is. I mean, there's a few of us
who, I mean, for me, it was in 2021, I
heard the Charles Hoskinson Lex Friedman
podcast. He mentioned Ergo. In about 2022,
I started really getting into Ergo and
believed in the mission.
So I got my first set of ergo i've been a
part of the community in the last few
months i've kind of fallen off because you
know sometimes real life gets in the way
of of you know my crypto journey but it's
like the the issue isn't with
The community size, it's too complicated
to be an ergo user, simply put. Back in
the day, I was buying ADA on Coinbase.
sending it to KuCoin, swapping my ADA for
Ergo on KuCoin, sending it to my wallet.
And then it's like, am I really going to
go through all that effort and then donate
my Ergo?
Maybe I'm just speaking in circles. I
don't know if anyone has anything to add
off of that, but it's simply put, it's too
difficult to be an Ergo user.
So you're in the US, I assume, Ben?
Yeah.
Yeah. So when I first got into Ergo as
well, Ergo felt like a scarce resource,
right? Because it was a pain to get into
the US. And I'm from New York, which is
even more restrictive, right? I had to use
a Florida address from my wife's account
that lived there to purchase Ergo from
Coinbase early on, or ADA, and then do the
same path you did until they cut us off
KuCoin.
So there's an accessibility issue right
there. I agree. But my question is to you,
what do we how are we framing that? So
there's no accountability in raffles where
there's something like Apple PayLink with
cash, right?
So let's take, for example, that Ergo
raffle setup where you could donate ERGs
or here's an Apple PayLink to a cash
account, right? On Ergo raffle, we can see
exactly what happens to the ERG after the
raffle finishes. It goes to a wallet. It's
used. It's locked. Whatever who's using it
kind of thing. And with raffle two we'll
see tokens be able to do that as well. But
with the fiat there's no trail
accountability or anything right. I guess
you could demand that you see it here on
chain after that or or what it's used for
some accountants it's
And I appreciate your sentiment towards
transparency. But at a certain point, it's
like, we trust that GoFundMe is going to
send the funds that we send to GoFundMe to
the user. And I know this is a big thing.
You shouldn't trust. You should verify.
But at a certain point, when does
verification become an inhibitor towards
growth of a product.
Right, so I can see immediately when you
were speaking, ideas came to mind, like,
if we want to reach the broader community
as a Sigmanauts and we're fundraising for
something like the Ergo Meetup, I agree.
There could be, you know, here's a raffle
to fundraise this and here's a GoFundMe as
well for people who want to donate fiat.
So I think that's a great idea, for sure.
But here's the problem. The base of your
idea is accessibility, which, you know,
it's always been a strain, a rough thing
for Ergo, for sure.
Yeah, I also think... Yeah, sorry. Go
ahead, man.
No, go ahead. Go ahead.
So I think this is the perfect example,
actually. And yeah, it makes sense to
maybe make a list, right, of such like
tests, right, for accessibility. And then,
yeah, so for Ruffle, in particular, also,
what's doable?
So I think, well, not sure when but this
is achievable so first we need for raffle
version 2 right to have stable coins and
then yeah some breach where you can get
stable coins supported on ergo in exchange
of Apple Pay payments, right?
But as Grayman said in comments, so yeah,
that there is HQ already with the VoltPay.
So maybe is it supporting Apple Pay?
Probably not, right?
No, it does not. Yeah, well, and you can
get gift cards out. But yeah, we go from
the conventional financial world and into
ergo. then Banksa is our best bet in the
United States currently.
It's not outrageous the way that they
operate, but setting up something so that
you could just click a button and have
your $10 Apple Pay go into a raffle I
mean, it's just UI, UX development. The
fact that the backend is a raffle is good
for traceability. That doesn't need to be
in conflict.
In fact, it could just be a value add,
but it's not being added to anything right
now because in order to participate in an
Ergo raffle, you have to be an Ergonaut.
You have to hold Ergo in a wallet and
understand how to use it.
I think Ben's making some good points.
And I applaud you for going out on a limb
and doing that, Ben, on video, because we
need somebody to stand up from that
perspective.
And say, hey, look, this is not about the
latest technical nuance so much as it is
about making it super easy to get people
involved. I also like what Dmitriy was
saying earlier. At first, I was sort of
dismissing it, but then I got his point.
Let's talk to communities outside of Ergo
and get those people to be interested for
a variety of reasons and that'll you know
any any way that you can connect the real
world and other communities into it that's
great but then ben said hey look that's
all well and good but then they're going
to have to go through this process of
setting up a wallet and all these other
things it's a friction that we need to
overcome and the only way to overcome it
is to
Apply lubricant, right? And that's a UI
UX dev issue, and that's hard to do. You
know, kushti's given me the thumbs up here
because you can't push a rope. I mean,
he's developing, you know, the next
innovations in the core and the node.
It's hard for him to switch from that
into being somebody that writes a bot that
works with X to press a button and then
suddenly you get an Apple pay that goes to
a particular, all you have to do is sign
it, right? That would be nice, but it has
to be done.
Sounds like a skill issue for kushti.
We need to get HQ on this call. Where has
he been? He's probably with his little
one.
He's in Pakistan probably still.
Interesting.
Yeah, helping some victims of floods.
The floods there are outrageous. Yeah,
outrageous, crazy. Himalayas are some of
the newest mountains in the world, and boy
are they unstable. When it rains hard, it
is hell to pay.
So I'm interested to do a test, really. I
think there's probably some fundraising
opportunities and the things we can do.
Oh, sorry.
No, no, I think it'd be neat. I think,
Ben, I think we're gonna, I think I'll
integrate that into at least the tech side
of Next Ergo Raffle that the SIGs do is do
a side go fund me for it for fiat users
and we'll see what happens. I think it's a
good idea, see what happens.
I mean, I'm ready to take criticism by
like, oh, you're a crypto group and you're
still using fiat to direct fiat payments
kind of thing. So that's fine, I think,
but yeah.
Well, it's also like, the fact of the
matter is crypto is great, and I love the
idea in the community, but God is it a
pain in the ass to use. If I could, I'd go
to the local pizza shop and pay with my
ERG. That'd be great. But that's so many
steps. That's why when
I haven't kept up with this, but Tabi
POS, that was super interesting to me. It
was like the first real, and I don't know
what the deal with Tabi POS is currently,
but it was the first real blockchain
product that I saw that was like, oh, this
is actually useful in real life.
It's like, you know, DEXes are cool, kind
of useless to a regular person. A lot of
these things are really, and I understand
that DEXes are important on the backend to
make a lot of things work. I get that. But
to a regular user, to a regular person, no
one cares about a DEX.
Like, my dad, for example, isn't going to
be like, oh, my God, look at all these
features that this really cool DEX on Ergo
has, right? That's not taking away from
the quality of these things, right? But
it's just a fact that
60-something-year-old people
Who see Bitcoin and they're like, oh my
God, Bitcoin's a way for me to preserve my
wealth over time. Great, but then you get
like, that's like layer one, and then
like, ergo's down here at like layer
seven. And I appreciate ergo for being at
layer seven, but the layman,
Is just like money Bitcoin, money
Bitcoin, money Bitcoin. And they're never
going to use their Bitcoin in real life.
Right, Ben. So Ergo's had that, that's a
good reality check. I think Ergo's
slightly aware of that and Devs are, and
you'll see that in some of the products
that come out, is that they are
transparent to the user, right?
So like MGPi's team was originally
working on a ticketing system that allows
concert tickets and things, Lilium, right?
So that you could, you know, you could
have on-chain governance of your ticket
system. And the normal user wouldn't know.
They just download an app that had an
integrated wallet that passed the tokens
back and forth kind of thing.
So I agree. I think when developers
develop, they should keep that in mind,
especially in Ergo, that people might not
want to know that they're holding Ergo per
se, but they want to know that they're
holding a product. They're using a product
that uses some crazy stable security and
peer-to-peer network that their data and
their value is safe.
Yeah. And once again, I'm speaking out of
hand because I don't have the experience
to implement any of this. So if any of
this is bullshit, I'm sure some of it can
be. But it's, hey, you get them in with
the Apple Pay GoFundMe type thing. And
then that gives you the opportunity to
educate people, meeting them where they
are, rather than trying to...
It's like if I'm in New York City and
you're in, I don't know, Woodstock, New
York, it's like, how am I going to get you
from Woodstock to New York City? It's, I
don't even know you, right? Like, I'm not
gonna be like, hey, come to New York City
and you're gonna come to New York City.
That's not gonna happen.
Well, you brought up some really good
points, Ben. Likewise, the Grayman about
the stuff he was saying. But I think it's
more or less a product of the time,
because if you rewind time, older people
kind of had a distaste for the internet.
Now, if you log on to Facebook, that's
where they hang out.
So I think it's more of a UI thing, like
what Grayman would say is the ease of
access. And then also to what qx() was
saying about the criticism from going from
fiat real to dual purpose. I don't see
that as a valid criticism at all, because
for us to even get into Ergo, you have to
go from your bank account to dual purpose,
right?
So it's like, using Ben's point, which is
a good point. That's not a criticism
because people are They already if you're
donating to a go fund me. It's a purpose
attached to that go fund me So I don't
even see it as a valid criticism to say
that hey people want to use their dollars
for their ecosystem debt So that's not
even a valid criticism to me.
It's a medium of exchange I'm excited to
try that method out Byron. I think it
would be an experiment
Yeah, so, from our developers point of
view, I think, well, there are, multiple,
steps still right to, to get to the, but
so possible after all. So, what's needs
probably is, to. Yeah, well, maybe at
least what steps are needed now, right,
and then reduce one by one.
So I think with Ruffle version 2, it
would be better already, right, with
stable coin support. But then, yeah, well,
there is need for more bridges, right, to
get from Apple Pay in particular to stable
coins on Ergo. After all, it's possible.
I think there needs to be an easier
version of something like, what's the name
of, what's the name of bisque? There needs
to be an easier version of bisque, but for
fiat, right? So essentially imagine,
imagine a GoFundMe as an on-ramp, right?
So everybody donates a certain amount to
GoFundMe, a hundred bucks. So you call it
the DCA GoFundMe, right? Dollar cost
averaging GoFundMe. Everybody donates $100
and puts their address in their donation
comment. And then some party or some DAO
is then in control of that GoFundMe and
then brings that liquidity on chain and
deposits the DCA into the person's wallets
that they designated on the GoFundMe.
So there's probably some legal
implications involved there, but I'm sure
there's a country that can handle that
where this crypto is not tracked or taxed
as far as that goes. Things like that
would be a really easy entry point for
Apple Pay users on GoFundMe.
It might be a little more expensive to
get on chain, but you could say, yep,
here's a DCA GoFundMe. It rolls every
month. Every month we push it out and get
in with how many ever dollar, $10
increments that you can, and we'll put it
up there. I think that things like that
would be very interesting.
Yeah, sorry.
I was just going to say that if I could
buy an ERG on Coinbase, I'd pay a pretty
premium to be able to buy that ERG on
Coinbase.
Have you tried Banksa?
What? Have you tried Banksa, the new Fiat
OnRamp wallet integration?
No. To be honest with you, I have been
focused on real life. So two years ago, I
got really unhealthy. And that's when I
was at maximum crypto mode. I was just in
my basement all the time. 45 pounds
heavier than I am right now like I was
just super unhealthy and since then I've
kind of Not stepped away from crypto like
I still hold all my crypto but Like slowly
I've been getting back into it so I have
no idea what's going on right now But it's
like Even if there is this new Fiat on
ramp
If I have to make an account, I don't
want to do that. I'd rather pay an extra
10, 15 cents per ERG than make a new
account somewhere.
You know what I mean? Interesting. Yeah,
gotcha. I hear you. Yeah. I think people
who have been in crypto for a while forget
about that.
If you think back to when you first got
into crypto, I remember thinking, if I
want to be in ADA, if I want to be in
Ethereum, if I want to be in Ergo, I hate
the thought of having three wallets and 20
different seed phrases and that kind of
thing. It bugged the hell out of me. I
wanted to see everything in one spot.
And that's a big attraction of central
exchanges to new users, right? Now that
we've been in crypto for many, many years,
that doesn't bug me very much at all. It's
just how it works. But we can't forget
that. You're right, Ben. That's very
attractive to new users that you just log
in somewhere. There's all your stuff with
many different chains. You don't even have
to know they're different chains and going
from there.
Byron, your hand's up. Go for it. No need
to raise your hand. Just jump in. Be rude.
Interrupt. Go for it.
You scared me. Maybe it's an accident.
He's like, oh shit. I didn't mean to have
my hand up. I think it's connections
lagging a little bit, perhaps.
But yeah, while he chimes in, I was going
to jump in and say like, Bitcoin's been
around for how many years and the ease of
using it to pay today is still a barrier,
no matter how popular it is. So I think
it's more or less a function of time than
like, you know so it's like the criticisms
is kind of i get it though i definitely
get it
Yeah guys let me ask you something it's
just a theoretical question in terms of
difficulty of development. So we have
Rosen Bridge. And for instance, there is
an Ergo raffle. And is it possible to
invite people to participate in a raffle
or in crowdfunding something via Rosen
Bridge so they wouldn't have so they would
be able to pay like with Bitcoin to take
part into or with something else?
If the liquidity pools existed 100%, you
could even make all the things end up on
Ergo if you wanted to. So you could
essentially have a...
Thank you, Randy.
All right, so we got our first troll of
the show. Luckily we have his face. We
could post it somewhere and shame him.
What an asshole.
Anyway, moving on.
That might also just be some video that
he put up there.
Oh, yeah, yeah, it's not his, I'm sure. I
know. He was white. He was white. The
person in the video was not white.
Why is there a video on his phone?
I think maybe we ought to cut the feed
for YouTube before we get in trouble. I
don't know. It's already there.
Andy can clip it. Andy can clip it. It's
not a big deal. All right. So before I was
distracted, I even forgot what the hell I
was going to say. Dmitriy, what were you
saying?
Oh, yes. So some, yeah, so cross-chain.
Yeah, so as long as the liquidity is
available on both sides, Dmitriy, so let's
say you want to do a raffle and broadcast
Ethereum, Binance, all those things, but
you want to use the funds on Ergo. As long
as those liquidity pools exist, then Rosen
could develop, essentially, except tokens
and Ethereum. It goes into a wallet and
then automatically transfers across the
bridge at the end of the raffle once it
knows that it's a certain amount.
So yeah, development-wise, it's totally
possible and would be totally neat. Or you
could, yeah, yeah, that would be really
neat. Yeah. I'm still a little
shell-shocked from that. It's 10 o'clock.
Maybe we should end on a good point.
No, don't end it yet. I want to do an
advertisement that will tie it all
together.
It's for the Autolykos DAO and Venture
Capital Collective, which is formed
recently on Ergo. It's a project being led
by LifeOfIFA. And it's an experiment in
doing governance on chain in ergo in a
sort of standard corporate form.
And it's a situation where there's a
token, which is called Lykos, which
essentially represents a share in this
enterprise. And it's been through the seed
round. The next round is the sow round.
And then the round after that is where we
start funding projects.
And the first project is a payment
gateway. And I think there have been a
number of things that we need to take into
account when we end up developing a spec
for that, one of them being that mixing
would be involved.
But I think another would be that it
would actually be a way to accept and
process payment from Fiat into any other
currency, I guess, again, assuming that
you've got the liquidity to support that.
So that's my little advertisement for
Autolykos.
It's permissionless, so you don't need my
permission to join, but maybe some
encouragement. The So Round's coming up
soon, so keep an eye out for it.
Awesome.
Very cool. And I think we missed those
two things I just want to mention as well
that we missed on the dev update. Nautilus
wallet has some stuff that came out.
FleetSDK upgrades. Nautilus is
investigating ledger connection issue.
Machina Finance is finishing limit orders
on unit tests.
Also, with speaking of spam, like we just
had spam troll just now. Ergo's had a
couple airdrops recently of fake tokens or
tokens that lead you to a fake site that
want to try to get you to connect your
wallet to.
So just a reminder to everybody that
Nautilus has those baked in, ignore spam
tokens, ignore NSFW tokens, because those
come as well. So if you have those
clicked, and I think they're clicked by
default, the Sigmanauts and Ergo Explorer
communities mark
Tokens of spam as they come in and
they're automatically hidden from your
wallet so you'll never even see them if
you utilize Nautilus for that. And then
you can use Terminus wallet a mobile
wallet to burn them if you want to as well
which is great and I think you has a burn
option on their site as well if I'm not
mistaken. So just keep in mind
Nautilus is also going to integrate on
that community list, we're going to start
putting addresses there that are known
scammers so that when you send, when you
try to send funds to a known scammer
address that the community's marked as a
known scanner,
Nautilus won't stop you per se, but the
idea is to pop up a little message that
says, hey, buddy, this address has been
marked by the community as a known asshole
or a known scammer or whatever. Are you
sure you want to do this? And maybe a
default check to no, and then you have to
yes and confirm it kind of thing.
So that's a new thing coming out of
Nautilus at some point in the future with
these community lists. If you are up at 3
a.m. and you recognize that a spam token
went out and nobody else is awake, go
ahead and submit a PR to our GitHub or go
to ErgExplorer and find that token and
mark it as a scam as well or pop it in
chat. Someone will take care of it this
morning. We're a community and it's up to
us to keep each other safe for that kind
of thing.
All right, everybody.
Actually, there are more updates. There
is also a reworked basis contract and we
have some new developers contributing
there as well. Yeah, well, let's discuss
during the next call maybe.
Yeah, yeah, there's Basis right there.
There's Cyberverse Update Report as well.
Cyberverse and Moja. So yeah, let's
discuss during the next call.
Yeah, sounds good.
It's always awesome to talk about Ergo.
Every week, man. I hope to see you every
week, man. Come in. It's awesome to have
your opinion.
And join Autolykos, man.
Come talk to us on the radio.
Dude, I have to find my Ergo seed phrase
first.
Uh-oh.
Create a new wallet and send your shit to
it.
Well, that requires me finding my seed
phrase first. I think I got logged out of
Nautilus.
Oh. Okay. No, I'm not.
I'm not logged out of Nautilus. Great. So
make a new wallet and send it ASAP.
Yeah. Yep. Yep.
And everybody go to Colorado if you can.
Yes, I'm going to announce the first two
speakers. I'll announce maybe today or
tomorrow, the third speaker, three out of
three out of the six speakers or seven
speakers we have. Please come. It's going
to be a lot of fun. We're going to live
stream everything, but we'd love to have
you guys here in person.
The Twitter stuff.
Yes, thank you, Odi. August, October 11th
then. So people are showing up Friday,
October 11th is Saturday, and then there's
a breakfast, community breakfast thing on
Sunday as well if people are still around.
Yeah, it's gonna be fun.
Later. And everybody check out Dmitriy,
oh, he just left. He was developed, oh,
he's right there, your picture boy. Ah,
here, I'm here. Mind healer as well. I
poked around it kind of thing, but super,
super interesting idea, neat idea.
Thanks, thanks. Yeah, so let's discuss
MindHealer maybe also.
Yeah, hop into DevChat and talk about it
as well. Yeah, Grayman. Grayman will bring
it down. There's not enough ERG in the
world to support Grayman sessions.
All right, everybody, it's been awesome.
I love these community talks. I think
they're a step up in what ergo is, so
fantastic. kushti, any closing words?
Awesome atmosphere. Very pleasant talk.
Let's continue next week.
Great.
Ciao.
Thanks everyone.