Welcome Ergonauts to the July 31st 2025
episode of the AMA with a lot of Ergonaut
luminaries on board to educate you and
answer your questions.
If you are on YouTube, welcome. If you
want to ask questions, we will try to have
a look at the comments there. But if you
want to participate directly, please join
us on Zoom. Links are in the Discord or
the Telegram channels.
And without further ado, here is Mr. QX.
Are you going to pass it off to me?
Thanks for the intro. Fantastic. Well, I'm
on the road today, but still joining you.
If I crash, you'll witness firsthand the
first blockchain death. So that could be
something that would elevate Ergo to new
heights. But otherwise, yeah, please join
up.
The links are in the Telegram chat or the
recent Twitter post from Ergo platform.
kushti put up some topics for today. One
of them is Sigma Lock, so I can comment on
that real quickly before I pass it off to
kushti for the two topics that he popped
up and maybe wants to talk about.
We have not had any progress this week
with it. Last I talked to 4i's consulting,
they are going to push it to their
reversal for sigma testing. The domain is
already, it's going to be sigma lock at
sigmanauts.com. That's a lot of sig, I
guess, right? But hey, you can't have too
much Sigmanauts.
And we're going to test it out in our
group first, just a little bit, and then
we'll release it to the wild once it gets
on to our permanent server. So looking
forward to that.
For those of you that don't know, we
used, we did a DAO vote in the Sigmanauts
two weeks ago to buy the kushti two-hour
token. And what that does is kushti put up
his own time on MewPhysicals, MewFinance.
Then you can buy a token which grants you
two hours of whatever you want to do with
kushti. I don't think you got specifics,
so if there's any time left over, I might
get creative. kushti, you better watch
out.
So we did a DAO vote and we spent 70,000
Mew, which is around 500 bucks at the
time. And we purchased two hours of kushti
time and the SigmaLock contracts are going
to be officially reviewed by kushti
himself. So that should bring us a little
bit of confidence into the actual platform
that we're trying to put forward here for
everybody to use. So we're really excited
about that.
And then on top of that, since kushti has
70,000 Mew now, if you guys didn't miss
the chat yesterday, he offered like
bounties for people willing to do videos
on MewFinance and MewPhysicals and the
things that MewPhysicals, the swap app
that you just made, all that kind of
stuff. So if you're looking to make some
cash and you do videos then reach out to
kushti and see his post there to see what
you can earn from doing that. But yeah
excited about the release of Sigma Lock
and looking forward to it.
Yeah, so I've announced three prizes for
20K Mew for creating tutorials on how to
use some new services, any of them because
I think like everything is not so well
covered with guides and tutorials at the
moment right. So yeah it could be text or
video so yeah please share in the
MewFinance group and Ergo platform group
and yeah I'll check them a bit later.
So yeah, well, I think we need for more
tutorials and yeah for more circulation,
right? So yeah, I mean somehow you make
those 70k Mew. Then, yeah, I've got them,
right. I'm paying for tutorials with them
and hopefully, yeah, the guys received
those Mew will do something further.
So, yeah, well, I think we need to do as
much as possible positive circulation of
different monetary value of ERGs and
tokens in the ecosystem. Yeah, so there
could be a lot of inventive ways. And
after all, as well, the ecosystem is not
that big now. So it's basically the same
money after all, right? Going circles,
making multiple hops, working efficiently,
right? So yeah, well the more circulation,
the more velocity, the more services being
created and sold along with condenser and
so on, the better for the ecosystem.
And kushti, something I use at work for
tutorial videos when I make them quite a
bit is I'll record the video, usually one
take as best I can so I don't have to
edit. And I'll push that video through
Whisper AI so I get a beautiful
transcript. And then I'll take a few
screenshots of different screens of the
video in order, and I will feed the
screenshots and the subtitle file into AI
again and ask it to make me written
tutorial on the spoken tutorial and it
does an amazing job. So if you're okay
with just hitting that record button and
recording a tutorial, you feed it through
AI the rest of the way and it makes a nice
set of written tutorials for you as well.
Right, and yeah, well, we need for some
experience, right, with Mew and other
services. So, Jimmy, maybe you can write
about your experience of selling Canon or
Mew. And QX, you sold some Mac, Mac what?
Mac Pros?
Yeah, yeah. We sold some Mac Pros. We
sold a Macbook. We're going to sell some
of those little Intel machines as well. So
we're going to keep at it for sure. Yep.
It's funny too, because the other day, I
think, I don't know if it's on Cardano or
whatnot, but I was reading a post, and I
think HQ actually commented on it, so
maybe HQ can speak more if that was him.
People were like, oh, you know, there's an
issue with the blockchain. You know,
everything's digital. We need a physical,
you know, way to sell and trade goods and
that kind of thing. So it's definitely
starting to have an awakening of people
thinking, hey, why can't we use these
tools for this? And I mean, of course,
like everything else, Ergo has it long
before everybody even thinks about it.
Right.
Also, we now have a lot of conversations
in the LETS group, so welcome. So, yeah,
we now have more people contributing and
brainstorming what to do because it's,
well, as I described a few times, quite
generic, right, to create, well, monetary
systems of quite different kind.
So yeah well currently hopefully well we
will come to some design of application
rights to try and yeah it would be good to
make some Ergo-based application for
trading rights, not necessarily using
SigmaUSD or ERG even, just maybe like IOUs
created on the fly, but yeah with
blockchain guarantees.
blockchain reserve sometimes and yeah
well we can think about some demos like do
some I don't know hopefully markets around
the Ergo meetup or visit some event like
such a market and yeah well trade with
such location there. So yeah or something
like that, so please join LETS.
Mark, how's the EF doing? Ergo hack's
over? You guys announced the winners and
everything?
Yeah, yeah, it's all done, all wrapped up
now and just on to the next thing. So
there's been a lot of trying to work out
the budget, trying to stretch it as far as
possible past the missions. And just keep
it going, keep the development and
infrastructure going as long as you can.
And yeah, apart from that, we've kind of
fallen back on the editorial the past few
months because our editor left due to
personal reasons. So the past month, I've
just been trying to blast out as many
articles as I can. And try to spread them
around different chats. So like the Lithos
and ChainCash and stuff, that's really
good to kind of pull people in if you get
into those spaces and can explain it.
So yeah, we should be trying to push that
kind of stuff out more, try to build up
our editorial more and kind of catch up on
that backlog in the past few weeks.
Have you tested out the Banxa integration
into the Nautilus wallet yet?
I have not and I've just seen a
screenshot, but I can't test anyway
because the UK has got these new crazy
laws that you need to be FCA approved or
send every tweet and blog post to a
company you pay like five grand a month to
approve everything. So it's just this
massive barrier. It makes us pretty much
the most restrictive place in the world
apart from sanctioned countries to provide
fiat ramps. But it's a big uproar.
Hopefully there'll be some, enough push to
kind of get it softened a bit. It came to
effect late last year. But yeah, it's a
bit of a pain that one.
Wow. Do you know if it's just, I didn't
look, but is the Banxa button or Buy ERG
button, does that just take you to the
Banxa page or do you do it inside the
Nautilus wallet?
I'm not sure what kind of level is going
to integrate it. I'm sure we could do it
to the wallet itself. We may just be doing
it the first way for quickness at the
moment to get out. But yeah, I think
ideally we'd want it integrated right in
to the UI.
What else we got guys?
As far as I remember, you need some
credentials to integrate Banxa and apps.
So you will need to partner with them and
you will need to kind of dox yourself. So
I'm not sure if Nautilus wants to do that,
or maybe EF would just get those
credentials for them to just integrate in
the wallet.
Yeah, they'd be getting it through us.
They've offered to give us the contract
and stuff with them.
Well, in that case, if I can use those
also, I can even add them to the post
chat, so people can directly buy from
there. Or even I can add Banxa page at
VoltPay page so if there are people who
want to KYC and buy with it they can also
buy it from there.
Yeah I'm looking to see if that's
something we can do.
Speaking of wallets Minotaur was also
released 3.0.1 for desktop and Android. I
don't think the iOS built this build,
right? I think you have to go get yourself
where it's not built. But for people who
haven't used Minotaur, it's a pretty
fantastic wallet. Just to have kind of a
personal standalone wallet, right? It
works really good on Android. It looks
pretty. They've integrated some new
changes for Multi-Sig as well in version 3
that make life a little bit easier. So I
encourage people to give it a test run.
Again, great wallet made by a great team.
What else is new, guys? kushti, how are
sub-blocks?
Going well, so I think there is need to
present some quite accessible writing,
right? So, well, I'm starting to work on
the white paper. Other than that, adding
some API methods and yesterday I realized
how to commit merge mined sidechain state
well quite efficiently using the current
API just and p2p messages so yeah we'll
describe it in the developers chat maybe
forum tonight so oh yeah it seems it's a
quite solved question so working also on
specification for merge mined sidechain
rights to pass it to our guys then.
It will be in Rust language, so yeah,
well, it's for Rust developers. Well, I
can contribute also, but yeah, still needs
to catch up. We will Rust and a little
bit. So, yeah, well, we'll do a call for
contributors once it's ready. Yeah, well,
assign boundaries and so on. And then,
yeah, it's the question, how to fund it,
right? I mentioned my sidechains
development. We'll discuss it with Ergo
Foundation, how much do we have, so we
still need to pay for Keystone integration
to PGR456.
And yeah, we paid Dusig also quite a lot
in recent months for 6.0 in Sigma Rust.
But yeah, probably we have some, so I can
start with that and then continue. Then
yeah, well, for other projects, well,
there are some new projects in Rust also,
such as Git Circle announced by my friend,
so I look for possibilities to assign
issues there. Maybe some bounties from
him.
and then yeah well ChainCash and so on so
yeah well there is need to attract
probably a little bit of funding after all
but yeah it's still interesting how much
so there is need for more developers right
i think now it's time to get more
ErgoScript infrastructure peer-to-peer
developers on board right maybe try to
look through rust circles specifically
because it seems a lot of open source
contributors now around that language
specifically
Then, yeah, so, well, more contributors
and yeah, well, I think it's a good time
to do another round of promotion for
ErgoScript, right? To get some more
contracts developers and then, yeah, well,
good maybe to also share some knowledge,
right, how to attract funding for
developers in the ecosystem right now. So
what options do we have? Using Raffle,
Raffle version 2 coming, Mew, what else do
we have? Well, different bounty programs,
right, and some grant programs. But yeah,
well, there is need for more, I guess.
kushti, when you talk about the other day
in chat, you said something like, you
know, you expect at some point to be
hundreds of merge mine chains once this
gets full rolling. Can you talk about the
benefits of another chain merge mining
with Ergo on these sidechains?
Yeah, sure. So in the first place, it is
a security budget for the chain itself,
right? So miners would receive some
additional rewards. Like they're receiving
additional rewards in Bitcoin, right, with
a variety of sidechains, like Rootstock of
Namecoin, but it's not quite live Fractal
and so on and then yeah in Monero so now
they have Tari they will have Dark DeFi
and so on so yeah it would be good for
miners to get more rewards right it's good
for the base chain and then yeah well as
we have solutions for trustless transfers
so it's unlike Bitcoin, Monero probably as
well.
Then, yeah, it also would be good to have
more liquidity locked, right? And
liquidity pools act as sidechain tokens
and products. Yeah, so let's have more
liquidity pools, tokens, material. All
right, would be good, I believe. rate and
yeah it's stability and growth.
So yeah but we need also for more
experimentation right so somehow to get
folks that's why Rust was chosen in
particular right to get people maybe
thinking already on some blockchains, new
blockchains, blockchain-based peer-to-peer
networks, right, so to get to the right
available and yeah, easy bootstrapping
option and then yeah, easy liquidity
option, right, so well.
for new proof-of-work blockchains, not
just sidechains specifically. There are
not many choices regarding centralized
exchanges. big need for decentralized
on-ramp, off-ramp options. So if I
mentioned my inside chain, you will have
trustless swaps with Ergo, right? Then
presence of Ergo DEXs and then Rosen also
writes about immediate bootstrapping
against the biggest chains like Bitcoin.
So Monero is coming to us, hopefully. So
then it's kind of a win-win, right? So if
you want to do some blockchain
experimentation, then you are getting
liquidity, hash rate, and yeah, Ergo
miners are getting some additional
rewards. Well, for liquidity traders and
so on to unlock more ERGs in DeFi.
They'll be able to pull the merge mined
rewards as well as ERG, as well as storage
rent. It's like a triple.
Yeah, yeah. So yeah, it's basically the
next kind of box to unlock right after
Storage rent. So, yeah, so emission, then
storage rent, then, yeah, merge mined
sidechains and so on. Well, unfortunately,
we don't have memes, right? But yeah,
maybe we'll have some alpha.
Can I ask you a question about this merge
mined sidechain security issue? Is that a
two-way street? So, for example, if
there's a merge mined with Bitcoin and
Ergo, in the long run Bitcoin has sort of
a security budget issue coming down the
pipeline, maybe four years from now, maybe
eight, whatever it is. Are we going to be
able to help them, especially if Ergo
begins to take off as a mechanism for them
to engage in DeFi and whatnot?
Yeah, so merge mined sidechains are
helping Bitcoin with security budget
issues, right? Yeah, well, currently,
merge mined sidechains A rather small ride
in comparison with Bitcoin, such as
Fractal, Namecoin, Rootstock, Rootstock,
probably the biggest one. I'm not sure
about Stacks, if it's merge mined or not.
For example, for Litecoin, the biggest
provider of security budget is Dogecoin,
which is a merge mined sidechain of
Litecoin. And yeah, currently, well, when
you see script ASICs advertisements, so
they're advertising doge mining in the
first place, not Litecoin even. So yeah,
well, but it's helping Litecoin, right, to
prevent attacks and so on, so to grow the
hash rate also to get more appreciated in
this regard. So yeah, then in the long
term, yeah, it would help Bitcoin as well.
True.
And we've got a question from Canon as
well. Merge-bind liquidity pools require
liquidity. It seems that whales and ERG
are more passive with their, but for work
coin/value, what are the benefits for
whales that provide LP at one or two
percent? Probably doesn't cut it. How to
target that?
I'd say probably do bigger LPs, but I
think the best way to incentivize them is
to kind of get them excited about the
prospects of a merged chain and things you
can do with it. That's the best motivator
if they think it has potential.
And Ella asked, are the plans to make
Ergo quantum proof? As far as I understand
it, the cryptographic protocols that would
be quantum proof just now are still a bit
too exotic. And there's no rush, really.
The best option would be once they're
closer, it's an active threat. You could
just fork to a chain that has those
cryptographic protocols that are quantum
proof. But I think we're still quite away
from that, at least Ergo. I know the old
wallets in Bitcoin are exposed because
they use a weaker form of crypto.
eight years ago plus and one was actually
moved recently and a whole bunch of
bitcoins moved and they left a note on
trading saying if this is yours come claim
it. So people are speculating that
sometimes they break that old cryptography
on those wallets but it's less of a risk
for Ergo because we don't use that one.
Yeah, I asked about that a couple AMAs
ago, and I'm not sure, because she gave an
answer, but I'm not sure he was
specifically aware of that situation. In
the OP_RETURNs for some of those
transactions, there were sort of almost
legalese notifications about seizure and
sort of threatening that whoever owned
those wallets needed to take action
within, I think it was 90 days, which sort
of corresponds to American law about
squatter strikes. So I wonder, is it
possible that those actually were hacked?
And if so, how did that happen? It
probably wasn't a quantum computer. So is
it possible that there was some sort of a
problem with the early Bitcoin wallets of
that particular type and the way that
their seeds were generated. There was also
something along these lines about a year
and a half ago with Ethereum wallets where
a lot of Ethereum OGs were finding their
stuff just yanked and nobody really ever
got to the bottom of it. And then the
scuttlebutt kind of died down.
Can somebody comment on whether or not
there is some mechanism that we don't
understand or is it something that we do
understand and are aware of and have
avoided in Ergo?
Yeah, it was a few weeks ago, so I've had
to refresh myself. But yeah, they used
early reused secp256k1 nonces. So people
have known they've been a lot weaker for a
while. But yeah, it's not actually known
how they got to it. It may just be the
actual person that's got it trying to do
money laundering or something. So it's
kind of up in the air. It's a bit of a
weird one. Why would they post that? only
just moving this to an anonymous place and
cashing it out. So yeah, it's a strange
one.
Yeah, so the brute force for now due to
poor entropy or nonce reuse, which
undermined independent security
guarantees. We don't use those in Ergo.
I mean, in fairness, Mark, I can see both
scenarios, or I can see what you're
saying, like I lost my keys in a body
sitting kind of thing. They're trying to
launder the money. But look at Ergo in
that instance with the zero-day storage
rent bomb, right? There were several good
actors who spent the boxes and reformed
them to the same amount, of course. to
help out the people that the storage bomb
rent bomb affected so i don't think it's
out of the realm of possibility that
there's good actors in the bitcoin sphere
that you know said okay somebody's going
to steal this eventually but we'll give
them 90 days to try to figure it out and
then we'll just take it because it's
better us than somebody else perhaps
Yes, it's definitely a possibility. It's
just obviously Bitcoin is not that
tight-knit anymore, and it was a lot of
money. I think if somebody found a hundred
thousand on their own ERG, it's probably a
higher chance to take it than somebody
finding a couple grand.
True, wow.
HQ, you built anything last night while
you couldn't sleep?
Well, maybe I merged chains pulse. So
there should be decentralized on-chain
messaging between two chains. So it's
basically sending message on one chain,
sending message on another chain into a
smart contract in front and you're just
compiling and parsing the messages. So
both chains users can interact with each
other by just signing the access.
Oh, wow. So that's Ergo and Alephium. You
might be emerging those two?
Yeah, I was planning to add Cardano, but
looking at that you need to spend two ADA
to send a message. I'm not sure if people
would like to do that.
Maybe people will send smarter messages
if it costs 1.7 ADA. They'll really think
about what they're saying. Oh, that's
pretty nifty. So cool. So in theory, you
could have people stay on their home
chains and still participate in a chat
across all these chains.
And the best part is that you can
showcase your product there, and if they
like it, they can use VoltPay to just swap
Alephium for Ergo or Alephium and
participate in both things and the
ecosystem. So the plan here is to have at
least a working or non-communities which
are there to create our own global
economy.
Very cool, sir. Very cool.
Is there an analogy?
Yeah, you can send a kind of financial
messages, right? Basically, but then it
sounds like wormhole, right? Basically has
similar cross-chain messaging protocols.
Technically, here we are not doing any
cross-chain stuff, so one person is doing
one thing on chain, another person is
doing another on chain, and the front end
is just passing the messages and showing
that on this chain, this person is saying
this, this person is saying that, another
chain, and you can reply to them by
registering their TXID or maybe their UTXO
box ID, and then you are just threading
the messages and showing them in the front
end, like it is a proper conversation
happening between two chains and two
users.
So, I can find those messages only with
the front end.
I mean, from another... Yeah, you can
find them on their chain too. You can find
them on... If they are messages on
Alephium, you can find them on Alephium
and if they are messages on Ergo, you can
find them on Ergo. And if you want me to
create a registry which does grab all the
messages and register them on Ergo, we can
do that also and use that as a ledger. So,
many stuff can be done.
That would get expensive though, I
imagine. Posting to all 10 chains at once,
if you had 10 chains involved in this, I
imagine.
Yeah, we can set a fee on top of sending
message and it should cover the minimum
UTXO amount. Well, on Alephium it is UTXO
and on Ergo it is box and Alephium is
0.002, Alephium on Ergo is 0.0004. So we
can maybe set 0.01 fee and each person
when they are submitting the message,
they're just creating another box and
they're paying for it. So yeah, I think
that can be done.
Right, or you could incentivize, you
could put extra fees in the box in Ergo
and incentivize a batcher to run to dupe
messages over to the other chain and
collect that fee essentially.
Yeah, the main idea here is to somehow
find a way to communicate with other
people, with real people, real users
outside of Ergo, to bring them to Ergo and
showcase them the DeFi they have on Ergo.
And if there are people who are building
nice DeFi on the other end and they want
to promote it, they can promote it also.
And you still plan to release at least a
simple front-end open source so that
people can at least use a simple part of
it if they want to on their own machine?
The multi-chain version you want, there
is the Ergo version is already open
source, the Alephium version is already
open source, I'm just merging them into
one. So whatever message you're sending on
a Alephium, it shows on a Alephium one,
whatever message you're sending on Ergo
one, it's showing on an Ergo one, but this
one will just aggregate the messages in
one.
Gotcha.
All right. So, will more blockchains be
supported like Bitcoin?
I guess we can integrate more blockchains
to this. We just have to find a way to how
to parse a message on chain and then read
it and show it.
All right. But for Bitcoin, you can just
use OP_RETURN, right? I mean, it's a bit
limited, like 80 bytes, but probably
enough for most of the messages, short
messages.
My main plan was to just go with the UTXO
ones because they are not the most simple
ones. But yeah, more chains can be added
too, but it depends on how the volume and
other options come from, because you have
to understand that thing has to be here
when you stream. As we were talking about,
there has to be funding to build
something. It's not that I'm asking for
integration charges to the chains, but
there has to be incentivization for the
developer to develop something so more
people can use it. If you build something
and it's not getting used, it's just like
building for nothing, for me at least.
What do you do if you've got an EVM chain
and the transaction doesn't go through,
gets rejected?
Well, then we don't go to the shitty
chains.
So there is, there is one theory which I
was trying to, to, to check is that
technically in Europe, you can buy a gift
card in any stores. So where you can go
and pay and you can get a gift card and
you can just redeem that and you get that
BTC in your, in your wallet.
They don't check KYC, but can you buy it
in cash? That's a question.
Yeah, you can buy in cash.
What? How?
Yeah, they're gift cards like, like
Nintendo Switch ones, Amazon ones, you
just go there and you just pay with cash.
And you're positive you don't have to
take that gift card to their portal and
then register your name and birthday and
that kind of bullshit when you, when you
try to extract your Bitcoin.
The last time I tested, you can input
anything you want there. So yeah.
And you can have some bullshit account
with, you know, some stealth email address
kind of thing. Yep. Oh, well, that'd be
interesting. Sorry, go on with your
pathway. Go for it. Sorry.
So what was I'm trying to do is you can
buy BTC by that way, right? And then you
can maybe swap that BTC with ERG. So
you're technically buying with your fiat
money. Another thing you can do is you can
buy that card or redeem it into BTC and
you can buy a prepaid card on VoltPay and
you can add that to Banxa too but I'm not
sure how Banxa works because as far I
heard you are required to KYC on
registration because if you have a prepaid
card you can add it to Google Pay and
Apple Pay and you can buy with that too so
instead of fiat you are paying with the
credit card you get with BTC so yeah there
can be many routes can be done for this so
but I guess I will have to the sacrifice
code to test all this.
We had a couple of comments from Canon.
One was to point out that the MindHealer
Cloud app is active and he provided a link
to that. It's mindhealer.cloud, which is a
service for paying for sort of I guess
therapy and also advice like for example
dietary advice using the blockchain
specifically Ergo right now I suppose that
could be expanded using Rosen or whatever
and I think that's interesting especially
because right now in the United States we
have this new process that the Trump
administration is launching to get all of
the big tech companies to start keeping
track of medical records, which sounds
like a complete nightmare to me. But it
does introduce an interesting potential
alternative to that.
And then he also made a comment about
merge mining. He said, merge mine
liquidity pools require liquidity. It
seems like the world, the whales and ERG
are more passive with their, with their
coins and what are the benefits for whales
to provide liquidity of one or 2%. How do
we target the whales? How do we get them
to be more active in the community? HQ
says we already answered that one.
And then we also had a comment from Jumei
saying, I guess this is a question for QX
asking about updates on the InfraDAO. When
is it happening? How is that going to
happen? What's it look like?
If you guys give me one minute, because
right now, as you mentioned, Jumei, I was
donated yesterday .erg and .mew subdomains
on FAKU. So me and Jumaia are going to
find a way to provide hosting on our
group. So if there are any people who want
to buy a host, so they can just get in
contact with us and we can just set up a
hosting service for them. A part of that,
if you're interested in buying some .org
domains or .me domains, so can be done
too.
Awesome. Yeah, InfraDAO. So the vote just
passed. I think I just saw the transaction
into my wallet from Paideia. Lovely
Paideia, just a reminder. So with Paideia,
I put up a vote that says, hey,
Sigmanauts, I would like 50,000 Paideia so
that we can form the official InfraDAO on
Paideia. I am and I'm the vote and I
attached 50,000 from the treasury of
Sigmanauts in to send to me after the vote
succeeded and the vote succeeded and I saw
I think it was last night of the night
before Ergo monitor bot popped up and said
you have 50,000 Paideia.
So that's in my wallet now and as soon as
I get a moment this weekend I'm going to
form the DAO and invite the initial four
or five members to it and distribute the
tokens there and then we'll dump the rest
of the InfraDAO tokens into Paideia once
we have those four or five founding
members in the in the what's it called in
the DAO so that we can invite other
members via vote and then we'll go from
there but yes it's it's a lift for me to
prep the four or five machines that we
need to do i just need to clone them and
put them out so that's a bit of a lift but
the bigger lift is for the people not
using our machines we are going to
I'm put the version of explorer Docker
that I use. It was based off of easy
Docker and easy. I forget what it was
called. It was called explorer front end.
It's on the Ergo Foundation website. It's
a little outdated, but you can modify some
of the Docker comps in there to grab the
latest versions and tweak some things. So
that's been fully done. That's what I use.
It literally takes, it's like a zip file
that I use and I drop it down. to, what's
it called? And that's it. And it's been a
couple of things to say.
So that's one of the steps that I can do
that's a little easier than setting up the
machines for people that want to join and
use their own machine. So you'll see that
on GitHub with some instructions on how to
do it. And that will be available, I
guess, for now if you need it. But the
other thing we're thinking about as well
is I offered a Ergo hosting just like HQ
did on the InfraDAO, depending on You
know, it's not just the InfraDAO is not
just going to exist for explorer and node
It's also going to exist for Ergo docs for
sigma verse Those kind of things as well
as long as we have room on the machines
You know, we can we can fit that kind of
stuff and also some machines might not
run, explorer, and be part of the
InfraDAO. They might be running things
like Ergo nodes if they want to jump off.
Think of it like a community IPFS
essentially, but actually running web
servers for that. Currently, as I said,
the plan is volunteer out of the goodness
of your own heart. It'd be really nice if
we could find some method of helping fund
this to help pay for electricity or that
kind of thing for people. But for now, to
build it is just out of your own heart.
I don't know if it was last week or this
week, it all blends together. There is an
InfraDAO dashboard that I built. That's
the spin up. And that has the main
explorer nodes. It's got all the P2P nodes
so far. It's got most of the websites for
Ergo as well. And it has test nets up as
well. So that dashboard is in chat
somewhere. You guys can find it if you
need it. And it does more than just a
simple ping. It actually does four stages
when it tests the websites. It goes in,
tries to load content, tries to execute
scripts, and responds based on that. So
it's fairly thorough in the checks that it
does to see if the site's actually mine or
not, other than a ping.
So that's kind of the first build for
that that I put up. So yeah, come along.
It's a big project and it's going to slow
burn for a bit as we get it. But it's not
something that I'm going to let pass away,
that's for sure.
All right, guys, I need to, I'm pulling
off to the airport right now to pick up my
friends. So I am going to, I'm going to
sign off, but you guys enjoy the rest of
the AMA. Thanks so much for joining
everybody.
Thank you, QX. We're actually running up
on 10 o'clock, so I don't know if there
are any more questions. I don't see any in
the chat, but now would be a good time to
chime in. If not, let's back to the salt
mines for all of us, right?
I'm going to take that as a vote for
everyone yearning for the mines.
Let's continue over the Telegram.
All right. Welcome to join the Telegram
or the Discord. And there's great chats
constantly ongoing there. If you compare
the Ergo community to many others in
crypto, you will see that we are active
and people care and it's not just a few VC
fans that are hoping that they'll get some
crumbs, it's people actively developing
and discussing the future. So welcome
everyone.
Thanks guys, so I'll catch you in just a
second.