All right. Hey everybody, my name is
CannonQ.
Thank you all for allowing a non-dev to
talk to you today.
This says, I actually think pretty decent
implications are a vector for devs to put
their head around.
It's getting out from behind the keyboard
a bit, but there's a lot of protocol that
would need to be developed.
So anyway, long and short of it, I talked
to this a little bit over the last year,
mentioned it to Joe a couple of times, and
he asked me to give a presentation on it.
I think it'll be interesting, and so I
did. So here we are.
Commercial barter meets permissionless
infrastructure.
I will try not to read the slides.
That'll be the only one, so let's get
going.
A hidden B2B economy, but we're here for
peer-to-peer.
Most crypto is looking at speculation,
right? Look at yesterday, big crash,
people on DEXes, sort of playing lotto.
Bartering worldwide is or in North
America is about a 12 to 14 billion dollar
market.
What we're focusing on is a smaller
subset that is like, non governmental, non
big, huge corporate kind of moves.
So anyway, they're tax compliant. That's
one of the things that people often get
confused by.
And you don't really need to convince
these guys about not using fiat. They use
their own barter currency.
So what is a barter exchange? It's not
eggs for tomatoes. Sorry, Jemai.
Not getting chickens from the Russians
down the street or selling them.
It is not skirting tax laws, doing
something for cash to try to get a little
bit more juice in your pocket.
And it's not government counter trade
deals. Now, that is a larger barter thing
where like a city might give somebody like
advertising or something at a big fair and
they, you know, you reciprocate, that's
part of the bigger number.
It's a formal B2B exchange network. This
is probably one of the only few slides
I'll read, but they do real accounting and
tax reporting.
So you actually get a 1099B. So those of
you in the U.S. that have been a
contractor before, you get a 1099.
You usually don't look at the letter, but
B is for barter, C is for whatever.
There's several of them.
There are large networks, 140 million
annually. iTex is the biggest.
IMS is independent. They have franchises.
And then you have regional networks, like
the local trade partners, which is in my
area. They're a couple hours away from me.
They're doing about 10 million a year.
And we'll talk about them a little bit
more specifically.
And then Rocky Mountain Barter, I found
one that's actually here. I think they're
out of Colorado Springs.
They do about half a million a year. And
again, this is not using cash.
It's using, I mean, you're bartering and
then receiving credits in a barter
currency.
So what about regional currencies? It is
not Berkshires, Ithaca Hours, Petite
Monet.
I think I showed that to Luca. It's
outside of Montreal in sort of a little
enclave.
They've printed their own currency. I
mean, it's sweet looking.
A lot of those are geographic based their
time based and they get a big bump and
then they fall apart and most of them
don't scale beyond a million dollars.
So it's really it's not that they don't
fail, but from a dev standpoint or a
protocol standpoint, it's hard to create a
business around something that doesn't
scale beyond a million dollars.
I mean, it's a pretty small fish.
These are business to business networks.
They have their own ledger systems. We'll
get in that just briefly.
The network operator actually provides a
ton of value. They will mediate.
They will help make push deals across the
table.
And their scale, I mean, it's two and a
half billion conservatively a year for the
last, I mean, growing, but I mean, it's a
big number.
Here's an example, local trade partner in
my area in the Ozarks in sort of central,
mid, south central in the U.S. Alice
builds a deck for somebody, gets paid
50,000 or 50, 5,000 in credits.
Those credits are LTP credits, so local
trade partner currency credits.
You get a statement every month from them
like a bank saying, hey, here's how many
credits you have.
She gets that full value. It's pretty
small up there, but her variable cost is
$3,000.
Come to find out a couple months later
that year, whatever, she needs to get a
couple crowns in her head for teeth.
There's a lot of dentists on these
things, honestly.
And so, she pays that dentist $4,500 in
credits. That dentist gets the full
$4,500.
What she has to do in our local trade
partner exchange is she has to pay 10% to
the local trade partner like organization.
So she pays 49.50 out of pocket or using
her credits.
And so you're sort of thinking, well,
that's just a swap, right? Like you're
swapping horses, nothing really happened
for you there.
Well, if her variable cost was three
grand and she just got $4,500 worth of new
teeth in her head, she actually made a 50%
ROI.
And so we're gonna hammer that home a
little bit in this. It's pretty common in
business.
Not a lot of people do it well, but it's
variable costing.
You can have fixed costs. You always got
to pay me. I always got to pay rent.
You always got to pay payroll unless you
got guys on a really flexible schedule.
You got cars, you got equipment, but what
was your actual variable costs?
So for her building a deck, she had a
little bit of lumber, a little bit of
labor, and that's it.
So she was able to turn that $3,000 into
$4,500 worth of teeth.
Do you have a question? Yeah.
Okay, yeah, variable. I use this Alice
example sort of throughout and there's a
few others, but I try to carry this one
throughout the thing.
And so, it's idle capacity arbitrage,
right? So, Dev, perk up your ears. You
heard arbitrage.
How do I make money on this?
So, without barter, she has an idle crew
and equipment that day that they were
building that deck. She didn't get the
business.
You will once you're in these networks
and you're established and you've sort of
like put your name out there you start
getting business that you wouldn't
normally get because people have this sort
of fake ROI you can create from you know
your own value.
So basically the dental work would cost
her 4500 bucks out of pocket.
Like we said with barter 3000 variable
cost she makes about 1500 bucks the
difference between the 3000 she spent to
build that deck for somebody and what she
receives in value from the dentist.
So sort of think about like Airbnb with
an empty room or a hotel with an empty
room, right?
Like what's that variable cost for them
to book you one night? It's not a lot.
Or think about your mining rig with
excess electricity, right?
Or you've paid off the cards so you're
not worried about depreciating those cards
into the cost of the coin you're mining.
So this is, we talked about it a bit,
about two and a half billion in the retail
barter exchange sector.
That's mainly, I'm looking at North
America. There are definitely some in
Europe as well and Asia, about 400 across
the globe.
This is, again, only about a 20% of the
subset, and this is really the only one
that I would think anyone would focus on.
Geographic industry, we'll get to that.
What makes an ideal business for
bartering high fixed costs or no fixed
costs? low marginal costs, perishable
capacities.
I think a time constraint. Think of your
hotel rooms, restaurant, your tables.
You can only have people eat that night
and then it's gone till the next day.
Having excess capacity and being an
independent owner.
So there's some ratios I put on here and
whatnot. People can look at the slides
later.
A few of the things
This will be a little hard to see. Maybe
it shows up pretty good.
Really your best options. I sort of went
through these and sort of scored them out.
Your best ones are hotels, advertising
media. I'd put programming in there as
well with advertising media.
Pet boarding, because if anyone's boarded
their dog, right? No one's doing anything.
They're checking up like once a day or
twice a day. Like, I mean, they're already
there checking other dogs.
Chiropractic, a lot of them are, they're
already doing a lot of cash business.
So this is another way for them to sort
of enhance it.
Legal services usually have to be solo.
It's hard to do it as part of a bigger,
like, legal practice because billable
hours and all that kind of crap.
Accounting if you're tax focused.
And then dental is a little harder. If
you're an independent standalone, that's
great.
Like my cousin, he has his own dental
practice for less like 25, 30 years.
If you're newer coming out of dental
school, typically you start working for
somebody or a corporation that owns like
multiple dental offices.
It's harder to break into it because the
debt coming out of school and the
equipment cost same thing for
veterinarians.
If they're independent, that's a good
one.
So real world economics hotel. You have
300 hotel rooms here in downtown Colorado
Springs.
federal government shut down so you're at
least a third behind if you charge a
hundred bucks a night on those rooms you'd
make fifteen thousand bucks actual causes
some cleaning supplies, maybe have to
bring in one extra person to clean them,
two extra people.
And so that's, you can start looking at
what your effective return is.
Again, that's another example, the sort
of variable cost versus fixed costs.
They already had to pay electricity for
the day, water bill, everything else to
maintain the hotel property.
But your variable cost in the hotel is
truly only your cleaning staff and the
supplies they use to clean the room.
Deep dives. So the network operators, the
people who run these barter exchanges,
they are a trusted intermediary.
So think of maybe like Rosen Bridge even,
like in between a transaction, like you're
submitting it, you know, sort of you can
see it.
They're a little bizarre. They're all
over the map.
Some charge a sign up fee, the one I'm in
is free, like no fees other than that 10%.
Some charge you a monthly fee in cash and
currency.
Some charge anywhere from six to 15% on
your spending.
Some charge you when you receive as well.
So I mean, it's like, they're all over
the map on where they're taking your money
or taking the credits.
This one doesn't really matter.
So they have a dollar peg mechanism in
theory. And I say in theory, ITEX, they
were a public company.
Again, they're the biggest one. They had
a SEC fraud case right around the dot-com
bubble where they were inflating their
revenues and sales to get everyone on
there.
And there was basically a flash crash.
People went out of business, turned the
dot-coms, and there weren't enough credits
to go around.
make it work. So they actually had SEC
fine. They're no longer public.
They sort of took it private after that.
But it sort of goes to show you like, you
know, danger of opacity, like we talked
about several times today already.
In fragmentation, so this sort of made me
think of Rosen Bridge a bit, right?
Talking about your stranded value.
Alice is in the Ozarks. She has 50,000
worth of credits built up over several
years.
She semi-retires and just shuts down the
business, which not everyone always sells
their business.
It may just be her and one of the two
other people and she just shuts it down.
She moves to New York, gets an itch,
starts up a business there.
She can't really use any of those credits
because you can't take a trade currency
dollar in the Ozarks.
No one in New York City gives a shit,
right? Like they're not gonna give you any
money for it.
So you get stranded.
They will facilitate a little bit at this
point, but that's a huge missing layer.
So these guys do a great job vetting
members, bringing them on board, tax
reporting, dealing with issues between
vendors on the exchange.
They're not interoperable across the
different exchanges.
There is no transparent reserves, no
capital efficiency, they won't lend you
money, you can't borrow credits, you can't
lend your credits, and there's no neutral
settlement layer across the different
exchanges.
Which is why I think this is a very good
opportunity for the right people.
So there are two actual federated, if you
want to call them bridges.
Barter Association National Currency.
NAIT is the National Association of Trade
Exchanges.
You as a vendor on an exchange cannot use
it. Your local exchange that you're part
of has to pay a fee.
Then they take some cut of your money
going across to a new exchange.
They have to approve everything. There's
a lot of horse swapping and a lot of phone
calls to get this thing done.
That one, they have to approve your
exchange. Only 40 exchanges are in there.
There's over 200 exchanges across the US,
so it's not that big.
They're basically the bigger ones working
together, keeping the small guys out.
And then you have universal currency,
which is bigger, the international, shoot,
I'm not going to remember, something in
Trading Association, Retail Trading
Association, I think.
They have a hundred of the exchanges
globally. They're a little bit larger.
They charge a quarter point on every
dollar that flows through them across
these different networks, which isn't too
bad.
To be a member of that trade organization
is not hard. It's not like it's more of an
open option.
But there's several hundred that
basically aren't connected anyway, shape
or form.
And they might be, but when I talked to
my guys and said, hey, I'm coming out to
Colorado as an example, what if I had
credits and I wanted to use them at a
hotel here, Airbnb, restaurant, whatever,
book a restaurant for everybody, you know,
with some free credits I had.
And he was like, well, I'd have to make a
lot of call, you know, like, it's always
like, yeah, it can be done, but it's not
probably doable.
or very possible.
Ergo's value proposition or a project
protocol on Ergo.
Economics, one million a volume cost 1%
probably on the other exchanges on Ergo,
you know, it's a couple hundred bucks.
Access, you can make it permissionless.
You could also make it permissioned, you
know, just to vet the exchanges that are
coming on board.
Transparency would be there, privacy, we
can use Sigma protocols, zero-knowledge
proofs, etc.
We'll get into that a little bit.
And you allow the networks to do what
they do, what they're good at, right?
They're good at being the local person,
holding everybody's hand and shaking hands
and kissing babies locally, and we can
handle the actual settlement, moving
things around.
Being that kind of layer Again
addressable market. I'm hitting this
again.
Just so you guys see it two point five
billion And that's a that's globally but
probably 80% of that's North America
Current exchange volume, it's not really
And I mean inner exchange volume it's not
really published anywhere but in total.
So it's probably about 20 million. So
maybe 20, 30 million out of 2.5 billion is
moving across these exchanges.
I'd say if you only got 10% of adoption,
you're looking at a quarter billion moving
annually on Ergo.
And again, you don't have a lot of
gatekeepers to overcome, and it's not
about replacing these exchanges.
I've sort of gone down that route. in
real world assets.
Total volume on Ergo, I have no clue. I'm
sorry.
Like, I mean, maybe half a million a day
before the price is lower now.
So maybe like three, 400,000. Yeah,
probably.
And it's not about replacing these
exchanges, right? It's about connecting
them.
They're good at what they do. They are a
value add for their members.
It's not like they're doing a shitty job
necessarily.
It's that they don't really have the
tooling to do what would even make it a
better tool for their members.
Programmability, privacy, you know,
blockchain in general, efficiency,
sustainability, permissionless, you have
security.
So multi-party settlement, escrow, I
mean, Luca, MGPi, and NZ, who was the
other?
Yeah, it helped us with SigmaLock. We'll
show you guys that a little bit later on
today.
But I mean, that's a pretty sweet little
escrow or conditional logic that we have.
Be applicable here or something similar
to that would be applicable here.
Why not other chains? And, you know,
you'd see this if anybody else gave this
from Polkadot or Cardano or anything else.
But Bitcoin limited programmability,
Ethereum, high fees.
How are you going to do small
transactions? Unless you got a layer 2,
and then you got other issues there,
possibly pre mind foundation control.
It's not really as neutral as you want it
to be.
I think earlier we're talking about
privacy and proofs on some of those
networks and are they really private.
If that's what they're pushing you
towards.
permissioned chains that sort of put,
like, proof of stake pretty much right
there.
You still have gatekeepers, network
politics, and then most other L1s, I mean,
it's centralized, expensive, or their
tokenomics aren't really sustainable.
Ergo, we know we're expressive on top of
UTXO.
Perfect fit for if you're trying to move
a thousand credits from this network to
that network.
And boxes can reference other boxes. I
mean, I'm talking to devs, you guys know
this stuff.
It's not really, I'm giving you guys a
whole lot of info here.
Sigma protocols have been noodling around
with the opportunity of if you brought on
one of these exchanges, say the local
trade partners in the Ozarks, their
software has API access.
You could prove credit history. You could
prove collateral.
You could prove borrowing requirements
for the actual individual vendors, right?
Some of that data can be fed in to a
protocol. And we'll get to that in a
little bit.
I mean, there's some cool things you can
do.
Storage rent, it sounds hokey, but I
think demurrage is pretty cool.
Some of the more successful local
currencies have had a attrition, like it
expires at some point in time, so you
could just tell the exchange as part of
the deal.
This stuff's only going to be there for
four years. Use it or lose it.
And that should actually be a motivating
thing for the exchange because the vendors
will then use their exchange more.
They make more fees, et cetera, et
cetera.
Transaction finality, two minutes for
block time. It's a day for full lockdown
confirmation, but two minutes isn't a big
deal.
Sub blocks is coming up, so it wouldn't
even be a deal. Low fees, developer tools.
We have some of the existing frameworks
or concepts that could be applied to this.
current isolated islands. So you got the
ITEX network, the one that committed fraud
25 years ago, the one with mine in the
Ozarks and the one here in Rocky Mountain.
If they're going to connect, they got to
make phone calls, faxes, emails.
I mean, just old school crap, right, to
get it done. I don't even know.
They might even be using mail still.
There's no liquidity moving across. And
again, it's the whole stranded value, dead
capital.
Say you build up a lot of business, but
you haven't been able to spend it yet.
You might have $30,000 worth of credits
like Alice.
She has built a bunch of decks for
people. Now she needs to wait till the
winter when she can actually do the
maintenance on her equipment, buy new
equipment, whatever.
Future shared infrastructure. ITEX has
5,000 members, the Ozarks have 500, the
one here locally has 100.
So now you've combined this and made it
5,600 members with a settlement layer that
works and sort of feeds what they need.
Yeah, the real innovation is not
technical. It is, don't get me wrong,
devs, but it's recognizing that the
network is the value creator, not us.
They're not just rent-seeking shitty
middlemen like Coinbase.
The blockchain is an infrastructure
layer, right? It can be their account
ledger that's open, transparent,
Simple contracts are better than a
complex bridge.
Not looking to build a replacement or
some kind of super complex bridge.
It would all be settled on Ergo. You
wouldn't have to like move across to
theorem and different stuff.
We could, because Rosen Bridge exists,
but there would really be no need to do
that.
One of the discussions today about AVL
trees and things like that, I mean you can
do some pretty neat stuff with their
ledgers and just like keep augmenting
them.
Let me just unchain. Let me have an
easily viewable what's happening.
So yeah, potential core innovations,
cross network settlement bridge for them,
it would be a big thing.
So let's talk about Alice again. She
needs some specialty wood for this deck.
She's building something for one of my
clients and has like a $20 million house
that looks like an art museum.
He has really nice teak wood and he wants
it Aspen. He wants to be able to tell all
his friends about it.
she could call Bob, and he's like, hey,
I'm in a barter network.
She asks him, and then, you know, how do
we make that happen?
And Bob's like, well, hell, I'm coming to
those arcs. I'm going to Crystal Bridges.
It's the nicest art museum in the U.S.
outside of New York or D.C. and has the
largest
Just for a little plug, the most American
art in the world at one location.
In fact, that's what it's dedicated to
and it has a Frank Lloyd Wright house that
they deconstructed reconstructed there.
It's pretty sweet. So he's going to go
there. He's already planning on it.
So he's like, sweet. Yeah, I'll give you
the wood, you give me the credits.
But how do we make that happen? Different
networks, they're not operable.
That's where we come in or innovation
would come in.
Same kind of things that we've talked
about with SigmaLock or some of the other
staking locking protocols.
You know, if you don't accept, it's
auto-refunded. If an oracle doesn't attest
to it, etc.
I mean, there's, you know, different
things to fail safe this.
So Alice would initiate the request. It
goes to Bob.
I mean, this looks like any, you know,
cross network swap, nothing fancy to us,
but to them, it would allow them to
actually do a business deal and get what
they wanted.
So it's pretty neat to me as more of a
business guy, not a dev guy.
Lending and borrowing pools, think duck
pools, think something similar.
Some of the staking you guys were talking
about that sort of comes into this as
well.
right now I have not found a barter
exchange out of the 2.5 billion of annual
volume.
I haven't found one that allows people to
lend their barter credits to others.
Might happen, I don't know, but I haven't
found it yet.
So I think that's a pretty, you know,
neat, easy thing for Ergo to be able to
accomplish for these people.
Even if it's within your own network, I'm
not talking about using Ozark credits to
get Rocky Mountain.
I'm just talking about, I got a bunch of
credits I don't need right now, let
someone else get them for cheap or borrow
them.
There's a scenario here, it's not really
that important really, but it's Alice's
seasonal rights.
She builds up a lot of credits in the
spring, summer, fall.
Then in the winter, she needs to spend
credits because she's going to buy a new
vehicle or some new equipment, whatnot.
So in the summer, she has 40,000 idle
credits just sitting there till the winter
when she can actually upgrade her
equipment.
And that's sort of when she has time to
work on the new equipment, get it all set
up ready for the next year.
With lending pools, she can put that out,
let other people borrow it.
You can do something. I mean, similar
duck pools just say, hey, it's a 3% or 4%
base.
And then it's based on utilization,
right? Just put a utilization curve on it.
Nothing exotic. These are regular
business people that have a bank account.
3% is nice.
There's a way for the protocol to capture
value here because they're allowing that
to occur.
Then in the winter, she needs to get
$25,000, $35,000 worth of stuff.
Then she can either borrow and just have
like a two or three percent spread against
her borrowing costs versus her lending
costs or cash in her credits.
I mean she may want a bigger truck next
year so she's going to keep the credits
and just pay that marginal spread.
There's a lot of ways to look at it.
You can do some on-chain credit scoring.
It seems like it's possible.
these exchanges. The one in central
Arkansas where I'm at is, it's on AS400
and grain bar paper.
Like, I mean, you ain't getting nothing
out of them.
The one up in the Ozarks, there is one
platform. He continues to buy out other
platforms.
That is the software platform that powers
these networks. He's good at what he does.
There's API access, things like that. So
they have all the transaction volumes.
They know reliability of vendors, grading
of the vendors.
Yeah, one guy. He's out in Boston. MGPi
may need to go meet with him.
But yeah, I mean you could create a
credit scoring, right?
Like off of the data that the network
already has.
And think about if you're Alice trying to
get wood from Bob and maybe you didn't
have enough credits, you could say, hey,
let me give you an IOU, right?
Like, and he would accept your network
IOU because he sees you have great credit
score and you're not welching on your
bets, right?
Like you're a real person.
So yeah, a little bit about like the
interest rate discovery.
This isn't new to anybody who's used duck
pools or a lot of the other lending
protocols that exist now, but just a
utilization based.
For example, my line of credit at my bank
is 7.75%.
So I mean, 8%, hell, I'd borrow all day
on that. Like that wouldn't bother me at
all.
If I could get credits and I knew I was
going to earn some more that year and pay
them off, that's no big deal.
14%, 20% might be a little iffy, but what
it does is as those rates get higher,
people add more to the pool like you guys
have seen with duck pools, and then it
starts pushing the interest rate down
until borrowers go back up.
You just hit that equilibrium.
Decentralize lending pool mechanics. You
guys know the drill if you've used duck
pools.
But think if you're the hotel. I mean,
you can just start making extra money on
this, right?
If you're an independent hotel or
independent franchise is allowed to do it.
Say you're the landscape guy that's
starting up your own company and you don't
have all the equipment you need, you can
go out and now borrow money in the network
and then go to the Toro dealer that's in
the network and get your equipment.
And again, the local barter exchange is
happy about this because you just created
more volume for them to pocket 10% or 15%
or whatever it is, and they have more
members.
Provable reserves, like a centralized
exchange, you don't know.
And some of these have gone under. So you
could build up credits in one of these.
And again, you don't get paid cash,
right? So if I do work under this
exchange, I get no cash.
It's all in these trade credits. But this
trade organization goes out of business.
I effectively just did work for worse
than free. I paid materials into it too,
right?
Like not just time and effort, like not
just the variable cost, but everything's
gone.
So, you could do, you know, again,
provable reserves, you know, that
everything balances out in these things.
You'd have a dashboard, pretty simple. I
mean, in theory, right? Some UX issues
there, but.
There's a fraud case. It's impossible to
inflate reserves if it's actually there on
chain.
This would help people if they want to
join the network or trade with the
network.
You may not want to send your credits to
the Rocky Mountain Network because it
looks a little dodgy or they're not that
well collateralized.
There's more on one side than the other
just because of the imbalance that's
occurring.
Oracle problems, like always, right?
Reputation, time delay, et cetera.
Scalability, user experience. I mean, all
these things, I think, are pretty simple
to do, but with the right tools and the
right people.
Regulatory. I haven't looked into this
all the way. I don't think that.
They already do this, right? So like my
exchange and the Ozarks will send money to
another one.
I don't think that there's a money
transmission license to deal with or
anything like that, or they already have
that sorted out themselves.
I don't think it really adds a whole lot
of tax reporting complexity.
The only thing it would add is 1099 INT
for interest earned on the old lending.
Yeah, and it's in the order of getting a
1099 B.
So, I mean, you're just giving them one
more data point to give to these people to
show that you earned interest on your
credits.
Yeah, the bigger issue is adoption,
right? It's always a chicken and egg
thing.
And so I think it would be starting with
a couple smaller ones that are accessible
and progressive and then going from there.
Yes.
Yeah, so the question was about
algorithmic stablecoins and if it's
pegging to that, I'm not saying peg it to
the algorithmic stablecoin.
Yeah, if you had local trade partner
credits or dollars and then you had one
from New York or one from wherever, it's
still in that currency.
You're not co-mingling those pools per
se, right? So like you would set up a
lending pool for each of those networks.
And then you would give them the ability
to borrow in that network because you want
to buy Aspen wood from the guy right down
the street or from Joe and tell him to go
log a couple off his property.
You know, I mean, it's that's sort of the
way it would go.
Yeah. Yeah. So that's why everyone should
want to do it.
Because you can, as the vendor, you can
become your own bank or at least partially
your own bank, right?
So like you can now pay. I had this
concept in grad school.
So I used to audit a couple companies
that were small. like they did fishing
lures.
And then another one that was in Walmart,
right? And they blew up and Walmart blows
you up to a certain size, like 20, 30
million in sales.
And you're like, woo. And then you have
to go out and get a $20 million loan to
sustain that.
And then once they know you got that
loan, three months later, they come to you
and go, you know, I think I'm gonna have
to pay about 50 cents on the dollar, what
I used to pay you.
And like, they just sort of get you
squeezed in. And then on top of that, they
pay you at 120 days.
So it's like they're screwing you every
different way.
But now you can add a concept in grad
school that if Walmart actually became a
lender to their vendors, they'd make more
money than what they're doing now by
squeezing everyone for 120 day terms.
No, it would work like economically it
should work.
So I think this could actually create a
bigger alternative economy when the
business can become partially their own
line of credit, right?
Like you have free credits or you've
earned credits that now you can lend out.
So anyway,
You know, struggling business most eager
to borrow that gets back to the vetting on
the front end from the network and the
transaction history they already have on
these people and sort of bringing that on
chain so that I talked about the
equilibrium, but you can also put
penalties, right?
Like give them a credit score. And if
your credit score is bad or you're new,
you have a bad credit score, right?
When you're 17, 18, 19, you don't have a
good credit score because you haven't
built up credit, right?
In theory. And so they could have to pay
an extra 5% or 10% or whatever, right?
To get the credits.
That's sort of the presentation. So yeah,
they're already operating peer to peer.
So yeah, any other questions? I have a
bunch of just random stuff back here.
Well, no. Yes. So the question is, do you
need a credit score? Yeah.
Well, so what I looked at was
collateralized, right? Because we're
familiar with duck pools.
If it's more traditional, like bank-based
on credit scores, then you could hybrid
it, right?
And they might even be able to onboard
more businesses to the network because now
you can borrow at a better rate to get
equipment from the Toro dealer or the Ford
truck dealer, whatever, right?
Like it sort of makes that network even
more powerful in my opinion.
But yeah, that's the whole thing. Go
ahead, Chris.
So, yeah, so the question is, like, does
tokenizing the credits, like, add a new
tax layer for the vendor like Alice or Bob
that we were talking about?
So, I would look at it more like one, I
could be wrong, and I'm wrong every day
very often, but I think if you're
providing this service, right, if Alice
builds up 40,000 credits,
she's getting like say she gets paid 40
000 that year for building decks she's
getting a 1099b from the local trade
partners that you file that 1099b on your
tax return business tax return or personal
just however you're set up as a
corporation that flows through is 40 000
of income
Because you have your normal expenses,
you're paying out and Fiat, right?
So, like, it's already there. It's just
like a receipt.
And so the only thing I'm looking at is
the interest you would be earning would
then generate a 1099.
Right? Like, you get from a bank showing.
we paid you 0.02% interest this year on
your cash.
Thanks for parking all your money with
Bank of America."
So it would be that kind of thing. I'm
not looking at it where Alice necessarily
has, and this is going to sound funny, I'm
not looking at it per se where Alice has
an Ergo wallet and she has these local
trade partner credit tokens in her wallet.
were the settlement layer for it.
I'm not sure if you wouldn't just reskin
Nautilus to where that's all they see is
like their one thing.
Like I mean just make it its own silo or
even maybe do a side chain for all this. I
don't know per se.
Well and you would also send out a what's
the one we would also need to send out or
we would provide the information to the
local exchange network so that they could.
Give you. The 1099 and maybe 1098 like on
like your home loan.
This shows the interest you paid, but
it'd be like a interest expense, right?
Like they need to be able to put that on
their tax return. Like, hey, I borrowed
money and I paid a thousand dollars,
right?
Like they need to be able to put that on
their return.
This one. Yeah, we're like, she profits.
So yeah, so it's sort of convoluted.
It's a good example and it's not right
because you're trying to show business and
I showed her get like teeth.
Let's say she bought a, I don't know,
auger attachment for a skid steer, you
know, so she can put in deck poles, right?
Like, I mean, so she can drive them.
Yeah, well, in the auger bit, you know, I
mean, it's several grand, but it depends
on if you got it new or used.
But so that five grand, she gets
something that is reported to the IRS, and
then she reports the IRS on her business
tax form that she made $5,000 in income.
It's just like normal income.
The expense would then be, she keeps
record, like she's getting an invoice,
you're still getting an invoice showing
payment, right?
It's just that it got settled in this
non-fiat currency.
And then the extra 10% that she pays the
network, they report something to her
showing that she paid that fee as well.
So that's also a business deduction.
No, she built a deck, right? So, she went
out and built a deck for someone, got
$5,000.
She gives them an invoice. They pay her
$5,000 in credits.
They have the invoice to show that they
paid that expense, right?
So the question is, if banks are already
getting affected by it, does it... How do
I say this? Clearly.
Are they going to take notice and, you
know, is anything we're doing affecting a
bank?
Yeah. If this thing grows because of
this, like, because it becomes more
attractive to businesses, small and medium
businesses to do this,
Does it affect banks? Possibly. I don't
know. I mean, my family friend that owns
it, I mean, I don't know, it's like a 50
branch bank.
He doesn't give a shit about $2 billion.
I mean, like it's not all in his network.
Like it's spread across so many banks,
they don't know they're not getting it
right now.
I mean, honestly, $2 billion is nothing
to banking system. Like it's nothing.
Yeah, and you said, so what's holding
back this concept?
A lot of people, I think Joe may have
said it, someone else may have said it as
well, people are sort of inherently lazy,
right?
This takes a little bit extra hustle,
One, it takes you, if you're a barter
member to say, hey, can I pay you in
barter bucks, right?
And most people feel uncomfortable trying
to do something like that or hustle or
You know, whatever it's something else to
have to deal with.
And and yeah, so if I do a project and
make like. 810 grand and some guys
backyard doing this project for them.
How long am I going to sit on that 10
grand? Like, I better have very low fixed
costs and very low variable costs because
I might be sitting on that 10 grand for a
while before I can use it all.
And that's what I think this, to me, it's
a fungibility, like you said, and I think
it's also a network effect issue.
I mean, none of them have scale, right?
So, I mean, there's always that network
effect they've done really good so like.
Colorado Springs you guys have been
around here a bit, but it's like 750 like
MSA, maybe a million like it's a good size
population.
Northwest Arkansas fastest growing. MSA
in the country for multiple years now in a
row.
Yeah, it's about 750 K now when I was,
you know, like 20 30 years ago, there's
maybe like 250 people.
Yeah, 250,000 people. So it's
If they have about 750,000 in their MSA,
Metropolitan Statistic Association, or
area, and they're doing 10 million a year,
those guys are hustling.
But they're hustling because you saw
they're making 10 percent, right?
So that's like three people. One of
them's the secretary, one of them's the
owner, one of them's this business dev guy
splitting a million bucks a year.
That's pretty good coin, right?
And I'm not saying replace those guys.
They should be getting paid that if
they're hustling that hard.
The guys in Rocky Mountain are doing half
a million a year. Good.
I mean, I think the lending pools is a
big thing. I think there's a, you know,
the cross network thing is pretty huge.
Making that available, but that's a
chicken egg thing. I think the end network
lending, I think, is the biggest.
And I believe why it's also a hurdle is
the software that exists could easily do
this as well, right?
This isn't hard, it's a ledger. I mean,
not being nasty to blockchain or Ergo, but
it's a ledger, right?
The software is already keeping a ledger,
doing their 1099s.
it's not it's not it's not clear and
transparent right so like why would I lend
my bucks out of my account on this network
when I can't see where they're going or
anything else right so I mean I think
that's where blockchain trumps the
federated or you know closed system yeah
I haven't I haven't right like this sort
of been the back of my head for a while
and I sort of spit it out the last couple
of days.
What are you guys raising your hands here
in the front row? No? Okay.
We'll pay in FAKU. That'll get every dev
running.
Yeah, so the question from Chris was
like, you know, what would it take to
attract a dev to do this?
I honestly, I don't know. I don't truly
know how complex this is.
At the end of the day, I think it is
more, and that's why I said it's a non-dev
dev thing.
I think it's more getting the first
couple exchanges on board with giving you
the data, right?
Giving you the API access to the data or
whatever the output from their system to
get that data.
And then what can you do with it?
With the lending pools, I think, one,
two, three, four, five, six, Seven I think
there's seven devs in here that whole side
of the room actually I think any of them
could take duck pools and modify it for
this.
I mean or find a way to modify it for
this And so, you know, I mean if you
started with that as a proof of concept
right just the lending pool
So, I mean, I think, again, to Joe's
earlier point today of we strive for open
protocols for a reason.
I think this is a good bolt-on reason. I
mean, it's sort of segued into what I was
talking about.
But, I mean, I think anybody in here that
I'm looking at that's devs on this side,
they're all way more talented than
anything I would come up with or even want
to teach someone, you know.
I mean, they can modify that stuff. It's
there.
I mean, some of the back end maybe isn't
or, you know, some of the front end stuff
we'd have to develop.
But I mean, some of it's sort of there in
a way.
Yeah, so that's a good question. So what
is the what piece of the pie is for the
dev?
The existing software that I said, like
several the more modern exchanges or ones
that have decent websites and whatnot.
I mean, it's sort of like a, if you want
to think of Zoho or, or, like Salesforce,
like CRM, like it's a CRM basically with
this bolted onto it, but a guy's built it
from scratch.
Like it's not, I've sort of looked at it
enough to see that at least I believe it's
not like a existing CRM package.
It's what he's built from scratch.
I don't know what he charges for that
software. I've tried to find out. It's
obviously not published.
There's not a lot of customers for it,
right?
So if it's one dev and he's charging five
grand a year to, you know, I don't know,
40, 50 customers.
I mean, that's a pretty good nut and he
can do other stuff because now he just has
a spinning top, right, without a whole lot
of, you know, moving parts going forward.
So what this would earn or yield, I mean,
to me, it's more, it's going to have to be
built at cost to figure out how to
monetize it.
Like, I don't know if it's earning off
the lending pool. I don't know if it's a
fee to the networks.
They're already paying a fee to this guy.
Does he try to replicate it?
You know, like, I mean, there's a couple
moving parts, so I don't have a good
answer for that because I really haven't
taken that step in my head because I was
still just, you know, noodling around with
the research.
Yeah, Luke.
Yeah, so the question is, can you chicken
an egg?
And do you do you try to replicate the
software for one and get others to join,
you know, for interoperability across the
networks?
I really don't think so. I think it's a
can of worms.
I mean, right now it's a one guy show
owns the somebody built a new one out of
Detroit like a couple years ago, he bought
them out and just here's your money.
Let's combo it up, right? Like let's I
don't want competition.
It's an oligopoly or a complete monopoly.
Yeah, maybe. I mean, there's a lot of
ways to skin it, but
Yeah, no, this was just more just to get
people thinking about. I mean, to me, the
biggest thing is it is a group that's
already organized, already licensed.
They're not doing anything shady, and
they're not using Fiat to the tune of 2.5
billion a year.
Is it a sales problem, dev problem? I
think for them scaling, it's always going
to be a network effect problem.
It's a super interesting because it's
like proof of work itself is most
profitable when you have excess capacity,
whether of energy or of computational
power, right?
And so networks like this potentially
allow people to redirect excess capacity
in whatever skill set they have and in
essence tokenize it.
Turn it into credit. Now, there's always
like the human element where it's like,
okay, if I'm a restaurant and my excess
capacity is my old shit, is it lower
quality?
Right? And then it's like, okay, how do
you create the right enforcement
mechanisms?
You know, some systems I would say
probably are a little bit aggressive in
terms of like, maybe they have credit
limits in terms of how much you can spend
or where or fees or whatever.
But, you know, we do see a lot of the
quote unquote gig economy that is
basically people trying to take excess
capacity and turn it into credit.
So it's a super interesting idea, you
know, in terms of how to coordinate like
on the organic side, I have no idea.
I'm the wrong person, but as, as a net
idea, it's quite fascinating.
Yeah. And I would, the only thing I would
add to that is it is that excess capacity
in the gig economy is growing.
So, I mean, I would say that was, A lot
of