All right, let me see if I can see us
online here.
Test, test, test.
We are going bootleg here.
Yes, I think I see us right here.
Yep, I think we're online.
Yep, let me just post it.
All right, why don't you go back and talk
about Dexy while I post these.
All right, so are we online?
Yep, we should be.
All right, so yeah, please check Dexy. It
should be considered as a funny financial
game at this point, like, I don't know,
maybe HODL coin. But yeah, well, also
sometimes you can get quick profit from
arbitrage, right?
Who made Crystal Pools? Can you talk
about that? What does that exactly do?
C8. So Crystal Pool is a DEX aggregator.
So you can work with many liquidity pools,
SigmaUSD Bank, Dexy Bank from the single
application. And yeah, that's quite a cool
idea, I think.
So that means, so it's kind of like Dex
Hunter, those kinds of things where it
finds the best price for you.
But here you also can interact with many
applications from one UI. I don't know
much about Dex Hunter, so these days I'm
using Ergo DeFi. I don't know much about
Dex Hunter, all that stuff. Yeah, well,
Crystal Pool is quite cool. It's still
raw, but it's getting better and better.
So, yeah, well, and the plan is to update
Oracle Pool to version 2, use the Oracle
Pool and then launch Gluon USD, so Bruno.
Bruno, Bruno. Such plan. And then DexyUSD,
yeah, so probably around September or
something like that, because we need for
some time to update the Oracle Pool first
and the testnet. Then in the mainnet and
so on so it takes some time but some weeks
even. But then yeah, we can have DexyUSD
so it would be good also to find some
liquidity providers right now. Yeah, so
also going to work on that.
And then, yeah, so with all those things,
so Rosen is also going to bring some USD
stables from Ethereum. Decentralized ones,
uncensorable, let's say. So, yeah, would
be quite good. And then, yeah, we need
stable to stable pools. So if you can do
such stuff, it's the right time to do.
All right, I think I saved all the
questions from before the internet
toasting. So should we start hitting
those? I'll read them to you since you
can't see them. Sound good?
Yep. So, let's, but maybe you have some
news from your side.
Some what?
News from your side.
Oh, you're right. I totally forgot. Yeah.
Yeah, guys. So there's something cool that
we're going to, the info team is going to
be doing. And when I say info team, I
mean, me and kushti and OnVR in the chat.
So the idea is that we have currently, we
have a main Ergo platform website, right?
That's Ergo docs. We have Sigma verse, but
we have the main Ergo platform website
where Athena's hosted that kind of stuff.
And we have the Explorer, which is
ergoplatform.org.
So how that works is that goes to a load
balancer in Cloudflare. And that actually
goes to three separate servers that are
running on a hosted platform that is paid
for by the EF, right? So in interest of,
you know, we all know the EF doesn't have
an endless budget. They're not going to be
around forever. So in the interest of
actually taking that burden off, paying
for that infrastructure, we're going to
try something different.
And what that means is we've already,
I've already started building three new
nodes on 6.1. I built them on 5.13 the
other day, and I just updated them to 6.1,
which is the rocks database, which loves
SSDs nice and fast. Once that is done, I'm
going to overlay Explorer on top of them
as well, which is GraphQL API, as well as
the web-based Explorer that you're used to
seeing. Once that's settled and working
well, I am going to add those all to the
load balancer. And then slowly, we'll
start removing the hosted ones from it.
And now you may be saying, okay, QX,
what's the difference between you hosting
three nodes, you know, an internet place
with, you know, same similar uptime as
Hetzner or wherever they're hosted, if
they're still the same place, still the
same provider. Well, that's where this
comes into play.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to
put two or three of these machines that
I'm using to host - they're 16 gigabyte
RAM, i7, one terabyte hard drives with
about 5,000 megabytes read write speed on
the NVMe. So they're really fast. They
should be able to be very suitable for
this. I'm going to put them on MewMart. If
you guys aren't familiar with MewMart, I'm
going to talk to HQ if he's listening now.
I'm going to only allow a certain token to
be able to buy it.
And then I'm going to decide who gets
those, depending on your interest and your
internet availability, your internet
connection, your static IP, your somewhat
limited amount of dev knowledge. You don't
have to be a dev, but you have to be able
to be able to jump into Docker and TMUX
and run nodes and explorers. And the idea
is that we want to spread three or four of
these puppies around the globe. And we're
going to add those as well to the load
balancer so that Cloudflare will see the
three machines that I have, and then they
will see the three machines or four
machines spread around the globe.
So then we'll have a load balance of
five, six machines spread around the
globe. So if all three of mine go down,
then we still have those three or four
hosting the same Explorer experience for
you guys. So that's on top of Nautilus
putting direct IPs into these rollovers
for the API and the GraphQL and the
Explorer.
So you'll hit one link,
explorer.ergoplatform, which will go to my
ones. It'll go to these three or four or
five locally hosted by these people who
have good internet connections that
volunteer to do it. And will be much more
of a decentralized kind of central node
hosting, if you want to call it. Everybody
wants to go to the main Explorer kind of
thing. So we're going to be able to do
that. Let's do that decentralized manner,
and let's not have it rely on funding from
the EF. We'll have it rely on volunteers
that want to do it themselves, which I
think is ethos of Ergo.
So we're probably about a month away from
maybe a full switch over for that. But
keep an eye out. If you're interested in
running an explorer slash node that's
official and through the load balancer,
give me a buzz. We'll talk about it. Maybe
I'll hand you a token if I approve and
you'll be able to get that swapped out on
MewMart for the shipping fee as well added
to that depending on where you are. Great,
so I think that's cool, kushti. We finally
get off that kind of thing and get to
fully, even though it's an official
explorer.ergoplatform, we can still target
community nodes and community load
balancers. So I think that'll be cool.
Yeah, sounds good. Would be happy to
participate.
Oh, great. Right, right, right. You got
one too. Fantastic. That'll be great.
All right. Let's jump on the questions.
So we've got Mathis Bori. He's saying, I
think he's saying, he's still trying to
figure out Ergo adds new stuff so quickly.
I guess he's trying to figure out how Ergo
adds stuff so quickly. Well, I can speak
from my own experience that the tooling
here on Ergo is absolutely fantastic for
the most part to be able to dive in at
different levels, whether I want to use a
full SDK in Scala, or I want to go into
something much easier like Python.
Or there's even, if Paul's watching too,
he's tried to bring the app kit over to C
sharp, I believe it was as well. So
there's lots of different options for
interacting with chain. And not only that,
but the end points are so easy to use. You
can spin up a node really fast yourself,
do a full index node, and if the API
endpoints aren't in that full index node
that you need, you can rely on Explorer or
you can say, screw it, we're just going to
interact directly with a Postgres database
that Explorer is keeping on top of the
index nodes.
So I've done both. It's very easy to
interact with that kind of thing. So at
least from a dev standpoint, that's a huge
turn on for that. But kushti can speak
more to how he's so fast at dropping node
updates all the time, as well as, you
know, sub-block integrations and cool
stuff that you announce every so often.
Yeah, well, actually, it would be good to
have more contributors to move faster
because I think it's possible. So, yeah,
well, I think it's about community, right?
So, well, a lot of developers, a lot of
independent efforts. Well, we need FOMO. I
think, well, what do we have now?
Structure-wise, it's quite friendly to
scale it up. So, yeah, let's move faster.
Like, hypersonic speed. Why not?
Let me see if I can bring up text here,
kushti. I think I can put questions on the
screen makeshift-wise.
Hi, kushti.
Alice project.
So, just the title and, yeah, I've put it
into the reading list, so, yeah, I guess I
can provide some comments before Monday,
yeah, so, yeah, it's in the reading list.
But, yeah, well, still need to read it
fully, right, but, yeah, well, I think,
well, at least from the title, the first
page a bit. Yeah, well, why not? So I
think it's time to think about starting to
build something like that.
But yeah, well, I can provide maybe
comments on the forum. Let's see,
actually. Yeah, we will have anniversary
AMA, right? So I can provide some thoughts
there, if not on the forum before,
because, well, next days are busy. But
yeah, well, anniversary AMA is also good.
And by the way, what time for AMA is it
said, you know, if Joe's coming, maybe
it'll be maybe it'll be an hour later.
We'll see.
One hour is okay.
One hour is okay for you. So maybe two PM
UTC. Let's do two PM UTC for AMA on the
1st of July, the kickoff of the
anniversary.
Yeah, sounds good.
And this Aletheia protocol, yeah, so I
found it over Twitter yesterday. So yeah,
well, I didn't have time to check in
details, but yeah, well, we'll do in the
next few days. Very cool. All right. So
yeah, so many. And it seems it's some new
author also writes some. I don't know,
maybe some anonymous guy, some new account
in the GitHub also. I don't know. Let's
see. Interesting.
All right. Let's see. We got another
question, kushti. How can a privacy chain
still aggregate statistics like Gini
coefficient, allowing users to evaluate
the market without sacrificing TX and
wallet balance privacy? That's a question
from Ursa Minor 2010.
Yeah, but this is, I guess, nearly
impossible, right? So if you want to have
some Gini coefficient for private chain
where every balance is private. I know, I
mean theoretically there could be
solutions for like MPC, but practically
not. Really not, because yeah, you don't
have participants which are willing to
participate in such a procedure, right?
Probably. It's not quite realistic to
bring them into this MPC protocol,
multi-party computation protocol. That's
what I can think about.
You can also have, I don't know, some
centralized party gathering statistics and
participants sending some zero-knowledge
proofs without revealing all the data.
Yeah, it's also probably not very
realistic setting, right? Because if you
have, for example, the richest wallet in
the ecosystem, probably you wouldn't trust
all this ZK, blah, blah, blah, and the
centralized party gathering statistics
anyway, right? So, well, theoretically,
it's possible maybe, but practically, I'm
pretty sure not quite.
All right, let's see what else we have,
kushti. We have, this is from our buddy
Aco. He wants to say, can you give a
little teaser about your call you'll be
having with Midnight? What's it about?
Ooh, I miss this. What's this talk about?
Oh, so it's from some, not so public chat
maybe, but yeah. There will be some call
in coming days, but yeah, about what is it
about? So there is some plan, right, but
it's probably quite obvious. Well, there
is interest from both sides, right? So for
Ergo side, we are quite interested in
privacy, right, in regards with maybe kind
of private side chain, right, to have some
private contracts, right? So the idea is
that you can transfer ERGs and then have
some private contract. But then, yeah,
well, there is some interest from Midnight
side in regards with proof of work aspects
and so on. So let's see what can we do
together.
Well, is that like, are you talking about
like integrating or like, I remember
Charles said on Twitter at one point, when
somebody asked him, he's like, oh, Ergo
can just become a partner chain. And
that's how Ergo can be integrated with
Midnight at some point. Is that what
you're speaking about?
Yeah, well, in regards to the partner
chain, so I made a tweet yesterday that,
yeah, you can actually do some options
like a merge mined side chain of Ergo,
which is a partner chain of Cardano,
right, and well, another option is double
merge mined sidechain, for example, merge
mined sidechain of both Bitcoin and Ergo.
To, yeah, well, use Ergo as a kind of
smart layer of Bitcoin with less trust
assumptions, right, if there is support
for some Bitcoin.
So, how does that work if we are dumping
like the full chain from Cardano onto into
Ergo blocks on a side chain? Are we just
like dumping hashes or proofs that
calculate out to whatever the result is on
the other chain? How does that kind of
work?
Yeah, so it's about reusing validators
from Cardano, right? And yeah, for this,
there is no need to know about the state
of the chain, I guess, because they have
some protocols for light clients, right? I
forgot the name. And yeah, it probably can
be reused. I guess that's the plan in the
context of Cardano sidechains as well,
right? Which is actually quite interesting
because for most proof of stake chains,
well, there are no such techniques, even
to the best of my knowledge. So, yeah,
well, then, yeah, it's quite interesting,
right? And, well, then, yeah, you can do
some interesting things also, right, when
you have consensus from both Cardano
validators and subset of Cardano
validators and subset of Ergo miners.
So you say, but that's not going to
technically make Cardano any more secure,
adding proof of work that way, right?
Because we're still relying on the
proof-of-stake validation techniques in
Cardano. We're just writing it to our
chain, no?
Yeah, so for sidechain, yeah, it's just
for sidechain concerns, right? But yeah,
well, you will have somewhat better
security budget, right, for both chains,
Cardano and Ergo, because of merge mined
side chain. Yeah, it would make consensus
more secure for both sides.
Yeah, this is actually quite interesting
direction to discover, I guess.
All right, there's another question for
you, kushti. kushti, when are we going to
see you in a more relaxed podcast, more to
hear about the story of Ergo? I think
people want to see you. Ace Pickle says,
kushti on Rogan. Maybe they want to see
you smoking a fat joint, kushti, and just
talking with squinty eyes.
All right. So yeah, about history of
Ergo. I don't know. So maybe I need to
write down some things first. Because,
well, the history is not quite known,
probably, right? Many actors are now quite
forgotten. Some are not alive,
unfortunately, even, right? Like Alex.
Skalakhan.
Yeah, so, well, actually, it was mostly
about engineers, right? Like, doing
something and dreaming about something.
So, well, it wasn't probably... So, even
Monero, for example, was different, right?
So, well, in this regard, it could be
comparable with Bitcoin early days, very
early days. Bitcoin of 2009, right, when
there were only engineers, there were no
marketing folks. Like Ergo before 2020.
And then, yeah, well, somehow we got,
well, some people doing marketing,
enthusiasts, and yeah, well, all the
community we have now.
So yeah, that's quite amazing. Because
usually, these days, it's quite opposite,
right? So first, you get marketing folks,
funding, all the hype. And then somehow,
maybe you hire engineers who actually in
most cases, hate the jobs they're doing.
Quite opposite story.
All right, let's see. We got another
question, kushti, banging these out.
Another one from Ursa Minor trying to get
a grasp on things like Midnight. Can
privacy stablecoin exist on a Sigma chain
with proof of reserves and collateral on
Ergo? They're just trying to understand
how people trust privacy chains like
Midnight.
Yeah, so recently discussed with Bruno
stuff like that, like privacy stable coin,
right? So there is a private instantiation
of a djed protocol called Zephyr. I don't
know. So I think that they got into some
issues at some point because of some bugs.
And so on, so yeah, I wouldn't recommend
to use it without research and so on,
because yeah, I don't actually know much
about it.
But yeah, so from what I know, so it's
some fork of Monero, but with djed,
basically SigmaUSD with some modifications
implemented in the core of the chain,
right, and for stuff like that, definitely
it's better to just build, I don't know,
some private side chain, right, and bring
SigmaUSD, so, well, transparently-ish and
already known stablecoin, right, or Dexy,
Gluon, whatever to this chain, right, and
then enjoy, well, privacy there, right? It
would be simpler and more secure option.
All right. Let's see what else we got,
kushti, we've got...
One more question, maybe. Time to run? Or
do you have to run?
I've got a minute or two. Byron says, if
kushti smokes, I'll buy another 1,000 ERG
next week. Guys, we want a good 6.01 node.
We don't want security vulnerabilities in
the node next time.
All right, let's see, we got, oh yeah,
we've got this. Byron also asks, any
updates on the meetup plan? It's funny you
should say that. The meetup planning for
Ergo. It's funny you should say that. We
just had a Sunday meeting last week where
we kind of mostly finalized the schedule
and I threw it in chat. Joe and I went
over it pretty hard, and then I threw it
in the main segment of the chat and asked
for feedback. And I don't think there are
many changes.
So later today, expect the meetup
schedule and speakers and how it's going
to stream to everybody on Twitter, as well
as the GitHub and the Google signup link.
You'll see that if you're interested in
coming and doing a meetup with us, then
please come out to sunny Colorado Springs.
I don't think the hotels are too pricey. I
did a lot of looking at Airbnb and it's
weird Colorado Springs is the only place
I've seen where there's going to be some
good speakers and a live hackathon, a good
hike at Garden of the Gods, and you'll
meet people in person that you just see in
chats kind of thing.
So great, looking forward to that.
kushti, you promised once July rolls
around, you're going to go to the
consulate and see if you can get here,
right?
Yeah, so probably. Yeah, around July 2nd
to 10th. Yeah, it will be known.
Yeah. Oh, here's a good one from Mark the
Shark. I don't think you've ever seen this
before, what it looks like, what changes
he did. I think there are minimal changes
to the node. But what would happen if
Cheese started just putting storage rent
stuff into the actual official node?
Yeah, well, I don't know how I haven't
seen.
Yeah, I'll talk to Cheese about that.
That's a great idea, Mark. Let's have
Cheese see what it's like and maybe he can
put some pull requests in the official
node, kushti. Is that something you'd be
willing to consider?
Yeah, let's see. So I need to check
modifications.
As long as it doesn't break anything
else, right? That'd be nice and easy.
Because the way that the SIGs pool are
running it is we run a modified node, we
run a modified mining core. And we run the
storage rent application itself, which is
a script.
So we run three things at the SIGs mining
pool. Most big pools are most likely not
running mining core. They're probably just
running stratum, so their own version kind
of thing. So they'll only need the
modified node and the storage rent kind of
thing, like Herominers, I doubt runs
mining core. Yeah, so putting the node
just like turnkey would be amazing if
Cheese could integrate his code into the
official releases. Then we could just
continue to stay up to date with the nodes
and mining pools could as well. And
there'd be nothing we'd have to really do
separately or wait for a sub release of
that once like 6.0 or 6.1 came out.
Awesome. All right, great. Well, Mark
suggest that to Cheese. Ping him. Ping
him, Mark. Ping him now. Let's see, one
more question we've got here, unless they
keep coming. Here we go, kushti. It is
from Byron. What were the thoughts behind
twin coins, and is that something still in
the works down the line? Maybe Armeanio?
Twincoin. Twincoin was a paper I've done
along with Professor Hong Shengzhou from
Virginia Commonwealth University. It's
actually a little bit theoretical result,
so to make it practical, we need to modify
it. Basically, the idea is to have one
proof-of-stake block after one
proof-of-work block, such a block
structure and yeah, to make it practical,
I believe we need to do more so it would
be like, I don't know, sub-blocks, but
proof of stake based sub-blocks,
basically, right?
So you generate, well, blocks via proof
of work and then yeah, via proof of stake,
you decide who will generate sub-blocks in
between blocks. Something like that, but
then, yeah, well, the whole security
analysis needs to be redone. And yeah,
well, so the main motivation was to show
some security against 50 plus percent
attack, which is actually achieved. But
yeah, well, aside of that, the protocol
proposed is not very practical, not very
efficient.
No, because you're using another
resource, right, so you use proof-of-work
along with proof-of-stake, so you need to
have both, right, not just proof-of-work
in order to write a chain suffix. So yeah,
then it actually provides better security.
But yeah, well, again, to make it
practical, there is need for more
efficient construction.
So yeah, well, maybe there is a need for
such a chain, but yeah, I think currently
there are more actual requests, rights,
demands, options to implement. Well, even,
for example, a private stablecoin, right?
So, well, it would be more appealing
probably because, well, currently, well,
in regards with consensus, there are a lot
of options implemented, but, yeah, I
think, well, for real-world adoption, so
you need for a little bit different things
maybe in the first place at this point.
I said that, what's it called? Thanks for
joining everybody. Sorry about the
downtime. I said that's a beauty of Ergo
and the decentralized nature, even on
things like this where Andy's connection,
who's the broadcaster all the time, goes
down, there's the ability for somebody
else. Like I just had to push a couple
buttons and set us up in OBS and we're
live again. It's hard to kill the voice of
Ergo or the Ergo stream or the Ergo
blockchain at all. So super, super cool
that we can just keep on cranking this
stuff out no matter what.
All right, kushti, any last words?
All right, all right. So see you,
everyone, around Ergoversary. And yeah,
busy days, but that's quite ordinary
state, right, of things. See you around
Ergoversary. So the summer is hot. And
yeah, well, after the really hot season...
Yeah, put those mining rigs in the
basements, guys. Don't have them up on
your main floor.
Yeah, well, keep in touch.