Good morning, Ergo community.
Excuse me, got a frog in my throat over
there.
Welcome to the 10th, 11th consecutive
community AMA, hosted by anybody who wants
to join and talk.
Today we have kushti, Richi, and Grayman.
It's good to see you guys. How you doing?
Doing well, doing well. How about you?
Hanging in there, a little sleepy, but
otherwise hanging in there.
Grayman was about to say hi too, Grayman.
I'm alive.
We here in the U.S. are suffering from
some crazy made-up time scheme called
daylight savings time. So it's 8 o'clock
for us in the morning as opposed to 9
o'clock, which doesn't seem like it makes
a difference, but it makes a big
difference on the first couple of days
when you're all thrown about.
It's better than losing an hour honestly.
But it is what it is. We fall back and we
spring ahead, is the term. Lose an hour in
the spring, gain an hour in the fall.
What new things are happening in the
ecosystem, guys?
So a lot of, starting from
infrastructure, there's going to be more
and more talks about AI, right, in
different aspects. Quite natural because,
well, Ergo is GPU minable, right, so,
well, a lot of intersections with AI
inference.
Here, then, I also believe that currently
payments in AI are mostly corporate owned,
right? And it's not quite acceptable. And
actually, I believe we have a lot of
solutions here because, well, after all,
the Ergo community is working on
programmable money for many years and a
lot of useful solutions for the AI space.
And, well, having a lot of talks with
different developers around the community.
Unfortunately, most are not so public, so
I believe, well, if we are going to act as
an open source money movement, then there
is need to communicate publicly, right?
Express ideas, get feedback and store all
those things in logs because some things
are actually revived a few years after,
right, and getting implemented.
So, well, everything is quite useful
here. Well, most of information, I
believe.
We even have an AI game coming up this
weekend. Tim Erg's AI game Sigma Quest
starts this weekend, Sunday morning.
Oh, what is that? Can you elaborate on
what that is, Grayman?
I don't know fully. I wish he were here
to explain it because he'd do a better
job. But in essence, it's sort of a
scavenger hunt type deal where you solve
three problems, probably with the help of
AI.
And if you manage to solve them for each
one, you get a few of the keywords from an
ergo wallet that currently contains 200
ERG, but everybody who participates has to
kick in 20 ERG, 15 of which goes into the
pot.
So if you got 10 people playing, you
could stand to win 350 ERG, which is not a
small amount of money, so worth it if
you're in the mood to have some fun.
Essentially, it's not like Game of
Prompts, but it's similar. I think you
have to solve these problems in order to
win. There was something sort of game
theory-ish about how it worked, because if
you got one of them and not the others,
then you had an advantage. And you could
share with other players. You could share
your seed phrase in order to leapfrog to
the win.
But I have to read the rules again before
it starts. It's on Sunday, if anybody's
interested.
I'm looking at it right now. There's a
couple of different ones. There's yes-no,
oracle version, narrative escape version,
sigma-not-guardian version. I see yes-no
version is dealing with an AI that is
damaged and can only respond yes or no to
your questions. That's pretty neat.
90% goes to the community pot prize, 10%
goes to the project treasury. Each
completed guardian rewards players with
five seed phrases. Oh, so there's three
guardians. So yes, no, oracle, the
narrative escape, and the sigma knot
guardian.
This is pretty cool. Did he start this in
the last Ergo hack? Was that what this is?
Yes. And unfortunately, he was right
about to release it. And it turns out that
he discovered that there were some ways to
kind of cheat it. And so he called it off
and said, let me get my hack together.
And so he regrouped. I think Tim, like
everybody else in the Ergo ecosystem, has
his own job and his own life, which is,
we're a collection of interesting people,
not VC funded with a team of five coders
and then a bunch of Red Bulls and pizzas
and trying to knock out solutions for the
VC if they crack a whip.
That's not our go. So he's got his own
life. It took him a couple of months to
get it back up and running, but here we
are.
He's using Lovable, I think, AI to help
him write it. I just put the link to the
Ergo website where they have an article on
this game in chat if people want to see
that. But it looks pretty fun.
I remember the fun puzzle games that
Maverick used to do. Those are really
incredible and fun and well thought out.
I've seen Maverick pop up in chat
recently.
Yeah, I did. Yeah, that guy's cool. He's
also somebody who's, his real life sort of
interrupted for a while. But he poked his
head up again in chat recently, said he's
doing great.
Oh, we got somebody in the waiting room.
Let's see if this person's a spammer.
We'll give it a try. Yeah, what else
happened this week?
We had a good kind of choke this week
about, for those of you who don't know,
some of our infrastructure is on Hetzner,
and historically it's been paid for by the
EF, and there was a billing issue midweek
or end of last week. They went down, which
shouldn't be a problem because we
literally have like eight other backup
explorers kicking around.
And if you saw chats, you saw that I
posted all those APIs and GraphQLs and
Explorer endpoints in chat in hopes that
in the future, dApps will just use a
rollover technique if they can't reach one
explorer to go to the other.
But that was interesting to see the choke
points, right? Because we witnessed a
choke point from Amazon and Microsoft a
couple weeks ago as well. But I think we
can be completely resilient to that kind
of stuff, right?
Eventually, so the way the infrastructure
is going to work, hopefully, is that there
will still be a choke point at CloudFlare
load balancer, right? The DNS has to point
to somewhere to go and then load balance
to the 10, 11, 12, exploring instances
that are out there across the globe.
So the way around that as well is create
unique IDs for each one of those load
balance endpoints. So that while we can't,
if we're going to rely on Cloudflare for
the load balancer or some other single
load point for the load balancer, at least
dApps can build in the individual load
balance machines as well.
So if a dApp tries to hit the load
balancer first for a user and goes
geographically to the right location
nearest the person for the best speed, if
that doesn't work because Cloudflare is
down, then it'll just roll over to one of
the load balancers directly and have
direct access to it.
So that's a hope there, that we're
completely impervious to that kind of
outage, those centralized outages.
We've got, as I said last week, those
three machines shipped out. And I think
two of the people got them. Maybe all
three did. They'll be syncing their nodes.
Once that happens, there is some database
optimizations we have to do to them all at
once so that there are a couple of queries
that are really database intensive and
fail if the database hasn't been optimized
in a certain way.
So once that's done and we do those tests
and make sure it's good, then either we
repoint the Ergo platform explorers
through the peer-to-peer network, kind of
like we did this week for a little bit to
test, and then we burn them down. And we
stop that $700 a month drain to pay for
those things. And the community takes it
over which I think is absolutely amazing
and how it should be, right?
Grayman, you were talking about joining
the network as well weren't you at some
point?
I can't use one of my customers fiber
lines for this purpose. I'd have to get my
own and I live out in the county. So it's
coming my way. But apparently the company
that was going to roll it out here got
bought out by T-Mobile. So God knows how
long it's going to take.
You don't want to run a node off a cell
connection?
It's cable, but it's asymmetric. So the
upload speed is just too slow to support.
I don't want to join and be a worthless
limping piece.
At least the way Cloudflare works,
Grayman, is we can weight you a little
bit. So if we have a geographic location
and you're sharing it in the US with, it's
going to be five or six other people, we
can actually give you a weighted average
of how many times people hit you so that
you're not equally hit as many as other
people.
So if I'm on, the three here that I have
are on a 10 gigabit connection
asymmetrical, so I can give myself more
weight as opposed to you. I can give you
10% of the weight of the pool so that
you're not hit as much. So to the user,
it's going to feel the same, right?
Because not being crowded or jumped up.
So think about it, Grayman, if you want
to do it.
I am an old school IT guy. For the last
five years, that's mostly about migrating
people to the cloud.
Now you're coming home, Grayman, you're
coming home.
I miss the good old days. So maybe I'm
helping you.
All right, sweet. I think in the
corporate environment here or the
educational environment, there's been a
big push, I'd say, in the last, well, I've
been here 17, 18 years at Cornell. There's
been a big push to make everything easier
by going to the cloud, right? And I fought
it since the beginning simply because it's
used as an excuse to drain the most
important thing from the institution and
that's institutional knowledge, right?
If you can pay Microsoft to run your
mail, why do you need two mail experts on
staff here, right? You can fire them and
you can hire somebody at 30, 40, $50,000
that just pushes buttons and calls
Microsoft support when they need help,
right?
But if they were running an exchange
server before, it's not like this is holy
knowledge to know how to run Exchange
2013.
I love that that shit's outsourced. God,
I hate it. SharePoint was the worst, and
now that's somebody else's problem.
True, but it makes a huge hole in that.
And maybe exchange was a bad example for
that. But I understand that. But it goes
for many other things as well. A lot of
expertise has dropped.
There was an article one day about 15, 16
years ago from somebody in the education
training department here at Cornell and
the article literally was we do not need
IT people on staff anymore at Cornell
because we just need IT architects and the
way they described that was people who
they could bring in that knew how to
design and call Dell and something breaks,
send it to Dell or get a Dell parts locker
here or ship it over here or set this up.
So sure, it's another method, but again,
it's an institutional drain. And actually,
I think that person's now CIO of some
college somewhere, unfortunately.
But back to the cloud computing idea.
Cloud computing really enables that for
corporate and educational institutions.
And I don't embrace that for most things.
I think if we can build things to an open
framework that is shareable and we design
things that can be designed well enough to
where if somebody from another department
says, hey, I like what you're doing there.
It's really cool. Can we share it?
And I click a button because I've already
designed it in the framework that's
shareable like that. Or I say, yeah,
here's my git, go for it, do what you
need. And maybe they make something better
than me and I come back and I clone their
repository and go from that kind of thing.
So that's my belief that expertise and
things like that should stay local.
Exactly like we saw when two weeks ago
when Amazon went out and Solana and those
chains are scrambling and shitting their
pants because it's another sample of just
in time inventory.
It's just the way that things are done in
the modern world. And it is fragile, but
it's effective. I mean, and it's a
nuisance when something goes wrong because
nobody that's in the chain of solution has
any idea what they're doing aside from
their little part of the chain.
So coming from the old world and having
to troubleshoot this stuff, which is what
I do all the time, because I'm where the
rubber meets the road at the end user at
the client level. And so it's solving all
these weird problems.
And the tools that I have are not reading
the manual or futzing with stuff and
trying to fix it on a test server. It's
just patience and knowing what to Google
and talking nicely to this person in the
chain who is part of the solution and all
those types of stuff.
It's turned my job into a touchy-feely
thing that I hate, which is why I'm here
in Ergo. And so maybe it's not
coincidental that I'm interested in going
back to peer-to-peer and local solutions
as opposed to this. Maybe it's my
subconscious is telling me that I want to
escape my corporate job.
That could be. Yeah, I mean, think about
scaling, right? If you want to spread
yourself like with a chain that requires
cloud infrastructure, think about the cost
of spreading your assets over Amazon, over
Microsoft, over some other cloud provider,
hoping that there's not some choke point
in between that they both use, right?
So the cost there versus scaling it over
a system of peer-to-peer users who built
the nodes themselves so they know how they
function, they know how to spin things up
and down, and they know hopefully why
things break, and the redundancy there. I
think that speaks for itself in times like
a couple weeks ago with the great crash of
AWS.
So it's really excited about that.
That'll be really good to be able to boast
that kind of thing that all our main
infrastructure is held by the peers that
are part of the network. So that'll be a
good bragging point.
Infrastructure-wise, we need to do some
maintenance work and bug fix for Explorer.
Well, the first pull request just got in
the Explorer backend repository.
Also, we are looking for maintainers of
Ergo Wallet. I believe for now it makes
sense to update Android SDK and so on and
publish new versions of Ergo Wallet at
least.
Then we will consider what wallets of
future should be like, right, especially
in the presence of AI agents which can
make with certain things.
So, well, for humans, it's not so
convenient to have and to operate with
hundreds of tokens in your wallet, right?
But for AI agents, it's kind of trivial.
So, well, money for AI systems could be
done very differently from what we have
now, and it could lead to more efficient
economic interactions.
Then I need to think with MHS monitor our
team, right? Maybe we can find ways to
publish that mobile wallets also. Right,
because it's quite amazing. It's
supporting multi-sig, right, and so on. So
it makes sense maybe to add multi-sig
support to ergo wallet as well but we also
need to publish monitor, I believe.
Yeah, that was supposed to come out of
the mobile soon, I think.
Those are two important infrastructure
pieces, right? So I'll explore on the
wallets.
And, well, I'm also in talks with
different, well, guys, teams, circles and
so on. Well, with Grayman and Thomas on
real-world assets tokenization. Quite
specific and not like what most of
so-called crypto industry is doing, right?
So for chain cache basis, I'm still
testing and polishing things with white
coding, now small step. But I think, well,
some things can be announced in coming
days.
And for sub blocks. We are going to
launch Dev Nets in a few days, now bigger.
Now we have some contributors with
Raspberry Pis. Well, we have a few people
from different continents, so it will be
quite funny. And well, from that, we can
plan further.
What to do after white paper release and
welcoming to discussions, right? So a lot
of things going on in parallel and it's
November and Richi has plans also for the
USE DexUSD stablecoin launch.
So Richi, what are the current plans?
Yeah, hello. Can you hear me? Yeah, thank
you. So the current plans are to have a
large event called CLB, which was
presented in Ergo Hack 9.
So as long as we sort out the technical
part, and we understand that there will be
no basically delays launching the coin or
maybe we can even mint some coins but just
don't activate the smart contract or don't
activate the off-chain part whatever just
waiting for the initial bootstrap event.
So as soon as we know this we will start
probably two weeks marketing campaign. And
then we will go into a so-called CLB
community liquidity bootstrap event, which
will offer people to participate with the
ERG on ERGO as well as rsERG on Cardano.
And in exchange they will be getting CLB
tokens as well as some other airdrops,
bonus airdrops, but the main one they will
be getting CLB token.
In total I plan to have only 100 CLB
tokens minted with nine decimals, so it
will be 100 CLB tokens minted with nine
decimals and it will be distributed
proportionally to everyone who contributes
their ERGs to the initial bootstrap of
liquidity pool.
So, as an example, if you contributed 100
ERGs and total overall contribution is
10,000 ERGs, right, to bootstrap the pool.
I'm sure there will be more, but just as
an example. Then your part is 1% and you
will get one CLB token airdropped to you.
What CLB token means it will represent
your part in the liquidity pool. So after
that all liquidity collected will be used
to start the USE liquidity pool, initial
pool, bank.
So half of the ERGs collected will go to
bank reserves, and another half will be
collected, will be connected with the
liquidity of the minted tokens. And that
liquidity tokens that will be created will
be locked for two years. And instead, you
will get the CLB representation.
It may sound confusing if you're not
familiar with how the system works. But
basically the whole idea is to have a big
pool of liquidity locked for two years and
then reward people who participated in the
bootstrap with the so-called
representation token.
Now that CLB token can be traded on Ergo
DEXes. So like I said, there will be only
100 tokens created and each token will
represent 1% of the liquidity pool. So
these tokens will be traded on Ergo DEXes.
So they will have value. And after two
years, the smart contract, redeemed smart
contract will start working. So if after
two years, you own CLB token, you will be
able to redeem liquidity from USE ERG
liquidity pool.
So with this approach, what we're trying
to achieve is we're trying to bootstrap
liquidity initially. That's very important
to have lots of liquidity from the start
of that stable coin. And because of that,
our free mint and arbitrage mint and all
the bank actions will work nicely.
So people will launch economics and
things like that on top of that. So I
don't know if people who are familiar with
this might understand what I was trying to
describe. People who are hearing this for
the first time may be confused.
But we will be talking more about it and
we'll be talking more about how to launch.
And I already started the white paper, so
I will publish it about the CLB and the
event. And also on Twitter, there will be
more announcements.
So, but at the moment what we are waiting
is for kushti to tell us a go ahead saying
that yes, all the technical part is clear
and we are basically on a finish line to
launch this protocol.
What will be the order of magnitude of
the amount of ERG that is required to be
part of these liquidity provisions to get
one of these tokens?
Right, so there will always be 100
tokens. It depends how many are collected.
I'm just saying, what are you shooting
for? If there's 100 tokens, are you
looking for 100,000 ERG? Do you need
10,000 per person?
Everyone will get proportionally to the
contribution. There are only 100 tokens,
but they have nine decimals. So if your
contribution part is very small, you will
get 0.0 something of this token, but it
will be your representation part.
So my goal would be to collect around
300,000 to 400,000. So one token will be
worth, so you can just divide it by 100,
right? So if we collect 300,000 ERGs, so
one token would be worth 3,000, right? So
3,000 ERGs would be one token. And you
will get proportionately to your part of
that overall contribution.
I hope that answers the question.
Yeah, I guess really what I was just
asking is, what is the order of magnitude
of the initial bootstrap liquidity? So
you're saying that you have to part with
3,000 ERGs, and two years later, you can
then draw them out of this. So what is my
incentive? Do I make additional earnings
on these tokens if I get one of these?
Yes, that's a good question. So what you
will get if you participate? So first of
all, you will get CLB token, which will be
representing your part of your
contribution. Anyway, after that, you'll
get some airdrops from our partners
additional as a bonus.
And then your liquidity pool is
bootstrapped with 0.3% fee. So during
these two years, all the fees will be
accumulated for all the people who will be
trading USE tokens with ERGs back and
forth, right? And I hope there will be
lots of trading going on in that pool.
All that fee will be accumulated and then
after two years, you will be able to
withdraw your part of liquidity with your
CLB token with all the collected fees as
well as all the airdrop bonuses that you
will get in the stock, right?
Now, if you don't want to wait two years,
you need something early. There will be a
secondary market for CLB tokens. I'm sure
a lot of people will want to buy those
tokens cheap and sell them high because
they clearly have the value. So each token
has a clear value because it's connected
to your liquidity pool.
So people will be trading it on the
MewFinance Spectrum on all our DEXes. And
yes, it will have a value. So if you don't
want to wait, you just contribute, you
collect your bonus airdrop, and after
that, you sell your CLB token on the
secondary market. And then there
definitely will be people who will want to
buy it. You don't need to wait.
Or you can hold it. Or if you think there
is lots of potential, and then there will
be lots of fees accumulated, you can buy
it from the secondary market as well, the
CLB tokens, as much as possible. And that
your part in the liquidity pool will grow
with it.
I hope that sounds clear.
So after two years, what happens? These
tokens still exist and you still get
rewards based on them? I'm still not
getting it. What's my incentive to be one
of the initial liquidity providers if I
can just buy these tokens on the secondary
market in one and a half years?
What unlocks in that second year if
there's a secondary? What am I getting? I
still don't get it. What happens after the
second year?
So after the second year, when you
construct liquidity, you get liquidity
tokens like LP tokens. These LP tokens
will be locked in a redeemed smart
contract with CLB tokens for two years.
So after two years, the smart contract
will unlock the redeem function. So you
will be able to exchange your CLB token to
liquidity token and after that,
conventionally remove liquidity from
liquidity pool. Okay? So with all the fees
accumulated.
Now, if you participate in the initial
liquidity bootstrap rather than buying on
the secondary market, you will get some
bonus airdrops, which at the moment we
expect to be about between 5 to 10% of the
value of your contribution.
And is that just done by like a database
that you have a list of wallets that
contributed and ignores the tokens that
are in people's wallets that they might
have purchased from the secondary market?
Well, people can purchase tokens from the
secondary market. It means someone sold
it. Did they get the air drops?
Yes, so if you contribute ERGs during the
initial bootstrap, you will get Airdrop
and the CLB token. After that, CLB token
will be traded on the secondary market.
So if you want to buy it on the secondary
market, obviously you buy it as usual
token, right? Nothing different. Also, if
you want to sell, if you can sell your CLB
tokens straight away as well as sell all
your airdrop tokens, and then possibly you
can even make like quick money on it.
So possibly there will be like, you will
probably make a little bit of money if you
just sell CLB tokens straight away on the
secondary market as well as all your
airdrops, because airdrops are meant to
cover between 5% and 10% of your
contribution.
So I'm too dumb to chase quick profits.
But I do wonder, like, so after the two
years are up, then this thing unlocks. And
at that point, is there any purpose left
to these original tokens? Or does
everything just become normal liquidity
provisions in the DEX?
No, these tokens, so this contract will
exist forever, right? The redemption
contract. So you can redeem the portion of
liquidity pool of liquidity tokens and
then redeem liquidity or you just can keep
these tokens in your wallet for 10 years
and just accumulate fees.
Your LP tokens will be locked in the
original USE LP liquidity pool and they
will stay there until you decide to redeem
them. So it's essentially like keeping
liquidity tokens in your wallet as long as
you want.
That's some good questions, Grayman, and
I hope people who will be listening to
this podcast will start digging into it
more.
Actually, I think maybe it makes sense to
have Twitter spaces next week, and
specifically about the USE launch, and so
on, the Dexy design, because still, I
believe, many people don't quite follow
even the basics, right, and so on.
And during the week, well, we can promote
Dexy Gold, right, so people will have a
chance to play with the protocol, then ask
questions and so on. How does it sound,
Richi?
So next week is busy because we have a
Cardano Summit and then some traveling.
I see, maybe in two weeks then. So closer
to launch and next week maybe we can do
spaces on basis changes, all that stuff,
so there is need to provide updates and
some digestible forms.
The recent weeks I am mostly just coding
and providing short updates. I think after
some more polishing and testing it makes
sense to provide more details on the
protocol, answer questions, and promoted
around, well, people interested in, well,
local payment systems as well as, well,
payment systems for AI.
For peer-to-peer payments now, quite big
topic and so on, right? So it's quite a
big trend now. Let's ride on it.
Yeah, sounds good.
Richi, somebody in the chat says, what's
the hardest part of launch right now and
how can they help?
So, launch will be done with MewFinance.
So, we already, actually, since ErgoHack
9, it's almost one year since we did this
presentation, ErgoHack 9, I encourage
everyone to go and just go to Ergo YouTube
channel, and look at the ErgoHack 9. I
explain how this launch will work. The
video is there.
And I'll be publishing more papers on
that. So the basis is already done,
everything for the launch. So, actually,
it's not much needed. How it will look,
you will see some UI. I can probably share
some UI how it will look, but it will be
similar to the other token launch paths
that they have.
Yes, when you look into MewFinance, you
will need, if you are contributing with
original ergo on ergo blockchain, you will
just need to leave your ergo wallet from
which one you will be doing the payment.
You will contribute your ERG, you will
transfer your ERG and then after that you
will immediately see how much ERG you
contributed and total ERG contributed so
you will know your share.
After two days, so I plan to run it for
three days, after three days we will
basically the final number will be known
and you will get your contribution part.
So for example 1%, 1.234% and you will get
CLB tokens as well as some other sponsored
tokens airdropped to your wallet.
And after that the secondary market will
be created and then you can trade this CLB
in a secondary market or hold it as well
as just enjoy the small little bonus.
How can you help at the moment? Just
attend spaces and subscribe to my Twitter,
USE Twitter account. So it's there. I'll
be posting some updates with my USE
account on Twitter, specifically dedicated
to this stable coin.
And just follow up on the news and you
will not miss this event. I think it will
be quite interesting. It's very novel to
current DeFi.
Actually, let me tell you a little bit.
Let's spend a couple of minutes talking
about USE and it's very novel and it's
trying to solve very big problems in the
current DeFi.
All stable coins that we have are
basically centralized, right? There are no
decentralized tokens. There are some kind
of attempts like Athena, but their
resources are also centralized.
So USE or Dexy has very unique design and
it's a lot of great minds behind it from
design perspective, as well as from trying
to build the trading experience and
launch, et cetera.
It will be working with Rosen. We will be
working with Rosen to make sure that the
distribution of this stablecoin is as wide
as possible. And as you could have
guessed, the launch itself, the CLB event
is also quite unique in DeFi space.
So what we're trying to do is not just
copy paste something that's going on on
Ethereum, but create something really
unique and sometimes unique DeFi.
If this project succeeds, obviously,
there will be so much recognition to Ergo
and I'll be doing everything possible to
get us there. Because all this technology,
we were talking for years about the great
technology and all our first principles
and P2P finance and things like that.
But for most of the world, what do they
see? They see us on a coin market cap. And
that's all. And they don't know about our
products. Maybe some people know about
Rosen. But mostly, that's it, right?
And we're trying to reach a wide
audience. Because for people, having
stable coin is very clear. You understand
what stable coin is, right? Okay, so you
know, okay, this coin is $1. That's all I
need to know. I'm not interested if ERG's
price goes to 10 or 0.1. I know that this
stablecoin is always $1.
And I'm interested in it because I use
the dollars daily, right? So with that, I
am trying to capture a big audience and
lots of eyes are looking to Ergo because,
like I said, the technology is very unique
that we have. We have great minds. We just
need a little bit more recognition and
then more attention.
Very interesting, Richi. I'm looking
forward to the launch.
From what I've heard, I think it makes
sense if you are non-dev and willing to
help maybe to watch those ErgoHack
presentations, right, and make some
simpler versions like a one-pager and so
on, right, so could be doable with manual
recheck by some dev.
Well, they I also I don't like that much,
but okay. So, well, I think, well, a lot
of help could be there, right, and in the
space of doing more and more materials.
So back in the days of SigmaUSD launch,
the community did some amazing job by
promoting, doing one-pagers all those
things and promoting them.
One comment if you allow me on that. So I
actually really like Ergo community and I
see how they're trying to promote it. I
like the initiative that people starting
with bootstrapping liquidity on Binance
chain, on Ethereum, trying to do
something.
And how we collected ergs for MC, it was
amazing. So what I'm trying to say is ergo
has a very nice community and people do
participate. Even for free, they just
donate.
Now, CLB will not be a donation. You will
actually make money with it. But people
are willing to donate. What we need in
their case is a little bit more
coordination and more like coordinated
effort.
And I think we can go a long way with it.
So I hope the launch of this stable coin
will be like a coordinated effort where
all the community can pick it up. And we
may see some amazing results with it.
There are still lots of plans. I have a
very, very long roadmap. I cannot say
everything now. Let's go step by step. But
let's start with the successful launch,
both from technical point of view and the
initial bootstrap. But there will be lots
of amazing things coming up down the road.
So we're here to shake the space. So stay
tuned.
Pretty much agree. So, well, for
coordination, we are discussing this all
the time, right? We are trying different
things. So, well, with many new faces now
joining the community. Well, there is need
always, I guess, to reconsider and
reshuffle some things, right? Not to be
like some old, I don't know, bureaucratic
kind of a rotten kind of environment.
There was a question on YouTube about
privacy from Mohit Tanwar. He says, as far
as privacy coins are concerned, almost
every privacy coin is booming. What's
wrong with ergo? When will we see the
booming price action in ergo? I know we
aren't supposed to talk about price, but I
do think it makes sense to talk about
privacy.
And it's true that privacy coins like
Zcash and Ergo, for that matter, yesterday
was trending on CoinGecko right along with
Zcash. But it does seem like our narrative
around privacy is different than the one
that is currently capturing the attention
of the market.
And you were talking about this a little
bit, I think, yesterday on Telegram. So I
figured that'd be a good way to prompt you
with a question.
I mean, my take on privacy in Ergo is
that it's at the app layer. I mean, it is
built into the core, into ErgoScript.
There's privacy tooling, and you can
certainly talk much more in depth about
that than I can.
But that it's good that it's optional,
because that means that if there's
optional privacy, that's optional
transparency as well. And so to the extent
that we're going to use Ergo for public
money systems, that transparency is very
important.
But eventually at the business layer, of
course, people want privacy. I don't want
my competitors to see how I spend my
money, where and when. I'm happy to report
my taxes to the IRS if that's what we have
to do for the last 100 plus years in
America, even though I wonder about how
that jives with the Fifth Amendment.
Nevertheless, I don't want my taxes that
I report to the IRS and all of that
transaction to be open on chain for
everybody to see. I do want privacy. I
appreciate optional privacy.
But at the same time, to even have an IRS
or a government money system, you need to
have transparency. Otherwise, you end up
with the worst examples of the Cantillon
effect and all these backroom deals, and
you get right back to the system that we
have right now.
It's important that Bitcoin was
transparent. It's not a flaw. It may be a
limitation, but it's not a flaw. It was
important. It would not be where it is
right now had it been Monero and
completely opaque, in my opinion. What do
you think?
So in many cases it's transparency,
right? What does matter? Especially we are
talking about blockchain. So all those
talks are quite strange. So well, it's at
the same time people praise blockchain for
transparency, right?
Then, well, there is need for privacy for
money. So I think, well, if we consider
blockchain as kind of a layer for reserves
mostly, right, so kind of digital
commodities then, well, in most cases
probably it should be transparent, right,
even then you need to privacy on cash
layer so basically something like basis,
right, so the privacy maybe even enforced
should be considered on the base layer.
So we have optional privacy, actually a
lot of tooling, so native support for
thresholds and ring signatures with
zero-knowledge properties being preserved,
unlike Bitcoin and so on, multi-sig, so as
far as I know, Ergo is the only one with
such properties.
A lot of applications for privacy
protocols that are done as applications
such as ErgoMixer, so non-custodial and
non-interactive tool to restore
fungibility of coins then. Stealth
addresses, so a tool to have privacy of
recipients and so on.
To be fair to Zcash they are optional
privacy.
And they are mostly transparent. So I
don't know about these days, but a few
years after launch, last time when I
checked, it was like 2% of total supply
was shielded.
So on the other hand, they are mined by
ASICs and that might explain their price
action, which touches on a whole other
topic, but again, price is not what we're
supposed to be discussing on the AMA.
Some people are now coming and demanding
for full privacy in Ergo, mandatory
privacy, but then I'm asking those people,
are they using ErgoMixer even or whatever,
so it seems. Well, there is no real
interest in privacy, so people are just
chasing the popular trends.
Well, to put a check on that, though,
it's not very easy to use Mixer. That
might be a really good candidate for a
dApp in a browser. In a browser wallet, or
even on a cell phone wallet.
But having the Mixer so that it would be
easy for an end user to just devote part
of their stash, part of their ergo, into
the Mixer so they can say, this is sort of
my private portion of my of my cash that I
can spend because it all spits out into
the stealth address and I can use that for
stuff that I don't want to be tracked and
traced on and having that be so not easy,
but.
Because you should never make it too
easy. People should think about what
they're doing and understand their
assumptions. But right now, it feels like
for somebody who's non-technical, the
mixer is maybe a bridge too far. So they
might genuinely be interested in privacy
and want that option.
I think what they're expressing is that
it's just too hard for them to implement
it and understand it. I sort of feel that
way. I've used the mixer a little bit, but
not really. It's a pain in the ass.
But in general, there were some arrests
of Monero users because of networking
security, right? Well, for the whole
stack, it's not easy at all to use all
those things. Even maybe if you are using
Tor, right, which is kind of red flag for
surveillance already.
There are a lot of things to consider
here, well, in regards with networking
security. So maybe we need to do some
encryption services and Ergo peer-to-peer
network rights to hide the source of
transactions with non-interactive and
non-custodial mixer. It could be the
weakest point here.
And then, mixer is not easy to use and
you need for counterparty if you mix large
enough chunk of liquidity and so on. Then
there are certain practices and maybe
default settings are suboptimal and so on.
So there is a kind of complex science
here, right? And not just in Ergo, but
here in general. So if you want to have
privacy in computer networks, then it's
not user friendly at all.
I have to say there are certain things
which we can do and should do but, well, a
lot of work ahead and not just here in
Ergo based on what's happening right
around and so for a few years also the
topic was basically silenced, right, in
the Ergo community as well.
So, good to see a revival of those talks
and, well, let's consider continue from
basically 2020 because, well. Regulatory
climate in America was very different a
year ago. Well, in the US, but then also a
lot of exchanges.
There were even certain attempts to
delist Ergo from some centralized
exchanges because they considered Ergo as
privacy coins. Well, it did not happen,
but there was a risk to get delisted from
some biggest exchanges by volume even now.
So, well, it was quite tricky even to
talk about privacy rights, well,
especially in public. I like tweeting
anything or whatever so for that you can
get ERG delisted rights from centralized
exchange or whatever.
So happily now it's a different climate
and we can continue basically from 2020
from that state and, well, it's good after
all. And, well, still it's not outdated
stack and so on. So we can continue.
kushti, let's just give a quick props to
the devs before we close out today. I just
popped a few things. We're a little late,
but we did start a little late. Let me
just roll through them really quickly in a
minute, just to give a heads up to people.
Let's see, kushti worked on R&D, reviewed
and opened an issue, worked on some sub
blocks, re-worked forking logic, continued
to work on white paper, and he worked on
Sigma SDK polishing and going to publish
more examples, and he got a review up
there.
Big update from Rosen Bridge. The final
test milestone for Bitcoin Runes release
has started. They hope to finish important
ones and start Bitcoin Runes development
deployment procedure. Awesome, by next
week. On chain token map they worked on
all supported tokens of the bridge is to
find an adjacent structured file very
cool. Let's see a UI app summary. They
added a new extracted a fetch token map
boxes Added callback to Rosen service and
added a wrap token map Rosen bridge guard
app they updated and they updated the
Rosen bridge app as well very cool.
So then ergo wallet and so there is need
to update ergo wallet and, well, consider
maintenance and then development, right?
So, well, if you guys know any kotlin java
android developers so, well, so try to get
them to our...
I'll talk to kushti. Awesome. We've got
Updating I think one of the last ones from
cyberverse. They're trucking along still
making their in-game battles a thing
They've completed their first version of a
death system low HP neutral Neural
distortion and visual corruption. Yes
collapse sequence and hospital response
and recovery breathing fogger. So that's
pretty cool. Very cool And that's it for
the dev updates and we are definitely over
time guys
And there are also updates from Git
circles, Lithos and so on. So we need to
push the teams to publish over the dev
chat. Not just them. And by the way, so we
can also do Twitter space on Lithos,
right? Because they have planned to launch
a test at mining soon.
Yeah, we should do that. That should be
some afternoon sometime. So Joe and Cheese
can be awake and participate and talk
about Lithos. That'd be great. I can ping
them right now before I forget.
Alright guys, thanks so much for joining
us. We'll see you next week around the
same time Thanks for those that popped on
for those that come into the waiting room
and chat And we bring you in and then you
leave I can't tell if you're a spammer or
not So if you want to chat and have your
video here of your audio here coming
before the start of the meeting is always
the easiest and Pop on your audio or you
video in chat with us for a bit so we can
verify you're not a racist spammer drawing
bad things on the screen or sharing
pornography standard on on just Following
the chat or the one that's on youtube Or
maybe you do on youtube and then that way
people can participate but we just
You know, we copy those because
otherwise, I don't know. Oh, I was
reading. I've got the questions. I've got
a question. You pasted them in chat before
I could get before I did. But we put
questions up. I think we're following
these. I mean people who want to come in
person and push in and talk with audio.
Great man is what I was referring to.
We hope to have more of them as long as
it works.
It's a proof of work, though. So you
actually have to work to show us that
you're not going to spam us or scam us on
the live stream, that's for sure.
In this regard, maybe Twitter space is
better, right? So it's immediately seen
there, I mean, in some history. Who you
are.
That's true. That is true. Maybe we can
try that next week. That's probably a good
idea, kushti.
Okay, great, everybody. Thanks so much
everybody have a good day and week ciao