All right, we are live.
Hello and welcome to a late night special
episode with everybody's favorite ergonaut
Joseph Arminio.
Joe, it's a pleasure to be here with you
tonight. How you doing?
Pretty good. I think you oversold me
there.
Did I? No, no, no.
We are live. Hell no. I don't think so,
sir.
I just checked our stream. Our stream's
working. That's a good sign, right? I'm
going to post it in chat to see who's
there.
Perfect. All right. I've got my water
glass to make sure that I have enough
hydration during this chat.
You got some apple juice there, Joe?
Perfect. Nothing like Colorado apple
juice made from the fresh Colorado apple
trees.
We have some somewhere.
Perfect. All right, Joe, how's it going?
How do you feel in this? What's it called?
You know, I was talking to Glasgow today
and I was like, if you listen to some
people out there in the space, most of the
time, I've been so busy lately with Ergo,
with the infrastructure now trying to move
machines around, trying to get them off
centralized like Hetzner servers or
unreliable cloud flare load balancing,
that kind of thing. You pick up your head
once in a while and you listen to these
guys. It's like the freaking world's
fallen. It's like, what are you guys
looking at? Because I'm seeing these
structures that we're building that are
absolutely fantastic. What the hell are
they seeing, Joe?
Well, most people don't run
infrastructure. I don't know how else to
say it. Crypto has moved pretty far beyond
this idea of peer-to-peer networks and the
space has only gotten dumber and dumber
and dumber as people don't localhost
anything. And so they care less and less
about what they're running and why they're
running what they're running. And it just
becomes like a leveraged form of
speculation. I can't, I don't really deal
with that crowd. I try not to because you
look at Rosen, right. Project I work on.
You want to be a watcher. If you want to
be a watcher, you need to run it, right?
Not only do you need to run it, Joe, but
you need to run it. You need to pay
attention. You need to make sure that you
want to make a profit off it. You want to
get all those transactions recorded and
get that funding from there. You got to
pay it. You got to upgrade when the
upgrades come.
You got to make sure it's running. You
got to run it. You look at Lithos, the
same thing, it's software. So if you want
to use it, you got to run it, right? And
so if I get a hard time from people that
don't really run anything, I don't know
what to tell them. At that point,
everything is just a ticker, a letter
subject to price charts over a five, ten,
twenty minute timeframe, I don't know, a
week timeframe. Well, if you're trying to
build stuff, you're running
infrastructure, your mindset's just a lot
longer, right? So there's a certain
disconnect between this idea of like being
a peer in the network, or a network
anyway, versus just being like a user or
investor. And it's a different mentality.
I am what I am, right? So I just ignore
it. Honestly, I just ignore it and then
like, well, what am I building? I know why
I'm building what I'm building. And that
makes me happy. Like if you take Lithos,
right? It's like, OK, the most interesting
property in proof of work is that anyone
anywhere can silently compute, submit a
block, get a reward. There's no cap.
There's no artificial bound set of actors
that can build blocks. It's just anyone,
anywhere at any time that has the energy
and hardware. You would think that a
system like that, in theory, could be
quite efficient in terms of having as many
block producers as possible. But you run
into this economic incentive issue where
if you're solo mining, you are in essence
playing the lottery where you're going to
win every once in a while, but you're not
going to win a lot.
You play the law of averages there,
right?
It just depends on the size of the
network, right? Every once in a while
there's someone with a BitAxe that throws
out a Bitcoin block. That's pretty cool to
see.
Oh, did you see the article about those?
There were these little, some of those
little things with LED screens like the
lottery miners, right, for Bitcoin. Come
to find out all it did was play a basic
image on the screen animation and the rest
was just bullshit. Just like selling
paperweights for people to plug in and
burn a tiny bit of electricity and feel
like...
It's almost like open source code is
important.
Almost, right?
Yeah, I think there was even someone that
was using like NiceHash, renting some hash
rate and decided to play the lottery and
hit a Bitcoin block, which is pretty damn
cool. Anyway, so what is Lithos designed
to do? It's we're trying to put everything
on chain so that everybody can build their
own blocks. Simple as that. And that's
something that because you have a huge set
of people that they're not peers, they
don't run anything, right? What they run
is their phone on CoinGecko or
CoinMarketCap and rotate, hop around,
chase whatever the flavor of the day is. I
can't handle that mentality. I would be
too stressed.
I get it. I think the separation I have
there, Joe, is that's fine. If you want to
speculate on tokens and do that kind of
thing, that's great. Try to make profit
off stuff. Try to make honest profit off
stuff. Arbitrage. Use the toolings that we
have to do that. But I really get hot and
pissy about value extraction. One of those
things, if you come into a project and
your number one goal is to extract as much
value from it as you can for your own
pockets instead of building up and being
part of it and growing that, that's when
you're going to hear from me and probably
not for long because I'm probably not
going to talk to you for much longer than
that.
You're nicer than me. At the end of the
day, you're nicer than me. Whenever I run
into that, I just tell people pain is the
best teacher.
That is true. That is true.
Pain is going to teach you better than I
ever could. And whenever in my life,
whenever I have a problem, I run into
something and I have to hit my head
against the wall to figure it out. It's a
powerful, powerful teacher. So there's a
lot of people that in crypto they've
chased whatever. Whatever cartoon, meme,
pump fun stuff is out there. They got
burned. Pain is a teacher, right?
My hope is, too, that we can at least
show them some resemblance of usefulness
and what the blockchain is about. So even
if they do get burnt, they can at least
say, Ergo had something cool. Ergo had
something cool. They're actually using it
for this. This is what they're doing. Let
me just peek into that a little bit. So
maybe there's some hope of light there
that we're at least projecting into
people's eyes when they come by.
Crypto was a lot better when there were a
lot more miners because people were
actually running things, right? And we've
shifted so far away to like everything is
delegated through someone else some other
service some other person some other pool
and you get further and further and
further away from like being a peer that
for a lot of things, that's just the
marketing, right? Because it's like, okay,
well, if you have information that's
flowing between the point of like order
execution and the user, and you have the
ability to see that as it's moving before
it gets there, that is information that
has value, right? So you do see a lot of
VCs actually just doing like more
infrastructure plays. Hey, maybe we can
create a wallet, and they're probably not
making money from the fees, I'm gonna
assume, right? It is what it is like that
that is why you want to be a peer in these
networks is because you have the ability
to run your own transactions You have the
ability to run your own software.
Yeah, I always have this fantasy, not
fantasy but I was of this idea of miners
as the digital farmers of the world right
like you look at I think I use a
comparison of like I imagine a futuristic
miner of a blockchain that sustains their
family perhaps with the transaction fees
and and the rewards like you look at like
the kind of futuristic outfits like in
Star Wars those half underground houses.
They have all this machinery and they're
out with their moisture condenser things
that they're doing. So same kind of thing.
I feel like what other industry can you
literally go out and get consumer goods?
And when I say consumer goods, I mean
definitely with Ergo, right? Because we're
ASIC resistant and you can use consumer
level video cards. What other industry can
you go out there, build your way up,
create something in your own environment
here, control it, point it where you want
to, do what you want to, run a solo if you
want to, and reap the benefits of that and
also contribute to the network.
I tend to look at proof of work from the
perspective that it's most optimized
whenever there's excess capacity, right?
We've already seen that in Bitcoin, where
you have like flare off gas mining, and
they'll try to build their miners close to
power infrastructure points, and then load
cycle the output. I do think that as more
people get like there's going to be a lot
of developers out there. They're going to
have their little GPU rig for AI, right?
They're going to have a lot of big AI data
centers that have cold capacity, right? I
think these things naturally plug in
really well to GPU proof of work.
Even when people realize that AI
companies aren't making money right now
and they're cooking up books and it's
actually good.
The amount of leverage that they're
taking on to scale is fucking wild, right?
Crazy. It really is wild. And then it's
like, okay, well, for in the first order,
right, you have capacity, right? Where
let's say the popular LLMs, what
percentage are they actually running hot
in that data center versus what is like
cold storage that is in essence waiting to
come online when demand peaks? That's an
interesting question. I don't actually
know the answer to that across different
systems. But then you have kind of the
second order effects, which is like this
cutthroat competition to always have the
best hardware, right? Because that is
something that's going to lead to better
models is better hardware. And then it's
like okay well realistically you take I
don't know the H100 how many years is it
going to have before it then passes on to
like a secondary market secondary life and
at that point you're upgrading these
facilities and installing new hardware and
at some point those are going to recycle
out. And they do trickle down, right?
They do trickle. And speaking in more
nuance than that, Joe, it's just like ASIC
miners, right? It's in the interest of the
people creating these chips to flood at
least a small sector of the market for a
discounted price. So let's say you flood
1% of the market with a discounted price,
right? For these chips and also these
chips are now beating the pants off every
other chip out there in the market, right?
Because there are older chips out there in
the market. Now everybody's going to buy
your chips to catch up and you have that
rat race going there too. So it's
absolutely corporate driven in these
circumstances.
Yeah, and then you have a guy on the
mountain that it's like, hey, if I can buy
an extra 3060 and plug it into my solar
system when I'm running at excess
capacity, why not mine a little bit,
right? Eventually, that'll pay itself off.
And I've already invested all this stuff
in power for my house. So why wouldn't I
want to just take that excess capacity
that I have and do something with it,
right? I actually personally. One of these
days, I've always wanted to hook the solar
up to a little mining rig, heat a
greenhouse, then I get food. Then I'm just
passing on that excess and the different
outputs that are beneficial to my reality.
You have enough panels to run your whole
house, Joe?
It's not a ton of power, but yeah.
You can run a beer fridge and a grill
probably, right? That's enough.
I don't need an electric grill out here.
Just start a fire. I mean, those type of
setups I think are the most interesting
thing where it's like, OK, you have the
ability to capture heat. You have the
ability to capture excess power
production. You have the ability to like
capture cold computational power with GPU
mining and that's huge because if you look
at the actual hardware on the ground
that's scaling right there's going to be
probably more.
The dollar values in GPU added into our
economy then the entire Bitcoin market cap
and people are I don't understand I don't
understand why there's not why there's not
startup companies going around right now
to all these facilities saying look we can
increase your profit margins by 10% if you
do these kind of recapture processes with
heat with with extra electricity on mining
other things I can't believe nobody's
tried that yet.
I honestly believe that that sort of
thing will come. It'll just be the
natural, when the incentives there and
someone realizes it and chases it, there's
a lot to do there, right? Is it something
that I think about every once in a while?
Yeah, I mean, I've made an article, I
don't know, six months ago, like, here's
how you would optimize Autolykos and make
a sigma chain that's for clusters, right?
Is that something I actively want to
chase? Not really, but I always come back
to it when I look at all the hardware
that's coming online and I'm like, wow,
this is not running at full capacity. Now,
there are Bitcoiners that are like, hey,
you know what you should do is you should
buy ASICs and then plug them in and then
you can mine Bitcoin and also like balance
your power for all this other computer
equipment that might have another use,
right? And I'm just waiting. I think it's
better to just focus on Lithos because if
that type of mining does come online and
you do have that type of solution where
all of these different centers and users
can potentially build their own block
template, produce their own blocks, that
would be really cool because it would be
more decentralized. I do think mining
pools have been terrible for Nakamoto's
consensus and proof of work. Absolute
shit, right? I get why they exist. But
even on Bitcoin, you have things like
Ocean showing up that are quite
interesting projects. Now, it's funny that
when I build on Bitcoin with Ergo stuff,
Rosen, we're validating off-chain. And
when we're working on the mining stuff on
Ergo, we're validating everything from the
mining pool on-chain. But then you can
look at Ocean is validating everything
off-chain. You can do what you can do. But
I do think that there's a lot of really
interesting potential for GPU just because
of the net amount of hardware that's going
to come online in the next 10 years. It
makes no sense to have a data center,
right? I mean, let's say you own a
business, right? And it's like, okay,
you've invested all of this money in
developing this data center, buying these
cards, setting up the power
infrastructure, et cetera. And you
probably have pretty damn good power
prices. If you have any common sense,
that's why you placed your center where
you did, right? And you have a lot of
leverage debt that you've taken on to
scale. And you're basically burning your
cards at some floating rate like it's not
that hard to say okay what can you create
some sort of like micro controlling
software that just balances proof of work
with demand right then you're always
running hot all the time. and you're
getting as much value out of your hardware
stack as you can. I think that makes
sense. It doesn't take a lot of extra
capital expenditure versus Bitcoin mining.
And the truth is, most of the value of
Bitcoin has been captured a long time ago
by miners. So I think there might be some
interesting things with like super cluster
mining and that type of proof of work. And
I think if we can break the dominance of
mining pools, that's where things get
interesting. That's where you have a
really decentralized global system where
you have all of these different actors,
potentially building their blocks and
submitting it to the chain. So I'm
excited.
I mean, I do hope. Initially, Autolykos
was used for to resist mining pools,
right? Initially with Ergo, was that the
deal? You didn't want mining pools.
Well, mining pools are pretty toxic in
terms of the security assumptions, right?
Bitcoin, it's like three entities that
control block production and like that's
terrible. But nonetheless, you have all of
these individual miners that do have like
local custody of their hardware. They are
running their own power. It's just a
matter of where they're pointing it, but
they don't necessarily understand how he
who controls order flow, like controls
everything in markets. And when you have
just a basic payment system, it doesn't
really matter, right? Like on Bitcoin,
it's like, okay, if I send it to you and
it's mined in this block or five blocks
from now, it's just going from Alice to
Bob and who really cares. But when you
start building markets on these systems,
right? where it's like okay well now you
have race conditions now you have DeFi
like now you have this like competition on
top of the blocks where you're constantly
trying to arbitrage or race for the better
price, the better trade, suddenly this
ability to control order flows is massive
in terms of the economic power that you're
controlling versus just Alice to Bob who
gives a fuck, wait 10 minutes. Sit down,
go outside, have a cigarette, it'll get
there next block. Versus when it's like,
hey, you have to pay back your collateral
or you're going to get liquidated, right?
Then suddenly it's an entirely different
ballgame.
So now, but with Lithos, right? The
individual miners are going to have to be
more in tune to that and pay more
attention to stocking blocks and stacking
them full of transactions.
Yeah, I think there's some really
interesting potential like in terms of
building markets, right? Because that's
ultimately what you want, is to build free
markets on top of these systems. Or it's
like, OK, well, can we create channels for
me to submit a transaction to you, the
miner, through Mixnet for privacy? So I
never broadcast my IP address, right? And
then pay for a priority fee for you to
mine it. Or can we create these other
layers of markets for priority fees in
DeFi, et cetera, where you're passing on
value to the people building blocks,
right? I think there's a lot to build on
there. You may even have Demurage
potential. Storage rent has come online
enough to where it is actually releasing
DeFi operators.
Yeah, for sure.
You think we'll see other chains adopt
Demurage after the fact, Joe?
It's really dirty, too, in my opinion.
Pretty rough assumptions to throw on a
chain. I'll get on like Twitter or X or
whatever the fuck people are called these
days, and I'll talk about Demurage,
because I do think that it's a really
clean solution in terms of like UTXO state
management, right? So suddenly you have
this live set of UTXOs that just moves
forward in time. That's really a beautiful
system that Alex came up with. You have
supply availability become some things
that you can accurately project forward
through time versus supply availability.
Bitcoin is unknown because it's until you
sign your transaction, who knows if you
lost your key. And then you have something
like Solana, where they just find a
fucking bunch of coins somewhere else. And
they're like, oh, yeah, sorry, guys, we
forgot about that. Right. What was it?
It was a chain that we minted. Was that
the chain that we minted like a massive
amount?
You always have some weird fuck. Yeah.
That was they have a stadium in L.A. It's
an exchange out west.
I live in the mountains, man. I don't
care.
It's closer to you than me, sir.
But no, I honestly think like supply
supply integrity, and the ability to
predict like the available supply is
incredibly important for a monetary
system. Right? That seems really, really
basic. And you do have crazy fucking
projects that are like, oh yeah, we're
just gonna fork and change the amount.
We're just gonna increase the cap and then
maybe we'll increase the cap again. And
you gotta ask like, at that point, do you
have a debt ceiling versus a supply cap?
Or you randomly find a bunch of coins
somewhere else. How the fuck does that
work? That seems to not be very sound
monetary policy. Let's just say that.
It doesn't seem to dissuade some users
from still utilizing the product though,
Joe.
Well, yeah. Listen, man, some people will
take the long bet and then they'll just
try to back their money, right? I don't
think they actually care. I don't think
they're running software. I think they
have chips on the table, so at that point,
red is better than black, obviously,
because their money's on red, right?
Yeah, true, true, true. I think Luca
wants to come join us. Let's see if
he's...
I'd love to see Luca.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Let's see what he says.
I accidentally left the old Zoom link at
the bottom of the YouTube video. Send him
one. Bring him up here. He may have been
bluffing. We're calling his bluff. It's
okay. I don't want to intrude. Oh, stop,
Luca.
Luca was my DJ when we had the Ergo
meetup. I don't know if you knew that but
he had like when it was like, at the end,
he took over the sound system and was
blasting tunes for us.
Oh, nice. What am I doing here? In the
wrong thing. This is going to really jack
our interface. So bear with us, people.
I'm going to set the interface back to
just us, the whole window. So hang on one
second. Keep talking, Joe. Keep talking.
Well, I'm just here for decentralized
money, man. That's it. Peer-to-peer
networks with decentralized money, right?
Think Napster, where anybody anywhere can
connect, right? I think that's the best
outcome. And people get opinionated. I
mean, bags have their own. It's no
different than red or black, right? They
put their money on red and suddenly, if
you're not red, you're dead, right? It is
what it is in this space. There's no
escaping it. It's a weird industry. But if
I look at it as money, I think it's really
interesting. Ergo is we have privacy
assumptions, but we're not a privacy coin,
right? And some people will say, well,
that's a terrible idea. But if you ask
them, should we audit Fort Knox? Should we
understand what the gold supply is? Right.
They'll be like, oh, that makes sense. You
definitely would want that sort of
audibility, especially if you're trying to
be commodity backed money. Right. But even
that, like, how do we live in a reality
where that doesn't just have like a
hundred live cameras, anything happens,
everybody will know. Right. instead of
just, Oh yeah, we haven't audited it since
the seventies.
I don't know, Joe. I don't know. It's
hard. Every time it gets discouraging,
especially.
I know. I think you're good at staying
out of that part of it to not let it
affect you. But I can, I can... I've said
for years on these videos that it's like,
listen, I can go to the casino. I can play
poker. The drinks are free. I know the
drinks are free, right?
I would much rather do that than be like,
hey the ladies are nicer looking in
person, I don't know all that. Let's see.
Here comes Luca He's gonna jump in hot
Come on, right? Load Luca load load load
He is getting his camera ready You have to
turn your camera on Luca so we can see
you. Maybe he doesn't want his camera.
We'll put it down there. Look, at least
connect to audio buddy. All right. Well,
he figures out his Mike smartest
programmer around and he's, he's having
Mike trouble right now. Isn't that how it
goes, Joe?
Listen, that's all right.
He's got Luca. Can you hear us? Luca? I
see his little mic icon. Was Luca in, did
Luca go to India with kushti? Did he go on
that trip?
I don't think so. I think you just made
that video.
Oh, OK. Oh, for stability, Nexus, right?
Yeah, that was a good video. That was a
great, that was a, it was fun. I had a lot
of FOMO for the Colorado meetup, but you
guys look like you had a lot of fun. And
you did spend twice the budget you were
supposed to, Joe.
Yes. All right, Luke, I can't hear us and
we can't hear him. So he's leaving and
coming back. That's fine. We'll keep we'll
be here looking for you afterwards.
After we went to the Garden of the Gods,
I took Luca.
Did you do a nice little sunset walk
holding hands kind of thing?
No, it was like dark. That's fun. Anyway,
nice spot.
Nice. Very nice. Does it like darker? The
sunset was gone kind of thing. It still
looks nice. Oh, the sky's gonna look
gorgeous out there by then, right?
Yeah, it was beautiful.
All right, let's try this again, Luca.
We're trying to... Is he here? Luca, can
you hear us yet? Maybe this is Luca just
trolling us, Joe. Maybe Luca's like, I'm
going to mess with them and make them look
silly. Well, we'll keep going. All right,
what else? What else is there, Joe, going
on in this world? This has been... This
has been bugging me lately too, Joe. I
have... I've always had a very strong
dislike for the standard corporatist MBA
type, right? It's just always rubbed me
the wrong way. Again, value extraction.
Their main goal in life is to come in and
suck as much money out of everything as
possible.
Make everything cheaper, shittier, and
make some money, and then fucking leak.
Fucking hate it, right? They got their
golden parachute, doesn't matter. They
made their money, just move to the next
thing.
We see that everywhere in life we see
that with the you know oh there was an
amazing listen i understand i'm literally
waiting to get on an airplane and they
charge you to take a shit right that's
that's like the peak MBA.
It's like they sit around and they think
how can we make people's lives miserable
enough so just miserable enough so that
they want to pay a little extra. It's
fucking crazy. That stuff really pisses me
off. Like I absolutely can't stand it. So
I've been in a kick lately. So for those
of you that don't know, I program in one
of the oldest languages known to man.
Perl. There's Luca. Luca, can you hear us?
Yeah, we're good.
Luca, what's up, buddy?
He's drinking water.
How you doing, buddy? Water, that's fine.
We are all inclusive here. We're drinking
water, too. Well, Joe's drinking apple
juice. I'm drinking water, of course. All
right, let me finish my rant. So I build
in Perl, and that also means that Claude,
ChatGPT are absolutely amazing at Perl.
They are extremely good at programming in
Perl. And the amazing thing about Perl is
that you can write it to print HTML, you
can write it to print JavaScript, you can
pretty much get away with almost not quite
as sleek and amazing as some of these apps
out there that are slow and sluggish, but
like we're talking about, I made a whole
printing pickup system and backend system
that I showed on the AMA the other day.
And like the script is like a couple
thousand lines of code, it's 46 kilobytes,
it loads like this. So I've been doing a
lot of that. And whenever somebody comes
to me at Cornell, we had a lot of money
taken from us from the federal government,
right? or held back, I should say. And
then there was a deal reached where we
kind of got some of it back. The story's
online, you can read it. But we've been in
a mode of money saving recently. And it
adds up. So if you think there's five
departments in my college alone, so if you
think there's a couple people in every one
of those that are using something like
doodle poll or those kind of things where
it's like you know 20-30 bucks a month for
the pro version that you need because the
free version just gives you enough stuff
to be useful and you just need that one
extra feature but it's going to cost you
the 10-15-20 bucks yeah you got it. Yeah,
so those things have been pissing me off
royally. So anything that's like, I think
I can do and I do it. So I've made about
four or five, maybe six duplicate apps of
these. I've made a polling, like an
iClicker polling app. I've made an
attendance app. I've made a doodle poll
app, a full on schedule. It's even better
than that. So I've made a handful, maybe
even a dozen. I lost count. I have a huge
page of these things. that are geared at
being like, fuck you to these applications
that just feel like you can write
something and be a billionaire and just
nickel and dime everybody. So that leads
into my frustration in the blockchain
industry with value extraction. I guess
that's where my stories connect, but it's
just so damn frustrating. So yeah, Luca,
welcome. The amazing Luca, how are you
doing?
I'm good. I'm okay.
I heard you presented a video you sent a
video to the hackathon that kushti was at
in India or the presentation there that
works.
No, that was the hackathon and then there
was a workshop on the Monday like academic
workshop. So I presented live on the
Google Meet. So I did one presentation for
Dexy, and then another one for the gluon
proofs or theorems, and then another one
for the theorems in the orb staking
protocol.
The orb staking?
I've heard rumors that there's copies of
this on somebody's computer phone but I
haven't seen anything what do you mean the
video I've heard either Bruno or Alex has
like recording it yeah like I think when I
was on the Google meet I could see them
and I think Bruno was like recording with
his phone
Yeah. So it's on Bruno's phone.
I might share the Dexy slides in the
Telegram channel.
That'd be awesome. Oh, if you guys want
to preview, right? You've got a really
nice presentation from the Ergo Summit.
People can get their chops wet with it
before they dive into your Bruno video.
Were you doing any judging on that
hackathon that they did?
Oh, Luca's very judgey.
I wasn't in I was in India for two days.
It's a long story.
Yeah, we got lots of time. Luca, tell us
what are you doing in India?
Well, I was, I was going to go to, I was
supposed to be in India for like two weeks
to go to this hackathon, like to not
participate, but like help out and then be
in the workshop in person. But I kind of
had a bad jet lag and culture shock.
Are you talking about you, you drank the
hotel water and you shit yourself for two
days?
No, puked. But I thought I was getting
scammed by a travel agency.
Oh, come on. Fill us in. Come on. We got
time. Come on, Luca. Tell us.
So I was supposed to meet up with Bruno
at the National Museum in New Delhi. And
so I took the metro. There's poverty
everywhere. That's rough, yeah. But no,
but what's surprising is that if you see
like a homeless person in like a city in
like North America, it's odd. Or like you
feel like, like pain or feeling bad for
the person.
Luca, you're from Canada, aren't you?
Yes.
They have homeless people in Canada.
In Montreal? Yeah, in the subway.
Especially in winter. Because warm.
Yeah, but it's a little bit downhill
around here. I went out in Denver. I went
out and some dude steal my windshield
wiper and I chased him out.
Why do you need your windshield wiper?
Yeah, somebody. All right. Sorry, Luca.
Keep going. So it's homeless people in
America. You feel bad for me. You want to
help them. But in India, you're not
supposed to. Is that is that the idea?
Well, because the poverty is like kind of
like everywhere. So it's like normal,
which is the weird. That's like the weird
thing. you're there. And it's like, Oh,
it's actually just like normal, every part
of everyday life. Which I don't know if I
could do that.
I don't know if I could go there.
My empathy things are through the charts
and that those cases I feel so terrible.
Sorry, go on, Luca.
And yeah, so I go, I get to the metro
station. It brings me I take like three
rides to the train station and kind of
lost. And this tuk tuk driver, he like
talks to me. He's like, Oh, you're, you're
lost. Let me bring you to this, government
tourism info center. It'll help you find,
find your way to the national museum. So I
was like, okay, I didn't, whatever. I'll
go in the tuk tuk and that was 30 miles
out of town. No, they brought me to the
place and it's called like tourism center,
but it's not a government agency. It's a
travel agency. And yeah, the guy, I got
like pressured into buying something.
No, Luca, was it a lot? Did you lose a
lot?
Well, I might get a 50% refund.
Okay. Wait, is it the 50%? Is it like
crypto where you have to give 10% to get
the 50% back?
No. I might get 50%.
I'm sorry, Luca Luca got real life. So
you never made it to Bruno at the museum
ever?
No, I met him. And then I got into a
driver's car. And the guy brought me to
the national museum. So I didn't meet up
with Bruno, which was cool, but I never
had to buy you a bunch of dinner. No, but
yeah, unfortunately I didn't get to meet
kushti in person, which would have been
nice.
I'm so sorry, Luca. It's okay that we're
laughing at this after the fact, right?
Yeah. Like, so I basically like, I got
freaked out and I got upset and left.
I'm sorry, dude. That's rough. Would you
ever try it again? Would you ever go to
India again?
Yeah, for sure. It's actually not so bad.
Well, New Delhi is really bad pollution.
When I came back, my shorts still stank of
the pollution. That's how bad it was.
Like air pollution?
Yes, yes. It's worse than China. There's
like a... Forget the site. I think it's
AQI or something or air IQ. And it's like
a leaderboard of all the cities and their
pollution levels.
And you tell these like, up five, we
should make an oracle out of that and do a
stable coin based on New Delhi pollution
air pollution. Joe get on that.
I don't know if it's like, it's terrible.
I can't believe you, Luca.
How's MG? I know that MG's finally almost
out of his.
He's almost done. You think he can
release our app, Luca?
Oh, yeah. Sorry about that.
Oh, you chose the wrong time to come
under this chair, Luca.
I've got a question for you, Luca. In
2026, what do you do? Should we do the
Ergo meetup in Colorado or should we go
out to New York?
No, no, we're going to Ithaca 2026. I got
it. We're going to do a big, we're going
to do a big thing. We're going to, we got
an auditorium. We're going to do a
conference. We're going to invite other
people, try to invite the Cornell
blockchain club. But yeah, sorry, Luca.
What's your opinion of that?
It's cool. I guess you like, I mean, it's
cool if it's in different places closer to
you, isn't it? Yeah. You could drive here
six hours, I think. Right.
Yeah, I don't have a car, but it is
drivable distance.
Take a rickshaw.
Yeah, you should go just to hit him.
Come beat me up, Luca. Sorry, it's been a
tough couple of weeks. This is good to
laugh. I'm sorry it's at your expense,
Luca. I really appreciate it, though.
Well, what are you working on these days,
Luca.
Yeah, what are you working on, buddy?
I'm trying to launch Gluon Dollar. Tell
us there. Well, there's like things I have
to update in the contract, but I'm sort of
like, I haven't gotten around to it yet.
And I found some, I did like an AI audit
with Rob from Lithos. Like I sent him the
contract and he like put it into the AI
and then he sent me back the output like
text of what it suggested. And it found
one thing that I think I missed or like,
but yeah, so I, and I asked Keith, Keith
from GoLend from Rosen.
Yeah.
Yeah. He's like, I showed him like, is
this a mistake? He's like, maybe he
probably, so yeah, it relates to Oracle
fees. Yeah. So I might have to, so it's
like, I'm not just as simple as like
changing the contract because I'm using
his Scala backend code, which was set up.
He set it up to like, so you can do, you
can like launch and you can launch the
contract again, but like, and you can
change like what it's pegged to and so on.
So I might have to also change like the
backend code in that application.
I'm still waiting for, for the silver
Oracle that we had put together.
Oh yeah, that would be cool too.
I'm curious. I want to see Gluon and Dexy
live in the wild and just see how they,
see what kind of data they print. And
that'll give me a good idea in terms of
like a silver backed coin. And I don't
know, I hope at some point, maybe we can
even merge with like Silver Sense. I have
the same jacket from the Ergo Meetup.
Greyman gave me a little silver dime.
He gave you a dime bag, right? Do you
bring dime bags for everybody?
Yeah, it says dime bag on it, right?
That's amazing. I had like a breast pocket
on my jacket and I was in the restaurant
the other day. I pull it out and I'm like,
what? Put it on the table and it says dime
bag and the waitress is looking at it.
It's Colorado. It's Colorado. That's
normal. Lots of dime bags.
Yeah, I guess. But no, I'm really curious
to see how Gluon evolves. I really think
that will be interesting to to watch. I
know that I know there's a couple of
different instances now that have been put
together. But that's.
So are you like, sorry, go on, go on.
Yeah, with Gluon Gold, we wanted to
update... Yeah, I'm supposed to... I'm
confused. I'm confused myself. I'm also
supposed to update Gluon Gold. Because...
Yeah, we wanted to change the reserve
ratio, so it's closer to 1. Like, is it
1.01? Because we noticed that it would
de-peg too fast. when people would like
use the protocol. And then also change,
one of the equations because when I was
working on proving the theorems, well, I
mentioned this at the talk in Colorado,
but basically like, stuff doesn't work out
properly because when you depeg, it makes
the reserve ratio constant. It has to be
like, it should actually be like, like
version of a line that so it's always
decreasing until it reaches one or well
the inverse of the reservation should be
one when or the normalized reservation
when r is there anyway is I don't know
like I don't get too technical here but
yeah yeah yeah hit it yeah so okay so if
you look at the glue on paper it says like
you just see an equation called Q or the
called the fusion ratio equals the minimum
of two values you have Q star and then
this number this fraction that's the
oracle price times the circulating supply
of the stable coin divided by the reserve
amount. So the fusion ratio, this Q
number, is like the minimum of these two
values. This Q star is like a protocol, a
fixed parameter. And you can think of the
Q as just like the inverse of the reserve
ratio. So the reserve ratio is defined as
your reserve divided by your liabilities.
So if the reserve amount is R, right? So
the amount of ergs in the bank, the
reserve ratios are divided by your
liabilities, which are, which is like the,
the, the price of the stable coin times
the circulating supply. Because those
units will like cancel out and you'll get
like erg divided by erg. So it's like a
unitless constant. But the problem is that
so that just like you can think of like
your raw or reserve ratio value. that
you're computing, just like some raw
number that's between like zero and
infinity, right? But then the value, the
number that's actually used by the
protocol in the equations to compute like
how many stable coins you get when you
want to mint some, or like when you want
to convert between stable coins and
reserve coins, it computes like an
auxiliary value called the normalized
reserve ratio, which is the number that's
a function of this raw reserve ratio. okay
so this normalized reserve ratio that's
like the inverse of that okay that's the
normalized fusion ratio and that's like
this q parameter in the paper which is
like equal to the minimum of q star and
the raw inverse the raw q okay so the raw
inverse of the the inverse of the raw
reserve ratio. And so when it depegs, then
the fusion ratio means it becomes less
than a Q star, sorry, above Q star.
Because it's like inverse, everything's
like flipped. So when the reserve ratio
becomes too small, that means the inverse
rate Q becomes big. So when the raw fusion
ratio becomes bigger than Q star, you're
depegged. So the minimum will be Q star.
But it's always going to be Q star when
you're depegged. And this causes a bunch
of problems. So you actually want it to be
so that if you're not thinking of instead
of the fusion ratio, but the reserve
ratio, when it depegs, instead of it being
like a straight line, it like goes down,
it always decreases. And so when it's at
zero, then the normalized reserve ratio is
one, and then this will like, fix the
problems. And what that means is, when the
reserve ratio is zero, then the price of
protons, reserve coins will be zero. Yeah,
anyway. It's like, it's like, it's like,
it's actually like simple math, like, so
high, like a high school student could
understand the math. But it's just like,
when you tie it with the concepts, that's
what makes it a bit confusing.
So what the so this is, this is a concept
that Bruno came up with, and then you, you
conceptualize with mathematics, or he
conceptualized the mathematics and you
implemented the code?
So, so what was actually cool is like,
he's been thinking about stablecoins for a
long time. So it's based on a, so Jed,
even if you go all the way back, it's like
started off from a paper on it from
Ethereum called Staticoin. And I remember
reading it and it was confusing because I
got used to the notation that Bruno came
up with for Jed and Gluon. It's much more
intuitive. So you're like, study that
Staticoin paper and then like improved
upon concepts. And then that was like what
that's how Jed came about. And then now
gluon is like an improved version of Jed.
So yeah, he had the ideas of the papers
and then like the theorems. And I just had
to prove the theorems. And so we're like
similar to Jed.
Jed's on Cardano right only Cardano right
now.
No, I meant Jed as in the paper.
Oh, the paper Jed. OK, who implemented
Jed on Cardano? Is that somebody? Cody.
Yeah, they did a weird job. Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
Yeah, they did. Can you extrapolate on
that weird job, folks?
I don't want to step in that pile. Come
on, Joe. Yeah, I think there's an article.
I think there's an article about it from
the... I can't remember if I can find it.
Anyway, to be honest, I think if you're
going to build JED on a proof of stake
network, you need a liquid stake
derivative to make sure that you can force
protocol returns into the treasury and
then you have natural growth. It doesn't
make any sense to build it with the native
coin. You should create a derivative of
that coin and then use whatever staking
you have from the base of that derivative
to increase the supply of the treasury and
then it grows. And I've never understood
that, but that's my own like outside
scratching my head looking saying what the
fuck are they doing over there? Which I do
that all the time in life. And sometimes
it's their issue. Sometimes I'm just an
idiot, right? That's the beauty of
learning.
So you would meant you would been shared
using the yeah, you need like the
tokenized data.
Yeah. Like if you, if you could create a
derivative, right. I'm not even, I'm proof
of work, but anyway, and proof of stake,
if you create a derivative, you should
create the treasury of that coin, right.
And then direct the inflation into the
treasury of that stable coin and it would
naturally grow. Right. And that makes it a
lot easier to stabilize things when you
have like natural, like capturing
emissions, right. Because like a proof of
work asset is hard, right? Like gold, if
you sit it somewhere, it doesn't grow more
gold. And if you put it somewhere else, it
doesn't grow more gold. But proof of stake
is set up to where if you, in essence, put
your stake to work, you get more of the
coin, right? So if you have that natural,
like nominal inflation, why wouldn't you
put that into the treasury of a stable
coin? I don't understand.
All I hear is you're promoting proof of
stake, Joe. That's wow. That's new.
Wait, wait, wait. So, okay. I was
confused because if the, so I understand
like you, the ADA, so I put, I lock up
ADA. I create this like tokenized ADA.
Right? You create Gluon ADA. You lock it
one-to-one, but you stake the underlying
ADA, right? The underlying ADA. The
underlying ADA grows and then what you do
is you mint, Gluon ADA into the treasury
of the stablecoin and naturally your
treasury is absorbing inflation as your
monetary policy is inflating, right? You
can't do that with proof of work. because
proof of work is more like a commodity
where if you take a barrel of oil and you
put it in one place, it doesn't create
more oil, right? Put it in another place,
it doesn't create more oil, but proof of
stake is very different because you have
the ability to absorb inflation. So why
wouldn't you direct that? Why wouldn't you
create a mechanism to direct that in the
treasury of the coin to either offset the
volatility peg, which then makes it more,
like incentivized for people to take the
volatility position or use it to create
more stablecoins. Like you have a certain
like monetary hack there. Like I'm
personally not, I'm from Ergo, right?
We're proof of work. Because a barrel of
oil doesn't naturally create more oil, but
in proof of stake, it's more like shared
dilution, where you can absorb nominal
inflation and then put that to work. I've
never understood it, but that's my own.
Where's the ADA growing from in this
circumstance, in this scenario?
Just protocol inflation.
Oh, wow, okay.
Right? Because you can capture inflation
and emission, why not direct that into the
treasury? I've never understood that. I've
always scratched my head. You have a
certain power there that you just can't
create with a commodity-based asset. And
proof of stake isn't a commodity-based
asset anyway, but I don't know. Anyway,
sorry to derail the conversation. That's
been something I've been wandering,
watching for some time.
Because in Cardano, you can like delegate
ADA in a contract to a stake pool.
Yeah, yeah. And in theory, in theory, if
you were to like create a stable coin on
Cardano and you were to do that, it would
be really cool to use that to, what is
that guy's name? Peyton, I believe. Like
Big Pay, he created something to like
split stake. If you were to create a like
liquid staking derivative that also could
like split the stake to underlying small
pools, that would be really good for the
Nakamoto consensus on Cardano. But that's
my own, like maybe a good idea, maybe
hallucination, say.
I got a question guys. We got a question
from the audience. You know, people
actually watching this at two in the
morning my time. Look, are you on my time
zone? Luca? Are you on Eastern time zone?
Yeah.
What are you doing up so late? Luca? Do
you sleep?
Sometimes, sometimes I was watching all
in.
All in?
All in podcast?
Oh, gotcha. All right, here's a question.
Ready? If Ergo is successful in three
years from now, what will people be using
it for on a daily basis?
Well, right now, if you look at what
separates Ergo from most other
cryptocurrencies is these derivatives that
we've created, right? So there's been a
lot of work that's been put into
censorship resistant DeFi versus just
creating the censorship enabled DeFi,
which is not really then DeFi because you
have an underlying party that can
essentially reverse or freeze or seize
everybody's assets. So if you look at the
total value that's locked on Ergo in DeFi
and how much of it is based on censorship
resistant protocols, it's basically
everything. versus if you look at most
other systems, it's like, oh, well, what
we've done is we've allowed another, we've
created a contract that allows somebody to
potentially rug and freeze everybody's
assets. And if you actually look, and I
would recommend everybody that's watching
this do this, if you look at USDT, right,
the total frozen amount, relative to the
cap of the supply is like 1.8 percent. So
that means that one like historically 1.8
percent of the value of their total supply
has been frozen which is fucking insane
for a currency, right? It means you you
almost have a 2% chance of just your money
disappearing. Like, okay, well, like if
you were to look at that as a bank, like,
okay, there's a 1.8% chance something
happens and your money's gone. Some shitty
fucking odds. Wow. Good luck.
So you say you say, sorry, go for it.
Look, what do you say to this to Ergo
three years? What are you using it for?
What's it going to be used for?
Well, like I would like to use crypto. I
would like to get to a point where like
cryptocurrencies normalized in general and
like society in general, like you just pay
for things on a regular basis. That would
be really cool. I don't know that it's
going to happen in three years
necessarily.
I don't think it'll happen in three
years, but I think there's a demand for
it. What does the gig economy represent?
It represents people trying to grind to
create some value to live their life well.
I mean, the bottom line is we've lost
cash, guys. We're losing the ability to
use cash. We're losing the ability to
privately pay somebody without any
oversight. It's gone. It's essentially
gone, right? You go to the bank and you
ask for more than a couple grand and they
ask you why and they may say we don't have
that much money on us right now. I went to
the bank when I was sending money to Peru
for my wedding, trying to get out $10
grand. They're like, nah, sorry, you can't
get it out. We don't have enough here. I'm
like, what the fuck are you talking about?
I hopefully people get sick enough about
that. But I don't know.
I think they will, honestly. I think that
the best marketing, historically, the best
marketing for crypto has always been
government overreach, right?
It's for your protection, Joe.
I don't think Luca is old enough, but QX
is definitely old enough.
How old are you, Luca? Are you 27?
I'm 29.
Wow. Do you remember the Cyprus bank
crisis that they went through?
What year, 97?
No, that was about 2012, 2013, I believe.
Oh, the recent one.
OK. Yeah, yeah. Where they suddenly
absorbed depositors' money above a certain
amount. I was not aware of that.
Yeah, don't worry about it. You're too
young. But QX is.
I'm sure I had my head up my ass or under
a rock somewhere.
Yeah, that was the point where Bitcoin
really started to take off, right? You
can't create that kind of marketing where
all of a sudden everyone's looking at a
system and saying what the fuck is going
on? Like that's outside of the parameters
of the rules that I thought I agreed to,
right?
Well, actually, even even even like even
just yesterday, like today, like the
European Union, just like $90 billion
euros to fund the war in Ukraine. It's
like none of them are like elected or
whatever, whoever decided or something
like.
Well, the Canadian trucker thing was
another good example, right? Oh, yeah.
Where they're like, hey, suddenly we're
just going to, limit your ability to
access your bank account that's when
that's when the normal people wake up and
they're like what the fuck is the user
agreement that I just signed up to because
most people when they download software
all they do is scroll scroll scroll scroll
scroll scroll scroll agree right they just
try to pass on to the next like the next
instance in the UI in the system, they
don't give a fuck. But when suddenly like
reality wakes them up where they're like,
whoa, what the fuck is happening? Then
suddenly like the idea of privacy and
censorship resistant and all of that
become interesting. We can't create that.
Like we can't fake that as an industry in
my opinion. It'll always come from the
outside. It'll always be like a bunch of
normal people are like, wait a second,
what user agreement did I just click I
consent to? And why the fuck is that like
part of the system that I'm in? And the
more that systems overreach, I think more
people will wake up and say, wow,
cryptocurrency is potentially powerful
because you do have stronger assumptions
as a peer rather than just a user that has
to click a box in order to get to the next
screen. That's where we win. I don't think
it'll ever take over the world. I think
it'll just be a counter economy. But if
you have 5%, 3%, 2% that actively use
that, it's powerful.
I think it can be sold also as, or looked
at as a hedge, right? And I don't mean
hedge as in, let's make a lot of money off
this kind of thing. A hedge as even a
one-to-one ratio, right? What other
system, even cash, right? Even cash, let's
say I have $30 grand, all right? What
other system can I put this into and know
by memorization, wherever I go, I have
access to this. If I have to get the fuck
out of Dodge, if I have to go somewhere,
if something crashes somewhere, where else
can I bring this with me inside my head
and still be able to execute systems of
trade with other people at some point in
time? That doesn't exist anywhere, right?
This is it.
This is kind of magic.
Yeah.
I will say that a lot of the time, over
the years when I've talked to like Alex,
have calls every once in a while talk
about what we're working on, what we're
thinking about is this idea of a neutral
settlement, right? So I don't know if
anybody's paying attention, but in terms
of what Luca was talking about with this
Ukraine, Russia, NATO fucking drama, I was
born into it. That all started before I
arrived on this rock and I'm pretty sure
both of you as well. The idea that
suddenly countries are going to take other
countries' central bank reserves, that's
pretty fucking crazy. Because I can see
within a system, you can have a lot of
control parameters, like reversibility,
freezeability. That makes sense in terms
of a higher level controlling a lower
level, basically. as in a very simple like
hierarchy term, but when you're talking
about how does the United States trade
with Russia, right? When you create
digital money that has freezeability and
reversibility built into it, who the fuck
would want to accept that? Because they're
no longer equals. It's like you have a
parent-child relationship or a
parent-child relationship, right? So why
the fuck would anyone want to accept
anybody else's money if it's a
parent-child relationship? You have to
have some form of neutral, like medium of
exchange where you have parent to parent
or peer to peer relationship. And when you
have all of these systems that are
cropping up that are all parent to child
relationship, fuck you, I'm not a child,
right? Country should be saying that to
each other. People should be saying that
to each other because the bottom line is
we need to get past this reality where we
just scroll to the end of a user
agreement, click agree and fucking move on
because we don't know what type of
liability we just inherited. And it's
super frustrating to be like, hey, know
your assumptions, know your assumptions.
But when the assumptions become more
complex, you need to be either a fucking
lawyer or a software engineer to even
understand what the fuck they are. And I
think that when we get into this idea of
simplistic systems like Bitcoin or Ergo, I
think there's a ton of value in that long
term because you can't create a unified
reality across different countries without
peer-to-peer, parent-to-parent trade. And
one interesting thing to look at on the
market side is since And since that
happened with Russia, a lot of the bonds
have been shifting much more towards the
short term, right? Which means if you were
to freeze US bonds, at least it's on a
shorter duration versus long term. Now,
obviously we have, fuck knows how much
debt today, but I do think those neutral
assets are absolutely critical. Because
with gold, there's always been like a
human assumption. I don't give a fuck what
you think. I don't care what you believe.
But you know, I'll take your gold. Right?
That's always been a like a neutral thing
that kind of balances human trade is this
idea of common money. And when you have
parent child money, it's fucked. And so
personally, I worry about this idea of
parent-child DeFi and parent-child money.
Nobody really cares. No, no, no.
I mean, that's the population. Look at
all these parent-child relationships with
how these corporation-run stable coins are
going to be, right?
Oh, even software, man. Like, why the
fuck do I need to pay a subscription to
run some fucking software?
Oh, Joe, don't make me stand up. We just
talked for half hour about this.
I remember when you could have a fucking
floppy disk or a CD.
Money, money, money, money, make more
money.
My first mobile phone was the Google
Nexus