If you want.
All right, welcome everybody.
All right.
Everybody that came in person, thank you
for coming. It's pretty cool to see a
little group of people focused on the same
thing. Ultimately, peer-to-peer networks
kind of replicate real life where your
community, people you know, people you
exchange with kind of create the basis for
everything in your life, right?
And that's one of the really interesting
things about decentralized systems, is
that on one hand you have like technical
parameters, but on the other hand you have
a social system. And kind of like any
social system you have various levels of
trust, sometimes you could call that
belief. And in the extreme, I would even
say it's healthy to have an element of
faith in each other, people in your
networks.
Now, that is both something that can
offer a lot of benefits. It can allow you
entry into a peer-to-peer system, but it's
also something that is an attack vector,
right? If you have people that kind of
exploit your trust or your belief or your
emotions, that doesn't always end well.
I had a presentation put together to kind
of cover the basis of Ergo itself. And
then I was thinking last night, everybody
here anyway, and many people that are
probably tuning in already know these
things, right? So what is the point of
just repeating I don't know what's
publicly available, and anybody with some
time, energy, or desire can easily read.
Now, I know that's somewhat of a skill
that's being lost, is the ability to read,
but it's there, right?
I do think it's fascinating kind of the
events of yesterday, right? So let's just
speak to the moment. Yesterday I was out
having some beer and some food with some
of the people that showed up completely
oblivious to the workings of kind of the
broader crypto ecosystem and you come back
and they're like, oh, there's been a
spiral effect of deleveraging and billions
have been removed from the market and
what's happening and all these people, I
don't know. Hopefully manage their risk,
right?
A good starting point is understanding
like risk management and leverage.
Leverage is a powerful tool when it's
needed, right? But it's also risky. It's
not without its trade-offs. And I think
that sometimes you have the talking heads
in the crypto industry that do not like to
talk about risk. And I think that's a
fundamental failure of the cryptocurrency
ecosystem broadly.
Because ultimately in our world, money is
a control system, right? We live, let's
say, within the United States. You have a
group of people on a hill somewhere, they
say, right? And they go into a room and
they discuss in private. Okay, publicly
they'll say we have two parameters. We
want to have employment at a certain
level. We want to have inflation at a
certain level. And those two don't
necessarily correlate in terms of how they
move anyway, right?
But they go into a room in secret and
everybody around the world gathers and
watches. Say, what are they going to do
with our money? What is going to be the
cost of money? And we sit around and
speculate and sometimes people have fun on
polymarket or whatever. And eventually
smoke comes out of the chimney and we say,
okay, this is our new updated policy.
forked the network, so to speak, and this
is going to be the cost of money.
And we go through this ritual regularly,
people around the world tune in and watch
and position and try to kind of front run
whatever that trusted setup is going to
be. And then on a higher level we have
this idea of, let's call it the type of
cross-chain tariff, where arbitrarily you
have new costs added to the system.
That's, I guess, what was a part of the
madness yesterday, more or less.
Let's see. Where suddenly, you have these
two economies that interact and we're
going to add a hundred percent tariff,
right? And there's no real consensus
mechanism to understand what is coming,
right? It's a trusted system where the
individual has very little power. They
have very little power in terms of
understanding what the assumption is today
and what the assumptions are going to be
tomorrow.
And that's not the type of environment
that produces I don't know. The right
mindset for risk itself, right? And that's
one of the most interesting things about
this idea that started with Bitcoin is
saying, okay, can we have a system where
the parameters are set? Right? Where
monetary policy is more or less set, and
then build economy on top of set
expectations. And based on how the network
is set up, within a certain set of
assumptions, you can assume honesty.
That's powerful if you look at kind of
the traditional system that we're all born
into. It's something we just naturally
inherit. It changes depending on where
you're from, right? But it's kind of more
or less the same. a system where you have
a high concentration of power and then of
course one of the most profitable things
is to be close to power, right? Close to
where money is being distributed from and
generally the further away you get from
that initial distribution point of money
the more inflation and expansion of money
supply tends to hit, right?
I would say a lot of the crypto industry
has really gotten away from first
principles. And in my opinion, that's
based on toxic social systems. Because
that social system is inherent to these
type of networks. Where you constantly
have people that are saying, trust me,
believe in me, have faith in me. And I
think that is not the ideal environment to
create the systems that we want to build,
right?
It's a part of why, at least with Ergo,
I've always tried to push for building
public. that we should ideally have these
primitives in place that are the
equivalent of public goods. They're open,
they're auditable, and hopefully through
time and with testing they also become
Extended right they become extendable.
You could look at something within the
Ergo network like SigmaUSD right you have
first it's based on research right it's
not something that is just willy-nilly
thrown together which we do see a lot of.
that in the space, right? So as an
experiment it has a solid foundation,
right? Then you have kind of open code,
open parameters around that experiment.
that even if the experiment itself
experiences difficulty, you have the
ability to extend it, adjust it. It's
open, right? It's open to new ideas. It's
open to new iteration. And ultimately,
through time, I think we can build solid
public goods with that framework.
And my hope would be that creates its own
flywheel effect. Everybody in crypto these
days will talk about the flywheel in terms
of financial games. The ideal, in my
opinion, is to create flywheels with
software. to where you have these public
goods that can then be reused, right? And
the more diverse these building blocks
come, you can suddenly cater to a larger
class of functions and applications and
build something that has a solid
foundation.
Sometimes we get away from this idea of
open code. And I think that type of
transparency should be a solid base for a
healthy social system because it's based
in trust, right? Not faith. We are a proof
of work network. And proof of work, one of
the interesting things is a coordination
mechanism is it's leaderless. It's
apolitical, right? And that's something
that people often struggle with, like
grasping in terms of the social system.
They'll say, hey, Armeanio, you need to
go dance over here. Go do over there.
You're supposed to be a leader. And it's
like, well, I have a certain set of
skills, right? But meeting everybody that
attended, and I'm sure everybody watching,
you have a different set of skills. No
different than in the off-chain
peer-to-peer economy, you bring different
skill sets, different abilities, different
specialties that you've developed through
time in your life, and you create value
using those.
I don't think there should be that much
difference. I'm not universally
intelligent enough to be the leader of
everything, right? I have my areas where I
would say I've learned and grown and
developed a certain skill set, but in
other areas, you do not want me in charge,
right? I'm not the guy. And people
struggle with that because in social
systems, a lot of the competition is to be
the guy, right?
Certainly if I have people's trust and
belief in faith and they follow me, I
guess that's an attack vector that we see
all the time in crypto. And it's funny how
the sheep are taught their entire life to
fear the wolf. And then in the end, the
shepherd eats them. Right? having that
basis of how do we create trustlessness,
not just in software, but also in the
social system itself, that takes
responsibility. It takes a collective
responsibility, right? We're going to
build things the right way.
And at least in extended UTXO, there is a
trilemma, let's call it. You have the
contract itself, you have the off-chain
logic, you have the front end, right? In
the ideal scenario, all three of those can
be replicated locally. That's what I would
say makes for a decentralized application.
That's pretty clear parameters, right?
So as an ecosystem, I think it's healthy
to really push for that. That's something
that I've always tried to promote. And
it's hard to build open code, right?
Because you are in essence being naked in
public. It is sometimes a process to get
there, right? But I think that is,
Ultimately, a solid goal in terms of
building public goods.
So we hear about this trilemma in
blockchain all the time. It's a selling
point. For lack of a better word term,
it's a selling point. But I do think that
within the Ergo ecosystem anyway, I would
like to promote the idea of our own little
trilemma, which are those three aspects of
an application. And ideally, if you have
those three aspects that are open, And you
have tooling that becomes kind of a common
knowledge base for developers to use and
build off of. You have things in place to
start creating the right flywheel.
That's kind of hard to bootstrap from
nothing, but I think we've done a pretty
good job as a whole of creating that
mindset and mind share. And there have
been a lot of developers, some of which
are here, some of which choose to remain
faceless, which I totally respect, that
have contributed to that type of mindset.
And so everybody that's contributed to
that ideal Public goods. I kind of have to
tip my hat to you. That's ultimately
powerful when it comes to not just the
network itself, but also the social system
of the network.
Now, from first principles, crypto should
be about the distribution of power. Proof
of work kind of represents that in terms
of the distribution mechanism of money
itself, right? It's something that you can
certainly compete for and build into, but
having clear assumptions in terms of
distribution of power is needed. And
sometimes that is buried behind really
good marketing. Sometimes that's buried
behind social systems. Sometimes it's
buried behind this trust me bro mentality
that permeates the crypto industry. And I
think that's toxic. And I don't really
care if people don't like that.
Because if you can't call a spade a
spade, your social system is not going to
work. That's just honest. I know there's a
lot of financial games and cultural
movements and things like that. I've said
from day one, for me personally, I would
rather go to a casino. I know the drinks
are free. That's a solid assumption that I
can bank on every time. And whatever my
parameters of risk are with the games that
I play, at least I know that assumption is
going to hold.
Now, security is another powerful
mechanism of both the network parameters
and this social layer, because we do need
to address both. Sometimes we see them as
separate and they're extensions of each
other in terms of what people accept.
Security, at least in our industry, is
something that's formed through time. You
usually have research as the bedrock of
computer science. Then on top of research,
you have implementations where people will
try to take research and Use engineering
skills to convert that into something
that's tangible. And then you have the
test of time, which kind of is the
ultimate teacher in life.
So having things that are built on a
solid foundation and are introduced and
kind of go through this test of hardening
through time ultimately should be a goal.
That doesn't mean you can't innovate,
right? It doesn't mean you can't extend,
it doesn't mean you can't provide
research. Certainly in Ergo we have led in
various areas of implementing things that
kind of came from the academic sphere. But
I think there's an element of wisdom in
being conservative, right? And sometimes
that is not the focus of the crypto space,
right?
Innovation is wonderful. But I would also
say that sometimes iteration is
innovation, right? Where you take
something, you extend it. it holds you
extended, it holds you extended rather
than trying to reinvent the wheel for the
700th time and it's good for marketing.
It's not necessarily good for security,
right? Because you have a weird curve
distribution where through time, usually
you have the research side, right? And
like the engineering complexity, let's
say, is much higher. And then through
time, as it becomes more of a standard, it
becomes easier to adopt, there's better
tools. Like that whole process of
evolution is not something that you can
cheat very effectively. It's something
that is much slower than the hype cycles
that people are taught, right?
So I want everyone to remember when it
comes to security that time is ultimately
the test. We can look at kind of the first
principle of privacy, which is probably
fundamentally one of the most important
things we need to explore. There is some
potential future where the children people
in this room have could grow up into a
world where every economic transaction
they touch is audited, stored, and you
could watch every penny that someone has
touched throughout the course of their
life.
That type of control system is getting to
the point where it's technically possible,
and that should frighten the hell out of
everybody, right? That type of system, I
do believe there are some powers in this
world. That's where they would like to
take humanity, right? Because it certainly
offers them greater power and control. And
so I think having the ability to remain
private, anonymous, have your personal
space is going to be one of the most
fundamentally important things that we
need to work to protect as an industry.
And that doesn't just mean we're going to
add zero-knowledge proofs to everything
and have more control systems in place. I
think that's a bit of a perversion from
privacy itself, right? That's a trade-off
that many people see is quite sexy, right?
Where we're going to have ZK compliance
and if you just get more and more and more
and more ZK compliance, you have a
stronger control system. So I think we
need to really look at this idea of
privacy, make that an absolute, chase that
on multiple layers of networks, rather
than have it be toy.
Because in some cases, yes, it does offer
like visibility assistance in terms of
people not seeing your transactions or
what's happening, but in terms of the
broader assumption, it's toy privacy, it's
not real. And I think we need to be very
clear in terms of what our set of
assumptions are long term with privacy and
what the goals are with privacy.
Because there are a lot of projects,
there's a lot of research Beyond Ergo
itself that is valuable in terms of
preserving privacy, preserving anonymity.
I think that ultimately should be one of
the most important tenets of creating
censorship resistant systems and
censorship resistant money.
The other area has to do with inclusion,
right? We are seeing a mix in the space
where it comes to regulated assets.
non-regulated assets, bearer assets,
non-bearer assets. And that needs to be
something that there's a lot of clarity
with, because not everything in crypto is
the same. I know that in the social layer,
everything is a ticker with some letters
in it, right? But the underlying
assumptions that you need to make in terms
of custodial, non-custodial, is this a
bearer asset, is this not a bearer asset,
is probably going to get even more complex
when we start seeing regulated assets
appearing.
We've kind of seen some of this freeze
and seize with stable coins, but the
crypto industry is changing. Even
yesterday or two days ago, there's an
announcement that these 10 major banks are
going to collaborate and create some
stablecoin instruments. Oddly enough, they
tend to be the same banks that are in the
corporation that's on the hill, but that's
the side journey that probably not the
rabbit hole for right now. But that type
of assumption of inclusion is going to get
really important.
I do know that Alex kushti, as many call
him, has been working on a whitelist
mechanism, which I think is probably the
better way to deal with uncertainty in
terms of power. where rather than you join
and you might get blacklisted at any time
for any reason, you make a voluntary
agreement. And hopefully there's clear
assumptions in that agreement in terms of
the risks that you're inheriting in doing
that, right?
Last is probably this element of
resilience, right? And ultimately, I think
that's why open source code is so
important because good ideas are hard to
kill. I do hope not just within Ergo, but
within various aspects of the
cryptocurrency space and some of the
privacy space that's been around, we're
able to develop tools that ultimately
develop into truly resilient systems.
I've operated under the belief that over
the long arc of time, the only thing of
value in cryptocurrency really is state
resistance. Everything else will probably,
in my opinion, distill down to the common
denominator underneath, which is
centralization. Right? Because if you're
not shooting for state resistance,
ultimately the most efficient thing is
going to prevail through time, and the
most efficient thing will be centralized.
No, maybe it'll be pseudo centralized. We
can have a debate whether Amazon Web
Services is distributed, decentralized,
because you have data centers all over the
place that optimize speed. But I would say
that in terms of power distribution, we
have to be honest and say, OK, it is
distributed, but the actual concentration
of power there is pretty apparent.
So over time, if we build on first
principles, I do believe that the crypto
space is capable of developing open source
tools for coordinating capital and
creating systems where within a certain
set of assumptions, we can assume honesty.
Right? And luckily, at least with Ergo, we
have this proof of work mechanism that has
a pretty well time tested mechanism of
what are your assumptions of honesty? What
are your attack vectors? In terms of the
contractual layer that we've come up with,
it is relatively conservative. So I think
those are solid building blocks towards a
larger goal.
Sometimes within the social layer of
crypto, you sign on to Twix, TwitterX,
whatever you want to call it, and you
listen to the commentary, the talking
heads. It does kind of leave you
wondering, what the hell are we doing? Why
are we here? And I think that ultimately
should be the most important aspect is we
need to have clear intent and clear
purpose. Because if you don't have clear
intent and clear purpose, you're not going
to be grounded in what you do. And crypto
as a whole, I would say, needs to be more
grounded, right?
I do hope that over time we create a tool
set that's diverse enough, and again, an
extended UTXO that's going to be
contractual, it's going to be off-chain,
it's going to be front-end-wise. We create
enough tools around those three problem
areas, the trilemma, let's say, that we
can serve a diverse set of needs. And I
think sometimes marketing and kind of just
social spam buries that intent. Right?
So my hope in going through All of the
presentations that we've set up, all of
the speakers, everybody here is doing
really unique things that are targeted,
that improve the assumptions, that offer
new tools and understanding that as a
piece that can be replicated within a
whole. over time I believe will lead to a
broader tool set that's powerful. And I
think we've done a pretty good job as an
ecosystem, developing open public goods,
sets of tools that have led to some
interesting things.
We just went through a major upgrade with
Sigma, Six new node version, right? And
that will open the door to a lot of new
capacity. And I hope that as we kind of
build to enhance new system capacities, we
stay focused in on mission. Because that
type of purpose I think is important. It's
not just important for like solid
programming, beyond the network, it's
important for the social system. And the
social system in crypto is very toxic.
It's just honest.
I sometimes have said, my favorite thing
is seeing all of these tools that enhance
individual power takes responsibility. My
least favorite thing in crypto is people
that look for a savior, right? Because
that's not really how peer-to-peer
networks work. That's the client-server
relationship, my friends. So if we get
back to this idea of saying, okay, how can
we distribute power across peers and
empower peers to have tooling, to have
access, to have software that ultimately
can serve them and their needs, that's the
ideal for cryptocurrency.
I would say everything else is just
digital money. And I think we need to kind
of lean into that because the
possibilities if privacy does not work as
an industry, if resilience doesn't work as
an industry, the trade-offs are huge in
terms of the world long term that could be
spun up around us. And sometimes I wonder
what kind of world my children will live
in, right? Like, I can see myself, I was
born into this strange system, you got the
people on the hill, you've got this
distribution of power that I can't really
touch or interact with much. But what
about the future? How much stronger could
that get theoretically? And that should
scare the shit out of everybody, in all
honesty.
So for me, I think that kind of sums up
the purpose, the intent of why I'm here,
right? It's the only thing that matters.
So I do hope that as an industry, it's
something that we can mature around, look
at all of the trade-offs of control in
different areas and build wisely. So I'm
going to kick it off to MGPi and Luca. I
need to set up their mics, set up their
presentation, get them ready to go. But
thank you everybody for tuning in and
enjoy.