What's up, everybody?
This is Mick from BlitzTCG.
It's been a little while since we've had
any sort of a real update from Blitz.
First, I want to say pretty much all my
fault.
My life has been quite busy, and to
demonstrate that fact, I thought I'd start
with something I know pretty much no other
update's going to give you, and that is a
look at my life and what I've been up to
for the past four to six months.
Where do I start?
I moved back in November. I changed jobs
back in November. I'm getting married so
that's a thing. I started building this
horse pasture, putting in these posts by
hand - some of my 225 posts. I built this
horse shed.
This is sort of like a work-in-progress
picture. Let's see if we can find a newer
one, or I guess a more completed one.
Here's a more completed one.
Here's the horses themselves.
So needless to say, I've been quite busy.
Funds have been quite lacking, as you
might imagine, just given the state of the
world, number one, the state of crypto,
number two, and Blitz is of course a
project that requires funding to complete,
primarily because I am not talented enough
by myself to do the very many things that
need to be done to make the game
successful, and of course to highlight
that here, any of you are welcome to sort
of peruse the many people that have helped
bring Blitz to where it is today.
That all is to say though, at the end of
the day, Blitz is still a passion project
for me, still near and dear to my heart.
I still hope to complete it in totality
sometime in the near future.
It is slow going, of course you all will
know that from those of you who are still
following along.
But I do keep it up to date
security-wise. Everything's still working
on the integrations, APIs, the back end,
so on and so forth. We're all still
working as you would expect.
There have been some minor updates here
and there. In fact, development was pretty
much continuing up until, I want to say,
April.
And then I had to pause again due to some
funding issues where I think about - I
don't want to overstate, but maybe about
halfway into completing all the abilities
necessary for Blitz.
So that's a positive.
And then the game itself, as many of you
know, is already downloadable, technically
playable, but you of course know if you
have played it, it's not in a great state
right now just because everything isn't
done.
So you can still log in, and I actually
added some animations. Animations are
freaking expensive, by the way, for any of
you who are curious about how much
hand-drawn animations are.
They're a lot.
The metrics screen is up there. I updated
some buttons to take you to the website
and stuff.
Deck Builder still works. I think I made
some updates to this to make it a little
bit more snappy and also a little bit more
accurate for the cards you actually own
versus those that you don't.
So you can see I own one of those.
I fixed all the hover to discover options
at one point or another. So basically you
can hover over each of these different
things and it'll tell you what they mean
because there's a lot of different things
going on.
And Blitz that get a little confusing
depending on how knowledgeable you are
about the game.
So all that's still in place.
Oh, and all the game boards are
programmed, so you can actually use all
the game boards now if you haven't played
around with that.
So a few things have happened.
But of course, I'm not going to beat
around the bush and make it out like we've
done everything that needs to be done.
We've done a lot. There's still a lot left
to do despite the game being in, I'd say,
a semi-decent state right now.
What else? I think that's really it. As
soon as, I don't know, the market bounces
even just a little bit, and I have some
more free time on my hands, I hope to pick
this back up.
I'm a little bit anxious to get my hands
back on the keyboard and do a little bit
more programming here. It's been a while
since I've really gotten into the weeds of
things, so hope to get back into the weeds
of things soon.
I'll keep you all updated when I have
updates.
The Discord knows that I don't post
updates too often, but if you do have
questions or you have any concerns or just
want to talk things out, I am available in
the Discord pretty much 24-7 and will
respond to you if you reach out.
What do I want to end this?
Let's just say the Ergo community is near
and dear to my heart. I really appreciate
all of you. I hope to see all of us
succeed.
I hope to see Ergo succeed.
And I hope to see all of you doing and
building on Ergo succeed.
I mean it's a lot of work to even bring
something to this degree live on a
blockchain and on a backend and on a front
end and with a website - it's a lot of
work. So make sure you all don't knock our
community developers too hard because a
lot of work goes into this stuff even if
some of these projects aren't maybe to the
point you want them to be quite yet. All
that being said, thank you all again.
Truly hope everybody's life is going
towards the positive in these crazy times.
I'll stay in touch and best of luck in
the year folks. Take it easy.
Bye.