Happy birthday, Ergo.
Yeah, cheers to the happy anniversary.
Everyone, happy anniversary.
We've made it to six years old, kushti,
Joe.
Six years.
That's quite a feat in this industry.
Yeah, still baby.
It sure is.
Still a lot of crawling to do.
Yeah.
So, well, when Bitcoin was six, for
example, I worked with it.
So yeah, it was exactly 2015.
And yeah, well, I think it was more raw
even in regards with multi-sig support.
Oh, for sure.
Yeah.
So yeah, well, I spent a lot of time
trying to do some multi-sig with the
script.
So to discover that there is some bug in
Bitcoin script, which I need to replicate
after all.
So, yeah, well, hopefully it's less messy
here, at least from my observations.
Oh, nice.
So what's everybody got planned today?
I know we have a cake coming, not on the
first, but our lab is going to make us a
cake on the fourth.
We've made the payment and he's got to go
into, I think he said he goes into the
city or something and gets a cake and
brings it back.
Takes a picture and then donates it to
the homeless or the hungry or the
unhoused.
However, you say that word and across the
globe.
So we got that picture coming.
You guys gonna drink yourself silly in
celebration?
Maybe you can do some drunk coding,
kushti.
So I had two coffees today.
How about you, Joe?
I'll get ready for the release.
I'm going to update some packages, test
it.
Let's see.
I was hoping to get it out today, but we
had something we needed to chase down in a
dependency on Ethereum with their latest
hard fork.
So that's been coordinating, updating.
Looks good now.
Joe, it looks like you've spent a lot of
time making some promotional videos that
are pretty nice.
Yeah, I did this weekend.
I was messing around with the video LLM
with the Doge and you know what I learned
is the most important thing for whatever
reason was that I needed to be quite clear
that the Doge needed to have paws when it
did the activities.
Otherwise, it grew these weird human-ish
hands and earned some credits.
But yeah, I played around with that.
I got some subscriptions.
So I guess I'll be the generative video
editor for a little bit.
Well, for Ergo.
Yeah.
Nice.
Well, let's focus right on what you have
for Ergo up your sleeve, kushti.
You have some announcements about
sub-blocks testing going on that we can
excite the crowd with.
Yeah, so there is sub-blocks DevNet
update which is doing quite well at the
moment and yesterday I did some load
testing even and it was quite good after
all, after some fixes.
So yeah, please feel free to join and
help with testing so I can provide some
load testing.
Scripts as well, which are doing
transactions every second from your
wallet.
More news in regards with Ergo Network.
Well, this week we will have maybe a
voting for 6.0 has been started, as well
as emission reduction, another one.
And, yeah, well, this emission reduction
would be more aggressive again.
Like, every emission reduction is more
aggressive than the previous one.
So, yeah, well, a lot of things going on
despite summer.
So, yeah, take a look.
It's always fun to check what's going on
around, I guess.
kushti, do you have a message in chat
where people can spin up DevNet to help
out with sub-blocks testing?
You can find some details how to join the
network in the developer's chat.
It requires some knowledge, like building
and running a node against the latest
commit in a specific branch.
It's doable for many people still, I
think.
And then, yeah, well, maybe we can start
building current jobs and do more in the
coming weeks.
So I think, yeah, well, we are pretty
much on track in regards with starting
injecting sub-blocks, supporting mining
nodes into the public test nets from
somewhat July, maybe like 15th to 25th,
something like that.
That's exciting.
I know speedy transactions seem to be the
thing that gets people excited.
So it's amazing that Ergo is versatile
enough to be like, hey, yeah, let's build
this into 6.0 and we'll do some testing.
And sure, you want faster blocks?
We'll make faster blocks in this way and
still keep the network secure.
So I think that's amazing.
Dan, what do you want, Dan?
What's the deal with the bracelet?
What is that?
This bracelet?
Or this bracelet?
You have a little Arts and Crafts name
bracelet?
Did you make that in the Arts and Crafts
class?
This is Cartier.
This is from my wife.
And these two were made by my child that
I wear.
Are you sure they weren't made by you?
What's that?
Yes, I do.
I sit down cross-legged and I pull out
the Taylor Swift bead box and I make the
Taylor Swift friendship bracelets.
Now that sounds more like the truth.
Is it supposed to be like your own chain
stuff?
Yes, you've got it exactly.
That's so lame.
That is just so lame.
Happy birthday, Dan.
Happy Ergo birthday.
Dan, when did you join Ergo?
When did you hear about it?
Did you know kushti back when he was at
IOHK or did you join after that?
Of course I've known kushti since like
what, like 2016?
Beginning of 2016.
We have pre Ergo.
Yeah, the first time actually I met was
2017, yes 17 maybe yeah but we've already
worked on Ergo back then since autumn
2016, yeah like October, yeah we presented
initial ideas so well in some inner circle
so yeah basically IOHK folks.
And then I started to invite more people
from late 16, early 17, something like
that.
Well, so, yeah, so the first time I
actually, well, I spoke to Alex in
meetings.
But the first time I actually ran into
him, actually became aware of his
existence on this planet, this human
called Alex, was he was in a series of
really, really early IOHK research videos.
So they made these videos with a handful
of researchers working back then and Alex
was obviously one of the first ones.
And so he was in the video and he had
like really long hair and yeah, there's
some video.
Yeah, like the first, the first Ergo
video is basically the same haircut.
I think he was talking about RSCoin or
something like that.
Anyway, that was the first time I saw
him.
Then we were in meetings, and then the
first time I met him was in Malta in 2017,
in the spring of 2017.
Charles gave him his favorite book.
It was the Good Soldier Schweik.
Yeah, the first English translation, I
believe, from Czech.
It's like from 1980, 1928.
I was there.
Alex got the first official translation
of his favorite book from Charles.
I was in the room.
I don't know if I should feel like I was
part of history or not, but that's
basically when it happened.
By proximity, Dan, by proximity.
I just, it reminds me of this one time
when I was at this like tea place and I
was in line with Tony Shalhoub and Matt
LeBlanc and they actually met each other
in line in front of me.
And I'm just like, hi, and I am Dan.
I'm not on TV or in the movies, but I am
here.
And so exactly the same thing.
I am Dan.
I'm not in blockchain stuff that you do
or blockchain stuff that you do Alex but
I'm here and it was nice and that's the
story end of story.
That is very touching, Dan. What about
you Joe, where'd you come along?
I've kind of been around. I would say
even when Alex was building DenXT, I was
at least watching that because
programmable money was like super
interesting, but I wasn't a fan of Proof
of Stake.
I was more into mining.
That's cool.
Yeah, I remember, I think I told you this
story when Ergo just launched.
So I was, in the beginning of all the
Cardano IOHK stuff, they were still like,
they really were, they were always really
focused on development.
So research and development.
So that was like the main, like the big
thing from the very start, they're really
focused on research.
So that's why Alex was in play.
That's why Aggelos then came in.
Mario, all these guys that have been
there for a long time, Oleg, all these
guys.
Actually, a lot of them are still there.
After I got done with project managing
and before Mainnet, after Mainnet, I
switched gears and I started doing more
business development.
I started project management in the
company because before that, it was just
like clans.
It wasn't actual project teams.
After that, I switched over to business
development.
So when we started business development,
we're kind of looking for different
opportunities to generate income.
And so one of the first ones that was
brought to me, or to us, by Charles
actually, was back in 2019 to set up a
mining rig for Ergo.
I think they actually did end up setting
it up, but I remember that was like the
first, one of the first things that came
across my desk in 2019, right after
launch.
But yeah, it was just, they were like,
yeah, we have to set up a mining operation
for Ergo, it's Alex's blockchain, he just
launched it.
So that was the first time I was directly
plugged in into the whole thing.
It was always from the business side of
it.
So, oh, and Joe, nice to see you and your
nice couch.
Once again, it's been a long time.
Yeah, it's good to be back.
Yeah, well, it's good.
Where's the crock pot?
You always had that crock pot behind you.
I don't know.
I think it's outside on the stove.
Okay, I got worried a little bit but okay
if it's there, okay, so like a Dutch oven
or a crock pot?
No, that's like this stone thing you cook
food in.
Yeah, nice stone that says that that's a
technical term for it.
All right.
Well, we got the hits, we got a history
of Ergo.
All right.
So what are we looking for for the future
boys?
What are you guys excited about?
Yeah, I look at it as kind of a natural
progression.
We launched Mainnet.
The first step out was the ErgoMixer,
which privacy.
Then we started playing around with
native assets.
Auction House came out.
Then we started playing with
programmability in terms of like SigmaUSD
and DEXes and,
I think that's matured quite a bit in
terms of what's possible to build on top
of Ergo.
A lot of our tooling has gotten a lot
better through time.
So I think the best next step is just to
get faster, get more decentralized in
terms of the hash rate.
Hopefully we see some layer twos that pop
up.
There's a lot of good designs out there
in the UTXO space.
Just keep chugging along.
Actually, you just reminded me.
I think that we spoke about this in one
of the AMAs a while back, but Alex, didn't
you actually at first say that you didn't
think it was possible to have auctions on
Ergo and then somebody did it and
surprised you?
Am I getting that right?
Right, so yeah, in just like few days,
yeah, contracts were presented.
It's reflected on the forum, actually.
There is some old topic from like autumn
2019, so yeah.
So yeah, it's quite surprising what's
possible.
So I think, well, at this point, it's
better to avoid breaking the protocol.
Well, there are always a lot of proposals
to do.
Yes, but yeah, I think it's better to
move gradually and always try to do things
in a soft-forkable fashion, so not
rejecting the old nodes so that they have
the right to validate the network.
In most cases, it's always worth to have
old validators.
So then, yeah, well, we can do like
hundreds of different things in regards
with optimizations and building around.
So, well, actually, the work on merge
mined sidechains already started, so we'll
provide some details in the coming days.
But, yeah, well, the coding already been
started.
Some coding design specs and so on.
Yeah, I think backwards compatibility is
underappreciated.
Please don't rug the devs.
I mean, it's both good and helpful at the
same time.
Look at Microsoft and their legacy code.
They're a huge juggernaut, but they're
still providing.
I can spin up a 16-bit app with some
compatibility there in the latest Windows
from back in the day, and it works just
fine.
There's something to be said about that,
that's for sure.
And I mean, certainly they're not short
of innovations.
I wouldn't say that Windows versus Apple,
just because Apple prunes all their devs
even.
Apple's famous for rug pulls on devs.
A new OS comes out and, oh, this doesn't
work, sorry, kind of thing.
I wouldn't say from using both systems
that one's more technologically advanced
or superior in that aspect of it.
But yeah, I think that's notable.
100% that Alex can say that these old,
you say 4.0 nodes are running, Alex?
What's the oldest node that's out there
pumping along?
Yes, some sudden, well, a protocol update
in regards with the difficulty
recalculation.
So, yeah, well, then it's about 4.0.100x.
And also, yeah, they're still in the
network since 2022, and yeah, I think that
they can stay for a longer time.
Yeah, I see.
I'm looking at the Ergo nodes list and
I'm right at the bottom seeing a 4024.
Oh, no, that's the name of it.
Let's see if I can see any old ones in
here.
That's quite a few new ones.
I'm impressed at how many people have
updated to 6.0 or 6.1.
Wow.
You guys check this out.
There's a lot of people that pumped the
upgrade to 6.0, kushti.
Oh, probably miners.
Because he did advertise around mining
channels and so on.
But yeah, I think also some guys updated
6.1.
Because there was no 5.1 release
corresponding to 5.027.
So yeah, I mean, we got into I've skipped
one, 5.1 release actually.
I see 30 nodes on 6.1, kushti.
That's impressive that people are doing
the rocks at that point.
Yeah, 30 of them.
That's amazing.
Yeah, that's quite a lot actually.
I don't know, maybe it was advertised by
someone in Oracle pools group.
So it was advertised by some guy, I
guess, in the SigmaUSD group.
And then maybe in Dexy Gold Oracle pool
group as well.
So I don't know.
I mean, yeah, that's quite a surprising
number, actually.
Quite big considering that the version is
just released like a few days ago.
Well, I'm here.
I need to check out something.
Let's see if it's still there.
Oh, no, I guess it's not running anymore.
Those love letters to Joe in the node
names.
Remember those?
No, let me find them.
Oh, Armeanio, Armeanio's wet dream.
It's one of them.
Armeanio's bitch.
Is that all you, Joe?
Are you doing this yourself?
Oh, that's not me.
I'm way too lazy.
I'm just going to run it with the
standard name.
Oh boy.
Well, speaking of nodes, I talked about
the interesting project that we dreamed up
last week at AMA.
And went ahead took kushti's advice and
sunk 5.13, I think it was, because he
said, yeah, 6.1 is coming out in a few
days.
So sunk that in the node, updated to 6.1,
dropped Explorer on top.
Throw it in the load balancer, and three
of them, and they are out there.
That's explore-p2p.ergoplatform.com and
node-p2p and api-p2p and graphql-p2p.
So the intent is that we're gonna move
off the reliance, not just the reliance of
the Ergo Foundation providing these nodes
at SONIA or other places,
But the payments from the EF coming down
to that, to pay for that, because those
are paying for servers draining money out
of the EF's budget.
That doesn't need to be done, especially
on a decentralized peer-to-peer network
like Ergo.
So right now I have three nodes running,
full explorers ready to go, load balanced,
Aco is testing them.
He mentioned that there were a couple
tweaks I needed to do to make them match
the current ones, so I did that.
They should be identical to the Ergo
Foundation's one.
And the idea is that we have about four
or five interested parties already.
We'll prep the image on our machine here,
unless you want to use your own hardware.
We'll ship you the device, and you run
it, and we'll add the load balancer.
And eventually, we'll have 10, 15, 20
community-run and managed explorers
that are all going through one URL load
balancer.
And we'll flip on the geolocation so that
if you're in China, then it'll use that
node.
If you're in the Middle East, it'll use
that node.
If you're in West Coast, it'll use a West
Coast node or explorer.
So that's the baseline that we're doing.
And then now there's also talk about,
hey, we should also have these guys host
the front end for Sigma space, have the
front end for ErgoExplorer 2.0, and that
kind of stuff.
And I love that idea.
That's fantastic.
I know the original Explorer is not
everybody's cup of tea, which is fine.
And I think these machines probably have
the head space to be able to host those
front ends.
So really excited about that project.
I feel like it's like, oh, you're a
decentralized peer-to-peer blockchain.
Where are your main nodes that everybody
points to?
Oh, they're hosted by the EF?
That to me is like, let's stop that.
Let's fix that.
And let's have them hosted by the entire
community and managed by a DAO.
So it'll be nice to shore that up.
Hey, hey, HQ, welcome.
Very nice, great to see you.
Hey.
Hey, everybody.
Hope you guys are having a nice day and
happy birthday.
Hey, buddy, how are you?
Can you turn on your camera, HQ, but
block it if you don't want to, so at least
your square shows up on the main page.
Just put a sticky over it and turn on
your camera.
I'm just using my mobile, so I won't just
keep it like my desk on that side.
All right.
So that voice that you guys hear is HQ
talking without a picture.
So HQ is, for those of you that don't
know, is a code dev of things like
MewFinance, MewDex, Mew everything.
Mew, mew, mew.
What's the new stuff now?
It doesn't really look like a red square.
That's actually his face.
He's very square and red.
All right.
Well, I know one red square in Russia.
I'm just, I'm not saying I'm not
connecting the two, I'm just saying I've
seen red squares before. They used to be
one in Kiev and then they changed it back
to something else and anyway. Look okay,
we're not going to go there but nice to
see, well not nice to not see you HQ.
And then we have, is it Shaya or she?
I never can pronounce things right in my
head.
So, so, so, so you have a lot of people
here.
Your voice isn't coming through, Shaya.
Maybe just sorry.
My name is Shaya.
I just joined in as a cloud.
I didn't know it's going to be such a
small forum.
This is our intent to trick you into
coming on an AMA, Shaya.
It worked.
Yes.
Yeah, so probably other people.
Let's invite for more.
Let me ping the chat.
So Shaya, how are you doing?
Do you need some documentation and so on,
maybe at this point?
I started reading the document you sent
me about the sub-blocks and sub-blocks.
Right.
And I'm organizing my thought about it.
I thought I'd just write down all the
questions I have and then come and seek
you out in the Telegram group.
Oh, nice, nice, nice.
So yeah, well, I will improve
documentation in coming weeks.
So yeah, well, questions and so on would
be appreciated.
It would help to improve.
There is Mark the shark.
And there should be a disclaimer.
He's not an actual shark.
He's an AI shark, actually.
Yeah.
Right.
That's fine, guys.
He might be a shark in a proverbial
sense, but not a literal one.
I met him.
He's definitely a land creature.
He is, for sure.
For those that don't know, Mark Leshark
is a community dev and runs the Sigmanauts
mining pool, which is the best mining pool
in Ergo.
It is a DAO, and it is fantastic.
Yeah, absolutely.
Got a lot of things cooking, for sure.
Yeah.
Also, Mark brought viper coding to
ecosystem for better or for worse.
And yeah, they did a lot of work on MCP.
So on the doing connections between the
blockchain and AI based analysis and
construction of different things.
Yeah, MCP is amazing.
Mark inspired me to bring MCP service to
my work, to actually do real things with
AI.
So absolutely amazing to see it working
against the Ergo blockchain.
Yeah, for sure.
I think a lot of the stuff, once you have
the base foundation, relative to AI, it's
pretty easy to branch off and extend it,
especially with MCPs.
I was able to take the Ergo MCP and tell
an LLM, hey, let's make this for price.
And then within a few hours, made the
price Ergo MCP.
And I think, too, kind of from there,
it'll be interesting.
I'm not sure if you guys have seen the
Thin Intelligence stuff that I've made.
Basically, it's AI agent that can write
some code.
And so I wrote some smart contracts for
that.
I haven't tested them or anything like
Still needs to do some work.
But the hope would be to kind of create
this platform to where people can throw up
their own their own LLMs be their own LLM
provider.
And then from there, people can use like
the Ergo MCP and things like that.
And instead of using like anthropic API
keys or OpenAI API keys, kind of like how
we're doing on CodeUTXO.
So it's a more decentralized LLM usage.
So that'd be kind of interesting.
Exciting, sir.
By the way, have you checked Aletha White
Paper?
Your thoughts on that?
I have not.
Which one is that?
So it's about autonomous AI on Ergo
blockchain.
Oh, okay.
I think somebody posted on X recently.
I think it's going to be about that.
AA Shannon, yeah.
So some new GitHub account.
Yeah, I couldn't tell if it was AI
generated or not because I know Stanford
actually just came up with a mechanism to
generate papers kind of around the same
time.
So I'd be curious.
But in any case, it looked interesting.
I think Ergo is a great use case for more
super intelligent type of mechanisms,
especially with the cheap transaction
rates.
And then from that sort of perspective,
having AI agents running on chain and
maybe having a token where they pay
themselves to do different tasks.
So you have an agent that does task A,
another agent that does task B, and they
can sort of rent each other to kind of do
specific tasks or have a human do that.
But we need the tools, I guess, from a
MCP potentially perspective to facilitate
all that.
But like it would be nice.
You're talking about an AI run local
economy.
That's interesting, Mark.
You come back in a year and there's poor
AI and there's rich AI and they're
starving each other out.
Yeah, totally.
You could have an AI that generates
images for you, another one that will put
them into NFTs for you.
You can have a trading AI and they can
all be working together.
Or maybe there's like a manager level AI
that somebody makes and hey, let's make an
NFT collection.
Let's try to make the most amount of
money if that's like what it's trained on
or whatever.
It would be interesting.
Obviously, it would be nice to kind of
use AI outside of just like, hey, let's
just try to make the most money possible.
So that's where I'm not trying to do
things like that, but how can we grow?
I suppose what's the best use case for
that?
Yeah.
We've got another one that joined us,
Luca from the Ecosystem.
Fantastic.
Great to see you.
He's just here to show Canada Day.
Oh, wait.
That's what he's here for.
He's here to show Canada Day.
Is Dan allowing you to talk, Luca?
I am not.
Are you guys in the same office right
now?
No, no, no.
He's back in Canada.
I am in my home office.
But I got to send him a message on Slack
though, cause I get it.
Oh, look, it's like, okay.
It's payment for not working on something
and being here, right?
Yeah, exactly.
Same with Shashir.
I'm like, I'm on vacation.
No, you're not.
So Luca, you're going to give, I hear
you're going to give a presentation with
MiGoreng on gluon gold at the Ergo meetup
in October.
Oh yeah.
Well, he sure was going to do the, he was
talking about like, I'm mistaken how that
works.
This is pretty different.
Yeah, it's pretty cool.
Now, listen, guys, I'm going to be in the
U.S. in what?
In August for Rare Evo.
And then for this thing, when is it like
October?
You said October, something like that.
When was it?
October 11th, sir.
October 11th.
It better not be like this many guys at
Joe's house where he invites a soul.
I told you this already.
Okay.
I told you that's not a conference.
It better not be like Surviving the Game
with Ice-T where he's just going to invite
us to his like retreat and he just ends up
hunting us for sport.
Like I don't want that to happen.
Okay, he's gonna, we're gonna get to
Joe's house. He's gonna have an array of
20 guns ranging from very deadly to a BB
gun and whoever, again, he's gonna say go
and you have to just run to the gun you
want and then be, it's all fair game after
that.
One of the first conversations I had with
Joe, he sent me, like, either photos of
stuff he has chainsawed or his chainsaw.
Like, I forgot, what was it, Joe?
It was either, like, something.
I was working outside.
Yeah, yeah.
He just built these random structures
with the chainsaw.
And I don't know.
That's art, Dan.
That is art.
Yeah yeah he might have summoned the
aliens with it I don't know what he did
with that but that was it so I don't know
I mean Joe is a friend, I like Joe, we
hung out together a bunch of times but
never at his like in his kingdom, never in
Joe kingdom. You see like that's, that
very selective about his invites.
Like that's another reason why I'm kind
of cautious to ever go to Charles's ranch.
He's rich, rich people get into weird
sports.
Okay, you never know. He might just be
like really hospitable and be like a nice
time or he might end up hunting you like
like a buffalo or something. You never
know these things. Okay, so I'm just
saying Joe.
I'm gonna probably most likely like 95%
I'm gonna be there.
I mean 5% leaving for like Ian does.
But yeah, I'm planning on being there but
like I said number one it better be more
than like me QX and like Luca and Shashir
because I've been there done that okay and
better be more than that and I am, look,
just give me a rifle at least, all right?
You get a boomerang, Dan, you get a
freaking boomerang.
You get a boomerang, okay?
Maybe a slingshot if you're lucky.
You get a plastic IKEA spoon, that's what
you get, QX.
I sell a lot of rocks in the spring, so
you can grab some there.
Yeah.
Mark's going to be there too.
We've got Allison coming as well.
We've got CannonQ coming.
It's going to be a nice, it's going to be
a nice meetup.
Yeah, maybe Timur.
Timur is fantastic.
Timur can teach us some BJJ.
BJJ.
Right.
Yeah.
Yeah, we can have wrestling competitions
during the hackathon.
Did I just listen that you guys are going
to have wrestling matches with BJJ?
Only if you show up HQ.
That's inappropriate.
That is very inappropriate.
Anyway, like I said, better be more than
like a quartet over there, okay?
It just means more beer for everybody
else.
So the Sigs are, we're voting on Sigs
providing a couple kegs of beer.
Unfortunately, Joe wants red beer, so
maybe we'll give him a six pack of red
beer to keep him happy.
And then we'll do real beer on the other
two kegs.
Oh, wait, quick, quick.
Where's the nearest IHOP to your place?
It's very close.
10 minutes tops.
Okay good good good okay okay we're good
we're good we're good okay no that's
breakfast on Saturday Dan you're hosting
breakfast on Saturday. I have, yeah you're
paying but I'll host it sure. No no you
can get Jamai to pay again just like you
did in Vegas. No it's Ergo breakfast
sponsored by qx yeah let me sell all my
Rosen.
Oh, Joe, I think it was a direct threat
right there.
He's gonna dump on retail.
Just a small pebble in an ocean, Dan.
That's all it'd be, don't worry.
All right.
I'm looking forward.
It'll be like the first, I guess, Ergo
meetup.
A lot of crypto conferences, they're, I
don't know.
Oh my God, Joe, they're awful.
Let's just say the barrier of entry is
really high.
And then so I don't know if that's, I
mean, I think it's good for like business
networking and people connecting within
the industry.
But sometimes I would say it's probably
just out of range for smaller actors.
And I've never really liked that because
I don't know.
I've always wondered like, hey, what if
we just did a I don't know, like a meetup
thing where it's like, okay, do you run a
node?
Right?
Great.
You're part of the network.
Well, like the thing, the thing about
most conferences is that I used to do all
the conference circuits.
And then you eventually figure out that
most of these conferences are either a
chance to get shit-faced and not have to
pay for food, but then you end up paying
for an insanely expensive ticket, which
basically you see the same exact people
you see in every other conference.
It's literally the same people.
Yeah, I've always thought it was
interesting like, hey, if you throw a
couple hundred down, like maybe we could
supply some entry level Raspberry Pi or
something and say, okay, let's take a
minute and teach people.
Oh, workshop.
Hell yeah.
Something like that.
But.
That'd be great.
I don't know.
Sometimes I think people forget these are
peer-to-peer networks, I guess.
Well, I feel as somebody who's been in a
booth in a conference and somebody who's
walked around a conference, I feel as
somebody behind the booth, it's really
hard to have super long, meaningful
engagement with the people popping by.
It's more like, hey, here's what we do.
Yep.
Oh, that's cool.
That sounds good.
Here's this stuff.
We'll never hear from them again kind of
thing.
I think these kind of meetups really give
the opportunity to really bind with people
like Dan.
I don't need you to do that.
That is the worst advertisement for the
Ergo meetup.
Come on, man.
It is inappropriate, okay?
I don't want to associate it with the
Ergo meetup or the Ergo conference.
QX.
You just had to do that.
It's going to be fun.
If you guys can't tell, the Ergo Meetup
is going to be fun, regardless if there's
100 people or 30, 40 people.
Not that kind of fun.
That's your kind of fun, all right?
QX, you keep that over in New York.
Don't bring that to Colorado.
Is there any illegal in Colorado or
something?
I don't know.
So look, the thing about conferences is
that like what I do, and I only do like a
couple a year now. I'll do Rare because
that's like our, the Cardano and Ergo
communities there.
So that's very specific.
But if I do something that's more broad
industry,
Maybe do a Consensus if it's close in
Hong Kong or Singapore or whatever.
I try not to go out to Dubai for Token
2049 because it's the same shit, but you
keep paying $1,000 to see the same people
five times a year for some reason.
I never figured that out because that's
literally what it is.
Yeah, but usually you can skip the main
conference and speak with the best people
on the side events.
Exactly, I literally have done that for
the past several times.
Is that why you disappear and make me man
your booth the whole damn time?
I went to Dubai, what was it, last year,
and Alex and Moa, MHS Sam were there,
And I was like, okay, I wanted to, well,
with my luck, it was when there was a
flood for the first time in like 100 years
in Dubai, the sky opened up and it was
just like a wall of rain, it got dark at
three o'clock in the afternoon.
But later on a few days later, we think,
and it opened up, we were able to go over
to the Palm and hang out there.
It was literally I literally did all of
my networking, all of my meetings without
going to the conference.
I went to the conference literally for
two hours and probably just got some
t-shirts and well, but you know what I did
actually MHS Sam was there and he was kind
enough to give me his pass.
And so I just went to the conference, he
gave me the bracelet and the pass.
I mean, I'm confessing to a crime here.
So I hope you guys don't, but I was just
like, I don't want to pay a thousand bucks
for this fricking thing.
But he's like, Oh, it's okay.
You take this and then gives it to me.
And I go in there and people are trying
to talk to me because I had like the name
thing turned around, the name thing turned
around and then like, I forgot to turn it
around.
And then, and they're looking, Hey, how
are you doing?
Mohammed Hassan?
Oh.
You don't look like a Mohammed.
I don't know.
Yeah, I got a couple of really strange
looks.
Like, how are you doing?
Mohammed Hassan.
Okay, well, yeah, yeah.
So, but anyway long story short, it's
most of the time just a waste of money.
Look, I even been to the ones with
Charles where he get I get like all the
VIP access and it was still complete
bullshit.
Like, you got VIP access, but it was the
thing is like the VIP access doesn't
really matter at all unless you're an
actual VIP.
Like if you're a VIP or with a VIP,
that's where all the cool stuff happens.
Because that's basically where everybody
flocks to.
But if you're actually buying access to
the VIP stuff, you're still stumbling
around there trying to get into like
another thing that nobody wants you at
because they know you paid to get in
there.
Yeah, I'm not the biggest fan of the
booth life.
Every year here, Denver is a couple hours
north, so I always go to ETHDenver every
year.
And I always have had the best time
either at side events or just talking with
people outside or eating next to people.
That's oftentimes where I've met some of
the more interesting characters in the
space.
I guess like the hackers and the hippies
versus like the people that are trying to,
I don't know.
I did the same thing in Turkey.
I was there for, what was it, ETHGunU,
which was their ETH conference, and
literally all the cool events were
actually not there.
They were literally other side events
that you could get in for free that were
just packed, and the main event was
actually kind of lame.
So yeah, it's I love that there's a lot
of common like I don't know I would say
generally it seems as though on one path
we have this idea of like unstoppable
decentralized money and then this other
path it's more like we have techno
dystopian money.
And you kind of see increasingly a mix
where, I would say, at least in the United
States, we've got stablecoin regulation.
And it's like, OK, well, we can put, I
guess, traditional banks on these systems.
And I'm not going to say that's a
negative thing.
I don't like seeing it directly tied to
the L1, just because then it creates some
contradictory assumptions long-term, it
seems.
I've always liked the idea of more
unstoppable money.
Privacy-oriented and better assumptions
for users than our current system.
But I see that split more and more
obvious going to those events.
It'll be weird when I go to ETHDenver and
it's Bank of America, stablecoin.
And then right next to it, you have NIM,
Bitcoin for layer zero.
It's like they're totally opposite ends
of the spectrum, which maybe is a good
thing because it's an open ecosystem.
These are open networks.
And so you can't really censor that.
But I think it is good to try to separate
assumptions into different layers so they
don't conflict.
I think the next round of conference,
once we're ready, and I think we have some
things that are ready, I'm going to be
developing another app at work that's
going to be relevant to this.
But not like spending the time to send
Sigs to Rare, but sending the Sigs to
something like Educause, where we can
promote some apps that would be beneficial
to the educational sector.
Like the integration I have into our lab
management center.
The next app I'm developing is to try to
do a blockchain version of that stupid
iClicker tool that they charge students
like $100 for the damn iClicker.
And it's all proprietary.
So imagine doing like iClicker voting and
attendance on the blockchain with your
free crypto wallet on Ergo.
When you walk into class, you just scan a
QR code with Ergo Mobile.
It marks you as absent in the class.
You're doing the voting, you scan a QR
code under the vote you want, it puts that
vote in kind of stuff.
So that kind of stuff, I think, is where
Ergo can really break out and show that we
have some tools that are beneficial to
other industries and just show up to those
conferences and advertise it.
Oh, how much does this cost?
Well, iClicker costs this much, this is
just cost the server and a little bit and
that kind of thing and it's open source.
You want to run it yourself fine or just
use our front end service and pay us a
small amount for the front end service.
So I don't think those big things can
compete with what blockchain
infrastructure can bring.
And have you seen the idea of simple
anonymous voting using stealth addresses?
So when you send tokens to stealth
addresses, just write along with fee for
follow-up transaction.
And follow-up transactions are basically
about sending voting tokens to yes or no
address like you did with initial voting
procedures.
So, yeah, well, you can just use stealth
addresses and then, yeah, the link is
broken.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
SPEAKER_04: