Good morning, everybody.
Welcome to the weekly community Ergo AMA,
where if you're brave enough to join, you
can ask live questions or be tested with
questions from us of why you're an Ergo
member and what you want out of this
space.
So please, we encourage you to join on
the link down there in the YouTube
channel.
You'll see it down below in the comments.
And hit us up and join the community.
This week we're wrapping up getting ready
to, well, let me say first hi to CQ,
Byron, Aberg, HQ3rr and kushti are all in
the chat with us today. Maybe one of them
will turn on their video at some point.
We'll see, takes a little bit to warm up.
But good morning everybody that's here.
Thanks for joining us in person. You guys
there anybody? Yeah, we're still here. All
right.
Good morning, kushti.
And then we got some chat people saying,
hey, great.
So we are wrapping up. I'm packing a box
up this weekend and shipping it out to the
Meetup event space in Colorado, sunny
Colorado Springs.
Shipping out projectors, shipping out
swag for people that are coming, given our
video streaming equipment.
So I hope that box doesn't get stolen
actually.
And we're going to stream the talks that
are there to you guys that can't make it
in person.
We're looking on some couple kegs to
drink during the party.
And we've got Chris on the hook for
making us Korean barbecue for dinner on
Saturday night. Kind of all hands on deck.
It's going to be a great time. Good
meetup in the fashion of community and
sharing so super excited about that.
So yeah. What's new with you guys kushti?
What's new?
A lot of things so yeah, you can actually
make all the participants co-hosts.
So yeah, all of them know.
You trust them?
Yeah. So Aberg is quite well known on
Twitter from three. Byron participated in
the last call, right? And EHQ also quite
known.
Great.
They are co-hosts. Kushti is forced to be
co-hosts, guys, so feel free to turn on
your cameras if you want to.
No pressure.
What's new, Kushti? What's new this week?
A lot of things so yeah, well quite good
developers chat yesterday and well
published also some thoughts on the main
telegram group right, not thoughts but
observation what's going on so that is
good progress which I see from the USC
stablecoin. Unfortunately Richie can't
join us right now because he has some real
life.
But yeah, from November, he's promising
to start spending in the community calls.
That's great.
To participate more. So he joined one
call, right? Not only one.
Then yeah what else, then yeah Git
circles, there is quite good progress and
the guys are quite preparing for initial
tests in coming weeks of this month and
then starting to reach developing
communities right and get developers to
build the digital economies on Ergo.
So, well, community, but digital also.
Native digital financial circles and
solutions, right? Around probably the most
natural environment for community counts
approach to be applied.
Rights of open source development
circles.
Then yeah, there is good progress with
basis Chain Cash.
So this month we can start some demos and
one developer started to develop wallets.
So there will be like two phases, right,
of basis.
Well, at least it is how it's seen from
now.
So, there will be some solution for
community trading, right, with off-chain
cash backed by Ergo reserves.
And then, yeah, another solution would be
for agents, robots, right.
So, no wallet needed here, but we need to
do some plugins for existing protocols
like A2P, or just existing solutions such
as peer-to-peer networks and agentic
networks.
Then what else? There is now finally a
fix in Nautilus for ledger as well as some
more news from Nautilus, right, covering
the dev update.
And yeah.
If you're reading the dev updates, let me
hit that right now.
We'll pop it on screen.
If that's what you're hitting through.
One second, I need to charge my device
also.
Yeah, so you were talking about Git
circles on the dev update.
I made another pull request for a smile
since three left and yeah, so we need
actually for Joe to participate more,
right?
Because a lot of like a storm of tweets,
having regularly, about rooms.
So, yeah, it seems a lot of insights and
yeah the guys doing a lot here and yeah
actually I'm now in touch it's not covered
in dev chats yeah HQ will answer a bit
later so.
It's not covered in the dev chat, but
yeah, I'm also talking with the other guys
on Monero. right?
So we are doing some, that'd be great.
What's the big challenge with that
kushti, with bridging to Monero compared
to other chains?
Yeah. So, there is no much fields to
write data we need for rights.
So, and if there are possibilities, there
is need for some well, support for it and
the users, right?
So there are some protocol possibilities
which are not covered in wallets, right?
And then they're not quite usable anyway.
So yeah, it's quite challenging, but
well, if this is possible, even in some
ugly ways, then yeah, we are looking for
better ways to do it.
You can't fragment it and spread the data
across several different entries, like
several different tokens?
So you can put data in the whole
transaction, right?
So not just you take the whole
transaction, test some fields.
But yeah, the question is also about
world supports and so on.
So it's not that easy, to be honest.
But yeah, we continue to explore
different options.
So at least there are some options, which
is already good.
But yeah, we need to find some solution
which is also quite comfortable for end
users, right?
Right, right, right. I mean, no, not some
command line scripts.
I don't know, like two hundreds of notes
around the world. Just.
Yeah, makes sense.
Okay. So let's see. And then, yeah, about
keystone.
So, actually, there was updates recently,
there was our group from, not from AnonBR,
it's not from TGR.
Let me check.
Last I see, I remember that he said that
they were waiting on AnonBR to do some
stuff for Nautilus and he will be maybe
launching an event, a competition for
custom keystone.
Oh, yeah. All right.
So then we need to ping AnonBR indeed.
Yeah. So waiting for Keystone. So
Keystone will let you buy a wallet with an
Ergo engraving or an Ergo sticker on the
back.
Yeah, but the community needs to do
something for that. So yeah, that's
awesome.
Anyone has information?
So, yeah, PGR told, I'm looking into
launching a small design competition for
the Ergo branded Keystone device they
proposed.
All right. Well, let's see. Let's hit
through the rest of the dev updates that
we may have missed real quick, and then we
can keep chatting.
So we've got your Git circles there you
already spoke about, Nautilus, fixed web
hit, ledger-to-ledger interactions,
researching on Bitcoin runes integration.
That'll be awesome.
Machina and Hermes, still working on it
towards an MVP, but nothing relevant to
report.
Let's see. Bro Etiquette is working on
LLM commands.
Comrades, he's working on Comrades. LLM,
what's he doing with LLMs?
So he is currently writing persistence
layer for Git circles.
Oh, nice.
Okay. Yeah, quite okay to do this with
LLM comrades.
So actually it's not on the chart, but
yeah. Actually, like two weeks ago, I've
pushed agents MD rules for the nodes and
the sigma SDK.
So it's going to be a quite important
topic in 2025, right?
And I'm just current different
possibilities to utilize AI agents by
myself.
And yeah, it seems they quite great in
analyzing the code, right?
So you know, before we just had a white
paper and then the code, right?
But you need to be a developer to get
through the code and extract what's there,
right, in details.
But now you can just launch an agent and
ask it to analyze the code, right?
Or even write some tests, some
simulations and so on.
Who is that?
Just another spammer. I removed him.
No biggie. Keep going, sir.
Oh, that's Brandon.
Yeah. It seems so trolls, which is quite
great.
That's funny.
All right. So, yeah. So, you know, now,
yeah.
So talking about trolls. So, a lot of
weird trolls, trying to spread lies even
about some very basic things, right?
But you can now analyze the code with an
AI agent, right?
And yeah, it will tell you about the
detailed properties of distributions,
well, supply and so on.
So you can ask it to write simulations
tests, write some showcase programs and so
on.
So yeah, well, it's understandable why
trolls are going mad.
So now it's quite easy to get code
concepts, right? Even without coding
skills, kind of.
So you just need to well, tech savvy,
right? To install an agent or an IDE with
a built engine.
Then, yeah, import the project from
GitHub, but it's not about coding skills,
right? So just tech stuff.
But then, yeah, two weeks ago, I proposed
rules for agents to limit them to just
working on the testing code, not to touch
the main code, because it's
security-critical, so it should be done by
humans only, totally reviewed by other
humans, I believe, because it's
security-critical and yeah, it should be
developed like an open source project.
But for tests, AI is actually working
great.
It's now helping to cover the behavior of
the tests.
Yeah, it actually can help just tech
savvy people to understand what's the
rights on the two or combats, wise,
they've been spread around sometimes.
Okay.
Yeah. I see you vibe coded a rough
prototype for basis Chain Cash.
That's pretty funny.
Yeah, but it's actually sometimes useful
or sometimes absolutely useless.
So yeah, I spent a lot of time to get it
doing well-correct Schnorr signature
implementation.
So yeah, it's made everything wrong again
and again for multiple times.
Yeah. Before I've provided, well,
concrete code from another project, right?
What are you using for, what tool are you
using? Deep Seek.
So it's Cursor and Deep Seek behind.
Yes. So, so the main part is Cursor,
which is iterative for kind of agent right
so it can run tests then write code then
run tests again right it can download
materials and code from internet so it's
yeah like it's not just chat right chat
bot it's like comprehensive toolset.
Which is also, it's not just composing
codes, right? So chatting with you. So
it's, yeah.
So, or you need to provide permissions,
right? To to write on this or download
from internet.
And still I'm using clean laptop for it
just in case, to avoid, you know, the
whole disk to be wiped out or, I don't
know, being uploaded to somewhere.
But yeah, so it's working great at the
same time.
Yeah, I find it rough prototyping those
initial things on the stuff I do here,
which as some of you know is in Perl joke,
right?
HG loves Perl.
It's so fast. It's extremely fast.
I just puked here, man.
It's crazy fast. It gets through that
whole spot of the, you know, I mean,
because most of the time when I'm writing
stuff for school, at least recycling a lot
of stuff, right?
So this essentially lets me get past that
stage immediately into some sort of
testing phase to see what works.
So, yeah, I hear you.
HQ never uses AI. He just speaks code. It
just comes right out of the fingertips,
right HQ?
You said fingertip, right?
Oh, you don't have any fingertips?
No, I was just referencing to something
else, but I will stop doing that.
Oh.
All right, taking silver so it's idea by
Grayman and others cool idea by Grayman
here if you guys haven't heard it.
Maybe we'll get him to talk more about it
at the meetup and he can stream some of
that stuff. He's gonna bring a couple
Grayman says yeah I'm gonna bring some
dime bags to the meetup and I was like
you're gonna bring pot to the meetup? And
he's like no, no, no I'm gonna bring
silver dimes in little bags and hand them
out. It's like well, that's a lot
different than a dime bag.
Engrain them.
So that'll be neat to have. He's got some
early century, 52 or maybe earlier, silver
dimes that he's going to hand out.
Math Spectator started a wallet. kushti
talked about that already.
We've got Glasgow on the Docs Ergo
Platform improvements.
He's done some nav tidying up. Start here
overhaul, which is great.
Developer and wallet docs. New developer
guides and wallet area now uses clear
language and updated links throughout.
New content, added a page for how to use
a Rosen Ergo on BNB chain.
Oh, nice. And fixes and polishes,
corrected URLs, text, removed typos, and
cleared MK docs for him.
Thank you, Sir Glasgow.
Let's see, kushti's got node, protocol
and reference client R&D, mempool and
wallet support for input box done, writing
a white paper on input ordering blocks,
generated more tests with an agent on 6.0,
and generated global transfer policy
contract example, fully in ErgoScript.
Braid version of native support would be
much simpler.
Let's see we got anything else here.
We've got USC stable coin more info about
that the USC oracle pool version 2
launched by 4 or 5 6.
Oh, when did that happen?
Yeah, so just few days ago. So now we
have four running USC oracle pool.
Amazing. How many oracles did you make
30?
Oh, actually, I don't know. So it was
done solely by PGR, which is quite great.
The time not involved in just another
venture.
Yeah.
So HQ says 12 oracles already in that
pool.
But, yeah, I think it's, yeah, 30 tokens
from what we discussed before the launch.
And, yeah. So now we are discussing with
Richie and the group that is telegram
group some launch parameters for the bank
and the LP.
Nice.
All right. Well, let's see if that is all
right. Good. That's that we got a couple
of questions.
We can bang out real quick. Let's see.
Oh, here's a tough one. Maybe a little
spicy. Let's see.
Oh, Byron, where are you talking?
Somebody was CQ CQ.
Yeah, I was just going to say before you
jump in on the AI agent stuff or model,
LLMs, DeepWiki works really good for
looking at the various projects repos.
It can, I mean, break it down and give
you a high level summary and ask a
question.
So anyway, it's just DeepWiki.com or .ai.
It does a great job. I've used it for
Rosen to send information on how Rosen
Bridge works to people and whatnot.
Anyone.
Nice.
Okay. Thanks. It's funny how these.
I think we can do a more exciting thing.
So, my hope to find some time, maybe to
prototype some whole application like
dApp, right. It's an agent just.
Yeah, and another idea we discussed
briefly about the dev chat I proposed. So
we have a lot of ideas from 2020 and now,
yeah, it seems it's possible to white-code
them into the tests, right, for Sigma SDK,
like we did back in 2019 when I designed
the interpreter on the high level of
ErgoScript language.
So, yeah, we did examples like DEX
orders, well, the mixing contract, right,
which then was evolved into the Ergo Mixer
ICO example, because it was time of ICOs
back then and so on.
And yeah, well, it's quite useful content
right and well as we have for much more on
the format to make sense to make more
examples now maybe assign small bounties
for people to do such stuff with agent and
I can just manually review contracts right
and the testing preppers that there is no
need for humans to bother with it mostly.
So if test is passing, then everything is
okay.
And the replica could be just generated
automatically.
And then, yeah, with that, we can go
further.
So I think as Ergo contracts are
templatizable, actually, they also are
friendly to AI.
HQ says, fun fact, it will take him 10
seconds to create a complete marketplace
with USC token utility trade swap.
I think if I'm not mistaken, that's the
same amount of time it took him to make
his child.
So he's pretty good at that. 10 seconds.
I'm the only one laughing at that. All
right.
Ten seconds, right? Because we just need
a front end to allow the selection of it.
And that's it because it is already
supported in my, in MewMart.
Oh, nice. Nice. Very cool. Very cool.
All right. Let's see this question. Here
we go.
Sigmanaut says, it would be cool if
someone were to clarify who is still an
active member of the EF, Ergo Foundation.
Who is responsible for what? Or are they
all afraid of bearing any responsibility,
thanks in advance?
Kushti, don't answer this one, please.
So...
But I have no idea, to be honest. I would
be interested to see an answer.
So we've got Justin, we've got AnonBR,
we've got Allison, we've got Glasgow.
Joe is I think off by now, yeah. I think
that he talked about it a while ago about
leaving and I think he somewhat made it
official unofficially.
I don't know.
So yeah, you got the core members right
there. During the EF, Glasgow, as you
know, is structure that you see online.
That would be the website, the docs,
working with those, all the discords and
telegrams as well.
That's his shtick. You have also Andy,
who's running the video show, right?
The EF has Andy involved for that. The EF
also hires Angie as well to do some
promotions, like some of the Twitter,
what's it called?
You'll see it for the ErgoHack, those
kind of things as well.
Finds writers to help write articles.
Pretty much it as far as that goes.
You know, we're trying to move everything
as community oriented as possible.
So there used to be a person they paid
for infrastructure and we're trying to
migrate that to the community
infrastructure.
I know that's taken a little while and
that's on my fault. Oh, MGPi, thanks HQ.
MGPi joined as well, the EF.
So that's something that I'm trying to
take in on mine, but you know, with the
meetup front and center it's kind of
slowed down.
I've got some machines I have to take to
Colorado I think to give to yeah I don't
think yeah there's a payroll person as
well says HQ.
I don't think people know our name I'm
not saying our name people can see it in
chat but yep so there's that person as
well.
But a couple machines that take the
Colorado handout and another one to ship,
but I just have to drive by the place to
do that.
So yeah, that's the idea that we're
trying to offload those kind of
responsibilities to the community so that
the chain can truly be community
organizing community run as opposed to a
centralized entity doing things and it's
possible just slow, right?
So eventually. Hopefully, I think at some
point they spoke about the EF being some
sort of research wing or something like
that.
But even at this point, I don't know what
the possibilities are considering kushti's
offshot is developer DAO, which could turn
into research and development as well.
So yeah, I mean, when community have the
power to do anything they want with a
chain, then anything can happen.
And that's great. So yes, that's
hopefully that was a cloudy enough answer
for you Sigmanaut on that.
Yeah, so on the ErgoDevs DAO site, we
have quite a lot of bounties proposed for
different issues, and thanks to our recent
crowdfunding campaigns done by some
community members, I don't know.
But yeah, we now have a bigger budget, so
we can do some more aggressive promotion
among developers.
And then yeah, I'm also investigating
possibilities to do a commercial company,
so vibrate and so on.
is about that, so I think it could be a
good time.
Bitcoin, for example, had a Blockstream
back in 2015, so I think it could be the
same.
They also had a Bitcoin foundation at
some point.
Then, yeah, Blockstream and now from what
I see, so the core developers are
sponsored by a few, actually not many,
like three or four commercial companies,
right?
It's important to have different entities
to avoid protocol development to be taken
by one party just.
It also would be great to see more
commercial entities around Ergo.
Yeah, well, it would be good in a way to
start with one, even like Monero, because
Tari loves, right?
And Bitcoin had a Blockstream, aside of
mining businesses back in 2015, maybe.
So yeah, it was a Blockstream only, I
believe.
Right, and yeah and then with time.
So what do we need is to have like a
stable foundation and I believe we have it
right like foundational documents like
manifesto and so on white paper.
Then yeah maybe there is need to compose
more but what do we need is to develop
Ergo itself as well open source kind of
project and yeah, the goal is to get the
protocol to provide a global neutral
settlement layer for programmable money,
right, of different kinds.
Where the native cryptocurrency, the
proof-of-work cryptocurrency ERG is just
the lowest common denominator, so the
collateral of the best quality, because of
it's been native, right, in the first
place.
So, yeah, well, we had a lot of talks, a
lot of things written here and there over
the years, so maybe it makes sense to
compile all this.
Yeah, we need to strengthen the
foundation and to grow.
So that doesn't make sense to rely on
some entity, right, to do everything.
So it's the time for that is over. And he
actually over like a couple of years ago.
I think so. Now it's time to to grow in
all the directions.
So Sigmanaut has a follow-up. He says,
thanks for the answer.
It's just a bit weird as a long-term
community member not to be informed about
major changes in the EF.
Community approach is great, but not
without officially informing the
community.
Yeah, Sigmanaut, I would say that we've
been very clear about this in AMAs and
Telegram chats and Twitters about people
leaving, about people joining the
foundation.
Many, many times during AMAs, we've
discussed about what the idea of the EF is
and what their goal was and what it is.
And the goal was to have a foundation
that could help bootstrap the community,
right?
And then slowly fade out into whatever.
either non-existence or a research
foundation or something else that just
helps with maintaining things.
So that's been, ever since I've joined,
that's been what I've spoken about it in
public, as well as what has been spoken
about in the channel.
So I think we've been, probably not
recently been clear about it, but it has
definitely been a topic many times
throughout the last several years about
what that is going to look like.
So I hear you, but yeah.
Okay.
And yeah, and according to the white
paper, so the original plan was to have
this bootstrapping entity for two years
and a half, right?
And now it's a year past, so yeah, it's
actually well, long overview, but it is
what it is.
So still, yeah, it's doing some needed
things, right? The sanctity, but yeah,
well, we need to act towards growth and
well, I think, and yeah, it's going from
the white paper, right?
And the white paper was published back in
2019, a few months before the mainnet
launch.
And that's, yeah, well, there was no plan
ever to have this bootstrapping entity to
to control the growth forever.
It's limited simply by the white paper.
Yep, yep, yep.
Okay, we've got another question from,
let's see, from Willem Jan Vandenberg.
Is there a cooperation between Ergo and
Palmyra? Are they building Palmyra
platform on Ergo and Cardano?
Perhaps one of you could provide clarity
on this, thanks in advance.
The best person to answer that probably
is Luca or Dan I think MGPi is not
necessarily involved in that specific part
of it in Palmyra last time I asked him but
the bottom line you have to remember yes
we've seen Winter Protocol being ported to
Cardano and running on there but the
bottom line you have to remember and the
best I can answer right now without being
involved with Palmyra is that one Ergo's
an open chain people are going to use it
right two.
nothing compared to Cardano. Scalability
of fees, network fees, to create all these
tokens and tracking is I don't think
feasible on Cardano necessarily compared
to how feasible it is on Ergo.
So as a company when you look at two
things and you're saying okay I can run my
Winter Protocol on this chain but it's
going to cost my clients this much and I'm
going to have to pass that cost on to them
or I can run on this chain and the cost is
less from a straight business decision.
It's obvious which chain is going to be
utilized for that.
So that's just where I think in my mind.
And I think that's probably what you'll
see in the future once Dan's business gets
in full swing with that kind of stuff.
Yeah, so I cannot probably because we had
a lot of talks with Dan and Sam, but not
in recent months.
Back in February, we were around
consensus conference and before in Dubai,
we had a lot of talks.
So, you know, Palmyra is a real-world
assets company and then, yeah, it all
depends on their real-world partners.
So, almost one year ago, we discussed to
use Dexy or Dexy lithium stable coin to do
insurance for lithium in Argentina but now
for many months I haven't heard anything
about lithium in Argentina.
Do you guys know anything about it?
Yeah. I mean, it, it heavily depends on,
the needs of real world partners of
Palmyra as well. Right. So we discussed
some things and yeah, well, there are
certain contracts implemented, I've
removed them and so on.
But then, yeah, it all depends on
concrete things on the ground, after all,
right, because it's a real world assets
company.
So the best thing we can do is to invite
then or look and ask them, right?
Because so here we don't have, anyone,
deeply connected with Palmyra, right?
So yeah, the the the best think we can.
Yeah.
Maybe we should invite Sam next time. I
think he's expressed interest in these
kinds of AMA.
Yeah. So Sam is quite devoted to
Ergonauts actually.
But, yeah, well, the thing is, you know,
it's still a super early startup and yeah
they are changing playing plans regularly
which is quite normal and yeah it all
depends on external actors as well right
because.
Yeah, well, a lot of instability in
jurisdictions they're working with and
yeah, a lot of instability in the
development of this space, real world
assets.
It depends on many factors such as legal
and so on, right?
It would be good to invite them and have
a detailed chat instead of trying to
invent something on our site.
Yeah, agreed. Yeah, I'll ping Sam. We'll
see what he says.
OK, let's see what else we have here.
We have in Zoom chat, HQ has asked, how
optimistic do you feel if we invited all
mining pool operators in creative mining
DAO and move the important chain votes on
Paideia instead of doing with changing
node settings as we do it now?
So HQ, I would say that I would say the
de facto final change is always going to
be on the node config, right?
So that's always the change period. So no
matter what you do in a DAO, on chain on
the DAO, no matter what you do, things
will not take effect unless miners tag
along and update their node configs to do
that, right?
So what's that?
So, actually, you can build some logic on
top of the node to read, well, voting
decisions from DAO and change config
automatically.
But in reality, it wouldn't change
anything really, right? Because, well, you
can just tweak the settings instead of
using web interface still.
You can always get around it. Yes,
correct. Yeah, exactly.
So that's HQ. That's the idea of what the
SIGS mining DAO was at some point, right?
To educate and to get people together to
group them up and have them interested in
tracking these changes and pushing these
changes and even proposing things, right?
And then pushing from there. But yeah, I
mean, it'd be neat.
Actually, GitBlock used this, right, for
some software.
Right, right. Yeah, they did the wallet
voting for the software. Exactly. Yep,
yep, yep.
So these things have that in the dial
right there, but it's not tied to a direct
change on the node, that's for sure.
But yeah, I think my thought would be
that if it could be iron clad, if there
was some sort of soft fork that changed it
so that this is exactly where we're
getting all details to, you could undo
that at some point.
So it's not de facto in the end. The only
de facto thing and the only fact is that
miners can run a config and have a chain.
So while we can't police that
essentially, at least you can have a group
organization like a DAO, like the SIGS
mining DAO. to at least gather people in
and have discussions before those things
are even tried to push to GitHub for
changes.
That's one of the things which I was
talking, at least you have a ledger of
on-chain voting and what we discussed,
what was put up on vote, who talked on
that.
We can at least have that. There are many
people who are trying to bring the
innovation and they're trying it.
But I think the thing is that we have
tools which are not getting used.
So what we have to do is adapt the people
to use those.
So how do we get, so the great idea would
be to create a mining DAO or modify the
SIGS mining DAO and invite all the pools
out there.
Invite every single pool out there as
well as any individual miners we have and
see if they'll participate.
My guess is that we're probably not going
to see much participation in a mining DAO
from big pools, right?
Ergo is just one facet of this massive
amount of other chains that they do.
Maybe you will, I don't know, like
Herominers is really good to us, right?
What's the other one?
Unless there is an incentive for them,
right? You can always mint a DAO token and
you can have an LP there for it.
So people are seeing that it is a DAO
which is working DAO and people are doing
stuff.
So there might be price change in them.
The only source of getting those tokens
would be by participating in the DAO
because they are staking, they will be
staking and they will be getting using the
DAO emission.
That's it. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
True. True.
It's like pre-confirmation votes before
the electoral votes. You got it. Yeah.
Yep.
But yeah, it can act as campaigns.
Like constitutional conventions. Yeah.
Yeah. But it still separates it from, so
you can say this is the vote, but this is
the actual votes.
It's like pre-voting.
Yep.
Yeah. Yeah, and the idea would be, right,
if you got everybody on board that's part
of the DAO, then you could be pretty sure
that the node config changes and people
would change their node configs and follow
through kind of thing.
And your votes actually ensure that the
pool operators actually show up because
the nodes that are pointing to them voted
for them to show up.
So you can de-stake, I suppose, or
whatever.
Yeah, that'd be interesting. If Mark,
maybe Mark, when Mark watches this later
from the SIGS DAO, maybe he could start
thinking about getting other mining pools
involved in the DAO.
Just because it's called Sigmanauts
mining, my DAO doesn't mean it has to be
just for the Sigmanauts mining pool.
It's just labeled Sigmanauts, I guess, at
that point.
So yeah, Mark, if you're watching this,
what are your thoughts on that?
When you wake up, probably sleeping,
because your baby's been awake all night,
right?
So, cool.
All right, what else we got? What time is
it? 9.52.
We got another question. Here we go. From
Zoom Chat.
That would be from Aberg. Says, does Ergo
have the capabilities of launching an
XMR-like privacy coin?
kushti, on the sub chain?
Yeah for sidechain it's possible and
actually one of the earliest ideas for
sidechains.
There is no any white paper or written
proposal but yeah possible.
So one option we discussed in the charts
is to do DarkFi based sidechain, but
DarkFi is not around yet.
So DarkFi is an merged mine sidechain of
Monero, which is bringing capability to
execute private contracts.
But yeah, it's in development yet. There
is only some early testnet and yeah. Well,
it makes sense to wait till launch or a
moment when it will be stabilized at
least. Right.
And would there be, would there be a need
for a mixer besides saving money on
bridging, when you have a privacy chain, a
side chain like that?
Sorry. Would there be a need for
ErgoMixer at that point besides the fact
that you'd save money running ErgoMixer if
you just bridged to the side chain and
then slowly came out on other endpoints
kind of thing utilizing the privacy side
chain as a mixer?
I don't know, so you can actually exit
from the side chain to the mixer on the
main chain, right? Or stealth address.
Yeah, I think it still would be useful.
Just for different tasks, maybe. Subtasks.
Gotcha.
Cool.
Well, anything else, guys?
We have a reduction coming up. I thought
we'd bring that up.
Oh, nice. Byron. What's it going to?
I think is what sub double digits now. Is
it nine?
Is it the first single digit?
Wow. That's crazy.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, so QX, I think there is need
to tweet and yeah, I think maybe next time
let's discuss Twitter strategy X strategy.
Let me use these few seconds to again
invite people up to trial on the
Sigmanauts account and then jump up to
Ergo or show experience that you've had
and jump right up to the Ergo platform.
We would love more contributors to
Twitter. I tweet when I can, and that's
about it.
And then Glasgow tweets sometimes as
well.
But yeah, if you're interested, please
let us know.
And we'll either look at the previous
tweets you've done and take you right to
the Ergo Platform one, or you can trial
run on the Sigmanauts Twitter and then
jump up to the Ergo Platform Twitter.
So please, please help.
I think someone asked when sub-blocks and
I think it's what mid November ish or end
of the year. It's time for it.
I think he's joking, but when sub-blocks.
Oh no, he means the voting. Oh yeah.
Yeah. Right. When's that, when's that come
into effect, kushti?
6.0 or what do you mean?
The vote's happening, right? Or when does
that actually switch?
So 6.0 will be activated in a few days,
like five days.
Five days?
Yeah, it's like 3,000 or 3,500 blocks,
something like that.
So, yeah, just like, five days.
I guess we need to tweet that too.
Yeah. That's two things I have to tweet.
kushti. That's going to, that's going to
send me back a week or two.
Yeah. So there is a lot of materials for
tweeting, right?
So, we have a lot of things are discussed
in the Telegram chats, unfortunately, and
not going beyond that, right?
So there is need to tweet for more, to
use forum for more.
Because forum is good for archival
purposes and yeah, to have more articles
and so on.
You know, I think I can point an agent at
the Telegram chat and just come up with
daily tweets from those discussions and
the dev chat.
Maybe I'll try that. That might help out
a little bit in the meantime.
Yeah, and yeah, even things which are
announced to our telegram groups. Such as
main even and dev updates and so on.
So yeah, makes sense to to tweets at
least great idea kushti great idea.
Yeah, we also need for like, catchy
tweets, more like I don't know
revolutionary tweets because drama kushti.
We had done with drama for the week or
the month or we have enough drama. I guess
it's a new month.
I don't know about drama, but I think we
always need to remind about principles and
so on while the manifest, when it was
tweeted for the last time like years ago.
New people are coming all the time and
well, my impression is that many Ergonauts
are considered a community as something
stable, right?
It's like a small circle of their friends
they're chatting with and so on.
But in reality, new people are coming all
the time and that there is need to
introduce them things which are very known
to the old members, right?
But still newcomers need to get into
them. To remind about principles and yeah,
to build everything for growth, not for
staying in the small circles.
in some charts. I mean, that's not the
way to get any adoption.
Yeah, I agree. It's manpower, too,
though. So, yeah.
So, please, anybody who wants to help out
with Twitter, that'd be great.
HQ just reminded us that Mark, sorry,
Glasgow used to do weekly summaries in
chat.
And I don't think I've seen those lately.
But those are AI runs. So, there's no
reason that we can't then extract from
that already agent that he's doing that
with to bring out tweets for the next week
kind of thing as well.
So let me work with Mark or Glasgow and
we'll see if we can get those back up and
see if we can extract tweets from these to
do from all the channels.
So yeah.
Yeah, and another point is don't forget
about national groups.
So back in 2020, we built a network of
national groups, Chinese, Indonesian,
Russian, French, Spanish, and so on,
right?
So it makes sense to even auto-translate
and publish, well, automatic translation
or ping moderators of national groups,
right?
Yeah, so from our observations many of
them are disconnected from the news stream
and that's quite unfortunate because we
basically have maybe more people there in
total than in English groups.
Right. So the, the main and, what else we
have mining concern. So, the, there are
national groups about mine concern.
Yeah. And then in total, more people
stay, but, they have forgotten often.
All right. We'll do better with that.
We'll try to, are you a miner?
Is my mic up? Oh, I have my monitor in my
living room, but it's not set up.
I need to set it up. I need to set it up.
But I was going to ask if the ERG-1 could
serve as like also using the DAO framework
as well to pick a community member like
the usual ones that we see that do a great
job on their own promoting to like help
you cold produce tweets and then they can
show that they are who they are that's
producing it.
Obviously their main account and tweet
from the account to help you out as like
winning the whatever the ERG-1 reward is a
week or a month or whatever it is or
something like that and rotate it.
So it's like community active actions.
So you're talking about getting those
people from ERG-1 involved and helping
send tweets and write tweets and pull good
tweets from their database of what's been
leaderboard that week?
Basically, approved members that's been
in the community for a while that already
support Ergo could help you produce tweets
on the main chat since you have other
things in real life and things to do as
well as work on Ergo that could help you
out, especially since they pick a winner
for something.
I forget the frequency and it'll rotate.
So it's like an active community involved,
like even membership.
Right, right. Yeah, so people write their
tweets and then they submit them to the
site and then depending on how many
retweets or likes they get or views, I
think that's how they're ranked, right?
So yeah, I mean that's a treasure trove
of probably really good Ergo tweets that
are promoting Ergo that could be used.
So yeah, all right. All right. So let's
see what Glasgow and let's see what Guifa,
Guifa, Guifa, Guifa.
I'm saying I'm butchering the name from
ERG-1. Have to say HQ knows what it is.
Good friend of HQ's.
All right. Sounds good, guys. It's 10.03.
I'm already three minutes late for my next
meeting.
Guifa.
G-I-U-F-A. Thank you, HQ.
Great. All right. Everybody, any closing
words?
Byron, you want to close it out? kushti,
you got any closing words?
Oh, kushti had to go. kushti was like,
okay, goodbye.
kushti Irish goodbye. Byron, close it
out. Go for it.
We're going to be in the clouds in
Colorado. Enjoy your weekend, guys.
That's right. Thanks everybody for
joining. Ciao.