All right.
Good morning, Joe.
How are you doing, sir?
Doing pretty well.
No complaints.
Well, thanks for joining me.
So this video is a part of a set of
content coming out for the summit.
And I was hoping to just do a little deep
dive into what Rosen Bridge is.
I would say right now, that's like one of
the most popular dApps on Ergo.
And in my eyes, like one of the things
that also expresses like the values of the
community and kind of executes really well
on a philosophy that's like not always the
easiest road, you know, and so I just
wanted to talk to you about that and get
your opinion, you know, maybe first tell
me like what is Rosen?
What makes it different and special as
opposed to other bridges?
All right, so Rosen itself is kind of an
interchange protocol, is a good way to
look at it.
It's a transfer protocol between
different endpoints, okay?
And part of what that gives the Ergo
community is an element of
interoperability, which is always nice,
but it's hardened access.
Access that basically we control right as
a community and that's powerful in this
space because there are certain terms and
conditions that
we kind of have to comply to or
potentially risk delisting, right?
So you can use the example of privacy.
There's only so far you can take that
before you run into a problem where it's
like the liability of your partners
becomes an issue.
And, you know, they have too much control
over your ability to access markets,
right?
Aside from the cost
of access itself, it's also a
permissioned environment.
So the general idea is saying, OK, well,
you have these different markets where
liquidity is concentrated, and you also
have these consumer-facing wallets, as an
example, that we have the ability to back
in without permission.
And so that puts us in a much stronger
position long term, where we're no longer
subject to the
grace of external partners right and
that's something that Ergo kind of
suffered with because it was a fair launch
system so you know our
market access for a long time was largely
dependent on, you know, who we could pay
and what their terms and conditions were.
Right.
And so I think having freer access that
we control as a community is powerful.
It's something that's new.
You know, I'd like to continue building
it out to where we're available on a lot
of consumer facing entry points, you know,
Coinbase wallet, Phantom wallet, things
that people are familiar with.
without needing the grace and permission
of a gatekeeper in between those
endpoints.
Yeah, okay, so you just told me the why
of Rosen, sick.
So just to restate, you built Rosen
because access to crypto was permissioned
and dependent on all sorts of factors that
were not in your control, and most of
those factors were not aligned with your
values.
Yeah, okay.
All right, sick.
So that's kind of what I was getting at
when I was saying like, yeah, Rosen is
like a good representative of the
ecosystem and just like, executes our
values very well.
But like, a lot of times, doing things
from a principal position makes them more
difficult.
Right.
You're having to do all this stuff.
How does that get accomplished?
How is Rosen actually different on an
implementation level?
One of my favorite things to do is look
from time to time at rekt.news.
Have you ever seen rekt?
It's just like this list of all the hacks
and two-thirds of them are bridges.
What is technically different about Rosen
that allows you to do this?
So we dove into the security assumptions
of bridging before we designed it, right?
So we kind of had like a first principles
approach.
If we're going to design a bridge, the
first thing we need to really understand
is why do bridges fail?
right?
And, you know, then take that knowledge
and try to implement a solution that, you
know, avoids the pitfalls that we've seen
in the space.
And a large part of kind of this failure
process
In my opinion, it's what I would call
nonlinear scaling assumptions, where it's
like every time you add an endpoint, you
move into a new environment, you get new
logic if you're going the smart contract
way, which means you have new
dependencies.
And so it's like your attack vector is
growing faster than just one to one.
And that's incredibly hard to manage in
moving environments, which blockchains
are, you know, living, moving environments
that go through updates.
You know, every once in a while we'll
have new standards, new logic.
And so it becomes something that's very
hard to defend.
Right.
Yeah.
So, so maybe in simple terms, if one
blockchain upgrades, the other one
doesn't.
your system now has to be reconfigured.
Yeah, we have to update and keep things
in sync in real time.
And that's just on the chain itself.
Then you have all of the standards, the
logic of each particular chain, the
dependencies that you need to program the
logic.
So you kind of have this chain of risk
whenever you get into
Like smart contracts right where it's not
just the contract itself.
It's also like the dependencies That
you're using to interact with the chain
could be broken and then that can be
exploited and then you have like a
downhill risk, right
So instead of this mint and burn, which
is how most smart contract based
blockchains are configured, we have this
idea of lock and unlock, right?
We use vaults.
And actually, you see that in Ergo
itself, where
You know one of the complaints that
sometimes we run into is we don't have
like a smart token standard where you have
this ability to just create a contract and
mint and burn from it and part of the
reason why is you have like infinite.
Mint risk right if somebody can exploit
that they can essentially mint infinite
tokens and so you know the first thing
that we do when we set up these vaults.
Is we will mint large supply of coins or
tokens will put them in a cold wallet and
then from that point is constantly audited
right and.
We rely on this idea of kind of a
dual-layer multi-sig would be the simplest
way to describe it, where how Rosen
functions as a protocol is first you have
this reporting layer, and their job is to
scan.
They're auditors, right?
Those are the watchers.
The watchers, yeah, they're auditors
essentially.
So they are constantly watching an
endpoint.
If something happens, they report it to a
smart contract on Ergo that creates the
first layer of consensus.
And the nice thing about that is we get
this idea of pre-truth.
It's like prior to execution, what is
supposed to happen?
Which is kind of a failure point for a
lot of bridges because
They learn something is wrong after it
happens.
So having this idea of saying, OK, well,
this is what should happen, and then we
execute what should happen.
In my opinion, initially, I was thinking
clearance and settlement in the banking
system, where there are two distinct
processes where you receive something, you
have to go through an auditing process,
clear the transaction, and then it moves
to another stage where it executes
settlement and funds are moved.
It works.
So you don't really need to reintroduce
new things.
It's just modernize it.
And being that it's decentralized, then
we get into this idea of decentralized
incentives, which is profit distribution.
That's one of the most powerful things we
see with blockchain is this ability to
distribute profit.
So Rosen leverages that to try to create
like a community and people that are
incentivized and earn from bridge
transactions.
So in a way, it's kind of like your
mining interchange, if that makes sense.
Yeah, it does.
It does.
I think I really appreciate the approach
where it's like, okay, we recognize the
limitations that we're dealing with.
in terms of people's intentions and also
just like, oh, like, why can't this just
be automated entirely?
You know, it's like, so we've come up
with a solution that aligns people's
incentives.
So as you said, it's like a community of
watchers.
I mean, there's hundreds of watchers.
Yep.
At this point, there's a couple hundred.
It's something like we could have built a
system that didn't include profit
distribution, right?
But then it's like, okay, you no longer
have a check on the system and you no
longer have an incentive for
participation, right?
And I really hope, I know Rosen is kind
of new and we're still working into new
environments and we're still in the
process of figuring out like the
politics on top of chains of how to get
added into different applications,
infrastructure, etc.
But my hope is that, longer term, we now
have this layer of people that are
incentivized and profit from growth.
And that becomes powerful because then
you have a community that can push the
adoption of Rosen itself versus just a
team building stuff.
Yeah, and it's also a functional machine
that grows over time.
Not like a burn, as you were mentioning,
having to pay people to access their
thing, you know, it's not you're not just
like subtracting funds out of the Treasury
until it hits zero.
It's an actual it's an actual working
machine that
powers itself through this profit
incentive.
Super cool.
And a lot of the times when you see
market listing, it comes with this
friction cost up front and there's a
certain incentive that the team's going to
recoup that.
And that creates a weird alignment of
incentives itself because now you have a
team potentially trading against their own
ecosystem to recoup the cost of working
with a third party.
And that's unfortunately quite common, it
seems, with listings because in many
cases, when you're talking larger
exchanges, you can get into the millions.
There was an article, as an example,
somebody
listing on a Korean exchange and paying
$10 million.
That's more than the entire history of
development, funds, exchanges, everything
we've done on Ergo just to work with the
third party, which is insane.
The incentives don't line up.
Wow.
Is there anything else about the
implementation of Rosen that you wanted to
talk about before the next topic?
Sure, I think that we've made a couple of
choices that are probably, I don't know,
non-standard in the space.
An example would be we call ERG that's
wrapped RS-ERG.
And it's because we want to let people
know that there is additional security
complexity.
A lot of the times, security complexities
in crypto is very buried.
to where it's obfuscated until we find
out there's a problem and then post-mortem
we figure out what the problem was.
And that's kind of a terrible design.
So my hope with the overall design and
having everything open source public
facing, anybody can join if they're
willing to stomach some economic friction
to make sure that the bridge doesn't get
spammed.
less that's hidden from end users.
And I think that that's a big part of the
strength of Rosen itself.
Just not ending up on rekt.news.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
That's the goal.
I would be rekt if that happens.
Yeah.
OK.
I think I agree with all of that, man.
And I think you've explained it pretty
simply.
Maybe one more open ended question.
Just kind of like long term, what's your
vision for Rosen?
Well, I think that we have a couple of
verticals that we can really build on.
So in the blockchain space, we have this
idea of layer twos.
And essentially what a layer two is, is
it's the idea of pre-confirmation with the
assumption things are going to settle
later.
And so like one thing we will run into
periodically is Rosen is slow.
It's slow by design, right?
But you want additional checks on your
funds.
So when you get faster transactions
between systems that like finality and
proof of work is based on how many blocks
have been added, right?
So the sooner it's final, the less secure
it is.
You know the same is potentially true in
proof of stake where you have like the
historical rollback You know or you know
you can say okay on this chain the longest
rollback has been 60 blocks So if we shoot
lower than 60 blocks, you know, we're
assuming that that's never gonna happen
again and it could right Yeah, so you're
inheriting a lot of
security complexities in different
environments that are not always
straightforward to understand.
And so we said, okay, let's build this
slow, let's make it secure.
And most users do want speed, right?
And it's something we have the capacity
to do, essentially what that would, again,
let's just take from what exists that
works.
In the banking world, if you want a
faster transfer, you pay a premium, right?
And so we potentially can build a system
around Rosen, not within it, but around
it, which is an important distinction to
make, where you have liquidity providers
on either endpoint.
Somebody sends and they say, I want to
pay extra to have this settle faster.
The liquidity provider will basically
assume the risk of faster settlement for
premium.
and then the bridge transaction will pay
them on a delay.
Users get their funds faster, the
liquidity provider gets a premium markup,
and the core assumption itself doesn't
change.
In building around Rosen, that's
something that we need to be very mindful
to protect, because as soon as you start
to introduce leverage into bridges, you
get economic security complexity, which is
its own crazy vertical.
We saw that with THORChain as an example,
where they said, hey, we're going to have
where we're going to create DeFi inside
of the bridge and that's a terrible idea.
Yeah, the whole thing was like a short on
Bitcoin and like, oh, it went up so
everything fell apart.
Yeah, it's potentially really, really
profitable, but it introduces just
assumptions that are breaking.
My base rule in bridge design is, okay,
we want to not rehypothecate assets.
Just that simple.
We want to keep everything one-to-one in
a way that's transparent, auditable.
Any user can check that.
And it's strange because we even see
custodial solutions on Coinbase, right?
And the auditability there is a little
foggy.
Somehow we've created a better custodial
solution than most of the exchanges that
are working with Fortune 500 companies,
which is kind of insane to think about,
but that's, I don't know, state of the
space.
Yeah.
Yeah, man.
OK.
So long term, you're imagining Rosen
connecting all the major layer ones.
Is that the goal?
Both.
If you look at product differentiation,
there are a ton of bridges that work with
ETH because you have parallel logic via
the EVM.
And so I think that if you're going to
compete, you need some sort of competitive
advantage.
And one thing that Rosen
The natural advantage of Rosen itself is
that it was designed to work across
non-compatible environments Right, so I
look across at other projects that you
know are similar to Ergo and in terms of
You know, they don't have this I'm gonna
call it an insider advantage in terms of
working with a lot of partners in the
space but they're technically rich right
and
You can look at proof of work projects,
Nervos, Alephium, Kaspa, they're real
projects.
There's a lot of research, a ton of
engineering that's just disrespected.
That's not what the space respects at
this point.
And so I'm saying, okay, well, if I look
across at different projects and I see
that they have these same friction points
in terms of market access, building into
them creates a richer ecosystem with a lot
more technical depth.
you know, versus, you know, you look at
Binance and, you know, it's a combination
of food and animal items, you know, that
they're listing today.
It's like, well, where, where is like the
technical depth and engineering and like
development mind share there?
There's none.
There, there really is none.
And it kind of creates its own like
idiocracy in crypto.
So I do think that using
So, Rosen is like, you're looking at the
problem that you experienced as an
individual, recognize that everyone who is
not operating under these perverse
incentives
also experiences that.
And so you're trying to really be a boon
for the blockchain industry and for the
principles that you really agree with and
saying, like, you don't have to jump
through all these hoops to take part in
this revolution that's happening right
now.
That's really cool.
Yeah, I mean, like long-term, if we have
the ability to backdoor where liquidity is
concentrated, we're no longer beholden to
that aspect of the industry.
And I don't like to deal with them, you
know, like I've had years of meetings with
teams where it's like they're, I don't
know, they're focused on flashy metrics
that usually- They look like Mr. Burns
like trying to take your money.
Yeah, kind of.
I mean, they're focused on flashy metrics
that don't necessarily translate into
anything valuable other than like this
ability to pseudo and honestly extract
value.
That's what I would say.
So, you know, it's hard to have a
technical conversation, you know, versus,
I don't know, there's a value misalignment
in crypto, in my opinion.
This is structural where it's like, if
you look at how traditional finance
operates in like the VC world, they'll
have like a five to 10 year window where
it's like, okay, you're gonna build this
and then we're going to slowly push for
the adoption of, you know, whatever you're
building.
And that adoption curve is not
instantaneous.
And so a lot of VCs in crypto, because
crypto has this amazing ability to create
liquidity right out of the gate, they're
looking at the liquidity risk curve and
not the adoption curve.
So their focus is backwards.
And so then you have a lot of things that
are introduced to market that have a lot
of marketing hype.
And they're very liquidity curve driven.
but they're not adoption focused.
Axie Infinity was like the biggest thing,
you know, it's like, oh, like, cool,
didn't really do anything, made some
people a ton of money.
Yeah, it doesn't relate to adoption.
And if like if you're focused on like the
development side and you're looking at the
adoption curve, you have to realize, you
know, okay, where is Rosen going to be in
five years?
That's, that's kind of the goal.
Where can Rosen be in 10 years?
That's the goal.
It's not like where is Rosen going to be
on the five minute chart against Bitcoin?
You can't think like that.
Never build anything.
And your whole approach has been like,
how do we build to withstand that 100-year
flood?
Not like what happened this past year.
And then think you're good.
I love it.
The crypto space is increasingly fragile,
in my opinion.
As things become more mainstream and more
subject to the whims and
like choices of like the political
environment you know things are going to
potentially be more fragile right and so
our goal is as like an industry at least
when i started was how do we create
non-fragile systems to where
something that's not going to fall apart
when the other team gets elected or
whatever.
Exactly.
We need to be able to withstand ideally
state level attacks.
That's kind of the idea Bitcoin was
founded on.
And so we've tried to follow design
principles that will
support that in really harsh
environments.
That was the goal of Rosen's.
How do we make unstoppable access that
way if KuCoin gets their access to work
with Americans pulled and exchanges say,
hey, you have this mixer on your chain
that we don't agree with, so we're going
to delist you.
How can we navigate those type of attacks
without losing our tether to larger
markets?
So, Rosen is kind of an ongoing attempt
to harden, you know, make Ergo hard to
kill, basically.
Yeah, I love it, man.
That's good.
Okay, so I just wanted to jump into the
Rosen site real quick and just kind of
show people what this is and maybe how to
use it.
So, can you see that all right?
All right, so this is the list of locked
assets.
So just to give people an idea, there are
like over 40 different tokens that can be
sent and couple of coins.
And these are across Ergo, Cardano and
Ethereum right now, is that correct?
And Binance is just now, yeah, Binance
just now started.
What else is like coming down the pike?
So I think one of the most exciting
things that we have been working towards
is been wallet integrations, right?
So right now we have this application
that the user needs to go to find and it
kind of creates additional friction and
complexity in terms of like the bridging
process.
You know, I've been like,
I don't know, on the Nautilus wallet team
since that came out, and MHS, who's my
co-founder, has his own wallet actually,
Minotaur, that he was working on in
parallel.
And so our goal long-term was to say,
okay, let's get the Ergo ecosystem wallet
game kind of leveled up, and then we need
to create an SDK to allow wallets to
actually integrate Rosen into the
interface.
which hopefully will make the bridging
process itself a lot simpler because it's
happening from a single UI rather than
bouncing across the website and the web
extension or the node wallet or wherever
you're coming in from.
I do think in terms of the front-facing
aspect of Rosen, that's going to be a big
development in 2025.
You know, part of the reason why, you
know, we were, I don't know, maybe a
little bit slow out of the gate with that
is when you create an open SDK, you, I
don't know, you kind of create this
parallel incentive to where
There's an opportunity for somebody to
integrate a thing that looks like Rosen
wallet.
That's not right.
That's like the downside to open source
code sometimes is it's like, okay, you've
just given this recipe that somebody can
tweak with and say, okay, well now you're
using Rosen bridge, but actually you're
bridging to my wallet.
Yeah, so you got to have enough there to
like make it super obvious that yeah, we
need we need awareness in that because
that does happen sometimes where you have
like fraudulent front ends and that type
of that type of nonsense in the crypto
space.
But I think we finally matured enough, at
least on the wallet side, where we have a
pretty good foundation to start plugging
that into.
And then we can start working with
external partners, right?
We can say, OK, some of the Cardano
wallets that could potentially support
Rosen in the interface and long term.
My hope is that we can take a lot of
these assets, you know, let's say Ergo as
an example that is traditionally seen some
friction in terms of how to access Ergo,
how to buy it.
and put it in consumer facing, wallets
that are very, you know, they, that have
adoption, you know, and when Ergo or RS
ERG can be bought in Coinbase wallet and
phantom wallet and that it's like, okay,
suddenly we can not only leverage the
liquidity of other environments, but we
also have like this ability to use all the
tooling built around them, which is
exciting.
Yeah, man.
And just like to that point, I was
looking at this chart and I see is that 3
million ERG, 3 million ERG are currently
on the bridge.
So one of my personal goals when we were
designing Rosen is it was like, okay, at
some point I'm hoping that the liquidity
in Rosen is equal or greater to the amount
that's held on exchanges, right?
Because I know the cost of those
listings.
Right, so I can't just say hey, this is
how much it was openly I'm sure people can
audit it because everything the Ergo
Foundation did was transparent But it's
like that that gives me a real Like
numerical value in terms of the market
that I've created and how much it would
cost and pair work with a third party and
so right now You know Rosen is one of the
largest
exchanges in simple terms.
So that kind of makes me look back and
say, okay, well, the cost savings was
definitely worth it and market that no
longer is beholden to regulations or a
company's internal risk assumptions.
Because at any point, any one of these
exchanges could, in theory, pull an FTX
and blow up.
You know, not only do we have the
regulatory risk, but you have their own
like internal risk in terms of how they
manage assets and leverage and hacks and
all this.
Yeah.
And now you have this system that
includes hundreds of people and is open to
including more people if they wish that is
securing this portion of the supply.
That's really amazing.
Good work, man.
Thank you.
I thought this page was really
interesting as well.
You can just like a live view of
everything that's going on.
And you can see kind of what's getting
sent from where to where.
You can check yours.
You send yours.
It's like, oh, it's been like 30 minutes.
What happened?
And you can see, OK, I'm good.
I'm good.
Just be patient.
And the whole thing is just really easy
to use.
So when I look at this, it's really just
picking, where am I going from?
Where am I going?
And then you plug your address in and
then you select the token that you're
sending and the amount.
Then you get a depiction of your fees and
the cost of transfer.
I know some people kind of, they didn't
like the time.
They wanted it to be faster and then they
also wanted it to be cheaper, of course.
But really this was really intentional
and I think I understand why
things are the way they are and you know
it's like you're paying for, you get what
you pay for.
Well you know even if you were to like
spin up a phantom wallet right now and
build a bridge from say like Solana to
Ethereum right in that inner wallet bridge
it's actually the exact same cost and the
difference is instead of being distributed
to like a
open group of watchers, that just goes to
one party.
So like on a fee footing, we're actually,
you know, pretty much in alignment with
where the industry is, you know, in terms
of like bridging.
The difference is where the payment goes.
Yeah, yeah, that's really good, man.
That's really good.
I get it.
I think what you're doing is important.
And and I hope that that people from the
other ecosystems can
you know, watch this video, see other
content and kind of recognize that it's
not just like us fighting them for like
the 400th rank in market cap total or
whatever.
Like, like, like, no, man, we're trying
to make, build some value and and really
like change what the whole top 100 top 50
projects looks like.
Yeah.
And there's one little hidden bonus in
Rosen that I really like.
That's just kind of a function of using
the Ergo blockchain is and that's like
when we create the initial like threshold
based report on Ergo.
we create a transaction that pays miners
downstream.
But we also create a box that lives on
Ergo for about four years and it does have
some ERG in it.
And then four years later, it's cleaned
up and it pays miners again.
So every Rosen transaction technically
will pay Ergo miners twice.
Wow.
Yeah, that's cool.
Storage rent strikes again.
Yeah, so long term, you know, it's like
if we can connect to enough ecosystems and
get enough transactions through, we're
actually paying miners twice for every
transaction, plus we're paying this, you
know, set of watchers on top of Ergo.
And ultimately, I do think that profit
distribution is the greatest power of
blockchain, right?
That's its superpower and unfortunately,
I think more and more we're seeing profit
extraction being used as the superpower of
blockchain, which is backwards.
Yeah.
So is there anything, any place we should
send people who want to learn more about
Rosen, maybe how do you participate as a
watcher or
How do you connect your chain, those
types of things?
Sure.
I would say that in terms of the general
public, if they want to learn about it, I
think one of the best places would be the
Discord or Telegram for Rosen Bridge.
And part of the reason why is because we
have all of these infrastructure providers
that are constantly checking and updating
and actively providing system services to
Rosen.
And so you have like a depth of knowledge
that is me plus 200.
And I would say collectively, the 200 are
better than me actually at troubleshooting
and figuring out exactly what's going on
with
you know, different problems, tweaks,
aspects of the system because they're, you
know, like actively incentivized to
participate.
You know, we do have Twitter where we try
to keep like the news feed rolling.
You know, we have Discord.
So it's something to, you know, kind of
dig into in terms of like if a ecosystem
wants to join one of the things I've kind
of done in parallel and again it's just
based on like our own history at some
point we were looking at bridges right and
so you had a variety of
Let's say documentation, sometimes coming
from an external system that's unique into
something that's standardized is not
really very straightforward.
And so we started really trying to cook
documentation and onboarding stuff with
DogeChain, which is in the kind of
integration stages of development.
We'll probably see that live.
I don't know.
I say two weeks just because we always
need end-to-end tests and everything.
I'm hoping that that comes with
sufficient documentation to where,
especially anything that's a Bitcoin fork,
it should be relatively straightforward to
follow and say, okay, you know, that's
potentially just that's a lot of value.
You have Bitcoin Cash Litecoin.
You know, I think Flux is a fork of
Bitcoin, Namecoin, you know, a lot of
different stuff out there that use kind of
the Bitcoin
model and extended it in some way and the
same is true with the EVM right having
Ethereum integrated really opens us up to
the potential to move across like EVM
compatible environments which I think will
happen naturally but
Again, one of the greatest benefits of
Ergo itself and, you know, Rosen is
non-compatible environment.
So how do we work with these systems that
are, you know, really unique?
You know, one of my personal goals just
for
I don't know, funsies, let's call it, is
going to be to create thresholds on top of
Monero and relist Monero on different
exchange environments.
Because that is ultimately going to be a
great test of, OK, we tried to build the
system to be resilient.
So let's break a rule and see what
happens, right?
Yep.
You've got to stress test it at some
point.
And I think that's a great way to do it.
And also potentially say, hey, this is
why we built the system.
Because Monero is famous for crossing the
line and getting delisted from markets,
which has been kind of painful for them.
But their community has adapted really
well.
Yeah.
Right on.
Hey, well, I think this was a lot of
really good information, Joe.
I appreciate you taking the time to meet
with me and explain all this stuff.
And also just like thanks.
Thanks for being a good representative of
a lot of the same values that I try to put
out into the world and for doing just good
work all around.
So good on you, man.
Appreciate it.
Yeah.
All right.
Have a good day, sir.
You too.