Good morning.
Here we go.
Good morning, kushti.
How are you doing?
Happy Wednesday, Thursday.
Is today Thursday?
Yeah, Thursday.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, yeah, they're doing well.
A lot of things as usual, so publishing a
lot, actually.
And we're watching 6.0 voting, so it's
going well.
Yeah, yeah.
I see that 97% of miners have put the
node in and are voting yes.
Right, right, right.
That's awesome.
That's very good.
I think on SigmaUSD we're still waiting
to compile a 6.0 modified node so that we
can run it.
And then hopefully we'll be voting yes as
well.
But we'll see on that.
It's a little bit more of a process when
we're running storage rent.
So another step involved.
Yeah, I hear you're out of country.
You're on a trip.
Yeah, so in Dubai currently, I met a
quite famous guy, Josh, a few days ago in
a coffee shop.
Just on his way to an airport.
It's quite hot here, but still a lot of
people in the town are making some
meetings.
What do you wear outside when it's hot?
120 degrees Fahrenheit.
Unfortunately I still don't have Arabian
wear, you know, like those white clothes.
Probably the best choice actually.
But yeah, I'm just wearing like t-shirt.
But then, yeah, well, you can be bombed
by the sun quite quickly.
Yeah, yeah.
Are you giving any talks while you're
there, kushti?
Sorry?
Are you giving any talks while you're
there, or just private meetings?
Just private.
So in regards with talks, not much
events.
So there were some meetups a few years
ago.
Now mostly dead, it seems.
And yeah, only big conference, it seems.
And they will be in October.
And then April, likely, like they have
what here, token.
2049 the biggest problem is in Singapore
still but yeah Dubai version is also
getting steam then yeah well last autumn I
visited Cardano summit and there was
Binance week around the same time.
Blockchain life and so on, yeah, so a lot
of conference, but usually, well, I don't
know, so I'm fed with those events,
probably, because yeah, it's mostly about
some marketing people selling some
nonsense and scammers, basically, a lot of
scammers around, right?
So, yeah.
But yeah, so the plan for this year is to
visit BTC Asia maybe in Hong Kong in late
August and then yeah, Korean blockchain
week.
So we're already talking with some peers
in South Korea.
So yeah, well, probably we'll go there in
late September.
Oh, that's great.
That's great.
I saw you had some comments in chat the
other day talking about the next big move
for Ergo, besides marketing or beyond
marketing, is building useful applications
and pushing those out into the world that
everyday people could use and it's
integrated in the blockchain.
Right, but not just billing, so I believe
a lot of tools already there, right?
So we just need people who will use them
and describe experience, right?
And describe pros and cons.
Yeah, like Bricks, for example, right?
Your experiments with students' currency.
Right, right, right.
MewDex, sorry, MewMart, those kind of
things.
Yeah, you're right, you're right.
There are quite a few tools already out
there that we can push out.
What else do we have?
Yeah, even DAO tooling, so yeah, I think
there could be a lot of options right
here.
Yep, we have, I keep saying this every
once in a while, but SigmaLock as well.
When that's done, CannonQ just pinged
them in chat the other day.
And I think there was just a temporary
pause on finishing up the development of
that, but they're getting to a point where
soon the UI will be connected to it and
built.
So that'll be really interesting.
That's something that you could
essentially sell as an alternative to any
crypto holder that wants to save and put
money away for their children or for their
partners or that kind of thing, with a
lock in place and with amount of keys that
you can hand to a lawyer or somebody else
with an expiry on block height or date.
I mean, that's a real life tool that will
be available for the blockchain that
doesn't exist on Ergo right now
essentially in that capacity or many other
places.
So yeah, things like that are pretty damn
cool.
That aren't possible elsewhere.
Yeah, so a lot of use case, right?
And well, most useful I believe is also
quite simple, right?
So don't require for complex smart
contracts or whatever.
Right?
So in most cases, well, what people are
looking at is just for things like trading
like MewMart, cross-trading, right?
Those lock-in schemes, multi-signature
does.
So yeah, like community currents.
So yeah, I believe in most cases, it's
about simple stuff.
Just people need to start using it.
Yeah, so I was thinking about this the
other day, because I was thinking back, I
think it was yesterday, the day before I
got home from my hiking trip, I was dead
tired.
I felt like I wanted to die.
And just going through stuff in my head
about some easy things that could be
pulled on chain and actually function
better on chain.
And it gave me two thoughts.
One was just a simple app that you could
make for helping to track your pets.
Right now there's like, I think I pay $80
or $90 a year for the chip embedding in
our dog so that you can scan it if they
get lost.
But you could do a one-way blockchain
purchase and put the encrypted information
on chain, print off a QR code, put it on
their collar, and have the same effect for
cheaper.
And it led me to the thought that I feel
that the blockchain enables people to
charge for proper effort.
I think there's an imbalance in
corporatism or capitalism where demand is
king.
So if one person's making an app that
does something, then they can charge
whatever the hell they want for it,
regardless of effort.
What I'm trying to say is effort isn't
relational to price charged.
And I think that's awful, right?
I think that if you develop an app and it
takes you a day and you put it up on there
and it's useful for people, that's great.
But should it mean that you retire for
the rest of your life for something like
that while people charge out the nose for
kind of things?
I don't think so.
Some aspects of that.
I think so if you develop a simple app,
you put it out there, then perhaps it
should be relational to the effort.
And I think the blockchain brings back
that true, I guess you could say
competitive capitalistic spirit where
somebody else could come along and do your
thing for better and for cheaper.
And that competition is right there.
And the base startup cost, since the
blockchain is already there and set, is
wiped away kind of thing.
So I appreciate that about the
blockchain.
I think we should see more of that.
I think we should see more
competitiveness in these scenes to kind of
get the price of things truer to the total
effort.
It's insane that they can charge you
close to $100 a year for storing a few
bytes of information on their servers,
right?
For this pet kind of thing.
And there's massive amounts of things
similar to that.
So yeah, so that's what I'd like to see.
I'd like to see the blockchain actually
push innovation and competition and have
effort equal value and cost in the future,
as opposed to these things where you buy
something digital, and they try to
digitally lock you from an upgrade path.
Here's this little extra bit we're going
to give you.
To the company, it's like, what, it costs
them nothing to do that?
To develop that it's just an upsell on
that part and the only thing that's
locking you out of some stupid code that's
stopping you from accessing code that's
already on your system that you just can't
run it because you don't have access.
So bullshit like that I feel.
Hopefully the blockchain can really help
deliver against that, especially with open
source tooling and that kind of stuff.
So sell yourself.
Sell the way that you present your
business and the way that you run your
business as opposed to safely locking
yourself into code that nobody else can
use or steal so that you just have a
proprietary package that you give people
and screw innovation or screw anybody else
from making it better.
Yeah, well I think Ergo is especially
about competitive capitalism, right,
because, well, there are no free money
here, right, to sponsor, like, parasitic
activities, basically.
And no VCs, right, to just throw away
smaller competitors as well, again with
money being spent on unfair competition.
You want something to win, you build it
better and you run it better.
It's as simple as that.
That's the key here.
Quite an amazing setting actually.
I guess there's still chances for
corruption everywhere, but I feel that an
open platform with open source tools might
help stave that a little bit.
Yeah, and then we have AI, right?
So even if some contract is not open
source, I believe it's pretty easy to
modify it with AI without ErgoScript.
You still have ErgoTree written on the
blockchain.
It's a pretty high-level description.
I think AI in particular can be quite
good about modifying it in certain ways
useful ways.
So yeah and then yeah so 6.0 what is
going on and yeah so for sub-blocks there
is well updated DevNet seed nodes and yeah
I'm continuing to fix stuff and optimizing
things like daily so probably around the
next week yeah there will be another seed
node update and yeah, we can start
thinking about injecting sub-blocks,
supporting mining nodes into public
testnet from...
That's very exciting, kushti. Yeah, late
July maybe, so summer July.
Awesome.
So what would that look like in a normal
block on Ergo?
How many transactions will be packed into
a normal block supporting sub-blocks?
So, well, after all, it will be the same
block being formed and written on the
disk, right?
Right, right.
It'll have the transactions or the hash
from the sub-block or something like that?
Yeah, so, well, current blocks would be
kind of like pruning mechanism, right?
So, well, few blocks after, so sub-blocks
would be just erased, right?
And you have just blocks for
bootstrapping new nodes, for example,
right?
So, and yeah, for efficient storage on
disk.
So yeah, so sub-blocks is just temporary
entity to be propagated our peer-to-peer
network, right, for quicker confirmation
and yeah, well, higher TPS as well.
But yeah, well, still we have like
blocks, full blocks we have now, so they
would be just kind of archival mechanism
right for your notes.
Okay so then yeah it's a kind of fractal
design right so you have sub-blocks, then
a few blocks after they've been pruned, so
you have only blocks.
But then you may prune the blocks with
the help of NIPoPoWs, right?
And it takes snapshots, so you can store
just less data with the same security
guarantees.
Right, so yeah, all those things
supported since 2023.
So, well, actually in the protocol
support is there since the mainnet launch
or even before.
But now we have also well-supporting
clients, a lot of printing nodes and so
on.
So yeah, that would allow to raise TPS
right for a minute.
So you can just assume for a bit more
pruning in the network and raise TPS
accordingly.
Well, there is no need to get into like
Casper setting, so store like three days
on the right, but that's also individual
choice.
So you can store a few days.
You can store the full history.
So yeah, well, we can just do things like
default settings.
Maybe at seven point, but yeah, well, a
lot of possibilities, right?
Prune without reducing security of the
network.
Yeah, well, there are cryptographically
strong securities, and actually, well,
very strong securities based on weakest
assumptions, not involving any MoonMath,
crypto, all that stuff.
So yeah, just certain things like hash
function properties.
So yeah, pretty much the same
cryptographic security assumptions as in
Bitcoin, but yeah, well, totally different
pruning capabilities in regards for secure
pruning.
A lot of options to explore.
There is a possibility to raise network
TPS significantly if needed.
But, yeah, so unlike different shared
coins selling TPS and having empty
network, so I think, well, the focus
should be on providing some useful
capabilities to users, right, because,
well, TPS can be raised.
There is foundation for it, but yeah,
it's not the goal to have theoretically
high TPS.
I like the Ergo developed tooling and
actually useful things first and now we're
exploring security implications.
Right, and then, yeah, so a friend of
mine just finished Git Circle spec, for
example, so it will be published, so,
yeah, well, developers, welcome to
contribute.
Also for Dexy, for example, testing is
doing well, so, yeah, the bank reserves
are growing quite nicely, so yeah, we may
think now about updating Oracle pool, the
SigmaUSD1 to version 2, and then, yeah,
deploy.
That's the best news I've heard all day,
kushti.
Every other week kushti sends me a DM,
check your Oracle please.
Like shit, I forgot to clean the dust.
The version to Oracle has some issues
with incentivization and so on.
But it's probably a good time to update
the design, which is proven to be more
robust already.
Do you think the Oracle set will expand
on the Oracle 2.0 for SigmaUSD?
Yeah, so we can have like 15 working
oracles like in gold, right?
So, yeah, well, and we can then launch
GleomUSD, DexyUSD, right?
Yeah, but that would be quite interesting
because yeah, it seems after all, there
will be some revived interests to
algorithmic stable coins and now crypto
backed, I believe, because here after
Terra and other non-backed stable coins
are a failure.
So it will be demand for crypto-backed
stable coins.
And then things like Glion, Dexy.
Very competitive, to say the least.
Great, great.
Speaking of 6.0, kushti, 6.1 has been
running flawlessly on the three
peer-to-peer explorers that I set up.
It's been fantastic.
It's nice and fast, very quick, very
nice.
Please also check testnet mining.
Is it down?
MGPy reported something.
Let's see, testnet is... Oh yeah, it's
been down for 15 hours, my bad.
Let me go kick it in my basement.
Yeah, but I believe we need more miners,
right?
You do, you do.
And you have one GPU, right?
I've got like a 2070 pointed at it for
now, yep, something small.
All right, so then maybe, yeah, so we
need to find more miners to test
sub-blocks, all that stuff, like a couple
more miners at least.
And then, yeah, maybe at some point we
can try side-chaining, right, to bring
TestNet ERG to mainnet to reward for
testnet mining.
The concept which not right saying other
networks, but why not?
Right.
Let's see.
I just rebooted my node.
That's how quick it is.
And we'll see if it's going to come back.
See if it starts producing blocks.
Yeah, so we need to do something with all
those things, right?
Yeah, kushti, I'd love to be able to
incentivize node running eventually
somehow.
I think that'd be great.
Maybe just even testnet node, just a
small incentivization to run that.
No, but it will be just testnet mining,
right?
Not running nodes.
Right, testnet mining.
Yeah, running nodes, so first we need to
define precisely, especially as in Ergo we
have a lot of modes of operation, right?
So you can run nodes with when you take a
snapshot, for example, you may store all
the full blocks.
So the first question is what to
incentivize here.
So is it about storing all the full
blocks or just some suffix?
Well, why?
So why to choose a particular option?
Incentivization options.
So yeah, it's not quite clear what can be
incentivization desiderator about when we
are talking about incentivizing nodes.
I haven't seen any clear answer yet to
the moment.
Some things are possible even without
touching the core protocol.
Once there was a scheme of running some
kind of proof-of-stake rewarding mechanism
on top of Ergo, an application as a
contract.
So without touching anything in the core
protocol and this way you can incentivize
people who are running the nodes and
having a wallet unlocked, right?
But maybe it's not the thing you are
willing to incentivize, right?
Because well, it's not that secure to
have unlocked wallet after all in many
cases.
Yeah, well, hard to say, so first we need
to define what to incentivize exactly.
Well, what else is new?
So, yeah, also started some writings and
some empty repositories for merge mined
sidechains.
So, yeah, well, as usually we are after
delivery of something like 6.0, which is
now, and they're winning.
So, well, we are working on sub-blocks,
right, but planning the next thing.
So, much more inside chains.
So, yeah, it's time to plan and maybe
start developments.
And yeah, this time it will be done in
Rust.
So, yeah, probably most of development
then should be done by other people
because I'm not even strong in Rust.
So then, yeah, it's about a lot of
questions, how to incentivize developers
and so on.
But yeah, I believe it should be there,
right?
Because a lot of ideas, well, what to
build from private side chains to like
very compliant ones.
To double merge mined sidechains, for
example, like Bitcoin and Ergo merge mined
at the same time to allow for more
trustless Bitcoin DeFi, right?
And then, yeah, to have... Sorry.
Then to have a partner chain of Cardano,
which is also merge mined chain of Ergo.
To have, well, in regards with privacy,
it can be like compliant privacy, like
Midnight-based merge mined sidechain.
So a lot of ideas, but anyway, we can
start working on merge mined sidechains
right now.
Okay, so what's up kushti, what's the
Braid thing that Joe posted about last
night?
Better Money Labs Braid.
So yeah, it's, well, exactly. Double
merge mined sidechain idea so still while
writing white paper so yeah we will be
published in coming days maybe but yeah
well in the first place discussing with
some partners so the idea you know is to
avoid like developing something which has
no interest right from outside, so to
unbubble with development efforts as well
now, right, so with double merge mined
sidechains.
So Braid is a double merge mined Bitcoin
plus Ergo sidechain, and yeah, we are
talking with some big Bitcoin mining pools
and so on, right, in regards to supporting
it.
Then, yeah, we can try for more options
like to have midnight powered and so on.
But yeah, there is also needs from the
users adoption side.
So yeah, well, considering different
options here, so stay tuned.
All right, cool, very cool.
Well, as far as the meetup going, just a
reminder that everything's posted on
Twitter.
I'll probably post again this week for
signups.
Joe got me in contact with the building
owner that we're renting out for the
event.
And she's going to actually help with
some of the planning and the setup.
So that's great.
We'll do some troubleshooting and not
troubleshooting, but some brainstorming
and get that all nice and welcoming for
everybody that's in attendance.
But otherwise, the order of events is
pretty much nailed out.
We have to do some sort of community vote
on what the hackathon is going to be
about.
And then the final result will be hidden
and revealed during that hackathon.
So that'll be fun to watch.
I gotta get my streaming equipment ready
and packed up so that I'm not missing
anything when we're streaming everything.
I think we'll bring everybody's screen
that's hacking into one interface so
people can watch people coding live.
So I think that'll be fun.
And then with drunk commentary by myself
and Joe.
Trying to understand what's going on that
could be even more fun.
So we'll see how that goes.
But looking forward to it.
Looking forward to being in Colorado in
October and seeing people face to face.
kushti, did you get a chance to, are you
going to go to the consulate after you
return from Dubai to see if you can get a
visa?
So it seems no chance because I don't
have a biometric passport.
It would take some time.
Can we at least zoom you in and have you
give us a hello during the conference,
during the meetup?
Yeah, so, yeah, and I can try to get a
biometric passport, but yeah, probably
that's, so with the traveling plans, can
do that not earlier than the meetup
itself, so like.
Right, right, right.
So then next year maybe, but yeah, let's
see, so.
Yeah, it seems that the US is one of very
few countries with such demand, actually.
Yeah, even to just... Right, we can't
even fly domestic anywhere without a real
ID, which requires quite a few different
proofs of citizenship and life and other
things.
So, that change just happened recently.
So, yeah.
Yeah, so let's see.
I mean, there is some option which I can
try in August.
But yeah, the chances are small, to be
honest.
Okay.
But yeah, we'll be happy to join remotely
anyway.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Maybe next year, yes, so we need to do
something with this biometric stuff.
All right, cool.
Cool beans.
And as far as P2P infra that I talked
about last week, we had about four or five
people sign up already that would like to
be sent a machine that's ready to go.
So that's on my task list for the next
month or so.
I'll build these machines up and then run
and sync.
I'll probably just clone some of the P2P
servers that I have set up already and
ship them out to the people that want to
run it.
And then we'll slowly add them to the
load balancer to make sure everything's
OK.
Once we have a secure network of known
machines spread across the globe, we'll
start bringing other people who just want
to run their own thing and be part of that
load balancer.
Depending on your internet bandwidth,
that's how we'll do the calculation of how
much load balance we'll send to you.
If you have 5% of the bandwidth as other
people running on the load balancer will
send you 5% of the traffic kind of thing
or maybe less depending on what that is.
So we'll all do that to make sure that
the nodes are spread and the load balancer
across the globe and that we're not
overburdening certain nodes from certain
people.
And then hopefully we can turn off or
turn down the Ergo Foundation's load
balancer with the rented servers on
Hetzner.
And then we could be a truly kind of
peer-to-peer decentralized node hosting
DAO for Ergo, which I think fits
perfectly, will be great.
So I think for July a lot of news, right?
So it's kind of hot, especially here.
So to be honest, yeah, well, I'm working
quite slowly these days because it's crazy
hot here.
So I can't do much with that.
It's like plus 41 Celsius, but it's in
the desert.
So I think in the city, it's like closer
to 50 probably Celsius.
But yeah, I'm trying here.
So published a forum post on some idea
for a sidechain yesterday.
Yeah, I can do more.
And yeah, over the weekend, some
weekends, hopefully we'll investigate
those private chains coming and already
spending some time actually on studying
Crescent chains with private contracts
such as Aleo, dark DeFi, Midnight, and
yeah, well, would be good to have private
contracts in a sidechain, right?
So, yeah, well, we'll write more coming
days.
So, also checking a bit VM stuff for this
double merge sidechain.
Yeah, it seems well, that's BitVM 3 which
was announced just like three weeks ago.
So it's already broken.
So just two days ago one guy had written
the chart with some critical analysis.
So yeah, it seems BitVM 3 is broken.
But yeah BitVM 2 is quite good still and
allowing for somewhat trustless transfer
but yes still still need to check but yeah
a lot of startups actually working on such
stuff already so we can just reuse the
work problem right so oh yeah well and for
sub-blocks i think to write something in
august maybe well feedback by Sasha will
be done by then.
He promised to provide some, so Sasha is
a developer from Casper, also quite active
in R&D.
Right, he joined the R&D anniversary AMA.
Yeah, that was quite amazing, right, when
people are just joining without asking for
permission or whatever, so yeah.
Alright, let's see.
We might have a few questions here we can
bang out, kushti.
Let's see.
Yeah, so let's have questions.
I'm sorry, it seems I have like seven
minutes or something like that.
You gotta leave in seven minutes?
Yeah, so I need to go to some meeting.
Yeah, I tried to figure out.
But yeah, like 10 minutes maybe, yeah.
Okay, all right, let's see.
I guess as Kent was asking about me, the
small app I was talking about for dogs, he
says, why do you need a record for your
dog's movements?
Ursa Minor answered him.
But in general, the way these simple apps
kind of work is that a user goes to a
website, puts some information like the
phone number, the dog's name, perhaps a
state or a town.
Maybe you don't want to put your actual
address on it.
That gets encrypted and put into a smart
contract that that person can then change
and update.
And a QR code is printed out with the
decryption hash or key of essentially the
password to decrypt the file, to decrypt
the text on chain.
And that is painted to a QR code that the
person then puts on the dog's collar or
the cat's collar.
And then if it's lost, it just says scan
me, you scan it, takes you to a website,
shows the information.
So the difficulty, what you pay for right
now in the outside world, is you pay for
the ability to update it, right?
Because you could put a little chain on
your dog and have it chisel out.
And if it doesn't wear off, that's fine.
But people enjoy having either the chip
in their collar or something else that
they can update and never have to change
it physically.
So that's essentially what you're doing
here.
You're saying, look, we can put this on
our pet, and if we move, we can update it
by spending the UTXO on the chain,
updating it.
The code stays the same for the data,
essentially, and that's all you have to do
kind of thing.
So that was kind of the idea for that.
But the main point of that story was that
there are so many things outside that you
can utilize the tooling and the structure
of Ergo for that will actually work better
than the outside world.
Not everybody wants to blow a hundred
bucks on that kind of service or not
everybody wants to spend money that they
could spend less of if using
infrastructure that's globally hosted and
peer-to-peer and things they could change
themselves.
So that was the main intent of that kind
of story, not necessarily relative to the
pet app itself, but in general, things
that can be created utilizing the
blockchain that are beneficial and cheaper
for people.
Let's see, Kento Crazy Fast says that, do
you need to run the node to mine the
testnet, or can you just point your rig at
your stratum server?
So the idea here, Kento, is that the more
nodes...
So I'm running a testnet node, right?
I think I'm the only... No, there's three
other people running testnet nodes, but
I'm the only one mining at the moment for
testnet.
So if people point to my testnet node, my
stratum to mine, and it goes down, then
testnet's down, right?
So there's no redundancy there.
Ideally, you'd want to run your own node
and you'd want to run your own stratum and
mine to it.
Then if my node goes down, your node
keeps producing blocks because you're
mining to your node.
That's the idea.
Granted, if you want to point to my
stratum, that's fine.
Then if my miner goes down, which is on a
different machine, then you're still
mining it.
So there is some redundancy in the miner
there, but it's not a full redundancy as
if I lose full interconnection, even
though my stratum, my node, and my miner
are on three different locations.
My stratum's in Hetzner, my node is at my
house, and my miner's mining testnet's
here next to me at work.
So there's some redundancy.
It's some safety there if you do want to
point to my stratum.
So yeah, I think I had MGPi pointing to
my stratum briefly or somebody else.
So yeah, you're welcome to do that if you
want to ping me, Kento.
Oh, here we go.
kushti, do you know the answer to this?
Evidently, 80k Bitcoin received from P2P
KH wallets with no activity since 2011.
How is that possible?
Do we know any more news about that or
how that may have happened?
I don't actually know what's surprising
in those transfers.
Back in the days, I know some people with
Bitcoin from 2010-2011 and having
thousands of Bitcoins were quite...
It's like having 10k, 20k ERG now, right?
It's just ordinary thing, you know, so
it's nothing surprising.
I know one guy from my city.
He got into Bitcoin in 2010 and then got
enthusiastic and started to reward.
So he started to promote Bitcoin around
some gaming forums, right?
Because they were GPU guys on the forums.
So he spreads mining software links
around forums, got banned for spreading
Trojan likely rights, because it was
totally crazy stuff back then, like some
internet money with some software able to
get the money.
So probably Trojan, so yeah, he got
banned immediately.
And then he started to buy some guys with
reputation on those forums, you know, and
paid like 100 Bitcoin to each guy, making
a post about Bitcoin.
That's like us now paying 60 ERG for a
mug.
Right so yeah so i mean that's that was
just quite ordinary so i don't know why
now journalists are writing all those
articles about you know some wallets
moving bitcoin not touched since 2010
because yeah i'm pretty sure there are a
lot of such words rights just ordinary
guys which just left Bitcoin in those
wallets and that's it.
And yeah, about ATK, so I don't know,
there are some theories, right, like Roger
Ware or not Roger Ware or whatever.
And yeah, so actually, all those talks
are quite motivating in regards with
having more privacy.
But yeah, the sad thing is privacy is
coming with less efficiency, much less
efficiency.
So, well, if we are talking about TPS, it
would be much less when we are going to
shielded amounts, for example, right?
So, well, even optionally shielded
amounts.
And I'm not saying about even more
privacy.
So yeah, it's a hard talk, but yeah, I
mean, it's better to have privacy rights
to avoid all those investigations.
Yeah, I'm reading the article right now
about using OP_RETURNs for Mt. Gox claims.
Interesting.
That doesn't seem like, maybe I'm looking
at something different than Ursa Minor is
asking about, but this looks more like a
social engineering masquerading attack.
I don't think, unless we're talking about
something different, Ursa, it doesn't seem
like an address hat from what I'm reading.
It seems like they are just claiming
legal ownership of it via that process.
Yeah, I'll read more up on that.
That's interesting.
Let's see.
What else?
You got one minute.
Do we have any more questions?
Oh, Congo says he's going to spin up a
testnet.
I know that's fantastic.
That's it, kushti.
You got time to go to your meeting now.
Enjoy your summer, right?
If you have summer in Southern
Hemisphere, it's winter, right?
Yeah, then what else?
So stay tuned, a lot of news coming.
Yeah, what else?
So, yeah, I think we may have some more
community chats, right?
Because we didn't have many around.
So yeah, I didn't want to organize
because I was tripping around.
So yeah, let's try.
And I have made more videos, for example,
on sub-blocks this month.
That'd be great.
We'd love to see videos on sub-blocks,
kushti.
That'd be great.
We could use those as clips on Twitter
and social platforms as well to build up
the hype and understanding of it.
All right, all right.
So yeah, you have to run.
All right.
Thanks, guys.
Thank you, everyone.
Enjoy your time.