I think the third consecutive Community
AMA, starting off with a few people today.
Hopefully we get more people to join in
throughout the hour.
We've got with us Joseph Armeanio, who is
enjoying his fake background at Rare Evil
Vegas.
Looks good there, Joe.
We've got kushti, who is coming live from
his kitchen, and we've got HQ.
Who knows where HQ is?
I don't know where HQ is.
Probably in a closet somewhere hiding
from his sleeping bride, I'm assuming.
How you doing, HQ?
How you doing, guys?
Yeah, my work space.
So yeah, a lot of traffic in August,
right?
Early August.
So yeah, it seems like most people are on
vacations.
But yeah, we are here.
We're active.
So yeah, HQ, how are you doing?
I thought I was living in all Ergonauts'
hearts.
But OK, I will just say that I live where
I live.
So yeah, good evening, everyone, and glad
to be here.
Great, good night.
HQ, I heard you just came out with
something new.
You woke up and you decided to write
another thing.
What did you do, like a simple DAO or
something it's called?
What did I do?
So that's the question.
So I just finished paper wallet
creations, paper wallet top-ups, and aid
drops, and vanity address.
And on the other side, I did some
on-chain voting into the Alephium side.
So yeah, I think I've done multiple stuff
in the last three, yesterday.
Oh, nice.
So your simple voting is fully on
Alephium.
Yep.
That's what they needed for that now.
Oh, cool.
Do they care about governance?
Well, I told them to use Paideia, but I
think it's not supported.
So no, I know.
It was a joke.
Okay.
Awesome.
Fantastic.
What else is up guys?
Before we dive into some topics that were
suggested, what else is new guys?
Who wants to go next?
What's new?
So a lot of things.
We published something on the forum and
we currently have super active discussions
in the ChainCash group about the different
stuff which I love like peer-to-peer
currencies, ChainCash based monetary
systems and so on.
Then preparing nodes 6.1 release and here
after that we can start testing sub-blocks
supporting mining nodes in the public
testnet, I guess.
So, yeah, well, things are going quite
well and 6.1 will be released later today,
maybe tomorrow.
Moin is willing to do some additional
tests.
So, yeah, let's see how it's going.
Then, yeah well for our sub-blocks some
good progress but yeah the writing is at
the beginning yeah going quite slowly but
yeah maybe the weekend next week there
will be a speed up here but yeah well in
recent days mostly polished.
The implementation did commence and so
on.
We will start to use LLM again to do more
tests and so on.
Yeah, a lot of things.
Yeah, also published some forum posts on,
well, better money labs and so on.
And we'll publish more different things
in coming days.
What's your need look like for helping
with sub-blocks testing?
Is it just going to roll out on the
current testnet when we update that?
Yeah, so ideally we need miners, right?
So we have currently a miner which is not
generating sub-blocks, right?
So it would be good to test a hybrid
setting where there are different miners,
right?
Because well, many deployment will look
like that.
So it's not mandatory protocol update,
right?
It's not a soft fork even.
No, it would be a soft fork at some point
because you need to...
You actually need to take a closer look
to activation details.
But yeah, for public testnet, we just
need for starters an additional miner.
So, well, we need to leave the current
miner intact, right, and add another one
with sub-blocks generation going on.
And then yeah, check inject maybe also
some clients and then test how things are
going.
Then, yeah, based on that starts planning
mainnet activation, but yeah, we also need
writing, right, and well, for some
security audit.
So currently write some things in the
codes, marking some places for like close
security audits needed.
Speaking of security audits, I heard that
you took a look over the SigmaLock
contracts.
How did those look, kushti?
Yeah, so I sent some notes to Luca.
But yeah, well, in general, it looks good
here.
Yeah, you guys can go ahead, I believe,
with that.
Fantastic.
Yeah, I think we're waiting on one of the
pieces in the front end or something like
that.
So we should hopefully... As I said last
week, we'll test on testnet, I think, for
now.
And then MGPi and I will move it over to
our own infrastructure, Sigmanauts, and
we'll open it up to the public.
So, excited about that.
That'll be fun.
All right, so what's the idea?
Did you post another kushti token on Mew?
Did you replenish that token or you
haven't posted it yet?
Not yet.
So yeah, I actually thought to check
some, well, Mew tutorial submissions today
and send out Mew I received.
And yeah, for the rest, I can just put
Mew along with ERG into a liquidity pool
probably.
But yeah, well, we will do more token
sales.
So yeah, it's actually quite, I think,
exciting to do more like community work
organized in such a form where you receive
something and then put it in the rewards
for other parties.
So yeah actually I think it could be a
good time to start some raffle also for
like two to three months maybe for another
ergo devs fundraising ergo devs now
because we always spending on something
like we now need to pay for Keystone
integration, right?
It's close.
Then, yeah, we paid for Sigma Rust 6.0
support and so on.
Yeah, so I don't know, maybe we can do
fundraising for sub-blocks, security
audit, or what else could be needed.
It's a merge-mined sidechains framework.
So hopefully, there will be some more
serious funding for that.
But yeah, we can start with a raffle.
Or just for sub-blocks, maybe.
It's already quite good, right?
Cool.
What were you asking?
You were asking what we're going to do
with SigmaLock?
Yeah, so from my observations, yeah, you
guys had like few different use cases in
mind, right?
Right.
The first most obvious one is a batching
of assets to somebody else based on a time
lock or a price, essentially.
So a simple contract that allows you to
pass your tokens on to a child or a spouse
or something like that, depending on a
time that has passed or else a price.
And the beautiful thing about these
contracts are that you know, because
somebody actually mentioned, I was talking
to somebody the other day who actually
sold life insurance in the past and
they're like, okay, what happens if the
person dies?
I was like, well, you know, they still
have to wait for the price to appreciate
to the strike mark or the time to evolve
to the past to the expiry there.
And I was like, but the contract is
flexible enough to where you could set up
for one year each time essentially.
So you could continuously update it and
feed it into another contract every year
for that as well.
And you could do it before.
So let's say I have tokens and I've given
them away already.
You wouldn't want to wait till after the
contract expires to do that because your
child could cash out your assets if that's
who you're giving them to.
So you essentially check the box that
says, I, as the creator of that have power
to change the contract at any time.
So once a year or once every 2 years,
whatever you think that span of time is,
you could just, you know, at day 363, you
could just push a new contract right out
for another year kind of thing.
So there is that option.
With that, which is neat, it gives you
that flexibility.
The other thought is, you know, the idea
was for vested tokens, essentially, if
you're working with a developer and they
want to know that they're definitely going
to get paid, but you don't want to give
them the tokens at the time.
Let's say I'm starting a widget project
and I have a widget token and I want to
pay the developer in widget tokens, but
you know, there's a liquidity pool in the
communities, you know, using it and the
project is kind of going and I don't want
the developer that I've hired to just dump
on it, right?
So I could essentially stage my payments
to that developer with tokens.
I could make a pocket of six months, give
him the unlock token.
I could make him a pocket of eight
months, give him the unlock token.
Make a pocket of a year and give him the
unlock token.
So then that developer could then sell
tokens throughout that time as the work is
done.
So there are those two options right up
the back that I think you can use for.
And then, of course, the diamond hand
option where you just put it in to hold
for yourself to protect you against
yourself, so you don't spend it yourself.
Either way, or send your token to cold
wallet.
Alright.
So a couple options.
Yeah, that's interesting.
So you can then use those tokens for
funding projects, right?
So they can get vesting basically.
Kind of like a ChainCash note almost, but
on chain, right?
A promissory note, I guess, or a
redemption note.
But it's more like vesting, right?
It could be based on time, but also on
price, right?
So it's kind of like an option.
No, not really.
And then, yeah, it's quite interesting,
right?
So it could be used.
So you can use vesting along with
price-based conditions, right?
To lock tokens, project tokens, for
example.
But yeah, I mean, it's probably... needed
to cover all those use cases with a few
articles, right?
Because it's quite vast functionality, I
believe.
Great, great.
What else is new?
Oh, so last night, nice and tired, I
pushed the Paideia DAO.
The vote passed last week, and I was
given 50,000 Paideia in my wallet so that
I could build the InfraDAO.
So I built the InfraDAO.
I have tokens.
I minted 1,000 tokens a month ago or so.
So those people who are interested in
initially joining the InfraDAO, please
reach out to me again, or I'll reach out
to you.
I have my notes somewhere with four or
five people listed that would like to
join.
So reach out again and we'll start that
DAO up.
Once we have a handful of people in
there, we'll dump the rest of the tokens
into the DAO.
On top of that, I also uploaded and made
a repository on GitHub for the Explorer
versions that I'm using currently.
It's Dockerized.
It's based off this, I can't remember who
originally built it, but it's based off
essentially that with some tweaks.
And that's what we're running here, so
there's a full list of instructions on
what you need, how to set up the, what to
set up beforehand, you need NGINX, you
need the full sync node, you need Git, and
then how to set it up and run it.
If you're going to be part of the
InfraDAO, there's actually nothing you
need to change.
You simply just clone the repository,
download it, and run it, and then you join
the DAO and you get the SSL certs from
Cloudflare from us and you insert those
into your system.
And at that point, we point the load
balances to you, do some testing and make
sure everything works.
And then you're part of the load balance
for that.
So, that's how we're starting off small
with the Explorer infrastructure.
And we're going to move to hosting
things, hopefully, like ErgoExplorer, like
SigmaSpace, like ErgoDocs, eventually the
Ergo Platform website, as well as
SigmaSpace and Sigmaverse, all those kind
of things.
And then beyond that, most likely we'll
move to something like anybody who touches
Ergo from a maintenance side, right?
Updating side can also be part of the DAO
and work on that kind of stuff.
So, yeah, starting off small slowly
building.
We don't want anything to crash.
So being conservative in our steps.
All right, all right.
Who'd we lose?
We lost Joe.
Joe must have gotten a calling over at
Vegas.
And yeah, at the time when I wanted to
ask about Rosen updates.
He can sense it coming.
Yeah, they made some more catalyst
proposals in particular about base.
And yeah, there was a tweet from base
recently that they will allow any assets
on base to be tradable on the centralized
exchange Coinbase.
That's we can actually get on Coinbase,
right?
So any assets tradable?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like any of 8 million assets they have on
base would be tradable on Coinbase.
So we need to get a wrap token over there
kind of thing, or is it ERG on another
chain?
Rosen ERG, yeah, and well, there is also
a need to find liquidity, right?
Some liquidity providers, but then, yeah,
it would be quite good for liquidity
providers.
So that means that's for trading, kushti.
So that means we would still enter
through another token on Coinbase and then
directly swap on Coinbase and hold Rosen
ERG on Coinbase.
Yeah, but that's not different, for
example, from listing Cardano assets on
Kraken, right?
No, right, correct, yeah.
So it's basically the same, model
liquidity, right?
So well, for base, they will be needed to
find liquidity, but for liquidity
providers, it should be quite attractive,
I believe, right?
Because probably as an onramp option and
offramp also.
Yeah, it could be quite popular.
So then, yeah, I mean, in a few months,
we can get another option for the US for
onramp and offramp, right, and to trade.
So yeah, that would be great.
Nautilus has been pushed to production.
So if you guys opened up Nautilus in the
last day or so, I'm not sure when it
happened.
You will notice that it has been updated
and there is a buy ERG button in it now
and the production version.
So yeah, you click on it and it takes you
right to Banxa.
I don't know.
How do you say that?
Banxa where you can buy ERGs directly
with fiat in the USA.
It's almost like a Bankster, right?
So that's great.
That's the first step in integration, I'd
say.
Maybe at some point in the future, we'll
see it fully baked into Nautilus wallet to
make it even easier.
And we all know that yeah, that seems to
be the thing of choice, right?
People don't like leaving their walled
gardens in those instances.
So yeah, super excited to see that.
I am yet to test out that on-ramp.
Has anybody here tested out Banxa?
Cool.
It's blocked in the UK, unfortunately.
I think it's blocked for you as well.
I think it's blocked in New York.
It's one of the states that's not
supported.
Oh, that's right.
I can't test it.
I should be able to test it from South
America, my account in South America.
So we'll see.
I can try that.
Good point.
New York.
Damn it.
It's New York and California, is it?
What are the two states?
It's like two states.
Yes, a couple.
It's a couple of weird ones like Alabama
or something in New York.
Yeah, I need to go look again, but yeah,
it's a few weird ones.
Maybe Illinois?
Illinois, okay.
Okay, interesting.
And yeah, some questions.
So yeah, I think it's KYC.
Yeah, it's KYC.
But can we get non-KYC options for the
US?
Probably not at all, right?
I mean, these days it's not quite
possible.
Yeah, not legit ones.
So and then yeah there is also question
when a new exchange so yeah I don't know
I've received a few listing offers which
are free, but you have to pay for
marketing campaign.
There are some MM requirements, but not
strict.
Yeah, the question are those options
needed, right?
Considering that they're not really free
and marketing campaigns probably won't
work.
kushti, maybe we should just ask the
Cardano treasury for listing fees to pay
those.
Yeah, that's actually quite fine.
But for this SNEK, right?
Yeah, I couldn't believe that.
It's fine.
Drama.
It's just funny to see that argument
online.
It's funny that people are masquerading
the potential to pump something by listing
it with the idea that it's going to be
better for the economy.
I don't know.
It's funny arguments, seeing these crazy
hollow arguments that are very transparent
to use community treasury money to list an
individual project.
Absolutely nuts.
Right.
But yeah, I mean, so for Cardano
community, I believe it would be better to
support base proposal from Rosen, right,
and then yet trade SNEK on base, right, a
Coinbase centralized exchange, as well as
other Cardano assets than Ergo, then what
else?
Handshake probably, right?
And other blockchains which are joining
Rosen.
The beauty about Rosen on base is that
you're essentially rug-proof, right?
Once Rosen is on base or once Rosen can
connect certain chains that are on base,
if something's rugged or pulled from base,
then just make another pair somewhere with
some other token that's already on base
that Rosen can reach, right?
So there's a level of protection you get
when you're using Rosen and ability to
traverse to another backdoor if one door
is shut on you.
Unlike when exchanges write you and say,
oh, I'm sorry, your fake washing and fake
volume is not up par with what we need you
to stay listed on this exchange.
That million dollars you paid us for your
marketing fee?
No, that's gone.
You're off.
Spicy today, kushti, sorry.
That's insane, but we need more
centralized exchanges maybe, but the
question is which ones, right?
So those exchanges which can list for
some marketing campaign amounts, let's
say, just they're like CoinDCX, which I
can give a pair with the Indian Rupiah
then, what else?
So there are some other exchanges, like a
few ones.
But yeah, the question is, will they
provide any value?
It's not clear.
And from exchanges which can provide
value, I think it would be good to get
maybe on some regional exchanges, right?
Well, what happened?
Is TradeOgre still down?
Has that gone for good?
Did you hear any news on that?
Any additional news?
I don't know so there are no any news and
yeah I mean people are saying that back in
2023 they went offline for 12 days in a
row but yeah I mean this time probably
people are nervous after ZGex right well
there are expectations of a new incident
let's say but yeah it's not quite clear
what's going on because yeah it's it's
fully anonymous exchange there are a lot
of questions but no one knows what's going
on there
Yeah, but let's hope it will be up soon.
What was that, Mark?
You're going to say something?
I was just saying it's still there and I
just checked.
Yeah, I'm looking at connection time down
for Cloudflare.
I think I've got 50 cents still there
from when I was trading USDT and ERG with.
I think it was a bot that... Can't
remember who made it.
Somebody in the Ergo mining made a nice
little trade bot that works with TradeOgre
that did pretty well, honestly.
It was just keeping the spread.
It was just trying to keep a spread there
between the two.
So yeah.
Mb says, from Kuwait, new, how can we
help?
Welcome and be new.
Fantastic.
There's a lot of things you can do here
in the ecosystem.
There's several DAOs to join.
There's a Sigmanauts, which is a
community DAO, which essentially tries to
oversee and help and bolster anything
that's related to Ergo from a community
standpoint.
They've branched off and created the Ergo
SIG mining DAO, which is based on a mining
pool, one of the first to collect storage
rent.
So there's that to join if you have a GPU
and you want to point that, even if you
don't want to mine, it's a fun group to
join.
We just launched, as I said, the Ergo
InfraDAO, which is working on hosting
infrastructure based on the community
input, as opposed to essentially funded
model.
This would be a more of a community
funded model to host all the Ergo
infrastructure.
But yeah, hop in there, roll up your
sleeves.
If you do any program, the core devs have
a lot of, the EF has a lot of bounties out
there that are ripe for the picking that
you can make some money off of and Other
than that the easiest way to help out Ergo
is to spread the word whether it be in
telegram Facebook Instagram Twitter or
x.com Or anything like that.
That's the easiest way to way to give it
a go and of course if you have any
questions about how it works or why Ergo
or anything like that and hop in chat and
somebody will be bound to correct you or
encourage you or give you the details on
why they think Ergo is important in this
place, this time, moment in time.
Yeah.
Yeah, and actually we have some new
generation coming, right?
So recently a lot of new faces in the
chats, actually, as well as our Twitter.
So probably there is need to repost
tutorials from 2021, 2022.
on how to use applications, what
applications are available, along with new
tutorials for Mew and so on.
So how to trade, what are security
assumptions, how it goes different in
regards with open source, know your
assumptions, minimizing trust, enabling
peer-to-peer interactions and so on.
Did you get any of your submissions?
At least one, but yeah, I need to check
the chat because I've been busy with other
matters in recent days.
But yeah, there is at least one
submission from Michael, so yeah, we'll
check.
Yeah, pay out reward.
Later today, hopefully.
Still a lot of things, other things, but
yeah, hope to find time for that.
Then, yeah, well, We, I believe, made a
ton of materials, right, over the last few
years.
Historically, we have so much.
It's insane how much materials we have,
kushti, absolutely crazy.
Yeah, most of them are still relevant, so
here we can just repost them for
newcomers.
I mean, you know, it could be a big
mistake to consider, you know, Ergo
community as something static, right?
Like people who came when even, right?
I mean, most of people high C rounds came
in 21, right?
22.
But yeah, well, most of my conversations,
you know, happened around 2019-20, right?
Because, yeah, after that, it got quite
hard to communicate with so many people,
to be honest.
So, yeah, well, there is need to limit
communications channels.
Mostly.
But yeah, well, it's not static, right?
It's not formed in 21, right?
Well, in static scene, so.
Yeah, well, people are always coming and
some going, right?
But yeah, most of people around, well,
periodically appearing.
But yeah, new face always appearing, and
there is need to basically remind, right,
about what Ergo is, what tooling
available, what are basic principles.
manifestos and so on, so on, so on.
Yeah, we actually need to prepare for
like new big wave of Ergonauts.
I think it's time, right?
Because, well, it's 2025 and yeah, well,
there is a new wave of interest, I
believe, in proof-of-work assets, right?
It's, well, uncontrollable major assets.
Well, even legally, right?
So in the US, there could be recognition
in the form of the Clarity Act.
Maybe, you know, more.
Yeah, well, it seems it's the time,
right, for major uncontrolled performance.
Oh, a big notice here, kushti.
Spectrum's winding down.
Ah, okay.
Yep, it looks like this.
So for those of you that are new here,
Spectrum started out as ErgoDEX back in
the day.
And then they moved to Spectrum Network,
they're branded and they pushed to Cardano
mainly, so they're very focused on
Cardano.
They still ran ErgoDEX for Ergo side, but
they've been off Ergo for quite a while,
I'd say.
But it's about Spectrum Network.
Yeah, so I think ErgoDEX will remain,
right?
But yeah, I mean, it's not being
developed.
Yeah, it hasn't been.
Mew uses the ErgoDEX front-end
modification, or Crooks did, I think.
I don't know if Mew uses specifically
that, but yeah, right?
Mew uses it, HQ.
Yeah, I think we are, we're using the
front-end modified version, but we need to
check with the team about the backend, so
if it's going to run, it's still good,
because last time we tried to run it, it
told us that it was, like, thick to run
it.
So I guess if they're going down, we
would just set everything with them and
get the backup.
The backend also, so far the backend is
working, so yeah.
Do you run your own batcher bots because
you have Mew HQ?
Yeah.
We have custom bots, which we have.
Other community members were also running
those, so there's no issue with those
bots.
Very cool.
But ErgoDEX, it seems untouched, right?
So it's about Spectrum Network, which has
a white paper, basically.
Who hosts?
Yasha doesn't host.
I mean, Ilya doesn't host ErgoDEX as well
on their infrastructure?
Sorry.
I thought that, posted ErgoDEX on their
infrastructure along with spectrum.
No, isn't that their infrastructure?
Yeah.
So it's, they front end, yeah, they're
hosting, but they're profiting from it,
right?
It's they're getting, that's true.
That is true.
Yeah.
But contracts on chain and contracts,
it's the same, basically, decentralized
exchange with different frontends, right?
So Mew and ErgoDEX.
But ErgoDEX seems to be intact and
Spectrum Network is a white paper they
published back in 21, right?
And yeah, well, not sure about
implementation.
So initially, they they stated that there
are some issues in Plutus, right, and they
awaited for Plutus version 3.
But then, yeah, well, probably the whole
concept of layer 2, right, as mentioned in
the white paper, became irrelevant.
So we have some layer 2s coming, right,
but of a different kind.
Well, I think the good part about this is
they are paying back people if they're
still holding SPF, right?
Because if you go down in the series
refreshment method, so people just need to
have their SPF in their wallets and they
will be paid back.
Once we return the provider to all the
SPF folders, it's on chain reserves.
All right, yeah.
But yeah, well, those SPF tokens intended
to be utility tokens of the network,
right?
Spectrum network.
But yeah, well, this network has white
paper.
I haven't seen any.
Oh, they had some vault contracts,
actually.
Would be quite useful to reuse them
maybe.
So it's it's left unnoticed, but yeah,
vault contract is actually quite cool.
So it has just single public key, I
believe, on chain, right?
So just like ordinary address.
the Ergo blockchain but actually
off-chain it's controlled by up to 1024
signers right and that they made some
prototype some demo of signing so yeah
could be reused I believe for some large
scale DAOs and so on right so in spectrum
network there was idea to have validators
controlled
Spectrum network validators control
vaults.
But, yeah, it's open source, so, yeah,
well, it can be reused in other contexts.
And, yeah, so for layer 2s, well, what we
have is kind of specific layer 2s, right?
Like, Lithos coming and in the ChainCash
group, we are discussing like multiple
trackers based off-chain cache, like bit
torrent trackers kind of model, but for
tracking state of ChainCash systems.
Any news on Silver Dexy?
But we don't have Joe.
He's coming back.
His phone, his battery died.
He's coming right now.
Look at this.
All right.
So Joe, you've got a question, Joe.
What did I miss?
You missed Silver, so the question is
when Silver Dexy?
That's a good question.
We do have the Oracle put together.
I would say Dexy's been out for a bit, so
we should have some information in terms
of how it's operating.
So all the pieces are there to put it
together anyway.
I don't think we've had a firm date
towards launching it.
It's been interesting.
I know that Gluon was working on trying
to fully verify their protocol.
And then we have Dexy in parallel.
So that's a big choice that the Rosen
community can make, which protocol to plug
in that oracle to.
Joe, you sharing a booth, Joe, with Zen
Gate this year?
Or are you by your own booth?
Or are you just going to float with the
t-shirts and just cannon them into people?
No, no.
I'm going to be around Zen Gate.
Very nice.
Is CKB joining you guys as well this
year?
Yeah, I was actually talking with Jordan
yesterday.
about what they're working on over there
and, you know, potential collaborations.
Watch out for Jordan and Dan.
They have sticky fingers when it comes to
t-shirts and merch, Joe.
Oh, yeah.
I'll be ready.
What were you saying?
Sorry.
Oh, no, I spent some time with them
yesterday.
I had lunch, was talking about what
they're doing, working on in their
ecosystem, what we're working on,
potential for collaboration.
Are you guys thinking of bridging to CKB
in the future?
Yeah, I would love to.
It fits a lot of the parameters that I
find attractive with Rosen, where it's
proof of work chain, oftentimes
underappreciated, and I would say
undervalued relative to, I don't know,
sometimes a crypto space can be weird.
People will look you straight in the eye
and sell you a cartoon.
What can you do?
Yep.
Yep, what's new on the EF side, Mark?
Any updates?
Yeah, we've got Allison's working with
Banxa to create a notification service, so
that will be a week or two, he said.
After that, we can get Banxa Withdrawals
live.
And finally, we've fully finished Horn
Loft Ramp.
So that'll be good.
I've just been working on lots of
articles, so I've got my 10 articles in
the go.
I'm just trying to flood them over the
next few weeks.
I'm also going to update the roadmap on
the docs, because that's been updated to
2024.
So I need to update that, and it will be
in the pitch deck as well, because there's
a bunch of post-launch investors.
So I figure it's worth it, I'll just spam
in the pitch tech out there, out to them,
try and get some more eyes on Ergo.
Because it's an easy investment, easy
win, if somebody's got the other side, the
marketing organization, if they want to
come in and just build that on top.
So keep blasting them out and try and get
some baits.
And then just doing a lot of things,
updating docs and stuff.
I've created a partnership guide page for
all these kind of requests we get.
It takes ages to kind of evaluate if
they're legit or not.
So I'm just trying to account for all the
things and put them to that page so we
don't miss anybody.
We always get loads of weird Twitter DMs
and emails and stuff.
We've got Baby Doge trying to buy Ergo.
They offered to buy Ergo.
and so it's not them but just anything
that comes in we're just having a
boilerplate and so don't miss anybody and
yeah so just do me things that last week
yeah Mark I'll sell them the GitHub links
for a few million dollars if they want
it's a good deal oh boy nice what else
guys
Anything else?
We had some topics, but as usual, we
don't stick to any topics whatsoever, but
it's at least good to have them there to
start.
I have a question.
Hit it Grayman.
And that's for like any other devs that's
been here recently or for a while is how
do you guys stay sane seeing the entire
space try to like pivot towards layer one
ZK?
In this been here, like from the
beginning, like, how does everybody stay
sane?
Cause I'm seeing it like quietly be
advertised in a lot of spaces.
And it's like, I feel like it's going to
take a lot of years and it's been here
since 2019, I guess.
And it's like, nobody talks about it.
I think the best way to stay sane is just
not pay attention to be honest.
Yeah, I mean, it's a bit hard to stay
sane in this space at all.
But yeah, it's better to just stay in
some circle, right, which is not as insane
as the whole space.
That's how.
I mean, there's worse ways they could be
pivoting.
At least it seems to be going a bit back
towards our favor.
Sure.
And not just pure nonsense and meme coins
and logs.
And so I kind of see it as an expected
pathway space would take.
So I'm just glad it's happened.
I try to think of it like a swimmer,
right?
When a professional swimmer is swimming,
they're not picking their head up every
second to look at the wall or anything
like that.
They kind of know where they are.
and they know their goal is every time
they pick up the head and breathe and then
put their head back down and swim.
I think of it that way.
globally with the stuff that I keep
myself busy with, at least locally here
with what we're trying to do here with
Ergo and with the blockchain and with
integrating it into everyday things.
So I look at that goal and think that
goal is going to serve a wider purpose.
So let me focus on that and push that
through and make sure that works smoothly
here and show examples and show real live
working things.
So that's essentially putting your head
down, taking a big breath and pushing
through and then picking your head up
again, looking around, being like, why is
the audience smoking crack and humping
dogs?
I'm going to put my head down and work
some more kind of thing.
So that's how I get through it, at least.
But it is frustrating to look at these
things and be like, what the hell is going
on?
Because they advertise it like it's new,
like they just found some new thing.
And it's like, what?
Yeah.
I like the swimming analogy, though.
Yeah, I would just say, try to find
entertainment in the madness and focus on
building neat things that we find
interesting, right?
So it's like, once you have your own
vision of what you want to do, just follow
that and let the noise be the noise.
I mean, most of the people that I talk
to, at least I'm like x.com or see people
posting.
90% of those people, it's a speculative
tool, right?
So it's really hard to have serious
conversations with those people.
But once you get into communities like
Ergo where people are focused on building
and making a difference and actually
making tools that will outlast them and
not just, you know, buff their wallet so
they can exit and pay for their house or
their car or their truck or that kind of
thing, which I get, but, you know, to me
there's more to it than that, that's for
sure.
Yeah, and I think actually there is a big
request from developers to build in such
an environment.
I think there is a need to do another
marketing campaign for developers like we
did back in 2020.
This time probably it should be more
ideological.
Well, there are a lot of developers
willing to change the status quo with
their work, right?
But the crypto industry is not allowing
for that these days.
There are just very few harbors, right?
Rebel developers can unite and develop
like Ergo.
So yeah, it would be good to make another
marketing campaign like that.
Oh, Grayman's got a question.
Hit it, Grayman.
Welcome.
Thanks.
Yeah, I just finished my smoking some
crack.
So my question is a little bit out of
left field.
It's about what's happening to Monero
right now in their battle with, what is
it, Qubit or this come from behind dudes
network.
And my question is, are they going to
move on from, you know, one proof of work
chain to the next, trying to take over
their mining or is that even possible with
a GPU based proof of work chain, much less
an ASIC-mined one.
Is Monero just an especially soft target
because it's CPU-mined, is my question.
It's hard to say.
It's hard to say how successful this
CFB's attack with Monero is.
They claimed they were going to do a 51%
attack, but they haven't succeeded.
to say maybe even the sponsor so that
they're sponsoring miners definitely with
their tokens but maybe it wasn't
profitable for them right maybe they
donated basically some tokens after all in
the exchange for marketing because now
well it's quite buzzing this.
I don't know.
Yeah, it's crazy.
What they're doing is they're having
their miners theoretically are supposed to
be contributing to some proof of useful
work AI thing.
But actually, they're just mining Monero,
which they get compensated in Qubit or
whatever.
And then they send the Monero to a chain,
change it for USDT.
and buy Qubit with it, and then they burn
that.
So it's just a straight up insanity, if
you ask me.
But that is their business model.
And evidently, they had a huge chunk of
the Monero hash rate.
So I just thought it was that just
because it's CPU-mined, and therefore,
everybody can have it.
Would this even be possible if it were
Ergo, and they had to get people to
contribute with their GPUs?
It just seems like maybe the weakness of
Monero.
I don't know.
Probably economically it's disaster,
right?
I mean, probably they're paying more
tokens than they're burning, right?
Basically, so it's just, so they just
basically paying for the attack, right?
Like you can just rent GPUs, CPUs, and
you can rent a botnet probably, right?
And attack Monero blockchain.
and probably it would be even more
efficient but here you also have a lot of
marketing coming from Monero community and
not only rights as we are discussing it
right now so yeah well I don't know so I
think it's mostly about marketing, right?
So economically, probably this attack is
complete disaster.
But yeah, I mean, but that's typical
CFB's show.
I'm trying to have patience, but I have
to think this is going to end in disaster,
like you say.
And it's pretty amusing.
Yeah, but after all, it would be
disastrous for this Qubit, right?
So if... So the only hope is that supply
would be increased, not supply, sorry,
demand would be increased, right?
Because they're increasing supply
probably by inefficiency of this attack,
right?
But then they need to increase demand.
They are trying to do that via this
marketing, right?
But if CFB is failing with that then yeah
i mean it's it's it's a bit disastrous
probably but also yeah i mean for for for
the whole Qubit and its reputation right
if it's proof of useful work for AI but
instead used as kind of botnet
It's in the long term probably not so
good play even.
Yeah, it's just trying to create some
kind of flywheel effect and make a lot of
noise.
You know, it's strange or it's like,
okay, let's say that in theory they did
succeed.
And taking over Monero, right?
They may just destroy the value that's
underpinning their flywheel, and it would
be worse than when they started.
Well, they dumped the Monero.
They dumped the XMR as soon as they can
to get Qubit.
So it theoretically would drive that
price down.
But I think the price has been pretty
static for the last few months they've
been doing this.
So, I guess the answer to my question is,
regardless of whether GPU would make it
easier or harder, we probably shouldn't
regard this as a threat because it's just
so stupid.
I find it entertaining.
It's one of those things.
It's kind of strange.
I don't know what it has to do with the
AI or what the usefulness is of the AI.
Does anybody?
Maybe AI came up with a marketing plan,
Joe.
Probably it would be more efficient to
rent a nice hash just, or rent some big
farm, something like that.
But yeah, for efficiency of this emulated
mining so you know it's it seems so if I
understand right so that they have some
computational task embedded into proof of
useful work then you're basically losing
efficiency right for for this emulation
basically but
I mean, in comparison with just running
Monero mining function or Ergo mining
function on hardware, right, on physical
GPU.
So here you have this level of
abstraction, so this Qubit proof of work,
proof of useful work function.
So yeah, you're inevitably losing a lot
of efficiency in mining.
would be better to just rent hardware,
right, bare metal and deploy miners there.
So I don't know.
So probably just crazy CFB style story.
Artificial stupidity.
Right.
Well, it's five minutes past the hour
almost another successful community AMA.
Thanks for joining everybody.
I think Andy's back next week.
So perhaps we'll take a change and go
back to the original format.