And I'm CannonQ.
We worked on a project with qx() who's
busy on a lake somewhere.
In Georgia.
Yeah.
So yeah, so this is CodeUTXO. We're
revolutionizing blockchain development
with AI, making Ergo development
accessible to everyone through AI power
tools and natural language interfaces.
And so basically we wanted to package
something that would address all of this.
Because, from my experience within Ergo,
there's definitely a steep learning curve.
And so you maybe think you know the ins
and outs, but then when actually
developing and how to actually do
something on chain or using the data from
the chain, it's more of a user issue.
And so we wanted to alleviate that.
There's a bunch of different documentation
from here to there. Most of it really
good, but again, there's just a lot of
data and, trying to eliminate... I don't
know, what do you think, CannonQ?
Well, yeah, I mean, end of the day, we
were trying to find a way to basically
compile a lot of what's out there but make
it to where you can ask questions of AI. I
mean, Marc's been big on trying to
spearhead different AI things in the Ergo
community and this Ergo hack was a nice
fit for this project we'd been talking
about.
And so, yeah, it's making the chain
accessible, making it accessible for
programmers based on other GitHub repos
and things like that where you can query
those or try to get examples from those,
get examples from the chain or get
information from the chain. So yeah, it's
trying to make it all accessible.
Yeah, and then I think there are the
documents, right, but there's just a lot,
it would just be easier if we could just
have AI talk to it. And then specifically
with developing, you have to have the
right context to do a lot of different
things.
And so hopefully with this tool, we're
providing the right context, creating
tools that allow you to just grab things
and move on from there.
So moving into that, our solution, we
have an AI chat interface. The platform
itself will have a native payment system.
So you can pay with ERG, pay with native
tokens. And then the two tools that we've
developed is what's called the Ergo MCP or
the blockchain query MCP, and then the
price data MCP.
And so the blockchain query basically
allows and utilizes the Ergo node through
a natural language interface. You don't
really have to understand what the APIs
are, what they do. Really what you need to
do is tailor your prompt and then ask that
question if, of course, the tool is
available.
And I mean that in the sense of just like
if we have that tool. So for example, if
you were gonna hammer a piece of wood
together, you need a nail. And so we just
make sure, if there isn't a tool,
definitely reach out. We'd probably most
likely be happy to create that.
Price data MCP, very similar. Grabs that
price data from Crux Finance. And we're
looking at other ways to be able to grab
live price data from DEXs.
So if you wanna cover the technical
architecture.
Yeah, I'm the right guy to cover this. So
actually, it's sort of funny. I hacked
this together. Marc had sent me sort of a
how-to guide, and so I put this up on a
server currently. qx() has this now, like
we're self-hosting this.
But basically, OpenWebUI, it looks and
feels like if you're on Anthropic or Grok
or ChatGPT, ask it questions, it gives you
responses or it goes through the
responses.
LiteLLM, basically it's a great tool set
for managing AI models or LLMs. So
currently for the Ergo hack we really
truncated everything and just put it into
small buckets. We're using GPT 4.0 but in
the coming weeks to month there will be
access to various levels of LLMs from
something simple like Gemini 2 or Claude
3.7, all the way up to Claude Opus, like
the latest one.
So it allows us to route the API,
everything else, back to those LLMs and
then bring the data back to you.
The MCP servers that Marc has created,
they sit there, you ask the question of
the, right now, ChatGPT 4, you ask the
question. It then goes, okay, what do I
need to do, right? And so it passes that
info to the MCP server.
It actually is doing the queries of the
Ergo node or doing the research from the
Ergo docs we've already provided it, sends
it back to you.
And so, what's nice about the way this is
all set up is you can do standard queries
LLM like hey help me with some code do
some other things like just to build a
project or to sharpen your own tool set
and then you can plug in on the Ergo side
and these MCPs Marc's more adept at
explaining this but what I like is they're
almost like little silos of data that we
can create.
So what he showed earlier is we have the
one that talks to the node or to the node
APIs, and then we also have a separate one
that's working on pricing, but there's
other things. So we can work with other
sets of data that we want them to
basically connect with or help coders on,
developers on their code and connecting to
the API sources themselves.
Yeah, absolutely. And the cool thing
about MCP servers is really, you can make
a tool for anything that you want. So I
saw somebody made a code repo for
validating smart contracts.
So what's to say someone creates an MCP
or I can create one, put that into our
service here or even download it and put
it into cursor or something like that. All
you have to do is paste in or point to
your smart contract. Then it runs that in
the back end and says, hey, it doesn't
work or hey, it does work.
So really what we're working on doing
with the MCP service is really
streamlining the whole process in some
sense with the context of Ergo.
Right. And then so the Ergo payments,
that's the last thing on this slide, but
it's connect to Nautilus, make the payment
so you're buying the credits or the tokens
to be able to feed the LLM or your
interaction with the servers.
Sweet, so yeah, so our MCP or model
context protocols, again, we already
touched this, but directly connects to
your node, natural language queries, so
for example, give me the top 10 holders of
this specific token ID, and then it
returns a formatted token holder address
and balance.
So price MCPs, real-time price feeds,
native token tracking, historical data, so
right, what's the price of ERG from the
last 10 days?
And then again, talking about why we're
doing this, so we're really empowering the
community, the ecosystem. So traders, this
might be a good thing to take a look at.
We could have further MCPs that are more
trading focused, where you're looking at
specific metrics tied to some sort of
historical perspective.
Developers, so now it's probably, even
with AI in and of itself, without our
tools, it's a lot easier to stand up
something, but now inject our tools into
that. It's definitely a lot easier to
interact and build stuff on top of Ergo.
And then for newcomers, like we wrote
here, a gentle introduction to blockchain
concepts. You can really explain it, say,
hey, how did we come to this conclusion?
And then our knowledge base is curated
from the community. So all the various
Ergo docs, code bases, smart contracts,
etc., it's all loaded up into that for
your usage.
And so here's sort of an example of what,
right? So what's the current block height?
And then it's like 1.1 million, two,
three, four, five, six. And then again,
show me the price of our trends in the
last three days. Here we go. But of
course, we'll actually give you guys a
live demo.
Yeah, CannonQ, you wanna cover this one?
Yeah, sure. So the tooling, we've stood
this stuff up, put it together during the
Ergo hack. The payments, so there's no way
to give this stuff away for free, right?
Someone has to pay for the models, someone
has to pay for the servers, all these
kinds of things.
So what we've tried to do is, I always
wanted to get like a subscription
Anthropic, but I'm cheap, right? Because I
didn't want to pay 20 bucks a month.
The way we've set this up, what it allows
us to do is basically you can buy credits
as little as like basically one ERG or two
ERG worth of credits. You can see what
your usage is after you do the question on
the query like literally real-time you'll
see it ticking down also when you're doing
the query after it's responded to you you
can see how many tokens to use, what was
the volume usage there so again right now
we just have 4o that we're presenting to
you guys but you'd be able to use
something less expensive to start and then
if you're really digging in go to a Claude
Opus or something more expensive, Gemini
2.5, something like that.
But the cool thing about it is basically
your credits don't die. So it's fair, it's
transparent, and you don't have to pay out
like a monthly subscription. You can buy
what you need, which I think for people
that are new to the ecosystem or casual
users, I think it's cool.
You can say, hey, show me, give me some
research on Cypex. Give me some research
on the Rosen token. I mean, you can start
messing around and saying stuff that you
can't easily see in Explorer or just by
looking at the chain. Because most normal
folks aren't coders, even though there's a
ton in the Ergo ecosystem.
So, and there's a lot of opportunities
obviously that we're looking at how to
people make their own MCP servers, plug it
in here, get a cut. I mean, there's just
all kinds of different things. We're
trying to figure out how to make it a
community effort, not us driving the ship
the whole time.
Yeah, absolutely. And then even goes to
say for say you have like a beefy setup,
you want to host your own LLM, plug that
into our system and somehow, and then you
can, we can call your LLM, serve that to
people, figure that out.
And then the MCP servers, a lot of these
tools are really built for users, but I'm
sort of building them in the mindset as
well as for AI agents. So they're going to
need to be able to pull stuff from the
chain like block heights, the price of
Ergo for like a trading bot and things
like that.
So a lot of this is very foundational
layers and hopefully continue to build
upon and say, once we have all these MCP
servers, you can make an AI agent that has
a specific workflow and maybe you rent
that out and then people can run that
workflow and you can rent it, they get a
cut, something like that, or just straight
up buy in sort of a marketplace fashion.
So a lot of possibilities here.
And so for our roadmap, we have the core
foundation here. So the core platform, be
able to buy credits, the LiteLLM running
in the background to manage our users,
OpenWebUI, serving everything together,
the MCP servers.
We want to make some future enhancements,
so again, more MCP servers, UI
improvements on our front end. Community
features even as well. And then I'd really
like to have some sort of trading agents.
The biggest hurdle right now is just
getting some code set up to interact with
the smart contracts on the DEXs. And then
once we have that, it's just a matter of
just coding them up and then giving them
the logic to run on their own. And that
part I feel like is the easiest.
Ironically, the AI part's easiest.
So again, DeFi integration, advanced
analytics relative to the trading agents.
Yeah, and go back for one second. I think
the other thing that's sort of crazy is
the more MCP servers. So the more that the
community interacts with us, gives ideas,
or builds on their own, things can get
plugged in.
So it's not a, again, like we're trying
to, as much as we can decentralize this,
right, make it a community effort, not a
top down. We had joked, hey, it'd be cool
if there's price stuff, and Marc hacked
that thing together in a couple days.
Maybe he'd been thinking about it for a
long time, but it was like, I mean, it was
a couple days, and it's like, hey, check
this out. This is pretty cool.
You can do a lot of amazing stuff once
you have the base tooling set up. And
that's what excites me about this project
is creating the platform or a base layer
for everything to stack upon.
I sort of, throughout this whole thing,
we sort of said, oh yeah, the web UI, the
LiteLLM, there's a lot of heavy lifting
that qx() did that's like, let me think
about it, and it's, there's a lot of
stubbed toes and busted knuckles on
getting this thing to where it's at right
now.
And I'm just really excited to see how we
can grow on top of this, right? Grow the
community on top of this and give people
access to better modeling, better data
sets.
Yeah, for sure. And I think too, like
we've been in the weeds for a little
while, so it'd be kind of cool to come out
of that for a little bit and then see what
other people sort of think in terms of
tooling like MCP servers and whether they
make them their own or give us the ideas,
that's gonna be pretty exciting.
And yeah, like the MCP servers, I feel
like were the easiest part of this
project, ironically, for the whole AI
thing.
They're easy for you, dude.
True, yeah.
They're not easy for me and that's part
of it though, right? Like the MCP server
and you sort of hammered it home for me,
but why they're great for what we're doing
is they're really good at like hitting
APIs, right? And like getting data, taking
the request, getting the data and
massaging it. I mean, that's sort of
what's nice about them, right?
Versus doing a big, I think we started
five months ago talking about let's build
a huge RAG, right? And that's sort of
shifted to this a bit. So yeah, it's
exciting.
Absolutely. So I mean, yeah, our expected
impact, I mean, I think some of this is
ambitious, right? But go home.
So, 10x faster development. I mean,
honestly, for me, using the MCP servers,
especially with the Ergo MCP, when I've
been using it, that definitely makes
things a lot easier for when I'm trying to
develop something.
There's something that I've been wanting
to make some time. It was sort of like a
token ID look up for users for total
tokens or collections and things like
that. So that's connected with MCP, but
now it'll be a lot easier to code. And so
probably can use a lot of the same code as
well.
So really want to showcase that over
maybe the next couple of months, how easy
it is to set that up.
And even from the documentation
perspective, the tools are now open
source, so if you want to clone the Ergo
MCP, the price MCP, feel free to do so and
build upon it, contribute, that would be
fantastic.
And there's some other ideas that we
have, from like, actually instead of just
trading with AI agents, more or less using
AI agents to curate sort of a knowledge
library. And so instead of creating
content for humans, we're gonna create
content for AI.
And so then that would make our knowledge
base more robust. And then when your
humans are interacting with that, it makes
it a lot more easier to get to what you
want.
I mean, yeah. Look at his MCP servers. If
you're that kind of guy or gal, tackle it,
figure it out and say, Hey, in a week,
let's see who gives us one. I'd love
someone so we can plug in another one and
just keep growing this thing.
Yeah, absolutely. And like, once you have
the API, this is really easy. I think when
I first made the Ergo MCP, the initial
version that took me like an hour to do,
and then the Ergo Price MCP to the state
where it's at now took me like four to six
hours, so it really wasn't that long a
time, and plus I'm like vibe coding it the
entire time, so that definitely was
helpful.
So, with that, supportive vision, with
what we're building, we have some various
advantages that we sort of talked about,
right? The first mover advantage, I
suppose, in AI, Ergo AI tooling,
sustainable pricing model. We do charge a
little bit more just in terms of the token
usage out of the box, but I think most AI
providers do that. And then we have a
clear path to trading AI agents.
I don't have any questions, do you?
No, man. I'll go ask CodeUTXO.
Okay, perfect. Yeah, good idea.
Sweet. So here's our actual front page to
get started. So just the gist, we can get
started through here, put in an address,
you can buy some credits, it'll take you
to our credits page. You can view your
usage into the accounts. Of course you
need to sign in.
And so just run through, there's our
website. Just like CannonQ talked about,
we have GPT 4.0. Here's the pricing. And
then here's some sample usage costs. And
then here's our token packs. So we can do
the small pack.
So we can see it's about 1.1 ERGs, and
then we apply a 10% markup for tokens. So
SigmaRSV, SigmaUSD, and then we do a 20%
markup for Quacks, Comet, and if you don't
see a token that we have on here and you'd
like it, just let us know, we can think
about it.
Click these buttons, we can see, so
pretty much 100 to 1,000 and then 3,000.
And then this will change live. And so
basically you wanna, yeah, go ahead.
Yeah, so the tokens, the reason why there
is a cost lift between just paying in ERG
and paying in anything else is basically
we're swapping it back to ERG. We're
taking best practices we've seen from
other projects, namely, honestly, Quacks,
right?
When they do arrays, they're swapping it
back to SigmaUSD right then. They're
raising ERG or they're raising ADA and
they're swapping it. And so that's
basically so that we have costs on the
backend that we got to cover.
So some of those other tokens have higher
slippage, things like that. We're just
trying to make it available if you have a
bag of it and that's what you want to use
and not use your precious ERG. That's
great. But there's a little bit more
volatility with some of those smaller
community tokens.
Absolutely. So we'll go walk through
getting started. We're going to sign up,
put in your Ergo address, demo user,
create an account and so we see you have
0.25 credits so we give everybody this
amount.
Please don't go overboard in using a
bunch of different wallets for free
credits, otherwise we might have to
replace that.
Daygens are gonna daygen, man.
Yeah, right, right.
Sweet, so here's our token page, or I'm
sorry, our account page, so you can know
your user, your wallet address that's
connected, how many credits you spent, how
many credits you actually have.
Then we can actually go to the buy
credits page, we'll connect the wallet.
Now my wallet's actually connected to a
different one at the moment. Let me
refresh here. Sweet, we're connected.
And then from here we can just pick
whatever asset you'd like to use. So ERG,
SigmaRSV, etc. We'll click ERG. I'm going
to buy a hundred credits and I don't think
it'll pop up on here. It'll be off screen,
probably on the recording.
Okay, so here we go. So as you can see,
1.1 is leaving the wallet. This is going
to our wallet, the network fee, sign it
and go from there. So it'll pop back.
And so basically what happens once you
sign it, it'll run in the server will wait
to see that's confirmed. And then once it
confirms, we'll pop back here, you can
sync with that. And then it'll say, Hey,
you just bought 100 credits, you'll have
100 credits, and then how we translate
that back into our system. We'll do that.
And then from here, we can then navigate
to the OpenWebUI portal. And you should
just have the GPT 4.0. But I'm gonna
actually show off the Sigma bot real
quick. I don't think we have this native
to our general users, but this is what I
was talking about with the code base.
And so we can say, what is the pros and
cons of ErgoScript? I haven't asked this
question before, so we'll see.
And so we can see it's searching the
knowledge base. So all those documents
that I have, I'll have to make a GitHub
repo or something like that and come up
with like sub modules so then it just
pulls them. But basically what I did was I
grabbed all the different, and I spelled
this wrong, but it knows what we're
talking about here.
I got rid of all the different files that
we don't really need. So like build files
and things like that.
Sweet. So we can see here's the summary.
So that's pretty nice, advanced scripting
language and we can actually see what file
it came back with 88% relevancy. So from
an AI perspective, obviously that is
important.
And this is actually where it got it
from. It got to 88%, so efficient
consensus, low fees. As we know, if you
build or trade or send TXs right, we know
our fees are pretty low.
Scalable, fast transactions, well, sort
of. Two minutes is sometimes can extend,
yeah, so.
That's why we didn't do the payments. No
shade to anybody, but if we do the
payments while we're recording, we know
we'll hit that 12 minute block.
Right, exactly, exactly. So smaller
ecosystems, certainly true. Ongoing
development, yeah, obviously, but I think
that's not necessarily a con here.
I don't know, what's a question that you
have for the Sigma Bot CannonQ?
Is this the one where we can actually ask
it, like show an example of code and
things of that nature, or is this more the
ecosystem, different that we have?
It's got all of that in it.
How about ask it about demurrage?
So searching through, and then while
that's loading, you can see here. So we
have 985 for completion tokens. The prompt
token is 1306. So completion tokens, I
believe, are output tokens. 1306 is the
input tokens, and then total tokens is
2291.
So demurrage is storage rent. It is like
a small fee you pay if you're holding onto
your box of money on the Ergo blockchain
for a very long time, specifically after
it sits there untouched for four years.
Think of it like having a piggy bank where
after four years you need to put a little
bit money to keep it.
In Ergo, this fee is usually about 0.14
for a simple box of money every four
years. This helps keep people from putting
their money on the blockchain and never
touching again and making sure the network
stays healthy.
Nice.
And then, yeah, here we go. rent.md. And
then if you wanted to, right, you can just
open this up and open up, well, you can't
see it, but open up the markdown file. And
so that's the SigmaBot. And that's coming.
You will not see that today, but you'll
see that hopefully in the next week or
two.
Yes, sir. Let me go. So now we'll do...
We got a bunch of different for us in
here.
Okay, cool, so we got, so we can see Ergo
Explorer, so that's the Ergo MCP, and then
we have the Ergo Price MCP. So we'll start
with Ergo MCP, or the Price MCP.
So let's say, what is the price of Ergo
from the last 10 days, and can you, okay,
that's fine. And then I'm gonna click this
code interpreter.
So the code interpreter basically allows
to take that input and this will rather
the MCP grabs that input for the LLM it
processes it and then it allows it to
output relative to that context and then
from there with the code interpreter it
can then take that data and then plot it
for us like we see here.
So now we see this price data. It looks
pretty accurate from what I can tell.
So let's do, can you make this plot bar
chart and add a moving average? I'm not
sure if it can do this. I was trying this
the other day with trying to add Heiken
Ashi candles and it didn't have a library.
So I think there's probably something on
our end. We just need to install that
library and then it can be able to have
that functionality.
But looks like it's analyzing it, so it
shouldn't be a problem. Sweet. So there
you go. There's your moving average. And
so we could probably extend this to look
at it for the last year, add some various
moving averages.
And so now you can sort of, instead of
looking through TradingView or something
like that, you could easily just use our
tool, query it, grab the data that you're
looking for, try to see if you're bullish
or bearish relative to Ergo, but also we
can look at specific tokens.
So let's grab our Rosen. Let's start with
something simple. And so for right now, we
have to use token IDs for this. It doesn't
natively know token name to token ID.
Price of Rosen, it's been quite stable.
Well, thank you for the last 10 days.
I think there might be some nuances with
this, just in how crux does it, but let's
see. And then while that's cooking, I'm
going to do, okay, cool, fantastic.
Now let's do two things. Let's...
So basically what I'm asking him to do is
plot those two tokens, Ergo and Rosen, and
then basically have the lines sort of
match up. So you have a y-axis for Ergo,
you have a y-axis for Rosen.
Yeah, and this is a good time to say this
is... Oh, okay, so... Yeah.
Well, that's good to tease out. So it
looks like, right. And this makes sense.
Yeah. But relative, it's like, yeah, this
kind of do be expected.
But again, so this is something that
like, hey, if this is really something you
guys want, we can add more tools and
functionality to more, I like to think of
like an MCP is sort of like, in data in
particular, like a cloth and the more you
squeeze it, the more data comes out and
stretch it and move it in different
directions. And so that's what we need to
do here.
Sorry, I cut you off. What were you gonna
say, CannonQ?
No, I was just going to say it's the
prompts, right? So like when we were
testing this, I asked it, I forget what
the question was, but it gave me like a
real cheeky response. Like the first 10
wallets and it gave me all the details and
I said, well, give me all 50.
And it's like, well, here's the first 10
and the next one, yada, yada, yada,
basically. And then qx() asked it the same
question, but just changed it slightly and
it gave them all the details.
So, anyone who's used LLMs, I mean, you
get that. What would be great is here, if
you let us know or let the community know,
here's the best prompt for me trying to
get this information. It took me a little
bit, but here's how I did it. Here's the
best way to do it because his and mine
looked identical but for a few words and
it made all the difference.
Yeah, and that's actually a feature with
OpenWebUI. We can create prompts, and then
all you have to do is like this, and then
plot, and then run the variables and
stuff. We just haven't done that,
obviously.
So here I'm asking it, I'm not sure, we
haven't done this type of one before, but
plot the holders of the token. So I'm
asking it like two separate things. So
grab all the holders of Rosen and then
plot those. So testing it, see what it can
do.
And really a lot of these use cases are
really, certainly not developer focused at
the moment, but really just sort of like a
learning sort of get the ideas pumping
Yeah. And I mean, that's the, I mean,
it's a hack, right? We had a week, and I
think people are going to see just from
this the power of it. We have great tools
in the community, but sometimes you have
to be a power user to get them to work or
to massage it further. And that's what
we're hoping this will do for you.
That's fine, didn't give it to me. Here,
let me try this.
Yeah, I was doing some cool analysis like
this the other day. And then I was
identifying myself like, hey, here's,
that's a DEX. Number two is a DEX
contract. Number three is a team wallet.
Now reanalyze this without those two. Like
what percent are those and what's leftover
for general holders, that kind of thing.
There's some good, I don't know if you
want to call it money flow, but economic
flow through tokens that you can do with
this that I can't figure out how to do it
anywhere else.
Yeah, I mean you can scour the Ergo
Explorer and just go from one to one to
one, but it just takes a long time. And so
if you have this process that you can
define, right, then that's what the MCP
server is. And then it's just a matter of
flowing the data into it.
I believe this is Rosen.
Yeah, so I did that one. It's a funny one
because there's the various team wallets
and hot wallets and cold wallets, all the
different spots that it is.
Yeah, so this is a great research tool.
It's like, hey, should I buy this token?
All right, well, let me look at the
tokenomics. Let me, of what the team says.
All right, well, actually, let me see what
actually on chain says.
CannonQ, you said, you would really like
a tool for liquidity, inflow and outflow,
how many transactions per day. And there
are some tools that do that, like, I
think, like, I think Crux shows that or
something like that, or, but in any case,
or maybe MewFinance has that now.
Well, one of the things I was curious
about, we launched the trading, I'm sorry,
the trading, the mining DAO released PFT,
right, the recycled token. It'd be cool to
look at the LP in there and understand
what's happening.
There's a big unlock coming in another
month, what's not locked, how many holders
don't own the locked portion, that kind of
thing. And that's sort of hard to see
anywhere without a ton of know-how.
Like a normal person can't just walk up
and go, oh, I can trade it on a DEX, but
how many people are making up this
liquidity pool that I'm trading with? You
may want to know. It may be five wallets.
It may be the same five wallets are on
every token. You can do some cool stuff.
All right. Well, while that's loading,
let me load up something else. I'm going
to get the latest big transaction. This
plotting is really taking its time.
Again, I'm going to have to cut this
short here in about five or three.
All right, cool. So here's this
transaction. It's got the inputs. It's got
the outputs.
Oh, nice.
Got a lot of ERG 33,000. And then we can
come here real quick. This is the actual,
and then we see 33,000, the various box
IDs. And you can do the same for box IDs.
You can do address balances.
So let me just do one last thing.
Now, I probably wouldn't suggest this
because you just look at an explorer,
right? Pay to look this information up.
But in any case, here you go. This is my
Tipper wallet. So you get to see 14 ERG,
all these different tokens. So yeah.
So yeah, I mean, again, if you want an
MCP server, let us know. Happy to make it
probably. Or if you want to join up, let
us know. That would be fantastic.
And I think a lot of these tools are very
curated for a lot of specific tasks. And
so we can have a lot of different agents
doing specific things, because a lot of
this is very complex. And so we can then
functionalize it, put it into an MCP
server, and then abstract that and put
that into the hands of something more
autonomous and then run in the background
for us doing whatever you'd like, maybe
forensic analysis, trading, grabbing
information, etc.
Right. And just the last thing I'll close
with is it's called CodeUTXO. We hid the
eUTXO in there, right, at the end of the
code. But we're hoping to apply this to
other UTXO chains.
So, I mean, it's... Hopefully someone
sees this presentation that's not part of
the Ergo community or they're involved in
other UTXO chains. We'd love to start
figuring out how to apply those, but we
have, from some of our research we've
already started, not everyone's nodes are
as easy as Ergo's to run, I'll tell you
that right there.
Yeah, or just space-wise.
Yeah, for sure. We've been having to kick
some bricks trying to get them to reboot.
But yeah, it's Marc, me, qx(). qx() is
the unsung hero here since he's not here.
And he's done a yeoman's job here, just an
amazing amount of work on the back end,
getting everything to talk and chatter
with each other.
But hope you guys liked the presentation.
We really enjoyed building this. Me
watching it more than building it and
throwing grenades. Hey, can we do this?
Can we do it that way? And Marc going,
yeah, qx() going.
Damn it. Finding good edge cases, that's
for sure.
Yeah. Good feedback. It's been a fun
project. And I think you guys can tell
from our querying, probably less in the
presentation, more in the querying and
just talking about it when we're getting
to use it. I mean, it's an awesome tool
and we're looking really forward to
everyone jumping in, getting a few credits
and making this better.
We're open for feedback. We're not an
ivory tower on this one. We want everyone
to be on the ground floor with it.
So absolutely. And with that, I will say
again, the MCP servers are open source. So
if you have a cloud subscription, you just
need to take that into your cloud desktop
and port that over and then you're off to
the races.
Same thing with cursor. So obviously,
maybe use our platform. But again, if you
don't want to, you can look, hook it up
with OpenWebUI yourself, hook up your own
MCP servers in there, and there's so many
different platforms you can use this, so.
Yeah, thanks guys so much. Alright, cool.
Alright, see you everybody. Thanks.
Alright, peace.