Introducing Pulse.
Decentralized messaging on the Ergo
blockchain.
True peer-to-peer communication without
central servers.
Private, secure, and unstoppable
messaging for the decentralized web.
The problem.
Centralized messaging platforms control
your data.
Big tech companies control your
conversations, data, and privacy.
Messages can be deleted, accounts banned,
and communications monitored.
Your messages are stored on corporate
servers and can be accessed.
The solution?
Pulse.
Decentralized messaging on the Ergo
blockchain.
No central servers are required.
End-to-end encryption with stealth
addresses provides ultimate privacy.
And a decentralized infrastructure means
no single point of failure.
Pulse has advanced features that go
beyond basic messaging.
It is a complete Web3 social platform.
Stealth mode offers anonymous messaging
with stealth addresses for ultimate
privacy protection.
Live streaming is possible where you can
engage with audiences in real time.
You can send or receive ERG tokens as
digital gifts to streamers and content
creators with animated effects.
On-chain achievement system tracks user
engagement and unlocks special features.
Intelligent chatbot integration for
answering questions and providing
assistance.
Reply to specific messages and create
organized conversation threads.
Key features.
Multiple wallet support, connect via
extension wallets or import seed phrases.
Create public channels or encrypted
private rooms.
Anonymous messaging with stealth
addresses.
Real-time updates provide live messaging
synchronization across devices.
A modern, responsive UI with light and
dark themes.
Technical Innovation Ergo smart contracts
make use of multi-UTXO transaction
building, custom box value optimization,
advanced register management and Fleet SDK
integration.
Real-time sync makes use of mempool
message tracking, optimistic UI updates,
message conflict resolution and
auto-refresh mechanisms.
Advanced UX features mobile-first
responsive design, context-aware
notifications, keyboard navigation support
and accessibility compliance.
Privacy features include end-to-end
encryption, stealth address generation,
anonymous messaging modes and data
minimization.
An exceptional user experience, designed
for both crypto natives and mainstream
users.
One-click wallet connection via Nautilus.
Optional stealth mode for privacy.
Easy token tipping with forward slash tip
commands.
Powerful message search across rooms.
Fully responsive mobile design.
Dark and light theme support.
Built with cutting-edge Web3
technologies, Ergo Blockchain, Next.js,
Svelte, Web3, and TypeScript.
100% decentralized.
Ready to experience Web3 messaging?
Join the decentralized communication
revolution and start messaging on Pulse.