Well, welcome everybody.
Happy Ergoversary.
I'm here with Alex and we wanted to
discuss kind of the state of the state and
some potential ideas moving forward that
we think are pretty interesting for the
community, for miners and I guess for the
world in general.
You know, we've said, many of you have
heard Alex say for, I don't know, a couple
of years that the world needs better
money, it needs better collateral, and
we're kind of still stuck in this cycle of
spiraling debt that's growing
exponentially across the globe.
Inflation is always rampant in certain
areas and that declines kind of the
economic purchasing power of people across
the world.
And you also have this vector of economic
freedom and freedom from surveillance is
becoming more of a let's say history
rather than a bright future.
So definitely there are issues that
hopefully we can create tools to address
kind of the economic freedom and
prosperity of humans around the world.
That's what open money is about and you
know Ergo is kind of this open source
project that explores these ideas and
tries to implement solutions so Alex how
are you doing?
Doing well, doing well so yeah well,
complex and quite a bit to have so
actually a lot of quite positive
developments right, like well recognition
of the need of well digital stable coins
right even in centralized form then yeah
well digital gold is going into different
reserves but yeah I mean it's also done
not very properly usually right so I mean
a lot of positive motivation maybe in some
positive moments but
Also, yeah, well, a lot of things done
quite properly, so yeah, there is a lot of
work.
Ideas can be wonderful, but execution is
always the hard part, right?
Right, yeah, exactly.
Proper execution where, you know, the
devil's in the details and you understand
the trade-offs that you're, let's say,
building into.
So I've heard a bit about this idea of
better money.
I wanted to have you introduce that to
the community and kind of share your
thoughts on, let's say, this idea of
ChainCash and building better money for
the world.
What does that look like to you?
Right so actually a lot of ideas right
which can be found in different forms on
the forum and
Yeah, saw some white papers and now there
is ongoing effort on getting Ergo book
done.
So yeah, well, what do we have now is
kind of good base money, so proof of work
assets, right, such as
Ergo Bitcoin Monero then yeah some assets
which
It can be good and also widely used such
as real-world assets rights.
The biggest one is USDT, which is, well,
tokenized
treasury basically, right, of some
private company.
Tether company, yeah, so the reserves are
made of different financial tools, right.
So it's actually the biggest RWA.
But yeah, well, people are trying to
tokenize also commodities,
real estate and whatever rights to build
then financial tools on top of rights in
case of USDC and other centralized stable
coins, tokenized private treasuries.
So, yeah, it's quite more
straightforward, right?
So we already see a lot of so-called DeFi
tooling, right?
Well, which is not maybe so decentralized
if it's based on some private entities,
right?
Reserves based on trust to the same
entity.
But anyway.
Yeah, I would say that that does tend to
be a really interesting thing that we're
seeing in the space is like, as this idea
of onboarding real world assets kind of
increases, we're seeing a really broad
spectrum of like, reserve assumptions,
right?
You know, maybe, maybe updated once a
month, you know, we're still kind of in
like this paper accounting world that kind
of digital
Money has this ability to disrupt, but
then you also have kind of, let's say,
less, let's say, clear assumptions around
certain reserves where you can't directly
or independently verify them.
Some of them haven't been audited.
It's somewhat of a mixed bag in the
space, if you ask me.
Right, so then, yeah, well, among us,
right, so some, well, core Sigmanauts.
Well, many efforts done for formalizing
trust issues, for example, and then build
better tools such as ChainCash, which is
basically a foundation for digital free
banking, blockchain-based.
also and yeah building also well
trustless derivatives algorithmic stable
coins and more right so well Bruno for
example presented a lot of schemes and
continuing to do that
So then there are high-level schemes to
ensure, for example, risks of non-delivery
of physical commodities, right, with
algorithmic stable coins and so on.
So yeah, well, a lot of theoretical
schemes.
And now I think there is need to push for
practical adoption.
That's why we are starting a better money
initiative to push all those things for
the real world.
So we are already connected with
different entities such as pro-private
companies,
well entities like some well African
nations interested already experimenting
with tokenization and having need for
things like project funding for small
cooperatives and so on.
So yeah, actually a lot of demand for
better funding
around many areas around the globe,
better funding, better money rights, then,
yeah, well, in case of, for example, a
site cooperatives producing something,
there is a big question.
Well, how to sell, right?
And how to buy.
So,
There is need for better kinds of money
for international trading and so on.
A lot of requests, right?
So yeah, well, it is still shaping how
well it will be done in regards with
structuring, funding and so on.
But yeah, nevertheless, so all the
principles are set and the mission I think
is more or less clear.
Yeah, I would agree.
Building kind of open source frameworks
that don't, let's say, capture people as
much as traditional finance has a tendency
to.
Right.
So yeah, well, there are areas where you
simply don't have a traditional finance,
right?
And also Lebanon, for example, two years
ago when I visited it and I am pretty
sure, well, since back then, the situation
is not better, maybe worse.
Right.
And then, yeah, many places in Africa,
Latin America, and so on.
And yeah, well, a lot of places with
hyperinflation and high interest rates and
so on.
So, yeah, well, big demand, right, for
better monetary solutions, funding
solutions and so on.
So beyond that,
How are we looking with sub-blocks and
kind of your latest work?
What are you working on these days?
So, just doing final sync for 6.0 to
propose it to miners.
So, at the moment of releasing this
video, probably, well, the miners probably
would update nodes already and set voting
configuration in the setting files.
Then, yes, sub-blocks, which actually
another.
Well, a point of interest rights in
regards with.
better money.
So it's also about high-performance proof
of work protocols, right?
And better proof of work protocols.
There are a lot of hot discussions these
days about proof of useful work.
And then, yeah, well, high-performance
proof of work protocols because, yeah,
since
The Merge, Ethereum Merge, it's quite
clear that Proof-of-Work protocols are no
worse at least than Proof-of-Stake in
regards with efficiency, right?
So there was a myth that Proof-of-Stake
is more performant for some reason.
which was debunked before the merge.
I think that's largely ignored, so now
it's quite clear that proof-of-work
protocols are actually more efficient,
right, because less overhead for
agreements.
Basically every miner is working on its
own.
There is no communication needed for
consensus except for propagating new
blocks found with already valid solution
in most cases if it's not a forked block.
And yeah, even if it's forked, then many
protocols is accounting for such blocks
somehow.
But anyway, so it's totally asynchronous
and most performance kind of consensus.
And then there are different approaches,
right?
How to achieve concrete efficiency.
not just asymptotic, how it gets more
even spread on peer-to-peer layer among
the blocks.
And here we have sub-blocks in Ergo,
right?
And well, there are similar proposals in
other blockchains, for example, Tailstorm
and Bitcoin Cash, but yeah, well,
It's not quite clear when it will be
deployed.
We still have privilege to deploy things.
without, you know, spending years on like
resolving some debates in the community.
But yeah, well, this time is limited, by
the way, so with growth of community, we
will get to the same states.
Obviously, so yeah, it's better to do
well all the
Things like that now, but, yeah, I mean,
they also non-controversial.
I mean, in, in comparison with, well,
other options.
So it's, it's kind of, pretty, soft kind
of soft fork, right?
Yeah.
In, in regards with activation, it seems
to be.
So, but anyway, so yeah, well, after 6.0
and
Sub-blocks, let's see what would be next
upgrades for the core protocol.
I think it would be dependent on, well,
sidechains implementations and so on.
And probably, yeah, would be about, well,
maybe taking the best ideas from
experiments done there, right, and also
start putting
Sidechain, but also, well, it's not
crystal clear at the moment, right?
What could that be about?
Yeah, let's see.
But hopefully, it will be about, well,
pretty soft forks anyway, right?
So gradual updates without breaking
applications, without splitting community
and so on.
Yeah, the backwards compatibility is
quite important.
Yeah, so on every hard fork, it's quite
ordinary to lose some part of community.
So when I used to be NXT co-developers,
so yeah, well, basically the community
disappeared after a few hard forks pushed
by the main JLP.
And well, a few forks cost quite
quite brutal even disagreements in the
community and so splits.
Right.
And yeah, even in Bitcoin, right, without
any hard forks.
So that's a block size civil war actually
cost some forks to appear such as Bitcoin
Cash and more.
So like, yeah, a few new kinds of Bitcoin
appeared.
And yeah, we can expect more because here
now they have talks about demurrage and
things like that, right?
So we may expect maybe some more forks.
That kind of leads into the Sigma Chains
idea.
In terms of the Bitcoin protocol itself,
one of the more interesting ideas floating
around, in my opinion, has always been
drive chains.
It seems like the most practical way to
increase the miner revenue of the protocol
from side chain activity.
kind of really reduce their let's say
economic reliance on the block subsidies
without needing to touch.
You know, let's say demurrage or the CAP
or, you know, some of the other more
controversial proposals for extending the
security model.
And, you know, I guess potentially open
up some avenue for innovation and
expansion on top of the protocol, which
right now
You know, you have all of these different
Bitcoin layers and you have some You know,
I guess more or less interesting designs
in terms of like You know trustless relays
on top of Bitcoin or you have something
like Rosen but kind of this idea of Let's
say merge mined drive chains.
I've always thought was the most
practical like long-term path to
I don't know.
Let's say sustainability and security for
Bitcoin itself.
And, you know, merged mining is, you
know, pretty interesting to watch.
You know, we see that in the ASIC world
on script miners with Litecoin, Dogecoin.
We're starting to see that show up in
kind of the CPU space with Monero and then
different merge mined projects that are
kind of
Creating additional revenue streams on
top of that security and so I do think
that there's a big benefit to pulling that
into the GPU space and potentially
hardening Ergo long term and opening up
the same potential path for sustainability
of security and
innovation and also some interesting
trustless interoperability that actually
does, I would say is probably the cleanest
way to get chains to communicate.
It's just a more complicated method than
what we see around.
What are your thoughts on that general
idea or direction?
So, yeah, I think, well, merge mined
sidechains could provide, well,
significant revenue boost, right, for
miners.
Well, it is especially clearly seen in
Litecoin, right, so when I visited some
conferences so I witnessed some ASICs
advertisements promoting some script ASICs
as Dogecoin and Litecoin, right?
So the Dogecoin put in the first place
but it's merge mined sidechain of Litecoin
just so
Yeah, Litecoin is number two, right?
The main chain.
And yeah, well, the sidechain is number
one.
So it's not so clear in Bitcoin, but
yeah, there are a lot of merge mined
sidechains.
Maybe not so many, right?
But there are a few more or less.
thriving well with their own communities,
even in the ecosystems, merge mined
sidechains.
And recently, yeah, well, some started to
appear around Monero, done by Tari Labs,
and well, there is upcoming
merge mined sidechain with private
contracts, which is dark DeFi, right?
And so, yeah, I think it's time to work
on such things for Ergo, right?
To provide, well, additional income for
miners and also to, well, create more
liquidity,
Right, and also to play with new ideas
without touching the main chain, which is
quite stable.
I think, well, it's actually
stable for good rights and still there is
a lot of unlocked potential right there in
the Ergo and its contractual layer and
block structure and so on.
And well, there is some unlocked
potential in regards with
sidechains also, especially I mentioned
my sidechains.
So as shown in my submission for ErgoHack
8, there is possibility to have trustless
two-way peg, right?
Just using some contracts on Ergo and
some actually quite small additions to the
And then, yeah, we can actually do very
different and interesting things there.
So what I'm thinking about is to create
some double merge mined sidechain.
So Bitcoin and Ergo merge mined, right?
Kind of ordering blocks, right, to be
written on the Bitcoin blockchain and
input blocks on the Ergo blockchain.
Right, and then... Yeah, so with double
commitments on both
Blockchains, there is also possibility to
somewhat DeFi for Bitcoin with quite
trustless transfers.
Well, with minimum trust assumptions.
Then, yeah, well, those ideas of drive
chain, so BIP 300301.
would be helpful but so yeah we can go
without them even so I mean that they
would be helpful for a better peg for
Bitcoin but here we can have also we can
adopt some
Well, techniques, others already working
on and then reusing Ergo applications and
also having trustless peg with Ergo
blockchain, right.
And then there could be different ideas
tried also.
So there are also other vectors which can
be tried.
So, for example, we may have some
privacy-oriented
I mentioned my sidechains, right?
So recently, well, I started to dig into
Zephyr, which is a jet protocol done on
top of some fork of Monero.
But yeah, it seems, well, you can do
better, right?
So you can have
Merge mined sidechain with a variety of
stablecoin protocol, even with one
stablecoin protocol somehow.
But you need to limit it somehow with
better oracles because in case of Zephyr
it seems it's just centralized oracle and
here you can do oracle pools.
But then you may have private transfers,
right?
Just using
Well, ErgoMixer or adding also private
amounts, right, so using more complicated
cryptography, even FCMP from the upcoming
Monero updates for full chain membership
proofs and so on.
So, you can do a dark DeFi based
sidechain, right?
So, have private contracts for ERGs,
right?
Possibility, right, to move transparent
ERGs to the side chain, right, and then
use them in dark contracts.
So yeah, well, possibilities are quite
Yeah, it opens up a lot of space for
developers to play and underneath the
network, it creates new increased revenue
for miners potentially, which is always
good for the security of a proof of work
network, right?
Yeah, for Ergo miners, but then, yeah,
well, it could be interesting to Bitcoin
miners as well, right, if it's about
double-merge mined sidechain.
There could be more options, for example,
making a merge mined sidechain of Ergo,
which is also a partner chain of Cardano.
Two kinds of blocks validated by Ergo
miners as well as Cardano validators.
And also with the goal of trustless
interoperability.
And in case of Cardano, it would be even
simpler to make it closer to, well, be
fully trustless.
Yeah, I think there's a lot of, let's
say, green areas there to explore.
I think that putting together some base
tooling and some EIPs around, let's say,
the implementation of merged mining opens
up a lot of green space for quite a while,
which would be great to see.
Right.
Then, yeah, there is the idea of
dedicated sigma chains, right?
Well, it's about not much merge mined
chains, but chains with dedicated proof of
work.
With the idea to tame different classes
of hardware and so on, right?
Which also does make sense because, well,
currently there is a lot of untamed
computing power, I believe, right, in the
form of ASICs.
Even if you go on to like WhatToMine, you
know, there are constantly new
Chains that I don't know what they offer,
but there people like to spec mine stuff
that pops up So there's obviously hardware
demand sitting around there.
That's you know Somewhere to park and
hopefully be profitable in the long term,
which is always its own challenge and
proof of work I guess but I Definitely
think the capacity is growing.
So the demand is there if there's kind of
the economic
Let's say a utility for directing that
computing capacity somewhere.
I do think proof of work is great at
absorbing excess capacity.
That's kind of its superpower, I guess.
So, yeah, a lot of untamed computing
power.
Yeah, in ASICs and GPUs, right?
And there will be more GPUs soon to be
outdated, now used for AI.
But then, yeah, well, there is need to
tame the power.
CPUs, some classes of CPUs probably not
so well.
suitable for Monero mining concern so
yeah well a lot of possibilities here and
well yeah instead of launching some new
blockchain like another fork of Bitcoin
with some well features which are not
needed
What people also doing some fork of fork
of Kaspa, right?
It was quite popular like one year ago to
to launch some forks of forks of Kaspa.
And so on.
So yeah, it's it would be better to
launch some.
Well.
Ergo similar sigma chain, right, with the
idea to
get rails with Ergo, and then Rosen
Bridge since day one, so liquidity with
all the chains, liquidity pools on
Ethereum, Ergo, Binance Smart Chain,
Cardano, and so on.
And then also applications.
Right.
And then, yeah, you can do some
experiments you want to do, well, in
addition to a new kind of consensus, like
taming new hardware.
Yeah, you can also do something on the
application layer.
And yeah, so I think Merge Mined
Sidechains is a low-hanging fruit, right?
And well, from them, it will be quite
clear how to extend
The contractual layer in easiest way to
introduce new features new contracts and
so on Yeah, right.
Maybe new Sigma protocols such as Yeah,
yeah now have Some generalized Sigma
protocols Suitable for a much more
powerful things But yeah, maybe not so
maybe not so efficient as what we have in
Ergo.
I mean, they have, but they're doing much
more also.
So, yeah, I mean, for concrete
applications, it would be good to provide
ways for developers to play with new
features and to
to open possibilities right to experiment
in those areas now are inaccessible rights
with other blockchains.
So well, you cannot easily play with
applications of
Some newer sigma protocols, for example,
by using EVM, right?
But yeah, here in sigma contractual
layer, it's more or less straightforward.
Yeah, I do think that that long term
opens up a lot of, I don't know, green
area.
You know, I'm excited.
I think that's
more or less the point of building kind
of these open source contractual layers,
open source applications.
You know, some, I don't know, you watch
like a sci-fi movie, right?
You always see people kind of interacting
with money on different devices having
different energy inputs, different
consensus models that are all
more or less interoperable, right?
And so, you know, to do that on top of
clear security stacks is really
fascinating to consider long term.
Right, right, right.
So yeah, and it would be also quite
eco-friendly, right, to utilize outdated
hardware for producing, well, money,
basically, producing commodities, right?
It's, I think, much better than, for
example,
I don't know, wasting huge pieces of land
to extract gold and other metals, other
commodities.
Then we have a lot of tooling on upper
levels such as
ChainCash rights and other tools in
addition to just non-DeFi tooling which is
also there right like traditional DeFi
tooling such as
liquidity pools, LPs and auctions,
lending pools, bonds and so on.
So what do we have on Ergo?
Well, valuable, right?
So just imagine if you can run some Merge
Mined sidechain, right, with shared
liquidity, with the main ErgoChain since
day one, with Rosen Bridge, and yeah, with
some new features developers would like to
experiment with, and yeah, with all those
applications, so.
Yeah, and with liquidity being created
naturally, right?
From block to block.
Gradually unlocked, so it's not about
launching, I don't know, memes or well,
rugpull tokens, where owners of the token
can dump.
making price going down like minus 90% in
one hour, like happened recently a few
times with different VC rugpulls.
So yeah, well, it's a much more natural
story, right?
And also beneficial to Ergo miners and to
the Ergo ecosystem because of more
liquidity rights going here and there to
side chain or back to the main chain.
So, yeah, well.
Quite exciting.
Yeah, I think you know more or less clear
path towards that future, which is
exciting, you know, sometimes in the I
Don't know the cryptocurrency space.
I think that like narratives consume
reality, but they are sometimes not even
based in reality and having like a
clear engineering path towards like I
guess how to put this together and what
the benefits are pretty more or less like
clear and straightforward which is always
a little bit more useful than kind of the
narratives that sometimes we hear around
you know this ability to build like an
open source
financial operating system or application
stack and then make it portable across
let's say different chains or value inputs
and that can all trustlessly talk to each
other is a powerful goal long term I
think.
Especially if it's more, I don't know,
clear from like pre-centralization, which
is what we're seeing more and more and
more in the space in my opinion.
Instead of like decentralization, things
are kind of come to market pre-centralized
and then are supposed to go through some
path where power is distributed.
You know, oftentimes they either
oligarchies form or, you know, that
initial people just leave and then do it
again, right?
Yup, yup.
Yeah, that's how meme coin clans are
working, right?
Often it's about a few people.
They're launching meme coins one by one
and promoting this nonsense, right?
New meme coins, then rugpull, then yeah.
And another guy from the clan is starting
another rugpull.
Narrative consumed to reality is what I
call it, rather than having a clear
foundation for a better reality.
Yeah, at the same time, I see a huge
request for a fair distribution right
after all those rugpulls.
Yeah, well, I don't know, maybe it's my
bubble, but yeah, my crypto Twitter is
full of that.
Yeah, mine too, but I think we're in the
same bubble.
But I do think, if people take narrative
and then they repeat it until it tries to
become reality and then it's not reality,
I think after enough rounds of
experiencing that, it kind of disillusions
people.
Right, but yeah, I think there is trends
indeed, right?
So yeah, well, when people observe those
nasty rugpulls and yeah, it's not
something unknown, right?
So the whole space works.
And then there is a quite natural demand
for fair distribution, right?
And then, yeah, I mean, the problem of
fair distribution was solved back in 2009,
right?
And it's proof of work.
Yeah, no, I completely agree.
Actually, this problem
This problem existed before Bitcoin,
right?
With first digital cash schemes, like one
done by Hal Finny, so it used proof of
work, but didn't have difficulty.
And then, yeah, well,
Hal used some trusted hardware, but yeah,
without difficulty still, yeah, so well,
the distribution was in hands of, I don't
know, the developers able to optimize
their miners basically, right?
I forgot the name, it was RPOW or
something like that, HashCash.
Yeah, so some pre-Bitcoin digital proof
of work based currency, but without the
Bitcoin emission schedule and difficulty
recalculation rights, also the much needed
part.
of the equation.
So yeah, and then the problem was solved,
right, among others by Satoshi.
And then people somehow lost it again.
And now having all those things.
I think there's just a desire to
replicate the success of Bitcoin, but
personally maximize profit potential from
it.
Call it what it is.
Yeah, but yeah, I think actually, well,
the ethos of Bitcoin is quite forgotten.
So people are just launching digital
tokens to grab some value from bigger
fools basically.
No, Bitcoin is taking on a life of its
own these days, but I still think that
like the initial, I don't know, roots of
having like fair distribution of money and
permissionless non-KYC anonymous or pseudo
anonymous ability to participate in like a
global network is still just as powerful
as it was.
It's just, yeah.
Somewhat different let's just say that
Um, yeah, yeah is what it is All right, so
Yeah, so I think this is direction which
we are discussing for some time, right?
Probably for about one year.
Yeah, one or two years we've been talking
about this on the side.
Now it's the time to jump on
implementations and motivate people to
implement.
All those things.
But anyway, I think that's kind of the
natural progression for most things that
we've seen on Ergo is they've been an idea
that's talked about, discussed, debated,
refined for like a year offline, and then
we finally get the bandwidth or like time
energy resources to do something in that
direction.
So I think that's somewhat natural.
Yeah, but also, well, crystallization of
ideas takes time.
Yeah.
So, yeah, then it's quite natural, right?
So, yeah, first there are discussions for
many months and then, yeah, well, some
action.
This is how it's going with sub-blocks,
right?
So it's been discussed since 2023,
something like that.
But yeah, implementation is ongoing now.
And yeah, it's quite good.
So I think to the moment of releasing
this video, there will be updated DevNet.
And yeah, well, in somewhat July, we can
think about injecting sub-block supporting
nodes into the public testnet.
Let's see.
Hopefully everybody out there that's
tuning in can throw some mining power
towards the public testnet when we get
there.
Yeah, it's just one of those things.
We sit and we try to build and we watch
the global debt increase at its own curve
and inflation pop its head all across the
globe and kind of this increasing march
towards less economic freedom, more
economic surveillance.
I would say that sometimes the systems
that I see pop up in the quote-unquote
cryptocurrency space actually support the
increase of debt and the absorption of
inflation and don't necessarily enhance
freedom.
Maybe they enhance user experience, but
on the surveillance side, it's a little
sketchy.
Hopefully, long term, we can build better
money with better assumptions.
that contributes to a better world.
That's kind of the net goal, yeah?
All right.
So, yeah, stay tuned.
A lot of news coming.
All right, everybody.
Happy Ergoversary.