Alright, welcome everybody.
It's kind of an annual thing where we do
a closeout for the year.
Cover the progress that we made in the
Ergo ecosystem.
Some of the community-driven
advancements, development verticals,
thoughts.
It's been a good year, I would say, in
terms of what we delivered.
There's certainly a lot that we're still
chasing, but we could start with something
like ChainCash, Basis, those are both
monetary frameworks that we've kind of
been hallucinating about for what, three
years?
Yeah, three or four, yeah, more or less.
Yeah, so that idea of putting together
kind of this off-chain cash allowing for
elasticity, credit expansion, kind of
peer-to-peer, potentially bot-to-bot,
AI-to-AI, these type of ideas we've been
talking about for quite a while, right?
We have seen some kind of a traction in
the space around that more broadly, but I
would say that our community effort
ChainCash basis.
The idea of these credit systems and kind
of putting the foundation in place have
been incredibly valuable and I think will
deliver real tooling for people long term.
All right, yeah.
So I believe it started even from like
2019, right?
Back then it was idea to do LETS - local
exchange trading system.
And then kind of LETS constellation but
then after some thoughts and yeah well
LETS a couple of designs were published
back in early 2019 so there was initial
blog post by me then of Amitabh so we
published designs for
like ordinary LETS, so
non-collateralized, purely trust-based,
and yeah, Amitabh did collateralized
version.
But yeah, well, it wasn't by design even
flexible enough, right?
So yeah, well, it's generalization,
ChainCash appeared.
So yeah, we discussed the initial design
back in like,
late 22, I believe, with Amitabh, but,
yeah, well, unfortunately, he stopped to
do his parts quite quickly, and, yeah,
well, Papa passed away in 24, early 24.
But, yeah, then there were a few
iterations, well,
most of it stabilized in 2023, most of
ChainCash.
But then, yeah, well, this year, so just
very early thoughts on basis of chain
version.
And yeah, well, this year, finally some
significant progress got made.
So after all, there is some working
Tooling, right, which I'm testing, so
it's a very prototype and yeah, well, just
ready for some demos now, some initial
tests, but we're already planning to do
some with it.
like purely local payments well with
blockchain reserves anyway right so when
you can go into forest and just do
payments over mesh network so yeah we are
considering such a demo and then and yeah
so and when you're
leaving the forest, right, but back to
connectivity, you can redeem, right, the
notes in the woods, basically.
So yeah, well, something like that, and
we can consider applications like
agent-to-agent payments.
We discussed some things with Hosimi.
like integrating into his peer-to-peer
network, chill out, and so on, so on, so
on.
Yeah, well, a lot of interesting things
can be done.
Then, yeah, I think subblogs, right?
Another big topic for 2025.
So for months, we have DevNets under
testing and well, white paper is more or
less ready, aside of security.
sections.
So yeah, well, we'll start to send out to
peers and then after New Year Eve, well,
there will be a public white paper, listen
discussions and then yeah, we can think
about deployment.
Based on discussions.
So yeah, and well, I think another quite
exciting thing is that, yeah, we had
unstoppable hackathon, right?
And aside of that, I see actually a lot
of new faces in development, like Super
Ellipse updated Ergo wallet, finally.
Then, yeah, well, there are some other
developers, some new faces.
So yeah, that's quite exciting.
And yeah, also a lot of interesting
projects, right, in the community, such as
use and yeah, well, sorry, GetCircles and
so on.
Yeah, go ahead.
Who was that?
I was going to say it was a good year for
kind of derivatives, right?
We saw Dexy Gold launch.
We saw Gluon come out.
We saw the use stablecoin come together.
That'd be good to have you hop on and
give us your feedback in terms of how
you're feeling about use and what you
expect going into 2026.
Yeah, let me give overall my thoughts
about the industry and what happened in
2025.
So first of all, thanks for inviting me
to this end of year podcast.
And I'd like to step back a little bit
and look at the blockchain industry as a
whole.
So earlier this year, as some of you
know, I attended Cardano Summit in Berlin.
I was actually quite well organized, but
I felt a little bit disappointed by many
of the discussions.
So during the several panel sessions,
speakers were asked a very simple
question.
What is the blockchain industry actually
for?
So what's the meaning of it, right?
And many of the answers I heard felt
completely disconnected.
For example, one panelist said that when
you go to the petrol station to collect
bonus points for fueling your car,
blockchain could make it easier and faster
to manage those rewards.
So, you know, things like that, answers
like that you hear in Berlin during quite
a big summit.
The impression that I got from it was
that very few people generally understand
what the blockchain industry is for, what
is it meant to achieve.
So we would all agree that blockchain is
here to create better money.
So, but better money, what does it mean?
People may have differences of opinion
about
what actually better money is.
So in my opinion, there are three
fundamental challenges that blockchain
industry can solve to get us closer to a
better money dimension.
So I have this in my mind three big
problems.
So problem number one is creating a
secure decentralized ledger with finite
supply.
The first and the most important
challenge is creating a secure and
decentralized supply.
No one has solved this problem.
Many people understand that Bitcoin, in a
sense, is kicking the can down the road.
At some point, its security model needs
to be addressed.
Ethereum and Solana, on the other hand,
have removed their hard cap supply
altogether and just keep printing money.
Cardano takes a different approach in
subsidizing network security through
issuing new coins to stake pool operators.
So, for example, stake pool operators
will be getting rewards for validating
Cardano and Midnight and potentially other
side chains, but essentially it again
comes down to printing new money.
Ergo has a different path.
It introduced demurrage.
However, we still need to fully
understand its impact.
So this is the biggest problem that our
industry is trying to solve and no one has
come close to it, I think.
Now, the second problem is out of three
is a scalable algorithmic stablecoin, in
my opinion.
So this issue is massive for the industry
to take.
And we already seen one major attempt
that failed catastrophically.
And everyone else hasn't come even close
to solving this problem.
Currently, centralized stablecoins
dominate the market.
So creating decentralized immutable
stablecoin is not optional.
It is a global objective that can
actually change the world, in my opinion.
This is the industry's second great
challenge.
And the number three is the private and
fair DeFi.
So with equal access to everybody, this
problem has some smaller components.
And to be fair, industry has made some
real progress here.
So for example, AMMs, automated market
makers, I would say it's one of the
biggest achievements of the industry so
far, but there's a long way to go.
A large part of the DeFi must move from
fully public ledger to privacy preserving
systems and obviously you cannot build a
private DeFi using something like USDC and
the list goes on.
So these three problems are for years
for our industry to take.
Obviously, the industry can help with
things like tracing stuff or moving
real-world assets on the blockchain and
many other things.
But I don't think they're
as big as the three that I described
above.
Now, when talking about me, myself,
personally, and my plans and what we have
done in 2025, obviously, I want to focus
on the problem number two, which is a
scalable algorithmic stablecoin.
Like I said, there was only one attempt
that failed catastrophically and as we can
see now and analyze platforms like
DefiLlama, there is no one even trying to
focus on this challenge now.
Everyone gave up pretty much and
centralized stablecoins dominate and
basically they are ruining the whole idea
of DeFi.
How can you have even DeFi if in the core
of DeFi you have a centralized
stablecoin issuer who can freeze and
seize your money at any point, right?
So yes, now we came up with this very
interesting design Dexy and its
implementation Dexy use or use let's say
and
To me, looking with the eyes of someone
who's been in the market for quite a long
time and been trading a lot, I see a lot
of potential in this design.
I don't want to go into details during
this podcast, otherwise it will take a
long time.
But basically, yes, I see a lot of
potential.
2026 will be fully focused on developing
this protocol, growing TVL.
Like I said, the first million use in
circulation is the biggest milestone.
After that, it will get faster.
I have a detailed roadmap in my head what
I want to implement.
But that would be my main focus.
And I'm happy to discuss more if a
question arises.
But I can say that I smell some blood
here.
This is really unique stuff that we're
building here on Ergo.
Thanks.
All right.
So Richard, do you want to accept some
questions?
Maybe so I'm reading telegram chats, the
main and there are some questions to you.
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
So the question is, yeah, what are your
plans about Crux, which you acquired
recently?
Yes, so what happened with Crux, I was
looking for a platform to develop use, to
focus on developing use.
And I checked some options and rather
than building something from scratch, I
thought it would be a good idea to pick up
a project that was kind of stalled, it was
not developing at all, so kind of
considered to be dead.
But actually,
few people use it.
It has a nice dashboard.
So I reached out to the previous owners
of the project and they were quite
collaborative.
So they passed the ownership to me.
So my plans with the Crux Finance is to
keep it as
as a platform as it is right now and
develop it, so-called like a top tools
type of a platform.
I want people to be, when visiting Ergo
first and trying to understand what
projects do we have on Ergo, visit Crux
Finance first, but I will also make it
use-centric.
So use would be the main trading pair.
I want to build a bank monitor there
where people will see how bank reserves
behave over time.
So to give them more confidence that use
is fully collateralized project that we
have reserves and how reserves behave that
the bank actually accumulating resources.
So I want one dedicated page there.
It will preserve all the current
functions.
I was surprised, but quite a few people
use Crux to fill their taxes, so we will
keep that feature.
People can continue using it.
So things like that.
And overall, I have some DeFi ideas and
some events that will be coming in 2026,
similar to CLB event.
And when the right time comes, we will
host events like CLB on top of Crux now.
So that's basically the plan.
The token will be used for different
activities.
Now you can pay for transaction fees with
tokens.
So that's already a good start and we
will add more features in the future.
But that's not the main purpose.
The main purpose for me is to develop use
and build TVL and cross-chain liquidity
with use.
That's my main focus for 2026.
Yeah, that was great.
Your trilemma, I don't know, people look
to liquidity for answers and I think a lot
of the actual solutions to what is good
money and what is going to be a solid,
scalable, stablecoin design and what is
privacy going to look like, a lot of those
break down to architecture.
in terms of how the solution is
presented.
We do live in the market space where
people look at noise and liquidity much
more than architecture.
I do think those are really deep
questions to consider in terms of what's
the architecture of good money.
Same is true with privacy assumptions.
That's becoming more popular and there
are a lot of different paths to create and
enhance privacy.
But when noise and liquidity are driving
markets instead of architecture and design
and systems, I think we're going to
continually fail to deliver something
meaningful.
Correct, Joe.
We definitely pivoted in the wrong
direction.
I feel like we are helpless kinda.
So there's nothing better than that
industry can come up with.
So you look at the hyperliquid.
It's a very good example.
They came up with a decentralized
perpetual DEX, right?
Six months after they came over, let's
say one year, we have plenty.
I lost the count, probably 20 of them
now.
They're just popping like mushrooms.
There's nothing else in the industry.
They lost their idea.
They're not innovating really.
Only one or two good projects come up.
here and there, but no one is really
focusing on the fundamentals.
No one is trying to solve algorithmic
stablecoin.
That's really frustrating.
No one is trying to create a secure
ledger with finite supply.
Everyone just keeps printing money.
Privacy kind of started moving a little
bit with Zcash giving a little bit of
boost and Night now catching up.
But we'll see just a simple privacy and
the private smart contracts are very
completely different beasts.
But at least there's something going on
there.
Yes, industry feels and actually the
price actually reflects where the industry
innovation is.
Innovation of the whole industry is in a
very low point and price reflects it now.
So we need to get back to fundamentals
and we need to start challenging status
quo as a trade fight.
and try to solve real problems.
And I think here on Ergo, though not many
people know about our project, but here on
Ergo, I think we're on the right path for
many of these challenges.
I hope we're on the right path.
I would at least say that I think we
asked the right questions, right?
Not necessarily that we have found the
absolute correct solutions.
That's always going to be something that
time shows.
But, you know, take Hyperliquid as an
example.
I have no idea how it works.
I can't see, right?
So I don't understand what the
architecture is, and frankly, nobody
outside the team does.
which is kind of wild to consider, but
that's where, you know, quote unquote,
DeFi is.
Now, I do think we have, you know, made
some good progress as an ecosystem.
You know, you can say Duckpools is
something that is always in the background
building.
I think V2 is going to be quite exciting
as that rolls out.
And we can see the architecture there.
We can understand what's happening.
And so that allows us not just the
developers, but as a user base and as a
community potentially to offer direct
feedback in terms of design and
functionality that wants to be seen.
You know, with Rosen Bridge, that's a
work in progress.
But 2025, we did actually integrate into
Binance Smart Chain first.
I think that was February, February,
March in there.
We've created the first, let's say, meta
protocol on Bitcoin that kind of cleanly
moves assets in and out.
That's not something we've fully
developed in terms of market function yet,
but the underlying potential is quite
interesting there.
This ability to move beyond proof of work
mining pools and kind of promote
individual miner control is something that
the proof of work space has been chasing
for, I don't know, since 2011, 2012 when
pooling appeared, right?
I think we have some quite interesting
solutions to big problems in the space.
Now, unfortunately, I would say that
attention and liquidity are kind of their
own animals in the crypto space that take
away from
I don't know, the underlying value of
kind of like architecture and distribution
of power and a lot of these underlying
mechanics that ultimately build solid
solutions, in my opinion.
But I think 2026 could be a good year.
I'm excited to see this idea of, you
know, sigma chains merge mining, trying
to, you know, kind of move in the
direction of some of the Bitcoin
proposals, but with a lot stronger systems
than Bitcoin is currently capable of.
We did actually see our first Fiat on and
on off-ramp that was integrated into a
wallet, which is pretty cool.
A lot of people were asking for that for
some time.
You know, with Machina, I do think that
we're going to have a quite interesting
peer-to-peer DEX design that, you know, is
something that could potentially support a
lot on top of it, right?
So in the broader focus, I'm pretty happy
with what we've got done.
I can't say that everybody is going to be
happy with markets, but the crypto market
is in kind of a weird space, to be honest.
I would say many times I feel like a
stranger kind of reading through the
latest that people are discussing.
Yeah, so, but I think after all markets
are right.
So yeah, it can be seen our 2025, right?
So a lot of VC rag pools starting with,
oh, I don't know, Mantra DAO probably or
any other rag pools.
But yeah, closer to end of the year,
I witnessed some events when VCs just
immediately dumped assets they invested in
right after unlock, so basically
kick-killing projects immediately.
So yeah, that's a little bit surreal,
right?
So if you invest into some projects, why
to kill it like immediately?
like normal VC industry, general tech, so
they wait for like five to 10 years,
right, before, well, planning exit and
executing it.
VCs are not even VCs if we are talking
about traditional VCs from Silicon Valley
originally and so on.
They are not investing in
ideas or technologies.
They're just buying tokens with some
discounts and then selling immediately.
Well, it seems after all markets are
rational, but in the long term only.
It seems many people are now running away
from all those projects.
Think about it.
If we go back to Richie's first
challenge, what is better money?
I don't think better money is something
with massive insider seigniorage that are
looking for an exit for profit, right?
That's not a core tenant of money that's
going to be sustainable in the long term.
I don't think that's like a
I don't know, controversial to say, it
just doesn't fit within the framework of
what is money.
Like I'm going to print 80% of the supply
and sell it to you and then try to exit.
Right, I mean, so if we are talking about
money or even assets, right, some more
broad things, maybe.
So yeah, it's a very strange beast.
So someone is coming basically to me and
saying, well, I've just printed
those assets, well, tokens, basically
private money like 80% to my personal
pocket.
So buy it.
And well, if I'm asking why should I buy
them, I just hear some, I don't know,
complete nonsense like Web3 something and
so on.
That's where we get into this idea of
noise and liquidity.
You can fool maybe people once or twice,
but after all markets stopped buying this,
so it's not possible to extract.
And yeah, I mean, even, yeah, well, those
selling pitches like Web3, something.
So when I am starting to ask like this
new breed of crypto world,
I mean, what's Web3 is and why do I need
it, right?
So, well, with Bitcoin, it was clear,
right, from first seconds when I've seen
Bitcoin Foundation Twitter back in early
2011.
Well, it was immediately clear, I mean,
what is this and what is potential of
money without central banks, right?
Like peer-to-peer money.
without trusted parties.
So even if you don't understand any
details, right?
So well, that's powerful pitch.
And well, when someone is trying to pitch
Web3 something, I just don't know, I mean,
how to use it.
Why is it needed at all?
So yeah, and
Joe, so what's Rosen-Lethos projects you
are involved with done in 2025?
Well, I would say after, what, two, three
years, you know, Lethos launched its first
version of Testnet.
We have had pretty decent participation
thus far.
Right now, we're getting ready to release
the third version, which is going to have
some additional fraud proofs kind of
update and be optimized.
You know, that's quite an interesting
problem to solve, right?
Pooling in proof of work appeared because
people want to minimize variance of
payout.
If you're going to run some sort of
business, you want some form of stable
return.
And so it's a predictability problem
that's economic at the end of the day.
Now, the solution for that or the
architecture of the solution for that
economic problem was just to centralize
hashrate, which has terrible secondary
consequences.
First, it affects settlement.
As hashrate is more concentrated, your
assumptions of settlement as blocks are
added gets worse.
If you're interacting with the system,
your security assumptions change the more
centralized the chain is.
The secondary toxic side effect is this
idea of censorship.
We've already seen that proposed anyway
and partially implemented in Bitcoin in
2020, but that had some kickback.
We saw it in Ethereum where they had
their OFAC compliant block producers.
And as you look at the market that's kind
of shifting towards these public mining
companies, I don't see that as that big of
a leap.
to kind of bring these censorship vectors
into quote unquote decentralized systems
because of where their footprint is.
And for me, that's concerning because it
defeats the entire point, right?
Like that's an architectural decision
that just fails.
It brings up a bunch of second order
effects that are toxic.
So Lethos is an attempt to kind of
democratize mining.
It does, in a way, I've been thinking
about it in some senses like a hardware
DAO, right?
Where you do have kind of like this
finite state machine or set of contracts
that
Enforce honesty and in terms of a miner
shares their payouts and you're replacing
a third party that's anchored in some
jurisdiction that could have some attack
vector to an actual
system of smart contracts, which are more
self-enforcing, which is powerful if you
really think about it.
I think the architecture decision there
is a great improvement over what is
generally around.
With ROSEN, one of the things that I
really wanted to see in 2025 was open
contribution standards.
Sometimes it's very hard to know how
these systems work because the
architecture is
basically a secret.
So having open contribution standards not
only allows external developers to really
dig in and understand how does Rosen
Bridge operate, why is it designed the way
it's designed, but then you open the door
for people to participate in that
architecture.
And so we have a couple of chains,
Handshake, Fiero,
that have been actively implementing and
kind of building based on those standards.
We do have Nervos, which is currently
kind of in the process of voting for a
grant for their developers to build into
ROSEN, which I think is great to see.
We've released some research on the
initial implementation of the Monero
network, which is a pretty strong privacy
network.
And so having like that architecture in
the open and being able to like openly
discuss, share, and kind of learn from
other projects, I think is incredibly
valuable.
So with Rosen Bridge, I would actually
say that was our biggest win.
I know Binance Smart Chain is, you know,
potentially a really good base for
liquidity, but it is an exchange
environment.
They say they're not, but okay.
I don't necessarily see how that's
possible given, you know, some of the
things that go on there.
I do think that building on Bitcoin as
well is quite interesting because you do
have, for lack of a better word, the
largest pool of censorship resistant
capital on the planet, right?
That is the Bitcoin network.
And so having additional uses that are
kind of brought in that access that
liquidity potentially is quite interesting
long term.
In terms of 2026, I think that it would
be nice to see Monero.
They need to upgrade their network.
There's a lot going on there.
Base is quite interesting as it's a way
to get a footprint into the Coinbase
ecosystem.
I did actually propose two Catalyst
proposals.
There's interest for people in the
Cardano ecosystem to potentially back end
an exchange environment instead of waiting
for somebody else to open the door for
them, which doesn't seem to be the
trajectory of how the ecosystem is growing
more broadly.
It's interesting to look at how crypto is
changing.
It does seem as though these entities are
trying to vertically integrate everything
into their own stack, but I guess that's
somewhat natural given greater permission.
In 2026, another interesting thing we're
going to work on in ROSEN is Raffle v2.
It's going to be an extension of the
first raffle protocol.
We're going to try to create greater
access for cross-chain liquidity to be
able to access these contracts.
You're going to have multi-winner
support.
In my mind, I've always said, okay, if I
can go to the gas station here and I can
buy the Colorado State Lottery ticket,
could I flip it over and you see the
payout odds?
Could I just replicate that and in
essence create the exact same game with
enforceable honesty that's open and say,
okay, here's a cross-chain lottery system
that, you know, I wouldn't even have to be
creative.
I could just clone what's already around.
Interesting thought long term.
perhaps.
But I do think that those type of
community fundraising tools, gambling
tools, etc.
have some demand.
So let's see what people use them for.
I would be happiest if I just saw
nonprofits around the world be able to
say, hey, we can actually use these as
fundraising tools to do some good.
Right.
And so, yeah, about the exchange
environment.
Actually, it's an environment for
different exchanges.
Right now, you already can arbitrage.
But yeah, probably in limited just one
way via ERG and
ERG on GATE, for example.
So on GATE, you can find liquidity pool
on BSC.
So RS-ERG to USDT, right?
And yeah, you can trade directly from
your gate.io balance, spot balance even.
So no need to transfer to a different
kind of,
accounts and so on.
So you can just buy from spot accounts,
spot balance.
I do think those aggregators will get
more interesting as we grow.
Yeah, and then maybe it's already
available on BitGet, this BSC pool and
that would be great because BitGet is
popular in some countries such as
Indonesia and CIS countries.
So yeah, that would be great to see at
least in arbitrage form.
Ergo on different centralized exchanges
via liquidity pools on BSC and other
chains.
That's quite interesting, because in 2025
many exchanges failed, unfortunately, so
we lost Zgex, and then TradeOgre probably
was the biggest loss in 2025.
it got shut down by police.
So yeah, huge loss for proof of work
assets.
Actually for many of them, it was the
only exchange and there is no any
replacement seen yet as far as I know,
right?
So yeah, big loss.
And well, then naturally a lot of proof
of work assets will go already going
centralized rails right like Firo already
integrating handshake and so on because
for proof of work assets it's quite hard
to get on centralized exchanges especially
biggest ones these days because well for
some of them as we know well there is need
to pay not just in
Not just some fixed amount in fiat, but
also transfer some percent of supply and
this is insane requirements when it's
mined.
So someone needs to buy from miners to
donate to centralized exchange.
It's a crazy assumption.
It breaks any notion of what is good or
better money.
Something where you're going to print a
bunch of the supply in your own pocket and
then you have to go around and bribe
intermediaries to interact with it.
That's insane in terms of base
assumptions of good decentralized money.
But that's where we are.
I don't know.
Right, so yeah, actually, those exchanges
are just pushing for worse kinds of money
to be created, right?
Yeah.
They're moving the whole industry here.
Well, kind of failed also in 2025, right?
So, well, there was a lot of heat towards
So some biggest exchanges in the space,
if you avoid to call names.
But yeah, it's everywhere.
It's in the news and Twitter.
So yeah, you can find a lot of heat
around and yeah, well, especially about
October 10th, right?
And so on.
So yeah, it was crazy year after all.
But yeah, in Ergo, it was more or less
stable, right?
So I mean, from what I've seen, not any
big dramas, whatever.
So just development, right?
So 6.0 activation.
Yeah, well, sublogs development, DevNets
testing, and yeah, a lot of new products.
Some of them we've discussed already.
More coming.
For example, you mentioned Gluon, so
currently we have Gluon Gold only, right,
and Gluon USD is coming.
And then there is need for stable pools,
stable to stable liquidity pools.
And well, I'm thinking to announce a
bounty for that.
Yeah, well, a lot of interesting
developments in funding.
So there were a few successful
fundraisings for development.
Thanks to ones who donate.
And then, yeah, well, development-wise, I
think, yeah, well, things are going quite
well, so maybe better than in 2024,
probably yes.
Yeah, and going back to BSC.
So, Richard, as far as I know, all your
plans for use also BSC centric, right?
Yeah, just to.
elaborate more on the topic.
If you know, Coinbase announced that they
will be integrating all Solana DEXes into
it.
So if we breach to Solana, for example,
then all our assets on Solana will be
available on Coinbase natively, like
ERG is available on GATE, like you said,
the same thing will be on Coinbase.
Now Binance also has Binance chain DEX
inside Binance, but they do only selective
coins.
So at the moment I wanted to see if use
will appear on Binance by default, on
Binance Alpha by default, but it will not.
So Binance has a kind of filter there,
But Coinbase apparently will, that's what
they announced, they will allow all Solana
decentralized, Solana tokens to appear on
Coinbase.
So if we at some point connect Solana to
our bridge, then for example, the pair
like rsERG, USDT or use USDT will appear
on Coinbase natively.
That's quite exciting.
At the moment, yes, I plan to start
strapping liquidity starting from actually
January 1st.
So consider this is an announcement.
On January 1st, we will have first
bridged use and use USDT pair with a
concentrated liquidity on Binance chain.
And some miners already expressed their
excitement that they can mine directly on
their Ergo wallet and in a 100%
decentralized way transfer with the Rosen
Bridge.
They might actually sell their ERGs to
use and transfer their use to Binance
chain.
with low fees and completely
decentralized way and then cash out on
USDT bypassing all centralized exchanges.
So we are trying to create a structure
that will replace TradeOgre and other
exchanges for miners.
It's quite exciting to see if people will
use it.
I hope they will.
So that's one thing I'm really excited
about.
And all the other proof-of-work chains
that are currently integrating into ROSEN,
also it's very interesting to see if they
will also embrace that use framework into
their communities.
If they will start using use, if some of
these chains have DEXes, maybe we can kind
of export use to their native blockchain.
If they don't have DEXes, then we can
integrate their tokens to Ergo and then
create a pair with use.
So anyway, there are so many options and
I think all of that will be beneficial for
all the projects that are integrating to
Rosen Bridge.
So yeah, that's my take on it.
I can say a couple words about my
expectations from 2026.
So in terms of core development,
obviously I'm waiting for the fast block.
Fast block will allow us on the next
level, DeFi on Ergo natively.
So we don't need to kind of look for the
fast trading environment somewhere outside
of Ergo to create this liquidity rails.
It will be much easier to bring assets
into Ergo and then connect different
trading frameworks, trading bots to it.
And I also want everyone to keep an eye
on our security assumptions as we will
grow
cross-chain liquidity.
In 2026, I have no doubts that we will
start growing cross-chain liquidity.
Now, the main liquidity pool is rsERG
with ADA, but I think in 2026, I have big
expectations for use and maybe some other
assets to grow more liquidity with ROSEN.
So, we just need to remember about
security assumptions here.
And yeah, we actually were talking with
Alex discussing some possible enhancements
to use protocol.
Maybe at some point, if Alex finds time,
we will add maybe one or two contracts
there if it depends on the complexity, but
we'll see.
Even right now, it performs very well.
It grows reserves, but I think it can be
done even better.
And yes, and the privacy with use is
something that we need also to explore.
This is definitely something big, maybe
not for 2026, maybe later, but something
I'll be definitely looking into, see if we
can add any additional privacy to use.
This is my expectation for core
development.
And for ROSEN, what I would like to see
from ROSEN is
and so connecting Base possibly yeah
everything what Joe already mentioned is
it's actually very exciting uh Base is
definitely there should be not difficult
to but will allow us to create a use USDC
trading pair for those who prefer USDC
And then Midnight, if in 2026, I really
doubt that Midnight will be fully launched
by the end of 2026.
But anyway, we will keep an eye on that.
Whenever Midnight becomes available,
obviously I would want us to have that
connection with Midnight as soon as
possible, because use is
So it's a perfect fit for Midnight.
Obviously, none of the centralized tokens
can live on the Midnight and preserve
privacy.
Maybe they'll be able to go to Midnight
and just remain publicly available without
the, you know, shielded features.
fully traceable.
That's not what people who use Midnight
would normally want, but use can preserve
all the privacy there.
So that's something I would expect us
also to accomplish in 2026 if Midnight
becomes available, right?
If they launch their network.
So this is kind of my, yeah, my plans and
expectations for 2026.
I'm excited for 2026.
You know, Lethos has been kind of a
thought experiment for a couple of years,
which really hardens the assumptions
around proof of work potentially, which
makes the ecosystem a lot stronger from
the foundation.
Rosen Bridge has always been this idea
that we should try to control our own
destiny when it comes to market access.
I do think that one of the big
accomplishments I would like to see in
2026 is where our SDKs get built out
enough to where we actually start
integrating into wallets.
I do think that rosen.tech as a website
will inevitably disappear for most people
to where perhaps it can be built into
applications via a widget or it can be
directly supported in some wallets.
I do think that we can put together the
right framework to create incentives.
that encourage teams to do that.
Ultimately, incentives will drive
outcomes there, so there's a potential to
add some small fee that then goes to the
wallet provider or the DApp provider, and
then it becomes more seamless, which
ultimately would be a pretty nice user
experience to build on.
Yeah, that's actually quite a good
comment, Joe, and we, during the last two
years, we've been chasing these bigger
chains,
who are not very responsive and even
projects on these chains are not very
responsive to the opportunities that Rosen
provides.
But now all of a sudden we see that the
vectors change and actually the main
growth
may come from these smaller genuine
projects that we didn't think of let's say
two years ago, right?
But now all of a sudden, you know, when
everyone
Everyone finds themselves in the same
trouble situation now.
They're looking for the solution and
apparently Rosen is one of the best
solutions available on the market.
So I'm very excited how it will develop
and I'm very excited if they will want to
extend their collaboration with Ergo not
only with Rosen but also with the
stablecoins that we have now.
I've always thought that long term, it
makes more sense to move into smaller
ecosystems that are more understanding and
appreciative of what Rosen Bridge offers.
If you're talking about Ethereum, it's a
very, very crowded marketplace.
So your ability to get traction and
visibility is naturally hindered by the
amount of competitors, versus if you're
talking about smaller ecosystems that have
kind of encountered the same
difficulties or challenges that Ergo has
historically, there's going to be a much
greater understanding and appreciation for
what that tool offers.
And if we can connect enough smaller
chains, the collective power of that in
terms of visibility and user base and use,
I think will ultimately be better than
just trying to compete in a crowded
environment.
Yeah, absolutely.
Something we haven't touched while
waiting for Alex, something we haven't
touched, I can speak a little bit about
our block reward emission schedule.
This is something also very interesting
coming in 2026.
We have a block reward reduction in four
days from the time we are recording this
video.
So by the time it's released, I don't
know, maybe it will be less.
and then we have only one more block
reward reduction scheduled for April 2026
and after that we will settle at a very
comfortable from monetary point of view
0.85 I think per year
inflation rate, yearly inflation rate.
This is something what Bitcoin has right
now.
Bitcoin is still very secure.
We don't know what will happen after one
or two more halvings that's coming.
But in Ergo, we will stay at that
inflation rate for I think like 14 years
or something like very long time, as well
as complemented by the demurrage.
So it's very exciting times because yeah
we've been
Under this high inflation and lots of
miners, obviously, they need to pay for
electricity.
They've been selling on the markets and
the holders have been feeling that.
But now, in four days and in April,
finally, in April 2026, we're getting to
the point of very steady inflation curve
that should play
in favor of long-term holders.
I don't want to speculate here, but
everything suggests that, yeah, we're
getting to that sweet spot that will last
for quite a long time.
Yeah, and if miners are worried about
that, I would say in 2026, very, very,
very, very high likelihood that we see our
first token with the primary emission
being proof-of-work driven, which is going
to be Lethos, right?
And hopefully, we also explore this idea
of merged mine sidechains.
And so then they have additional security
subsidies paying for their hardware.
It's coming online as kind of the Ergo
emission curve drops off, which will be
interesting because then it's a question
of, you kind of get to this multi-token
mining, I think probably like the
Litecoin ecosystem is probably the most
developed with that where miners will get
paid in Litecoin and Dogecoin and a couple
other merged mined projects.
So there is some, let's say new ideas
coming online for miners.
Yeah, and actually I've forgotten, but
this is very important.
So usually in some proof of work,
cryptocurrency is the biggest event,
right?
Because they don't have any others.
Basically.
But yeah, here in Ergo, well, it's
basically a storm, right, of updates from
different projects and so on.
So I've started posting videos from
unstoppable, not unstoppable hackathon,
but stability workshop.
which was just after the hackathon, so
posted a use video, I believe, right?
But there are more videos to post, and we
are recording another video, and yeah,
well, announcements are coming from use
use, Basis Tracker, and so on, so on, so
on.
need to check what's going on with Gluon
USD, other projects, a lot of updates.
Yeah, so somehow emission reduction is
not celebrated as in other communities,
maybe, unfortunately, because it's
It's very important, right, for the
underlying assets for its properties.
And yeah, well, it's changing a lot
outside.
It's changing a lot in the ecosystem and
beyond, right, also.
So yeah, it's important and it's quite
exciting to see finally, well, tail
emission coming.
So let's see.
Hardware.
Yeah, so anything else that anybody would
like to kind of drop in terms of the 2026
ideas moving forward?
All right, so going back to the
beginning, so to better money, so there is
urgent need for better money.
So we now have another fiat currency.
Collapsed again.
And again, actually, so it's Iranian rial
so.
Back in 2019 it was.
Like 100,000 rials per USD.
Well, official rate was 40k, street rate
was 100k.
So now it's 1.5 million.
So 15 times devaluation against USD,
which is also devaluating in six years.
So yeah, that's crazy.
And yeah, well, some protests started
already and that's not a unique situation,
right?
So that's happening like every week,
maybe even, right?
So every month at least in some country
around the world so yeah well fiat
currencies continue to fail they will
continue to fail and well in 2025 there is
a lot of disappointment seen about crypto
community that it is also failing to
deliver what was promised right when I
joined for example when
When I bought the idea of peer-to-peer
money without central bank
But it seems, yeah, well, here in Ergo,
we are standing on the very first
principles of the space and we are doing
progress.
And it's actually quite exciting.
So there is an article by none else than
Joe Armeanio about, yeah, basically
taxonomy of monetary expansion
cryptocurrency on top of
cryptocurrencies.
So yeah, well, that's quite
groundbreaking, I believe.
So that's what I tried to outline for a
few years maybe as well, right?
And well,
Now it's, yeah, done by Joe.
So, and yeah, well, unfortunately, right?
So, well, people think that, you know,
this cryptocurrency space should be about
competition, like horse racing, right?
But yeah, I think, well, actually, there
is a lot of room for cooperation and it
would be good to see
Well, understanding how to get to
peer-to-peer money, also useful for
real-worlds, not just toys for some.
nerds, right, doing some artificial
experiments, but well, money which may
have elastic supply, right, and fulfill
needs of digital as well as real world
economies.
For real, so yeah, it would be good to
connect to such people, but unfortunately
I don't see, right?
So here in Ergo, we are in quite unique
position.
And yeah, well, even more, somehow the
gap is even increasing.
So from my observations, so.
the crypto industry is getting more and
more hopeless in general.
I think a lot of people are chasing
things based on asking the wrong
questions, just honest.
So I do think that we need to continue to
focus on kind of architecture and
I don't know, control vectors in the
system, layers in the system, why they're
there, what they're for.
And you're always going to have this
social layer in crypto that's chasing
attention and liquidity, artificial or
not.
I don't think that's something that
directly we're going to out-compete with.
But I do think based on architecture, we
can build solid solutions that do stick
around, they do scale.
And ultimately if we answer hard
questions the right way, there's a lot of
value in that Right, so yeah, well
questions are wrong often right then we
have Well non-working solutions for
non-existing problems and Yeah, well
That's
That's quite a sad picture to see
actually when you see it year after year.
But here we are in quite a unique
position and I'm super optimistic so stay
tuned for Basis ChainCash.
Most of
Development done and that's also quite
exciting to see how development changed
well in 2025 mostly right so before I
didn't use AI-based coding and so on but
here most of the tracker so I did
contracts manually for sure
But then, yeah, off-chain part, the Basis
tracker, so it was AI-based coded, so I
didn't spend much time on it, just
reviewed everything manually, starting
from some point.
And that's also interesting, so it seems,
well, there is possibility now to make
great things without much developers
rights.
Well, but there is need for clear
understanding among those developers what
they're doing.
And I think then, yeah, well, asking
right questions again, helping a lot.
So yeah, well, in regards with
technologies in general,
AI and so on.
So, yeah, well, things are changing
rapidly.
It's hard to understand.
There was quite a famous tweet from
Andrej Karpathy a few days ago that even
he, one of the biggest minds in the AI
field, doesn't understand, well,
clearly what is development about these
days, because it's like old tooling plus
new tooling, and this new tooling is
changing like every month basically.
And not just evolutionary, but yeah, a
whole new concept sometime appearing.
out of thin air.
So yeah, it's very challenging and
rapidly changing environment, right,