Connecting, streaming, I think we're
live. Welcome, everybody. I hope we're
live. We'll see. I'll verify in one second
on the channel.
And welcome to another Ergo community
chat, this time themed on AI, vibe coding.
I hate the word vibe coding, but I guess
it's popular. By joining us to start, and
hopefully more of you join, we have the
join link in the Zoom in the bottom of
this video on YouTube, if you go there, as
well as the Telegram chat. But joining us
right from the start are the infamous and
famous kushti and HQ. How are you guys
doing today?
Doing well, doing well. So yeah, because
of the topics of vibe coding for the whole
day to get the better idea of what to talk
about. But yeah, well, these days
sometimes vibe coding a lot when it comes
to writing tests. Yeah, also playing with
basis. Server, basis tracker server, and
yeah, it's almost fully vibe-coded.
Wow, and I just heard in dev chat, right,
Louis Vatra made an entire node out of
Rust purely vibe-coded. Was that recent?
Yeah, well, the only question is how
secure is running it. I mean, if miners
are going to run it, then yeah, well,
probably a lot of hard forkish divergences
with the reference clients. That's what
we've discussed. And yeah, so some
divergence already now. Very cool.
You trust Fitz? We can bring him in?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. All right, all right.
Let me make him co-host so that he can
actually turn on his camera and mic. All
right, you're good, Fitz. HQ, how you
doing? Good morning, sir.
Yeah, good morning. So about vibe coding,
I just vibe coded Android mobile dApp. I
just tested testing working with the front
end and just build a WorldPay frontend for
it so you guys can swap.
So you got an APK we can download and run
kind of thing?
No, it's just that you just need a URL
after dApp and you go to your mobile
wallet, you go to the dApp section, you
paste the URL and you get the UI there. So
you just need to sign the DEX and that's
it. So you don't need to go to
WorldPay.store. So you will just have the
swapping inside. Like Cake Wallet has this
- it's in wallet swapping. So you would be
able to buy ERG or you will be able to
sell ERG for any other blockchain assets.
That's amazing, sir. That's fantastic.
How long did that take you?
I told you it was vibe coded. So it took
me maybe one hour because there are so
many components which don't work in
mobile. So for example, I was trying to
build a card with a toggle and drop down.
It doesn't support that. So I had to make
it simple as it can be. So now I'm just
working on the backend stuff and then just
getting it done and we will see how it
goes.
Well, let me kick start, right? I'm going
to kick start with some examples. And I
know HQ, kushti, Fitz, you can't see my
screen. But if you go to YouTube, you'll
see what I'm looking at. If you go to
YouTube and watch the stream, you should
see with a 30-second delay what I'm
actually going to be showing you.
So I jumped on the Vibe Coding Wagon a
bit as well. I was kind of inspired by how
much output Rob was doing with Degen's
world, with all that stuff he's been
outputting. So I was like, hey, you know,
there's been some stuff I've been meaning
to output. Let me try again. And the goal
of my outputs were to create something
that could interact with the Ergo
blockchain and be kind of unstoppable,
right? That nobody could take down, there
was no central server or anything like
that.
I came up with the first thing that I
came up with with this app right here.
It's called Site. It's an HTML file hosted
on IPFS. It's got transaction building
built into the HTML. It's about 10,000
lines of code for this one HTML file that
can be pushed. And what it does, it allows
you to do some sort of reporting online.
And I'm not going to say or mention all
the things that can be, because I'm sure
some bad reporting things or things that
are against laws could be reported on this
kind of thing, which we'd want to
discourage, but it's out of my control at
this point.
You can come, you can put in a tag, you
can see there's a node. I held a
competition last week offering I think
about $187 worth of Mu token, HQ's Mu
token, for if we can get about 67 nodes to
self-report on this site app right here.
It's as simple as just typing in a filter.
The filters are scanned at the refresh of
the page. Let's see if I can get it to go.
I'm going to refresh here. And you can see
right here that we're scanning. We scanned
everybody's wallet, essentially, for where
we scanned the blockchain for a certain
kind of token, which is made at creation
for this. It parses them in. You can see
there are 17 BERT, seven valid. So it's
showing these seven nodes. We can actually
filter by date as well. And we can filter
by actual time tag as well.
We can hover over these two. And you can
see that, well, if I zoom in here, you can
see I should have two data points right
here. Yeah, you can see I put in the
middle of the city my personal nodes and
my Cornell nodes right there. And you can
see there are some other nodes that have
started self-reporting as well here.
That's one that didn't put a note. That's
one that did. That's netims node. And then
I have a backup node in Singapore as well
that I put there. So this could be
anything. This could be, I think, HQ, you
were talking at one point of making an app
like this for flooding, so people could
report flooding on chain for that kind of
thing. Fires, dangerous presence of
whatever. So that's the idea. As long as
you have a NIPoPoWs node to be able to
submit to the blockchain that you can
point to and this IPFS link, you can do
reporting and you can't be stopped by
filtering or anything like that. It's
unstoppable as far as that goes.
And in the spirit of unstoppableness,
I've put in a section two where you can
put in your own Explorer and API for Node,
so that even if something's blocked, you
can point to somebody else's and use it,
or use your own node on your local phone.
We know Rustin can run that. So that's
that. It's really easy to report features
here. You can use mobile or Nautilus I
added recently, all built into the HTML.
There's a small proof of work anti-spam
verification that actually creates a hash
and nonce. So it's anywhere from 0 to 20
seconds when you click it. That's
essentially to stop people from using this
UI or to spam the network with stuff. And
it will not, our tokens won't even be
viewed on this page for display unless
that nonce is there, right? So that's kind
of a verification that you're tokens won't
even consider it as part of this map
unless you've done that proof of work for
that kind of thing. Then you generate the
link, and you send it out in a post within
a minute or two. It'll show up on that
site. So that's called Site.
Another thing that I threw on here as
well with Vibe Coding straight up
interacting with Ergo is Say. And that's
kind of a Twitter alternative where you
can link up your wallet, you can mint a
token, and that token is then read on
chain. You can see when I refresh that
it's loading all the say's, and then it
verifies that each say has actually been
minted by the wallet that it's held in.
So, you know, if there's a lot, it could
take a little bit, but you can see that
there's quite a few here, and it hasn't
taken a bit to load it all. You can follow
people, so you can type in up to 10
addresses, and it will show you everything
in their says right there. You can even
put in somebody's address. So I could put
in HQ's address and see who he follows as
well, kind of linking to that by clicking
down and seeing that. And we can load our
feeds down there.
Say is just easy. You're putting your
wallet address, what you want to say. Same
thing with anti-spam verification publish.
It opens it up in your Ergo mobile wallet
as well. You can also mint a token that
lets you browse a user's say, essentially.
And you can create a profile token so that
if you look, it says my name right here,
QX, as opposed to somebody just posting
their wallet. And I think somebody else
minted a token. Yeah, YongQ as well minted
a token. So that'll stay in your profile
and show up there as your name instead.
And of course, there's info here on what
it is. Just like on the site page, there's
info on what it is. And even on the site
page, there's info on how the transactions
are or how it's all built together as
well.
Now, you may say that, you know, how do
you make sure that people are using the
latest version of that you've built of
site or say, and that's the one thing that
I've linked back to myself, essentially.
If you look down at the bottom of these
pages, you'll see an updates. And all this
is doing is the HTML is hard-coded to
check in my wallet for an NFT that is
named a certain way, and it reads that
from there. So even if somebody is running
an older version of Say or Site, they can
see and hear that, hey, it should be
version 1.2 in the upper left-hand corner.
If it's not, click this link, bookmark
this link instead kind of thing. So that's
a way around these stale IPFS sites if
you're releasing an application on the
web, or at least that's a trick that I
found. I don't like that it's attached to
my wallet, but that doesn't stop somebody
from taking the HTML, making their own
editing, attaching it to their wallet or
some smart contract where a collective of
people will update a token for the
updates. So it's possibly endless there as
far as that goes.
And the last thing that I popped on there
was - And this is something that I've
spoken about for a long time in Ergo back
in the day, was a way to send messages
back and forth to people individually. I
know HQ spent a lot of time making a
messaging board, which is really cool
where you have chats that fly back and
forth, but this is more of a direct send
to somebody. So you can come to this site,
you can connect your Nautilus wallet, you
can scan for messages. You can scan deep
for messages too if you want to. If you
want to see all your messages or your
historical, you can scan a custom range
for messages as well.
And the way it works is you put in the
recipient address a message you can
encrypt with a passcode. So essentially we
can do a 22 or a 10 character passcode.
And this just uses an encryption method
with that passcode and salt to encrypt it
on chain so that nobody can read your
message while it's there. And then I would
essentially find a way to, like, if I have
a communication with HQ, I'd say, hey, HQ,
our communication is, HQ is a big sexy
beast. It's my 22-character password. So I
know that every time HQ sends me a
message, I decrypt it with, HQ is a very
big sexy beast. There's ways that we can
do auto-decryption, but that involves a
little bit of revealing from the Nautilus
wallet onto there. And I think it's safer
this way, and it would require Captain
Nemo to do some tweaks on his end for
exposing decryption from the Nautilus
wallet.
So that's that. You fill that in. You
fill out a message lifetime, essentially,
of how long you want this message to last
for, up to 365 days, which is one erg, and
then it scales backwards in time exactly.
So two hours is 0.01 erg for the fee. And
that's it. You enter the recipient. You
hit Enter. And it builds a transaction.
You send it. And then after two hours, you
can come here to scan. And then anybody,
and originally I was going to make this
just for miners to do, but anybody can
come to this site, fair game if they get
to it first, and can build a transaction
to burn. And then that message is now
burnt off the blockchain to be cleaned up
with some incentive to do it. So right
now, in 3.8 days, somebody has sent a
message. It's going to be burnt for 0.03
ergs they can burn it for and collect
whatever that 0.2 is after the transaction
fee.
So that's up and that's out of my hands.
The HTML can be downloaded and looked at
and rebuilt and taken somewhere else and
reformed. It doesn't matter. They're all
out there. And that's how easy, I think,
vibe coding connecting to Ergo is, right?
It was able to read the Nautilus SDK
libraries, the Ergo mobile libraries. It
was able to embed Wasm into the, at least
the site app that I used, which makes it a
little large, and all be self-contained so
that you could just upload one HTML file.
The site and the say are like four
megabytes for an HTML file. The Enfermo
messaging is like 400k, or maybe it's like
200k. It's extremely small, because I only
have Nautilus integrated into it. But
yeah, yeah. So that's me, guys. That's
what I've been banging out, just trying to
make some kind of unstoppable apps that
could be done quickly, vibe-coded, and
thrown on IPFS. What about you guys?
Well, I have a new feature for you to
add.
Let's hear it, sir.
So for a formal message, instead of using
the passcode, you could use the sender
private PK. So right. So if there is
message for someone, they can see that
there is message, but they have to sign a
TX and provide their private key. And when
they provide their private key, it matches
with the message. the token you have
minted. So that's how they can see the
message.
Yeah, so the issue there, I think, from
when I was coding is that, first of all,
the person has to have done a transaction
on chain, right? But in that case, they're
only putting their public key up on chain
for that transaction or something like
that. There was some issue from what I
tried to understand that Nautilus can't
expose enough during the signing
transaction. And the person sending the
message doesn't know enough about the
receiver to be able to encode something
that the person could then prove against
and sign kind of thing when you're doing
the initial encryption by the sender. So
that was what I ran into and how I
understood it. Maybe, kushti, do you
understand this better, HQ?
Yeah, I think there are pleat options for
it. I think it's go to address and I go
address to PK, which can be used to
convert because you are already providing
the sender address. So it can convert that
into the, into the PK, which will instead
of using the address, and then you can
just extract and mismatch matching between
the boxes or in your case, you are just
doing with tokens. So instead of ending
the description of the token, there will
be instead of address, there will be the
public PK of that address and that user
has to validate somehow. So that would be
one way to doing it, but yeah, I like the
way you do it. It's the more simpler way.
Yeah, it's simpler. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And
then I'll look into that again. I'll take
another stab at it, that's for sure. We'll
see what we can do. What about you, HQ?
What's the recent thing besides the
Android app that you built? So we're
talking with AI, right? Yeah, yeah, AI,
yeah.
So the last thing, I think the cart. 50%
of the cart, the front end was done with
AI. The back end logic for chain
transaction and everything was done
written manually, but most of the front
end stuff was done with AI.
For what, which app?
At MuMart, we have included a new feature
where you can bulk list and you can bulk
buy. Right, right. So there is a shopping
cart you can go and, and actually I forgot
to mention you that there is another
option on Mart. So instead of check mark,
you can just drag and drop those NFTs.
Let's show people. Where is it? MuMart,
NFTMart? MuFinance, yeah. So if we go here
and we look at these, we can click on,
where's the button that we can multiple
select there? Where'd you go, HQ?
In the bottom corner, you will see a blue
button. Just click on that. And then you
can just drag any of those NFTs into the
cart.
Not coming up for me. I see a yellow plus
button at the bottom, mart.mufinance.com.
You have to go to your slash explore, not
on the main screen.
OK, slash explore. OK, perfect. Yep, yep,
yep. So we click that. We check a bunch of
boxes. All right, now we're showing people
here. So if we want to buy those three,
then we go to our cart. Look at that.
That's so cute. And then it pops over on
the right, insufficient balance. Oh, no, I
don't have enough. I don't have enough
CYPX for these. And then, oh, you even do
buy more on your DEX. Then buy five
orders. So it's going to do five
transactions, right, if that's what you
had said before? But that's just how UTXO
and the smart contract works right for
that. So yeah. So instead of having to
click, refresh, go back, do the thing, you
can load them all up in the cart, hit buy,
sign a couple transactions, and be done.
That seems very convenient, sir.
Yeah, and instead of clicking on check
marking them, if you just like press the
NFT and drag the NFT to the shopping cart,
it will also add it to your cart.
Let's see. Oh, look at that, sir. Look at
that. Isn't that cute? Super cute. Nice
job, HQ.
That's 60 lines of code just for people
so they don't have to select.
When I code, I code very simple scripts.
I code in Perl, I code in HTML and
JavaScript, but we're talking like that
10,000 lines of code was absolutely
stupid, ridiculous. Most of them are like
500, 600 lines per script. If I get up to
1,000 or 2,000, that's a little too much
to take control in my liking. I want
something that's like 10 kilobytes. I want
it to load immediately because we're
dealing with IPFS as well. So I wanted to
come across the meeting. So I don't
usually run into an issue where I'm AI
coding, and I can't get something fixed,
or I run out of tokens fast. I know I'm on
the pro plan for Claude and ChatGPT Pro,
but I don't run into that issue ever. But
I hear people who have these big Node.js
sites with 30, 40 files in it can run out
pretty fast when they're trying to debug.
How do you guys do that when you're
running these bigger applications and more
complex things?
Doing what? Sorry.
So when I program, I'm writing small
scripts. My code is under 1,000 lines.
It's very easy. I don't run out of tokens.
It's very easy for Claude to ingest and
work on it. But when I hear about other
people running big Node.js apps or these
large applications, running out of tokens
or getting in a spot where there's just
too much for the AI to tokenize and bring
in, how do you guys get around that when
you're doing it? Or are you just focusing
on small things as well?
So usually you need to do specs all the
time and work through specs with an agent
like QuantCode, for example. So, actually,
bro etiquette has a lot of experience here
and he is working in particular on Git
circles. Using that approach, so first you
do a spec, right? Well, also, mostly with
an agent. And then using the spec, you are
working piece by piece on some specific
part of software. And so, yeah, by doing
that, you are managing the context window,
right, because, well, if too much things
there in context windows, so you are
getting worse results in code generation.
And Fitz, what is your experience? Are you
playing with basis tracker or with testing
scripts for basis?
Yeah, I have been. It's been pretty fun,
actually. I kind of remember a quote that
you said about taking over Ergo as much as
possible, and it kind of gives me this
feeling. So I've just been using Cloud
Code. I don't have extensive coding
experience. But yeah, I think the spec is
right. I mean, you've got to get it. For
me, personally, I just got to get it. It
has to know what it's aiming for. And
definitely, the prompt has to be, you have
to have a well-defined prompt. But it was
pretty easy, honestly, to get the basis
and do a test, like a Alice, Carol, Bob
type test. And it ran it for me. I'd just
been doing that for the last day or so.
Honestly, it's been a lot of fun. And I
think it gets me thinking about a lot of
other things I could do with Ergo.
So some other things I did that we can do
as well. Sorry, I don't mean to jump on
the horn again, but I forgot to say it. So
this is something that was Vibe-coded for
the SigmaNuts mining pool, right?
Essentially, I took an old app I had for
the mining pool, a very simple one, and
gave it all the APIs of mining core,
everything else, and told it to have at
it, make it look nice, make it look
functional. And it actually did a pretty
amazing job doing what it needs to do
there, showing all miners. We can go to
this miner. We can select a certain C. We
can see their payouts, all that kind of
stuff.
But one thing, too, that I wanted to
mention, the main reason I brought this up
is because then I did this. I said, guys,
we had a server go down, right? And I
said, guys, why don't we do this? So I
took right here, I took my file in my
repo. I'd like to fully host this on IPFS.
Is it possible to convert fully to HTML
JavaScript instead of HTML JavaScript
Perl? There we go. It explores it, does
it, creates it, does some changes. There
was an issue with one of the
click-throughs. And then there was another
issue with something else for a minor.
They did some changes. Boom. That's it.
And then it gave me an HTML file in my
GitHub that I could then throw up on IPFS
and hand to the miners, and they could
have it run serverless without that. So
that's some other cool stuff that I think
AI can do for you. Save you a ton of time
if you want to go from one platform to
another platform. I know I just went from
HTML JavaScript Perl to HTML JavaScript.
But still, that opened up the window to be
able to host it somewhere else fully. And
as you can see from Claude, it literally
took 10 minutes to convert an entire
working app to that kind of thing. So
that's a cool use case, too, that I've
found.
Yeah. And I know this might sound
non-trivial, but I honestly had a hard
time setting up a node and doing
interactions with the node. Now I just
feel like I can vibe code whatever I'd
like for the most part. I mean, of course,
there's constraints I have to go through,
but it definitely feels like an entry
barrier has been decreased. So you can
actually have fun.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, once Claude
understands the node endpoints, I mean,
it's like game over, right? You show it
what the endpoints are, what it produces,
and it does more than you could remember
to do at that point.
Exactly, yeah.
I had an issue with the Explorer running
on peer-to-peer machines, which are 32
gigs of RAM and one terabyte hard drive.
There's some massive queries that HQ and
ACO keep throwing at me that some of them
can't do. So with Claude and ChatGPT,
putting them in there, letting them watch
the terminal, and seeing the outputs or
pasting in the outputs of certain things,
it allowed me to do something that I've
never done before, which is to identify
where the SQL commands are coming in, the
Postgres commands are coming in, what
they're getting stuck on, what it's
hanging on, and then giving me the codes
to actually build a freaking index to
account for those large queries. And so
far, we've got three new indexes that
we've built on peer-to-peer, the
peer-to-peer infra that is still, I think,
I haven't checked the status, but I know
that a couple of people have installed
them on their machines already. But that
would have been impossible without AI. I
mean, absolutely impossible. We'd have to
find somebody like, what's his name,
Boris, who hardly answers his DMs to help
us out with that since he's kind of an
expert in that field. But yeah, with AI,
it's done in half an hour and tested and
deployed.
Yeah, and we are discussing a lot these
days in the developers' chat how to use
LLMs to improve things here and there. So
in particular, it seems... So I've used
LLMs to verify user contracts before
deployment and yeah, it's working well.
Actually, if you manage contracts
properly, so we had some discussions with
Rob. As a result, and yeah, I think we can
actually release some files with a
description of, well, popular problems
developers, well, mistakes developers are
doing in scripts and then, yeah, well,
they can be efficiently verified. So it's
much simpler than with EVM contracts and
so on. Because yeah, here is the approach
is simple and verification is also quite
simple and manageable for LLMs. So, yeah,
well, audit also can be done.
Right, so you've spoken for quite a while
now, kushti, of saying that you're running
iterated tests via AI. You're figuring out
ways to test your code or at least
security test your code some ways with
LLMs?
Yeah, so for our contracts, it's possible
to find some issues, at least because
usually it's about two or three vectors.
Usually all the issues known to the moment
can be categorized. Well, in a very simple
way. So usually it's about the developer
forgetting to check some register.
Correspondence from inputs or outputs,
right? just basically a human mistake,
quite trivial for LLM to detect and
report. And then another issue is, well,
possibility to spend two inputs with one
output, right, when it's not planned. That
was found in production in some Cardano
applications in Ergo. That wasn't
exploited or publicly reported, but yeah,
that's quite a popular issue and stated
even in the ErgoScript white paper. And
yeah, it's also quite easy for LLM to
figure out this kind of mistake made by
developer.
And then for testing, for doing off-chain
tests like Amitabh did a lot for Dexy and
so on. Yeah, that's also much easier,
quite trivial to do with. So this day, so
I did some tests for chain cash contracts
basically for free. Yeah, for four basis
also. There are some contributors like
Arcadia doing now some tests with LLMs
probably without scala knowledge even,
right? So, well, LLMs is just mutating
test factors. And yeah, that's also quite
helpful. So before a few years ago, we
spent many days for doing such mutations
manually. Then, yeah, well, with tests for
contracts, you can find also some issues,
right, when you're developing contracts.
And then, yeah, for the node itself, so
got better testing coverage. And, yeah,
for Sigma interpreter also with LLMs. So
they're working quite well when you
already have vast testing code base. So
when you have like 300 tests, it's quite
trivial to derive another one, right? So
yeah, that's where LLMs are working
perfectly.
And while you're talking, kushti, I'm
just going through all the stuff on
Degen's world that he's built so far,
that's accompanying your voice. Pretty
neat stuff.
Yeah, then developing some trivial
contracts, right? Like, well, from a
coding point of view, probably ErgoScript
is not quite complex, right? But then you
need to develop off-chain part and with
LLMs it's now trivial because well, it's
also quite simpletizable, quite
straightforward to generate after studying
existing examples.
Well, I would like to shout out our two
new devs we have, thanks to the vibe
coding. So we have Michael, who is vibe
coding, and also we have CannonQ, who's
working on some stuff.
Oh, right. Yeah, so Bro Etiquette,
Arcadia, and more, yeah.
Well, you guys are chatting. Let me go to
development and try to find CannonQ's
site. What's it called, HQ?
I think he did. It's cyberverse.app.
Yeah, but I think if you go to new dev, I
think there is this link for it.
Yeah, but I thought CannonQ had a name
for it. It's like Wallet History or
something like that. No.
I think he built two different things. He
built that one thing for cyberverse,
another thing was for the Wallet History.
OK, here's Cyberverse Viewer. Let me put
that up. Let's see how that looks,
everybody. So he built this. Oh, that's a
fast load. He's slow. Nice. Very cool.
Yeah, so he's got Cyberverse Viewer here.
Very cool. Do you know if he's using the
CDN from Auction House that this stuff
loads nicely?
No, I think he has the map. Oh,
fantastic.
Yeah, because it is fast loading. That's
really awesome. Dang. Amazing. Who else?
Who does the Cyberverse Wiki, right?
Doesn't somebody else?
Leximon, but he, I think, is not with us
anymore, at least in the chats.
OK. All right, so this is a kind of at
least take up from that. But this is
awesome, yeah. And then CannonQ also built
the kind of tax collector stuff, where you
can put in a range of time. And
essentially, it tells you what your tokens
and Ergo have done in that amount of time
kind of thing. So that's a pretty neat
feature as well. Nothing like trying to
murder all the nodes and stuff.
Oh, and I forgot about this, guys.
Yes. So it's becoming...
I have a question. So talking about AI
agents, is there any way we can have AI
agent on chain which can execute stuff
based on logic? You just provide them?
Yeah, but what does it mean on-chain?
I mean that the AI agent is on-chain. For
example, it's a smart contract on-chain
where you send something like maybe a
signal of something and the bot, instead
of the smart contract logic, it also runs
the AI logic to it. I know it's a super
solution.
Yeah, but that's AI logic is off chain,
right? So usually it's when people are
talking about AI on chain. So usually it's
about some trusted gateway to trusted. I
don't write.
So I'm clicking through on the screen.
You guys can't see it on Zoom. But the
Simple Explorer that I built with ChatGPT,
maybe like eight months ago. And then I
just recently revamped it with Claude a
little bit to make it a little better. And
it uses, what's it called? It uses the CDN
from Auction House to find NFTs that
they're holding and caching. So at least
for now, NFT should load fairly fast. And
I was going to look at, let's see, I was
going to try to show you an example of
that. Let's look for that.
So you can just type in a wallet, or an
address, or a token ID, or a transaction
ID, just like ErgExplorer, and it knows
which one it is and lists it. So let's
take an old NFT that we probably know
shouldn't be anywhere like Cyberverse
1129. Boom, there, it loads perfectly
well. And it loads from Ergo Auction House
content delivery network, as opposed to
the IPFS. Yeah, this one doesn't look like
it, so it's going to try IPFS, and it's
probably been too long to where it's been
un-pinned from an IPFS site. So some of
them will not load, ever, unless they're
re-pinned somehow. Oh, it's a kushti
Cyberverse skin. Look at that, kushti.
That's one of my favorites. Did you know
you're on Cyberverse? You have an Ergo
piece of armor on, kushti?
Uh, no, I don't know.
For all the stuff I have done for
Cybervese when I'm not even in the museum.
No, I know the museum's a little old,
right? When the game was open, I went to
the museum and I was standing with a
chilling friend. And I was like, okay,
he's here and I'm not here.
Do we know if Heroes used any AI? I wish
Heroes was here. It'd be nice if Heroes
watching. Please hop in. But what's it
called? I remember my password. It'd be
amazing if... Sorry, I can't hear myself
because I just opened up Cyberverse and
it's blasting. It's blasting in my ear.
Let me mute it. OK. It'd be amazing if
Hiro would let us know how much AI is
involved in his game creation now, right?
Because they just actually, and for those
of you on Zoom that can't see this, I'm in
Cyberverse right now streaming on the
right-hand side. They integrated the betas
up for the early people that can hop in
and test. And Pixel gave me access to it.
And this is a new section right here for
combat. Let me see. I'll go in real
quickly, and I will enter this part and
get the crap kicked out of me by some
squirrely guy. Yep. Yeah. Oh, boy. Yeah,
I'm going to run away. So I'd love to see.
Hiro, if you're watching this at some
point, or Mr. Pixel, if you could comment
or tell us exactly how much AI is involved
in any of your coding. I know probably not
with the artwork, right? You guys are
painstakingly hand-drawing all the
artwork. But with integration or anything
like that, how are you guys embracing AI?
That would be neat to know. Do you guys
know? You guys hear anything, HQ?
No, I have never talked about development
side of Cyberverse.
Gotcha. Gotcha. Yeah, that's that. Very
cool. We'll leave that up. That's a good
picture to have. It's such a beautiful
game. What else, guys? We got some class.
Yeah, go for it, kushti.
Yeah, so now it's easier and easier to
develop applications, right, on-chain
applications. So then it's changing, well,
economics of the process, right? So, well,
no need in most cases now to issue those
stupid tokens, like DEV tokens, right?
Because, well, it's becoming easier and
easier to do all that stuff. But yeah, I
mean, people are creating millions of meme
coins anyway, so those dev tokens are also
probably going to this category quite
soon. But if we are talking about some
serious applications useful for the real
world, then probably we need to think
about economic implications and how to
build economies around those imagined
possibilities.
Right, you said something on Twitter the
other day, kushti, that says, if there's
100 times more developers being able to
code on blockchains, then the only thing
that stands out among blockchains now is
the fundamentals of the blockchain, or
something like that. What was your quote?
Do you remember what that was?
Right, yeah, so ideas and yeah, they
soundness, right? So you need for solid
ideas and you need to be focused right on
principles. So solid foundations and
principles and well, the ideas should be
sound economically and monetary wise,
right? Because after all, the whole space
is mostly about money, right? Doing money
while optimistically producing better
forms of money than we have today. So
yeah, that's what does matter and well,
doing token for Web3 somewhat application
just because you want to dump this token
on others.
Yeah, it's... Wasn't there a dump of the
New York City token the other day or
whatever that was of Mayor Eric Adams? I
didn't get to the bottom of it to see how
legitimate it was, but
But that's about meme, right? There are a
lot of dev tokens and I think for them
there is need to consider well, soundness
also, right?
Yeah, but I think we're going to see at
some point with the people's ability to
make these. I mean, you can spin up a pump
fun site or something like that in a
matter of minutes now, right? So you might
see more deployment of those kind of
things at some point. Once the people
hungry for rugs and meme coins start doing
that more, you're going to see more shit
like that, I imagine. Maybe more hacks as
well. I mean, I can, I'd be afraid to, I'd
be afraid to vibe code on Ethereum
network. I don't know. Sorry. Go HQ.
I have a, let's say, I'm not sure if a EF
will be able to handle any Ergo hack this
year because of knowing the funds they
have remaining. So now that we are talking
about AI and what do you guys think if on
the main Ergo platform and GitHub, we just
create another branch with multiple
languages, let's say with SVELTE, Node.js
and different frameworks with projects,
simple projects with MD files with how to
sign transactions, how this works, how to
do that and create a simple hackathon
based on AI. So people have to build a
simple app using the frameworks which are
already there. So there is a base which
has wallet connection and everything, but
they have to build on top of it. So maybe
it would be nice to have a small kind of
hackathon for AI based stuff so people can
build stuff and it doesn't need to be a
bigger price for it. So maybe a small
price for all the people who participate
and see how people actually use AI and how
what apps can be built. So if outcome of
that, there is one app which is liked by
many community. So we could just grab that
app and make it more decentralized and
make it much cleaner. So having some
templates up with some readme.md with all
how transaction works and all that would
be easier for all the vibe coders which
are looking for blockchains one way to
develop on.
No, I agree, HQ. I think it would have
been because I have to essentially harvest
code every time I want to teach Claude how
to do a wallet connection or how to do
that. So it would be amazing if I could
just point him to a repo that's been tried
and tested and fixed that says, hey,
here's how we connect in JS. Here's how we
connect in Perl. Here's how we connect in
Swift. Here's how all this works kind of
thing.
Just have four different frameworks.
Let's say, then we have a simple HTML.
There are people who would like to build
on HTML. You have built on HTML and using
Fleet. So yeah, so just have a simpler
templates there for them so people can
just fork them and work on it. And then
you see all the activity it can bring on
chain also in all the development for the
new people who are interested in these
kind of things.
Yeah, but definitely save tokens and
time, that's for sure.
Yeah. Yeah, and so for AI-focused
hackathon, actually, we had one in
December. So that was unstoppable
hackathon in Jaipur. And so, yeah, there
were some Ergo-related applications, such
as updated visual coding tool. And more,
so me and Bruno are still, well, messing
with doing previous bit because, well,
most of applications were, well, vibe
coded again by students, right? And yeah,
well, a lot of them. And also, well, many
repositories are now full of vibe coded
pull requests, but yeah, usually it's low
quality slop there, but there are about
100 pull requests created in all the
repositories according to CannonQ. And
yeah, well, I've reviewed only like three
of them and two reviewed by Dusik to the
moment. So yeah, well, it's another side,
right? So it's cheap to produce code, but
well, if you're talking about core
repositories, then yeah, usually we need
higher quality than LLMs are capable.
Then for core repositories we now have
the interpreter and also the node
repositories. The code there now contains
agents.md file which is prohibiting to use
AI agents in main codes, non-testing. So,
well, agents may produce tests only
according to those rules for agents. But
yes, such rules are respected by some
tooling like Claude code, Quen code, Krush
and so on. But not all the tools even
respect those rules. So yeah, it's quite a
dynamic landscape, right? And yeah, so for
hackathons, I think, well, it's maybe
better to do, well, hackathons with
external partners, like unstoppable,
right? So that was quite an exciting
experience. Yeah, we've got hundreds of
students now, well, having some idea about
Ergo Blockchain. That's quite nice.
Oh, I got a question for all of you guys,
the vibe code. So imagine you run, you
know, you're in control of several repos,
right, with complex code. Now, I was
reading an article, not an article, a post
on Reddit maybe a couple of weeks ago
about somebody who's a maintainer of a
project that's on there that's somewhat
popular. And he said that the most
annoying thing that he sees is when, now
that there's a vibe coding around, that
there are so many pull requests with just
script kiddies or whatever, people don't
understand code, just putting it into AI
and recommending changes on the code or
feature additions and that kind of thing.
And he said he finds that his time is so
much more taken up with either ignoring
these things or actually seeing if they'll
work and that kind of thing, as opposed to
somebody who knows what they're doing and
knows how to really suggest changes in
PRs. What are your thoughts on that and
how busy that could become for a
maintainer of a project?
Yeah, that's true. So that's quite
challenging, right? So yeah, we also have
people coming with vibe coded pull
requests for the nodes or Sigma state
interpreter. And yeah, usually, well, it's
just slop, right? So quality is terrible
and the pull requests are not achieving
goals specified simply.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, even before that,
though, I mean, you'd have people submit
pull requests that weren't great and
hardly had to be checked kind of thing.
Even just with the language translations
we had to deal with, there were some
things there with that massive amount of
files, yeah, file that you had to go
through. But yeah. Yeah, I get it. Well,
HQ had to leave us. Let me check and see
if there's any questions that are besides
price talk in the chat.
Byron wants to know when Gluon is,
kushti. Let's see, anything else? Somebody
mentioned Deco? Yeah, we love Deco. Ergo
the Argonian commented on Deco, how it
hasn't been around for a bit. But that was
fantastic, listening to the Cheese and
LGD. Some of the videos are still out
there, guys, and LGD's been around a long
time. He's been on a couple videos lately
even. There's a video from the Meetup
where he explains Gluon. I think he also
has another presentation that he did for
Gluon recently, even after the Ergo
Meetup. So they're still around with that
kind of stuff, which is great.
You know what I'd love to do? You know
what I built for? Let me see if I can get
this up for you guys. I would love to be
able to get Cheese and LGD's voice, and
also Marty, those three, those
combinations. And I would love to do this.
So I built this based on ChatterTTS. It's
a Python PyTorch library that runs on a
machine with two 3090s right here next to
me, actually, in Iraq. So you take a
reference voice right here and you put in
a bunch of text, and it generates a pretty
darn accurate output of that person's
voice. So it would be amazing if maybe we
could fundraise and get LGD or Cheese to
be able to take text-based tutorials, and
we could make AI content out of them with
their voice kind of thing in that theme of
Deco. I know some people might think
that's a little creepy, but we're actually
using this here on the campus for a
specific medical reason that we're testing
out and on. And it seems to work really
well for people with speech difficulties.
But there are other opportunities as well.
Somebody wrote me after I released it and
says, hey, I do these tutorials online.
And I can't get through two seconds of
this thing or or, so I'd love to be able
to just use this kind of tool. So I'd love
to use this for DECO, you know, take tech
space, put the familiar voices of cheese
and LGD on there and go from there. Even
kushti, we could take your voice.
And the really cool thing about this as
well is we can convert them to different
languages too. So we can do multilingual
here, and we can choose different
languages. We can switch to Russian. If we
paste Russian text in here, it'll take my
voice and speak Russian. It'll take
kushti's voice and speak English or that
kind of thing. So I think that would be a
really cool tool for blending with Deco or
whatever that is. Just my two cents there
boys.
Well, in the developer's chat, there is a
guy, x10zyn, who is doing a Sigma book.
He's going through a few repositories and
documentation and creating a book on how
ErgoScript is working under the hood, the
Sigma layer. And yeah, it's actually in
some parts quite beautiful. And he is,
well, analyzing with agents the code in
scala, mostly rust also, and generating
snippets for his book in Zic language. So
you can translate, well, not in human
languages, but also in computer languages
also. So yeah, that's great. And well,
going back to, well, 100x more developers
and ideas, I think we need to revive work
on Ergo book, right? So well, to outline
the path, how to get better money for the
real-world needs. From those ideas, people
can work with AI agents also, with or
without AI agents that they can develop
from the, well, ideas from the Ergo book.
So I need to ping, guys working on that,
so Joe, Greyman, and yeah, I'm also
inviting Martin, so yeah.
Very cool. And Grayman's already written
a couple chapters.
He has written some pieces on silver and
history of US monetary system, including
pre-fed era. So yeah, quite interesting.
Very cool. All right, guys, well, five
minutes over. I think kushti, you're
interested in the spaces next time? Was
that your proposal?
I don't know. So let's do maybe chain
cache basis-related spaces. How about that
next Thursday then?
I'm down. That sounds fun.
All right. That sounds good, guys. So
stay tuned for Spaces on Chain Cache
featuring Fitz and kushti.
Yeah, we will invite more guys, so Joe
maybe, and so on.
Perfect. Awesome. All right, guys, thanks
for joining. Don't be afraid to speak up
in the developer chat. Even if you're vibe
coding, nobody shames there. Don't feel
embarrassed to do that. Everybody's
learning, and everybody's welcome, that's
for sure. Thanks so much, Fitz, kushti,
and HQ for joining today.
Thank you very much. And thank you guys
for the patience, too. Like you said, the
vibe coding, actually, it's been - It's
been like I haven't got any judgment. So
it's been awesome just to build. So yeah,
it's been a pleasure, too.
Amazing. All right. Thanks, guys. Ciao.
Take it easy, everybody.
Yeah. Thank you, everyone. Bye.
Keep in touch.